well welcome back folks so we are
looking at a rather brief overview of
the importance of journaling
and while I could have made this an
extremely long video I took more time
actually doing
the annotations then this presentation
will actually take to cover it but I
don't want you to discount
the measure of importance
that this topic has because
all of my profitable students everyone
has found their consistent model
everyone that knows exactly what they're
doing within price action whether it be
a day Trader's capacity short-term
Trader position Trader swing Trader
whatever it is
they went through this process they
didn't go through
a rushed pace of going out there and
trying to get
real profits before they were ready
and they spent time with this
before actually trying to demo trade or
paper trade
so if you'll give me a few minutes to
kind of like lay down some Foundation
here it's really important that you
listen to this part especially if you're
a new student or if you are a student
that has yet to find consistency
I promise you it's this very thing
that you're not doing and you're
probably not doing it long enough for
your personal
unique experience to
basically identify what it is that you
want to be Trading
often there are students that will come
to me and they'll watch just a few of my
videos
or they'll watch something new that I I
released for the first time and teach on
that specific element of my trading
style they want to rush into it thinking
they understand every aspect of it
and they don't really incorporate this
part of it
because it's very easy to get lost
in the chaos of price action when you're
just looking for one little thing
one component one little
Cog in the wheel
that makes this machine go
and that being as simple as a fair value
Gap
an order block an optimal trade entry a
breaker any one particular thing
in and of itself is not enough
you have to have a
well-rounded approach to reading price
action and the only way you're going to
get that and it's not by watching my
videos
it's not by watching other people's
videos it's not watching me trade live
or even watching my examples
it's by you going into the charts doing
this very thing tonight
now
admittedly
I can understand how some of you
probably the majority of you
are going to watch this video and think
you've already said this before or
that's all well and good but I don't
have time for this I need to make money
or I got to get to the point and find
the trade set up for myself and you'll
be like one of those in my community
where they'll complain
that they don't know how to find their
model or they can't read price action or
they're confused about where price is
going to go next or
they'll be asking me after I get
something correct in terms of where I
call the Market immediately they want to
go in and ask me what next
the folks that do this
part of it
this aspect of learning how to read
price action which is
back testing now back testing again is
to me it's not about taking a trade
it's not about going back air and using
a Forex replay or a market replay or
Market replay reports if you're using
ninjatrader
if you're just going back and looking at
the numbers
okay I want to talk to a crowd that uses
ninjatrader
you might see
folks out there on YouTube or other
mediums on social media and they'll post
Market replay reports and it says
this is how many trades were taken both
long and short and here's the net
results and you're just seeing the
numbers
unless you know what it is that you're
doing
why that specific
price action should be delivering the
way it should be or how to identify it
that allows you to go in and repeat that
same procedure that protocol that would
establish a reason to assume that the
Market's going to go higher or lower why
should the market go higher and lower
why should the market go to a discount
from a premium or from a premium to a
discount
those factors
in price action are critical
for you to be able to be successful and
consistent
but the secret recipe to all of this is
how much time you spend in a chart not
just simply gazing into it
with no real understanding of what it is
you should be looking for if that's
where you're at
if it looks like a foreign language to
you when you look at these candlesticks
I promise you it's because you have not
gone through the step that we're going
to cover tonight now I talked about it
in length over the years
and there are many ways to record
a journal experience for yourself
there are wonderful apps out there I'm
not going to name them by name because
you're going to assume I have some
affiliation with them which I have no
affiliation with any company
I don't get Kickbacks I don't get
affiliate link
bonuses or I don't get any kind of
financial Kickback from any company or
anything that I say if I like something
it's the honest truth and I'm sharing
what I believe about it if I don't have
an affinity for insulting or if I say I
don't like something that's my opinion
and
I want to remain that way I get a lot of
offers by companies that want to do some
kind of affiliate program and I don't do
that because as soon as I do that that
makes me
well in my opinion
someone that would be viewed as
led to say something because of some
kind of payment that would be made to me
that's why I don't do any kind of
advertising that's why I don't do any
kind of affiliate marketing none of that
stuff and I can make a lot of money
doing that but I choose not to do that
because I want you to trust my opinion
when I say something about something in
particular whether it be
a broker an application some kind of
resource or whatever if I say something
it's
used by me and if I like it that company
that resource that
whatever it is the application they did
not pay me
and I wouldn't take anything from them
if they tried so it's a very honest way
of doing things and I like to do that
and everything that I do so that way
when you listen to me you can trust me
and one of those things tonight
is trust me when I tell you that this is
the very thing that you have not done
enough of if you haven't found
consistency yet
if you haven't found your model if you
haven't found the trust
in understanding what order flow is
my order flow not the things that we see
banded about in this industry as order
flow
everything in these candlesticks tells
you everything that you need you don't
need to know volume
you don't need to know what the v-wop is
you don't know where the pawning control
is you could care less
you just need to know where the
inefficiencies are and where are the
liquidity above and below and you need
to know the time of day and what day of
the week you're at
none of that has anything to do with an
indicator
none of it has anything to do with any
kind of gimmick
that you have to apply to your chart you
don't need any of that stuff
but this I promise you this is the very
thing that you have to spend the most
time doing in fact you're going to spend
the rest of your career doing this very
thing
if you want to run it like a business if
you want to be extremely precise
detail-oriented
consistent
this is how you get it
so we're looking at the NASDAQ and I'm
showing you the NASDAQ continuous chart
so
if you're a user of trading View and I
hope that you are because it makes
learning from me a lot easier
the symbol is NQ number one and the
exclamation point
okay so if you put that into the symbol
window on trading View
and you put it up
on a one month time frame you'll see
this very chart here
okay at the time of this recording this
is
the time I captured a chart and I worked
on it a few hours capturing all the
annotations working out the details to
show you this stuff so like I said I
spent more time doing
the actual slides then it would take you
to do the actual
procedure of doing it okay logging in
your annotations and making the hard
time frame PD arrays visible on the
lower time frame and then working with
them on a day by day basis and on the
weekend
referring back to each day now I'm not
going to do the individual days today
because for
the sake of brevity
and also for your homework I'm going to
give you all of the pertinent
PD arrays that you should use one of the
lower time frames that being the 15
minute time frame five minute time frame
all the way down to the one and if
you're so inclined
less than a one minute chart
so the same thing I'm using here you
would use for euro dollar
if you're a Forex Trader the dollar
Index
you could use this on the e-mini S P you
can use it on any commodity any Market
okay so we're doing a top-down approach
but we're doing it so that way we can
look at how the importance of the higher
time frame
down to the lower time frame and how the
pdra Matrix is utilized throughout the
time frame
higher to lower
so we're looking at the monthly chart
here
and I want you to take a look at this
and pause the video for a moment and
think about what it is that you identify
in the most recent months so in the last
few candles in here
what did price refer to and what is
presently in price that might be useful
going forward
if you don't pause the video I promise
you you're not getting the most out of
The Learning Experience
all right for the folks that
did not pause I'm going to show you now
all right so here's the monthly chart
and looking at the monthly time frame I
want you to see and that kind of like
this will be somewhat of a
a review
also is showing you an example how you
might want to journal so you want to
bring in your own unique personality to
this I'm just giving you
the basic approach to annotating your
chart and how you might record some
observations but you might want to
include a lot more
self-love okay something that you might
want to do in your annotations is
really write in those
types of comments that you saw it coming
even if you didn't really see it coming
you're conditioning your subconscious
by recording these pseudo experiences
that way you're tricking your brain into
seeing something at a later time
referring back to these as examples like
on the weekend or say a couple weeks ago
you'll look at your Journal
and by looking at them with these
annotations and reading them out again
your brain sees these PD arrays and the
PD arrays are things like
the ferry Gap here
the breaker here
you're probably asking yourself you know
how could this be a breaker well we had
a high here
we dropped down and then we went higher
when the lower time frames this would
look obvious
as a breaker but this is also a down
closed candle prior to this runoff so
essentially it is a mitigation block
Breakers are mitigation by default
so
whether you identify that as a breaker
which is or if you just want to refer to
it as a mitigation block you'd be
correcting in either case
the high that candle is the monthly
bearish breaker High
and the low of that candle is the
monthly bearish breaker low
this candle is low
and this candle is high
makes the fair value Gap in the form of
a sibi South Side imbalance by side
inefficiency it means it's a down candle
that creates the fair Vega a very short
way of saying it
the market creates a fair value Gap here
in the form of a buy side of balance
outside inefficiency
this candle's High to this candle's low
the fair value Gap was formed with buy
side delivery in other words it's an up
closed candle that makes the fair value
Gap
this is something future
this is something that's already
happened
so over in The annotation section this
is something that I would
humbly submit and obviously I've seen
some of my students that are extremely
detail-oriented and they're absolutely
stunning in terms of how they annotate
their charts how they record their
observations just the just the overall
neatness and well-rounded presentation
of recording what it is they see in the
chart that's useful to them just a
beautiful illustration and approach to
doing it and many of them share by way
of Twitter
and
while I do believe that this part of
your journey should be kept private
you want to include over here some of
the personal things that
you want to include for that particular
time frame or that market
this is also why I teach
that you should only really be focusing
on specializing on one market
now you might have support behind the
very markets you're trading by using the
dollar index for instance and that that
serves you well whether it be an index
Trader like I'm showing an example of
here
or a Forex Trader
and or a commodity Trader because the
dollar Index is going to have a lot of
impact on all three of those types of
markets
but in your annotations for instance
I'll just read this out here
the NQ monthly journal entry
the NQ monthly continuous contract has
rallied strong from October 22.
blows right here
why did this Rally from here you can
include that traded down into this buy
Side imbalanced Sales sign and
efficiency which is a fair value Gap and
swept the sell side rate below that low
that's how much you can include you can
include all this in here
but for the sake of brevity
and also just to review and also show
you what might happen going into the
future from the time of this recording
I'm only including what's
Salient right now
I was anticipating the down closed
candle on September of 2021 to provide
characteristics of a ICT bearish breaker
that's this candle I'm referring to
there
it was long overdue for a down close
monthly candle after five months of buy
side delivery and price that means all
of this movement here
so it's reasonable to anticipate at the
time of this recording it's August
so we traded up five months being from
this down close candle so you have one
two three four five
and then in August because this is July
here August it's reasonable to
anticipate
August creating a down close candle it
does not need to close
lower
but we can anticipate the delivery of
price like this because we've had so
many up close candles
and we traded up into a breaker and we
fulfilled the redelivery to all this
down close candles range between this
candle's low and this candle is high
it's going lower right well inside that
shaded area we expect price to deliver
upside or buy side delivery not buy side
liquidity buy side delivery it means
this movement higher to overlap this
area over here when it painted lower you
want to see candles painted higher so
that gives us
a repricing
not necessarily
rebalanced yet
it has to leave this area on the lower
time frames
to be
rebalanced
so notice what I said here I said that I
was anticipating the down closed candle
on September 2021 to provide
characteristics of a ICT bearish breaker
now this statement was true for me
personally
but for you that might not be the case
referring that I can't you may not have
even referred to that candle at all in
your analysis you may not even notice
that or paid any mind to it
in your charts when you're back testing
and journaling you're going to be doing
this very thing here
you're going to be recording as if you
did you're going to use language like
this I was anticipating the down closed
candle on September 2021 to provide
characteristics of an ICT bearish
breaker what this is implying is
you felt when it reached up into this
area in here between these two heavy red
levels
that there would be some measure of a
draw to it and then where inside between
these two levels here the breaker low
and the breaker High where is their
liquidity well that would be right above
these highs here which are relatively
equal
any of the inefficiency in here
so is it required
for price to come all the way up to the
breaker High we don't want to see that
that's one of the rules about that
pattern or that very PD array
we don't want to see it trade to the
high it can
but we don't want to see that
so
in this range here we see the
inefficiency
and we trade it into the breaker this
down closed candle
and in your chart where you have spaces
where you at least have to Make spaces
in your chart so you have to scale your
time axis and your price access
to allow for you can annotate
now for me
this is enough to give you an example
but I want you to take away from this
the language I'm using here
I am very pleased to see price open near
the high of the present August 2023
monthly candle subsequent delivery of
lower price
the enqueue is showing respect of the
January 2022 fair value Gap sibi
which is located inside the range of the
ICT bearish breaker meaning that
I'm pleased that it's doing this very
thing this is a monthly candle for
August of 2023. it opened moved up just
a little bit it's barely very hard to
see but then it trades lower
after trading into and closing in the
month of July this fair value Gap sibi
that's what this is saying here and
notice what I'm using again the terms
that are very emotionally
positive
they're not
communicating confusion they're not
recording moments where you were
frustrated you're never recording
anything like that in your Journal
you're never doing that
do not use your journal to record scary
thoughts
don't record
periods of confusion or feeling like you
just don't know
you're cheerleading yourself and you're
annotating these charts as you do it
now for some of you that are male you're
going to have a problem with this right
away I know some of you are like this is
a waste of time especially if you're one
of the Macho type I ain't got time to
journal ICT I got money to make okay
that's fine
but the majority of you that want to do
this correctly will do these types of
things
and your brain is extremely powerful it
is the fastest it is the most powerful
computer that will ever exist because it
has a personality attached to it
a computer can only do what a computer
is programmed to do that's it it can
make calculations it can reason within
logic that it's supplied
but you
you can create
you can imagine you can regret
you can
feel good so you have an emotional
stimuli that's associated with your
previous learning experiences and your
future learning experiences so in your
Journal you want to filter out every
negative aspect that's not to say that
you can't observe things that you didn't
do correctly or that you felt
that you didn't see coming
always recorded like you did
if you had something that you did
incorrectly
okay if you have a moment in price
action where you know you were there
that day and you were literally looking
at price and you thought something was
going to happen a specific way
you want to record it in a way where it
sounds like this
this is a wonderful opportunity for me
to improve upon this area here because I
thought price would do XYZ or whatever
it would be that you're looking at that
you thought for instance maybe you
thought that in the morning session buy
side liquidity was going to be taken but
it never ran for buy side and went the
opposite direction
so in your Journal you could record
something like
I'm grateful that I had the opportunity
to learn why that the sell side was
attacked over the buy side today
see what I just did there I disarmed
that pain and frustration that you
probably felt by watching real-time
price action
but didn't see it deliver like you
wanted it to but then you go in and you
annotate the chart
and I'm seeking hypothetically here as
an example because it's not being shown
here on this chart
but you want to be able to record it in
a way where it doesn't hurt you it
doesn't hurt you psychologically it
doesn't form a memory or um
a monument to a period of confusion you
don't ever want to do that
because if you do those types of things
and that's what many of you do with
social media you'll complain and say
this is hard this is too complicated I'm
never going to do this you know I'm I'm
struggling and I'm about to quit
whenever you do that you're doing the
opposite the Very extreme opposite of
what it is that you should be doing
your Journal is your best cheerleading
vehicle
and it's also a way for you to build the
most powerful trading money making
manual you'll ever have in your hands
and you wrote it yourself
so buying books is not the answer buying
courses is not the answer
trying to trade and follow me tick by
tick real time is not the answer this is
the answer this is the thing that you're
supposed to be doing this is the thing
that most of you
will not do long enough to be able to
get good at reading price action you
have to study old price action and you
have to sweet talk yourself into
believing that these things were
identified ahead of time by you
and you record it as such
and here I say if and Q Finds Its way
lower and below the ICT breaker low
there's a fair value Gap busy formed on
the June 2023 monthly candle that's this
candle right here
now
over here in this area you may include
other things that you were identifying
or saw something in here that you want
to make sure you record and build up
this scary area in your understanding
you longer term bias you know how long
you should I expect the bias to stay in
effect well if you've been bullish it's
reasonable to anticipate it's eating up
into this
bearish breaker and if it does how far
can it go buy sides here above these
highs and then you have the inefficiency
and you saw July delivered that and the
wick goes just past it by a little bit
but that's okay because the Wicks do the
damage
the candlesticks tell you the story
that's the narrative
now taking everything from that monthly
chart
transposing it down to the weekly chart
it's very easy to do that you just
toggle down to the weekly chart and
every annotation that you have as long
as each one of these annotations that
you did on your monthly chart are shown
on all intervals so the way you would do
that is you would hover over top of any
annotation then right click your
Mouse and then click interval or show
intervals all
on trading View and that way when every
time you drop down to a lower time frame
or any other time frame The annotation
you put on your hard time for your
monthly chart will show up on the lower
time frames all the way down to the
smallest one
so what I have here is those same
breaker High breaker low
and fair value gap on a monthly
so you want to annotate your higher time
frame PD arrays
with what time frame they are notice I
have the monthly Parish breaker High
monthly fair value Gap CB monthly
bearish breaker low
this is a premium Wick consequent
encroachment that means this Wick of
this candle here
it's half of that Wick we treat Wicks
and Tails on candlesticks like gaps
okay so every Gap has a equilibrium
price point
and it's not called mean threshold it's
not called equilibrium it's called
consequent encroachment so whenever we
have a gap like this box says here
that would have a consequent
encroachment as a midpoint
an order block which is like the breaker
high in the breaker low that was shown
on the monthly chart let me go back up
this candle here midpoint of that
because it's an order block midpoint is
mean threshold
middle or halfway point of a gap very
you got the halfway point would be
consequent encroachment
so now we're on a lower time frame
weekly chart so now we can start seeing
more detail this price action here on
this very particular candle we have a
wick
that Wick projected out in time
it is a premium Wick consequent
encroachment
now when we drop down the lower time
frames which will be the daily and
subsequent lower time frames
this would have to be annotated as what
what time frame is this
weekly
this is a bullish order block
propulsion block
why is this a propulsion block because
this down closed candle is your order
block and then you have a higher order
block down closed candle that does not
pass through mean threshold
not on a closing basis so we're seeing
it trade very close to that
opening price but it's inside of the
propulsion block which is the high of
the wick down to the opening
the propulsion block has a midpoint or
equilibrium price point which would be
what
Council encouragement
or mean threshold
mean threshold
so we want to see does price show
sensitivity there that's what I'm having
annotated so I want to see what we do
there we also have a fairway Gap there
you can annotate that I'm just
mentioning here because I want to keep
the chart cleaner
so because we have that Gap because we
have an order block and a propulsion
block we might have sensitivity there
this week coming up
so does that mean it's going to go here
and go higher I don't know does it mean
it goes to it and through it I don't
know that so we have to wait and see
how does it trade on Sunday into Monday
now that fair value Gap
was formed on the monthly chart so
that's why it's annotated here as
monthly fair value Gap by 7 balance
outside and efficiency when we get into
lower time frames this will be annotated
as a weekly bullish order block
propulsion block because it's framed and
built on what time frame
the weekly chart
so the annotations are as such
the NQ weekly journal entry
The enqueue Continuous weekly chart
respected the premium with consequent
encroachment on the weekly candle of
July 17 2023
that's this candle here that's the
consequent encrosion or the midpoint of
that Wick and we're seeing it respected
here so this is last week's trading it
opened traded up into it we Wicked
through took out the previous weekly
High
but the bodies are staying below the
consequent encouragement of that Wick
and then price delivered below the
previous week's low
over this fair value Gap and trading
into the propulsion block here
right there now it looks like on this
chart it looks like it's touching the
opening price but it doesn't yet
we were expecting to see NQ price drop
into the bullish order block propulsion
block on the weekly candle of July 3rd
2023.
right here
that's the propulsion block and we are
expecting this very thing to happen so
what am I doing here I'm teaching you
how to
record it as you saw it coming
and then you record it here
I was not overly concerned with the
initial rally higher in the first part
of the week of price action the bodies
of the candles tell The Narrative of
price action and again that's annotating
this very principle here it opened and
the initial rally up that was not
concerning
that was not going to be a thing that
tricked us that's not what tricked me we
are anticipating prices to go up just to
sucker in retail Traders
the lesson formed misinformed Street
money and then delivery lower
so now we have these annotations here
premium with console encouragement and
bullish order block propulsion block
when we drop down to the next time frame
which would be what
up here in the left hand corner what's
below the weekly chart
the daily so we'll have to make sure
these two PD arrays are labeled
weekly
so this will be a weekly premium WIC
consequent encouragement and weekly
bullish order block propulsion block
all right now we're down into the daily
chart okay so now we can see
the weekly bullish order block
propulsion block now has showing it as
weekly
and the weekly premium WIC consequent
encouragement notice how much all these
candles create a completely different
perspective
this is why by doing this you train your
eye and you start to see how the
different time frames
respect the higher time frame PD arrays
and you also never get lost in the story
and context of what price action is
showing you across all of the time
frames
so the
the price delivery Continuum which is
moving from higher time frame to lower
for lower to higher moving throughout
the pdra Matrix
every one of these annotations here
did not appear
on the weekly nor did they all appear on
the monthly
now we're on the daily chart so the
daily chart has its own specific PD
arrays but leaning on the logic and the
context that would be derived from those
PD arrays from the monthly chart and the
weekly chart now we're on the daily
chart
and again it's the same symbol NASDAQ
number one exclamation which is the
NASDAQ continuous contract
for those who have been wondering what
this means the continuous contract means
that whenever the front month or the
nearby contract is traded when it
expires this chart will use the data
from the new next nearby contract and it
will become the front month so for
instance right now we're trading the
September contract of NASDAQ
When nasdaq's September contract expires
this chart this NQ number one
exclamation will start using the data
from the December 2023 contract
so it's always using the front month or
new nearby contract expiration
it uses that data to make the the
individual candlesticks
if you're trading with
the actual Futures Contract you're not
trading with the NQ continuous contract
you're going to be trading with the
nearby contract so whichever one has the
most
open interest and highest volume
being traded most actively traded in
other words that's the one you're
actually going to be Trading
and you want to do this very thing here
with the actual contract now you're
probably asking why did I do it with the
set thermal contract because September's
contract on trading view is not going to
give you the data that shows you the
higher time frame monthly
so I'm using the continuous contract
here to show you that higher time frame
monthly fear value Gap city which is
this shaded area here
and then we have the daily chart showing
you another PD array which is this
imbalance here from this candle low that
candle is high so all of this down close
movement here
this sell side delivery not sell side
liquidity sell side delivery it means
the candlesticks expanding lower
this inefficiency is a daily fair value
Gap sibi cell side imbalance buy side
inefficiency
it traded up into the high of that
civvy
on Monday
then Tuesday we traded down got really
close to the low
which would be this candle's High
and then we opened here on Wednesday
traded higher
created a volume imbalance got lower
extreme price delivery on the low end so
all this sell side delivery
trades below
this low here where sell side liquidity
would be and dug into this sphere value
Gap
which is a fair value Gap busy buy side
imbalance sell side and efficiency
this is formed on the daily chart so the
annotations have to keep referencing
what time frame these PD eraser anchor
dorms that way when you go into lower
time frames you're not losing sight of
what levels are what
everything will be in its proper place
and everything will have the proper
context so if you're using the higher
time frame charts to determine
a narrative a bias where price is likely
to draw to you're going to use all these
PD arrays and right now let me just ask
you this if you were just looking at
this without me walking you through any
more of it it might be a little
overwhelming it might look a little
complicated but as we go through it
you're going to see oh now that makes
sense and when you do this in your own
charts and you do months of it not one
day a week where you try to cram it all
in one day if that's not what you should
be doing this should be a daily
meditation for you every single day is a
day that you must Journal
you actively do this every single day in
whatever Market that you want to
specialize in so this is why the folks
that are trying to be jack of all trades
and you you want to trade 28 markets and
have 28 markets being followed all the
time if you don't have a model that
you're consistent with you're wasting
your time
you're not doing things efficiently to
do what it is that you're trying to do
which is become very good at reading
price which will eventually by default
make you a better Trader
but you can't get there if you jump over
this part
I promise you if you're arm wrestling me
and saying I don't want to do this part
I'm never going to do it ICT I'm never
going to journal I'm never going to do
this kind of stuff it's a waste of time
you will not be consistent you might get
once in a while lucky here and there
that you'll be either a break even
Trader or you'll eventually Crash and
Burn and you'll never tell anybody on
social media that happened
but you'll pretend that you didn't
don't waste your time
do these things I'm telling you to do
and I promise you the results the
understanding the logic behind the model
that you're seeking
will literally leap off these charts and
speak directly to you because the thing
that you're gonna gravitate to the most
whatever pdra it is you're going to see
it and it's going to be the easiest one
you see when you start doing this
I'm not saying only annotate the one
that you want to use for instance a fair
value Gap or institutional order flow
entry drill or it could be anything
Don't force that always annotate
everything after the fact
use terminology in your commentary in
your annotations like you saw it coming
and over time by doing this every single
trading day
and yes it takes a little time
yes it's going to feel tedious yes it's
going to feel like this is
counterintuitive and it's not productive
but it really really is productive
you are
hot wiring
your experience you're literally going
in there and supercharging and
shortening your learning curve
it doesn't feel like it feels like
you're doing everything opposite to what
you should be doing you should be trying
to trade the right side of the chart
but how can you do that if you don't
know what you're doing
if you don't know what you're looking
for how these things form where do they
form what do they look like across all
time frames
you cannot do it
you'll be wasting your time trying
so it's important to anticipate that
you're going to have months of doing
this before you probably get really
comfortable with what it is you're
trying to do
that doesn't mean you're trading
consistently it just means that you're
probably going to at that time months
from now
you're going to know what it is that you
want to look for in price action because
you've seen it repeat so many times it's
obvious
whichever PD area you like you'll know
don't take the ones that I'm talking
about the most it might be an obscure
one like the mitigation block
okay something that makes the most sense
to you and all of my students are
different they're all going to pick
something that makes more sense to them
then
many times the nature style is going to
be everybody wants to do order blocks
but then to discover the fair value Gap
then they discovered the model 2022.
so and now we have a silver bullet set
up which is time based so all these
things okay they're
potential candidates for you to build a
model around
that is Uniquely Yours
but don't try to force it by doing this
practice of annotating and logging with
price action actually did and then
recording the annotations
properly and organized and then giving
yourself annotations that were
supportive
saying well done to yourself for seeing
it coming beforehand and then delivering
what you thought it would
you didn't probably do that
but again you're tricking your
subconscious and you're tricking
yourself into believing by repetition
looking at these old charts because
these journal entries will be referred
to later on at the end of the week at
the end of the month look at previous
week and the week before that you
constantly go back and look at this over
and over again
it's like watching a movie you saw many
times before you know what's going to be
said you know what the actors are
wearing you know the outcome but you're
continuously watching it because why
you'd like that movie I have dozens of
them that I I like watching and I know
the script I know the words are going to
say I know the mannerism I even say it
just the same way that they do sometimes
and sometimes I'm in the shower and I'm
repeating a movie scene because I'm
looking forward to watching it again
why because it means something to me it
holds a special place in my heart that's
what you're trying to do with price
action you're falling in love with
reading price and if you do not fall in
love with this part of it or this aspect
of what trading is you cannot absolutely
underscore cannot be consistently
long-term profitable that's it this is
how you have a romance with price action
you do this very thing you're writing
love letters to your future self
encouraging your future self and you're
saying these are all the beautiful
things I love about price action just
like you want to be able to tell your
your significant other you don't want to
go up to your significant I want to say
you know
honey you got some really ugly hammer
toes okay I don't know what's going on
you got some toe jams we got we gotta
take care of that you're never gonna do
that not survive
[Laughter]
so you want to do what you want to say
honey you look so nice today that's a
lovely perfume you're wearing what did
you do to your hair it looks beautiful
today what are you doing you're focusing
on all the positive because you know
you don't want to go in a dog house you
don't want to be separated from the the
good aspects of being in that
relationship with that person because
you're going to say something that's
negative you don't want to do that in
your Journal because what you're doing
is you're trying to cultivate the
sweetest romance between you and price
action
you want to have a close-knit
relationship with price
you want to be able to warm up the price
real quick
see it when it starts trading real time
so oh yeah I know what you're doing
honey you do this all the time just like
when you're with a long-term
relationship partner you know what
they're going to do how they wake up how
they act before they have their coffee
you know how they act before they go to
bed you're either a night person or
they're a morning person you know their
little personal little quirky things
this is how you learn what price does in
its own unique personal quirky things
and then that relationship and that
language that love language between you
and price action
then it develops into what a long-term
committed relationship which is positive
profitability consistency longevity all
those things and you don't have drama
you don't want to invite drama into your
relationship with price action
so you start it as a love story you
sweet talk it you sweet talk yourself
your future self all this is what you're
doing by back testing that is back
testing that's my way of conditioning
you as a student to go in and fall in
love with what price does because it
does these things over and over and over
again just like your spouse your
significant other would know things that
you do all the time they know you're
like a well-read book they know you like
the back of their hand the same way you
know them so
by looking at the monthly chart and the
weekly chart and having those respective
PD arrays annotated on the daily chart
then we look at the daily chart and
identify what that time frame offers us
so we have a complete and comprehensive
approach from the highest time frames
which is monthly weekly and now daily
and every specific
PD array must be properly labeled
otherwise you will lose sight of what it
is you're looking at
this range up here
is that fair value Gap CB on the monthly
chart that was below the monthly breaker
High
and between that and the monthly breaker
low which is this level here
this daily fair value Gap in the form of
a busy which is an up close candle
this is only seen on the daily chart and
this is that monthly
fair value sales on efficiency
we have a sibi here
so it's a daily fair value Gap sibi the
candle was down down candles that make a
fair value Gap is a city
up close candles that make a fairway Gap
is a busy
Okay so
this inefficiency here
forms it what part of this monthly fair
value Gap City so in other words between
this Range High and this range low from
the monthly chart now
where is this
sibi forming
in the lower half of it
did you notice that
hi
to low that pink Range
halfway points about right here
so the high of that City also is in
close proximity to the consequent
encroachment which is not labeled here
of the high and low you might want to
include that in your chart
but this sibi stops right there because
not only is it the high of this
imbalance but it's also consequent
encroachment of the monthly fair value
Gap City
so now notice what we're doing we're
observing
we're appreciating and recording
the logic behind nested PD arrays
there's a convergence if you will of PD
arrays and levels that would otherwise
go unnoticed by you or anyone else out
there and these are the types of things
that I have done in the past years ago
when I would do recorded executions and
people would say you know why is he
trading there like what what's so
significant about that area it's things
like this
and I can say it in passing say hey look
you know it's it's a monthly fair value
Gap and check your charts for homework
you want to look at the monthly chart
there's a uh in inefficiency around that
price level but see you don't want to do
that you just want to watch me do a new
trick you want to see me do some new
teaching and not dig into the charts
yourself and appreciate what it is I'm
laying out there for you on a silver
platter but I'm not going to spell it
out for you not because I don't want you
to learn it because I want you to go
into the charts and do this very thing
here
which is what every one of my profitable
students are doing and have done
you're not going to be the exception
stop arm wrestling it
so we also have this area here
which is a what fair value yeah
but
think now
if this is an inefficiency and it's a
fair value Gap what kind of fair value
Gap is this
buy sell and balance sell sign
inefficiency just like this one is down
here
but what does this become if this area
up here is creating some measure of
unlikely price delivery going lower
and then we see support behind that idea
where price does this very thing here
as soon as this candle trades down below
these lows and below this candle's High
which is the low of this by side of
balance cell sign efficiency which is a
fair value Gap this pass through this
candle here makes this
and this
a potential what
inversion fair value Gap what what time
frame does it form on the daily chart
see we're up here daily
so your annotation here is the daily
inversion fair value Gap High which is
this candle is low
and this candle is high which is the
daily inversion fair value got low
an inversion fair value Gap is narrative
based
if we take away the context of it
wanting to go lower
prior to this lower this is just simply
a fairway Gap by Center balance also
inefficiency but as soon as we have
price deliver to the sell side
and then attack cell side liquidity and
Pierce the low end range of that bison
efficiency this sets the tone if
narrative is considered and we've
already established that early on that
we were looking for lower prices
so that means we can use
the midpoint or the low or the lower
quadrant
notice there's three specific levels
there not a Zone
very specific price levels
midpoint well what's the midpoint of an
insertion of a gap
the same thing that we would call the
middle of a fair value Gap the same
thing we would call the middle of a wick
or a tail
consequent encroachment
so we see the daily inversion fair value
got consequent encroachment is right
there
notice we have this inefficiency here
which is what daily fair value Gap sippy
so
anyone else watching my videos if they
don't really go through the process of
doing this or learning or take good
notes
they're going to assume that the
Market's going to go all the way back
out to here because they'll say this is
a liquidity void and the Market's going
to want to have to go up there not when
it's like this
like what
we have a higher time frame monthly fear
Vega
we went up and repriced to it we went up
to it one more time halfway consequent
encroachment and we also rebalanced this
area here because we went up into
repricing it and then we left the range
there so now this is a balanced price
range
and we had one two premium arrays
supporting what lower prices so as soon
as we pierced through this low here
this level here not that very candle
this
low of the inversion fair value got we
don't know it's an inversion fair value
Gap until price does this pass through
then we can anticipate the market likely
to reach up into the midpoint between
this candles
below and this candle's high and that
midpoint is daily inversion fairy value
got consequent encroachment
said midpoint between this level here
and this level there
we trade up to here
trade lower and close there next candle
we open trade up one more time trading
above the previous day's High
trading up into consequent encroachment
of the inversion fair value Gap
and what is this candle here
this big beefy candle
this is for the folks that like to say
my order blocks are engulfing candles
that's nothing to do with it this candle
here
is the bearish order block
notice this camera does not Pierce or
engulf this previous candle whoops there
goes that logic so it's the change in
the state of delivery which is the
opening price here as soon as that
opening price is pierced to the downside
right there on that candle this becomes
a bearish order block
now because this is an order block we
can take that range from the low to the
high halfway point of that is what
consequent encroachment no mean
threshold so we extend that to the
Future and it would be in this area here
but we have what what do we have here we
have this inefficiency from this
candle's low this candle is high
would we reasonably expect if we have
the inversion fair value Gap consequent
encroachment which is
half of this
by Center balance outside efficiency
the main point of that if we have that
and we have the opening of this bearish
order block and
potential institutional order flow entry
drill
we're expecting lower prices and we have
an inversion fair value Gap can it go
back up to the inversion favorite value
get high yes the chances of it doing
that are Slim
by far and large many times you're going
to see that inversion Fair rate gaps
given this type of movement where we've
moved about five months One Direction we
hit a premium array there's no reason
really to go up to the high of the
breaker and because the breaker is
essentially a pattern that you want to
trade the low or mean threshold of
you don't want to see it trade the the
high end if it does it becomes a little
less
likely doesn't mean it can't go there it
just means that I don't like to see that
and if it does that and I'm in a trade I
will scale something off to remove the
measure of risk that I'm holding if I
see it trading through the high of the
breaker
because if it trades the high of the
breaker it means that it's not as
bearish as I want it to be
and you don't want to see it trade up
here if it's bearish it shouldn't get
all the way up there same aspect that's
being shown here if we have this
City from this candle's low and this
candle is high
and we have this one big camel trade
down like that do we really want to see
it trade above
the daily inversion for everybody got
high
no we don't want to see that just like
we wouldn't want to see it trade on the
monthly bearish breaker High because if
it's bearish we want to see premium
arrays not be reached to
let me say that again
if we're bearish
if we see premium arrays in our pdra
Matrix in the the fractal that we're
studying in price action that means all
the data that's being shown here
if we can clearly identify
where specific liquidity resides or
where a premium PD array
is in price if we're really really
bearish we do not want to see premium
arrays traded to we want to see discount
arrays draw price to it
and everything smashed through down
closed candles
because what is that telling us order
flow is bearish
did I have to show you a Dom for that a
depth of Market that I have to show you
a v-wop
did you have to see a
component control
how about a volume profile
did you have to look at volume for that
no
everything is in the candlestick
everything
you just need to know what it is you're
looking at by time
so we also have the weekly premium WIC
consequent encouragement which was being
respected look at the bodies right there
see that
did any of the bodies cross over that
nope but we did have Wix go through it
and that also teaches you what
by annotating your chart like this and
seeing how the lower time frames go
through it just a little bit but when it
does that and if you're bearish you're
going to start to condition yourself and
say okay
this is acceptable this is why I say
this is permissible in price action
where you might get scared out of it or
you might put your stop loss just above
that thinking that it's enough it's not
enough
but I'm not scared or changing my
opinion about where the Market's going
to go because there might be a small
little mohawk little deviation outside
of the levels I'm looking for this is
all normal coloring Outside the Lines
okay
this algorithm is my baby it's my child
so when I look at Price action and it
colors outside the lines I'm still going
to take this chart and hang it on my
refrigerator hanging on my desk okay
it's it's something my child has done
and I know that this is my child's
fingerprints so I don't worry about
these things when I'm looking at it and
I'm not judgmental what price did in
these areas when it's normal to see that
very thing and you won't grow anxious
when you're studying price and it's
behaving this way because it's something
that you expect and it's likely to occur
where everyone else might get scared or
stopped out or they may even change
their opinion about where they think the
Mark's going to go because the market
creates these little wicks
at the real at the time watching it this
is a full-blown bullish green candle
at the highest high of that you know
when it touches the candle low there
real time I'm expecting it to just bump
just above it a little bit and then
recede back into the range
when you start doing these types of
annotations it conditions you to
anticipate that very thing so when you
were watching real-time price action or
tape reading
you will have that in your mind because
you've seen many examples of it
and then when you start getting real
comfortable with it and it happens to do
this that very thing it feels really
good it's a confidence Builder it's not
an overconfidence Creator it's a
confidence Builder and it builds this
understanding about price action that
you would never otherwise get unless you
were actually doing these types of
things and recording it and showing
snapshots over time not just I did it
for a two weeks ICT I'm done back
testing then you're not
in German is something you're going to
do the rest of your career you want to
be able to imitate and log everything
and the more you pour into this part of
it the better you're going to be
so we wouldn't want to see this area up
here in this city be traded to
we don't want to see that because above
the daily inverse repair by Gap High
we have this separation from this
candle's low in the high which is this
Candlestick load that's the inversion
Fairbank app high and right away if this
is one of the first times you ever
watched one of my videos this isn't
where you start okay this is for people
that have been with me for a while and
they just want to know how to journal so
before you even get to this part you got
to watch some videos okay there's a lot
of things you need to look at and then
if the first time you watch the video
watch my 2022
mentorship 41 videos okay just watch
that one and it'll give you some context
but then the Market opens here on
Wednesday we open rally up
and then Crush
the sell side liquidity
and we go below the low the daily
inversion pair that you got that makes
this low a real
low of an inversion wherever you got
Market trades the next day on Thursday
opens rallies up touches
the low of this candle here
which is what that's your bearish order
block it can trade to that level and up
to the opening price
can it just stop and dead in its tracks
yeah but what do we allow for
coloring Outside the Lines
so that opening price extended forward
what are we seeing right here
the same element of price delivery
that's going on right there
this is a mohawk this is a mohawk it's
absolutely permissible why because the
market dynamics and the underpinnings of
the marketplace is it's wanting to go
lower
so it's the one to go lower likely to go
lower anytime it goes to a premium array
that does touch
it does deliver to anticipate a little
bit of coloring outside the lines and
not freak out thinking it's going to
give way which is the reason why I have
a roll of three PD arrays
one the first one
it can do this and then that's all there
is it can do this and then trade into
the second PD array that I would be
viewing as a defense
but if I have three PD arrays if I'm
bearish if it trades through three PD
arrays I'm probably wrong
and if I haven't been stopped out
I'm going to take the trade off and
remove myself from risk
many times and you watch me recently
trade a live account live trade in the
NQ or Nasdaq real Futures Contract not a
demo you can see that over there on my
Twitter account
I was in a trade and I had one PD array
of the three
breached
and it was approaching the second one
and my third one was so close
and right above my second PD array that
if it went to my second one I was going
to collapse the trade entirely and
remove myself from risk
so it's a matter of knowing all these
things that you just can't get from an
ICT video one time
there's no way to compress and put all
this bandwidth into one single
individual presentation
not not and had the Precision that you
see me sharing and what my students are
able to utilize on their trading
so this area up here becomes what
between the daily inversion fair value
Gap High which is this candle's low
so this candle is low here that makes
this what
a breakaway Gap
it's not annotated right it's for you to
go in and dig into it
so we see it trade up into the bearish
order block
opening price
And Trades about this candle is high
rate there on Friday which is a
institutional order flow entry drill
what is that it is a entry taken that
would be inside of a imbalance like a
fair value Gap what is this it's a
favorite I got
shaded it's a daily survey Gap what kind
City
that means it's a down candle that
delivers the fair Vega
just the opposite of what a busy is okay
obviously is a fairway Gap that has an
up close candle
civi
what you remember easy is civi is sell
side delivery sell off
busy buy side delivery buy up
okay that's the way you can remember it
we don't want to see this area traded to
because why we have this High here that
you could trade to and create a turtle
soup
trade up above it and reject good alert
which is what it did but how far can it
go about that ICT
opening price here this is your bearish
order block that should change
Interstate delivery rate there and it
can go up to that area there and go
through it just a little bit
it's permissible price action
coloring Outside the Lines
and then we see delivery aggressive
throughout the day and going lower
taking out Thursday's low
digging deeper into this box out of
balance inefficiency
right there
and it's a daily based PD array
the next one is the weekly bullish order
block propulsion block you can see now
now that we're on a daily chart it
didn't quite get there yet that would be
my next assumption for you know if it
goes lower and then obviously the entire
closure and delivery back to this candle
is high
it doesn't need to do that we've done
enough trading into this Python and
balance cell certain efficiency the
close here is real close to
consequent encroachment which is not
annotated here but I want you to
annotate that on your charts and look at
in the lower time frames on the
Thursday's price action and Friday of
last week now with all that said the
annotations I have over here is that the
enqueue continuous daily contract
delivered the lower prices I expected
from the monthly fair value Gap sibi the
weekly profile now when I say profile I
do not use Market profile I do not use
volume turned sideways plotted on my
charts I don't do that okay I don't use
depth of Market I don't use v-wop I
don't use any of that kind of stuff to
me they're gimmicks if you believe in
them that's your religion I Ain't Gonna
Knock you for your religion but it has
nothing to do with why price goes up or
down
weekly profiles to me are like templates
what is the roadmap that price is likely
to follow
this weekly profile was an obvious
Monday high of the week bearish profile
that formed immediately after the daily
fair value Gap sibi was redelivered to
on the Monday price action that means
here's Monday's price action here we
opened traded down rallied up to the
high which is the low of this candle
this is that City the fair value got
civi it goes up here delivers it to a
Monday and stops trading right there
then on Tuesday we opened trade up a
little bit and then slam lower
the weekly profile was an obvious Monday
high of the week bearish profile that
formed immediately after the daily fair
value Gap sibi was redelivered to on the
Monday price action see what language
I'm using there
the weekly profile was an obvious Monday
high of the week now I knew the
likelihood of it forming on Mondays high
but you may not have but in
your annotations you want to record it
like you were anticipating it
going further Wednesday proved my
bearish bias on the week was absolutely
correct by creating a lower gap opening
that's this here you opened here traded
up you've got from the previous day
we got and then the large range okay in
the lower this led to an amazing large
range down close day for NQ
the daily range on the Wednesday
extended past the inversion fair value
got low which telegraphed the high
probability of repricing to the
inversion fair value got consequent
encroachment before repricing lower on
Friday's price action
that's saying this candle went below
this candle's High which is this
inefficiency so this inefficiency was a
fair value Gap
we went through it here that makes this
potentially a inversion Fair Vega
meaning that it has a lot of probability
that's going to go up to the midpoint of
it
why shouldn't it good that are high I
just spent time talking about it this
area up here we want to see that stay
open as a fair value Gap
no as a breakaway cap
and then Friday we see it open trades up
in here and then slams it back down
Friday wasn't easy short selling day
with the bearish institutional order
flow entry drill and bearish Order block
inside of the inversion fair value Gap
and using the inversion fair value Gap
consequent encroachment as the ideal
premium PD array to expect the higher
the data form on now
this is again recording it on the
context of
disrespecting the fact that it's not
from payroll Friday
somewhere in here you want to record
that this was non-farm payroll Friday
that you wouldn't be trading that day
necessarily as a new student but you can
still see and repeat appreciate the the
price action and delivery of that
occurring
[Music]
moving on to the NASDAQ four hour
you can see again all the annotations
that were on the monthly the weekly and
now the daily
say the daily fair value Gap City
daily inversion for everybody got high
daily inversion favorite consequent
encouragement and daily inversion fair
value Gap below
daily institutional order flow integral
daily bearish order block daily fair
value Cap City and now we have elements
inside of the four hour chart like we
see here the four hour bearish order
block over here
change in state deliveries there Market
opens on this four hour chart trades up
what's it doing it's trading just above
that candlestick's opening price this is
permissible price action this is a
mohawk okay it's just a little bit
outside the lines that's absolutely
permissible
the market trades there lower
opens here and moves lower again this
area in here
is indicating that inside of this daily
fair value Gap sibi
there's a little bit more detail as to
why we would not reasonably expect
the daily chart to see price action go
above that daily inversion variable you
got Pi y look closer
from this candlestick's low
[Music]
to this candlesticks High
that is your
daily
this is the daily inversion fair value
Gap High the midpoint of that inversion
variable you got which Costco
encroachment and the low of the daily
inversion fair value got below
so here's consequent encroachment
why did we not expected to trade up in
this area here on the daily it was
showing in one single pass
but on a four hour chart you can see it
went down
and then the next candle we opened and
went back up there again and then down
damn
delivery in here as well so what is
happening here went lower
lower
back up lower
so this is what
balanced so this is a balanced price
range
so what do we have from the daily
inversion Fairbank app High to the Daily
inversion fair value Gap consequent
encroachment we have a balanced price
range
nailing the bearish order block opening
price
coupling it with
a Confluence of the daily inversion for
everybody got consequent encroachment
of that
gap on the daily chart that we saw trade
through it here and then we expect the
midpoint of that to act as what the high
on Friday
it's not likely to go all the way
through all this just to get back up
into a little area here let me go back
up to the deal chart think about this
little area right here
okay now I'm going to show you that on a
daily chart
that's this little area right there
go on your own charts and you'll see
what I'm talking about
this little area here is not likely to
see all that trade back up to
this is going to stay open why because
on the four hour chart this is all
balanced back and forth price action so
there's no there's no inefficiency
there's no liquidity that's necessary to
trade to
so when we trade down through the daily
inversion forever you got low here our
attention goes to the Daily inversion
fair value got consequent encroachment
and the likelihood of that becoming or
just a little bit above it like we see
here
creating the Friday High
and we trade up small little Mohawk
above
the bearish order block opening price
which is this change in state of
delivery just a little bit above the
daily inversion Fairway got consequent
encouragement here and then we see what
non-prone payroll rip through it and
then attack the low
here
there
digging into that daily fair value sales
and efficiency
now notice in here also we have this
down move here in the next candle we
open and when the candle opened here
this Wick hadn't formed yet
so between this candlestick's low
and where we opened
this candle was just one single pass
down which would be looking much like a
what
fair value Gap sibi but this candle does
what immediately trades up
hits the low and goes just a little bit
past that what is that it's permissible
price action
And Trades lower
that is my immediate rebalance
when it does that whenever it does that
and you have a bias that's bullish or
bearish in this case it immediately
rebalanced here that is one of the
strongest algorithmic signatures you're
going to ever see in price action I'll
have much more to talk about that in my
books but for here I'm just reminding
you that I've already mentioned it here
on my YouTube channel my long-term
students know about this intimately but
this immediate rebalance is one of those
things that tells you that this Market
is going to be extremely bearish and
it's going to move fast and then we see
it run off
so we have a four hour PD array in the
form of a immediate rebalance
and then we have a four hour bearish
order block
apart from that nothing else on the four
hour chart is anything of importance to
me the annotations here show you that
the NQ four hour journal entry
the NQ continuous four-hour contract
shows how nicely the weekly premium WIC
consequent encroachment kept price from
rallying higher this week
that's this level here
okay
Tuesday bearish order block and gap
opening lower was the start of The
Descent and subsequent sell program
that's this Gap here
and bear shorter block so it's hitting
that and sells off aggressively as it
enters the cell program
daily fair value Gap CB can be seen as
well balanced in the gray area that's
this area right in here all of this is
well balanced because it's back and
forth price action it's not just one
candle it's back and forth up and down
up and down
which reinforced the probabilities of
the daily inversion fair value Gap
consequent encroachment being Friday's
high of the day and we see that actually
occurring here so it's going to have a
real hard time getting through all this
back and forth delivery when on a daily
chart it looks like it's inefficient up
here when it's not so that's the price
delivery Continuum that I'm referring to
you have to know what your higher time
frames are showing you and then inside
of those are time frames you get into
the details because as I'm showing you
here the lower time frames are going to
show you a much more refined
rendition of price delivery that is not
always easily ascertained by looking at
the higher time frame
the bias in the long-term draw on
liquidity that's the importance of those
higher time frames but the importance of
the lower time frame is refining
Precision it's not noise
[Music]
okay and finally moving down into the
hourly chart here this is the last time
frame we're going to look at in this
presentation because obviously you can
see it's you know it's very easy for me
to go on and on and make this a very
challenging for duration purposes
presentation
I know some of you my
well-rounded students like the really
really long lectures but I want to keep
it as short and as concise as possible
but still hitting the most Salient
points because I want all of you to be
doing these types of things because you
don't do it you're not going to learn
how to do it well
so we're looking at the 16 minute chart
or hourly chart and we have all of the
reference points now obviously this
looks like an entirely different market
now doesn't it from the monthly chart
the weekly chart the daily chart doesn't
even resemble the same Market at all but
yet it is the same Market
so we're using that price delivery
Continuum working from the higher time
frame down looking at how each
individual PD array respects and or is
negated
in here we see that monthly fair value
Gap CB this is that shaded area here
the monthly
breaker high is outside the range of
this time frame the monthly breaker low
is outside the time frame of this analog
chart okay so they're they're there if
we were to scrub down and squeeze or
condense this chart vertically it would
be up here higher and the low of the
breaker would be lower than this so for
the purpose of showing the one hour
chart time frame
the respective PD arrays and what was
Salient for this time frame I've zoomed
in just to show you this but you can see
this is that daily you get by sending
balance sell sign efficiency
and the monthly fair value Gap sippy so
we know the two premium and premium and
discount levels okay
and inside that daily fair value Gap
City you can see how it's important that
you label your PD arrays you can't just
throw a box or a rectangle in there and
assume that you're gonna remember what
it is and how to use it so everything
has to be organized everything has to
have its place and all the time frames
that you utilize
the weekly premium WIC consequent
encouragement
the four hour bearish order block
now we have
this sphere of a gap here
where's annotation for that it's coupled
with the four hour immediate rebalance
and 60 Minute premium fair value Gap
City that's this one right here
what's the candlesticks bodies showing
you
consequent encouragement half of this
Gap but what are the Wicks doing
coloring Outside the Lines
just trading just a little bit outside
which is completely reasonable but what
is it touching
the previous daily fair value Gap City
that's not random
so I have in my notes
when I'm working with price action when
I'm trading I have all these levels here
just as a list just like you see price
from 15 840 and then below that you see
15 800 and then below that fifteen six
seven sixty I have every respective PD
array that I'm showing you here just in
number format and it's annotation label
just on a piece of paper that's all it
is so I don't need a chart
like I don't I don't need a chart to
trade
I just need a piece of paper and know
what time it is and I can trade off of
that
so
this
60-minute favorite Gap
is a
[Music]
convergence with that four hour
immediate rebalance what does that mean
this movement right here is this let me
go back up to the four hour chart so
that way you know what I'm looking at
and what you're being shown
this candle here opening rallying up
right there this candle right there that
four hour candle inside that four hour
candle is this
right here one two three four candles
because for a single 60 Minute candles
is that four hour chart
that's that market
rallying back up creating a four hour
immediate rebalance
then what does it do it creates this how
could you use that well if you're
looking at an hourly chart
as soon as it does this complete run up
and then the body closes down in here if
we open here and rally and touch the top
of that fair value Gap or here's the
really fun part if we extend past that
fair value got right in here right in
there as soon as we trade above that I
could go short there you can go short
there
oh
that's delicious isn't it where would
your stop Need to Be Right Above That
Swing high right there why because this
is a fair Vegas
you can't use this one you can't use the
stop right about that because it's the
low of that previous daily fair value
Gap Simi it can touch that that's that's
reasonable
but this High here it shouldn't go there
if it's bearish it shouldn't go there
why because this should act as a
breakaway Gap
oh
that's delicious
sells off
and now we go back into this balance
price range you can see again all this
back and forth delivery that isn't
readily available in terms of looking at
it on a daily chart
but now look even closer if we take this
candlesticks low which is the high of
this daily fair value Gap City so this
shaded pink area here but this candle is
low
so this candle is high
that's the range okay that creates that
daily fair value Gap City
if we drop a fib
well neck handle is low and that
candle's high and you add in the 0.75 or
the 0.25 whichever direction you're
pulling the Fib from the lower quadrant
of that daily fair value Gap City that's
this shaded area here
notice what perhaps also on Friday look
at the bodies it's respecting that lower
quadrant
trades up in there there's a mohawk
right there
institutional refrigerator drill bang
sell short
sell side relative equal lows sell side
hello
so I want you to know that you know
doing these types of things it's
imperative that you are consistent by
doing it and by annotating your charts
and pulling out what's obvious to you
after the fact it will help reassure
yourself going forward looking at that
hard right Edge because you'll remember
things by
associating with them
previous memories that you've created by
journaling you're condensing and
compressing time
in a manner with experience that didn't
technically happen but you're recording
in such a way that it tricks your brain
into thinking that you did you see it
coming
The annotation for the 60 Minute chart
here is the NQ continuous 60 Minute
contract presented a really easy
Wednesday two o'clock in the morning
fair value Gap City that's this candle
right there when the four hour posted
its immediate rebalance that's this
movement here
and you can be seen respecting the lower
quadrant of the daily fair value Gap
City on Friday at noon
that's here that's this level here it's
the lower quadrant of this shaded area
half of it's here
and an upper quadrant would be here
interesting enough that it touches that
and then this one here now I ain't
making a big deal about that because the
inefficiency wasn't created until that
movement but look that right there we'll
talk about that in my book
[Music]
as the bodies of the candles tell the
narrative
of lower prices into the close
and we have that there
so
non-front payroll takes out the lows
here after taking
buy side then sell side that's what my
farm payroll does it runs both sides of
the marketplace
and I've taught that many times and it
delivered again like gangbusters
hopefully you found this one insightful
I hope you learned something about how
you can journal and the benefits of
doing so and how it builds an
understanding about price actions you
can't get by watching videos or reading
books or listening to anybody just talk
about price even watching them trade or
copying them you'll never get this type
of insight unless you go into your own
chart to annotate them and do it as a
daily meditation
and so I'll talk to you next time
be safe