welcome back folks to the April 2017 ICT
mentorship content
for teaching ICT day trading model this
is Lesson Four
specifically teaching projecting daily
highs and lows
okay as we just mentioned in the
previous teaching lesson number three
potential Bank dealers range
when we talk about the most likely Sell
days
moving up as high as three Standard
Deviation
and most buy days moving down making the
LOD as low as three Standard
Deviation from the CentralBankDealersRange
we can take this one step further
the range at which price Works Within
the protractionary state away from the
CentralBankDealersRange in other
words are we moving higher away from the
CentralBankDealersRange for a sell-off
or a Sell day
how much of that range are we moving
now this is not Fibonacci extensions or
projections or anything like that we're
looking specifically at the range that
IPDA will go into protractionary State
and move
counter the direction of the intended
direction of the day
in other words it's the Judas swing
we don't necessarily have to know
beforehand to the PIP what the extension
is going to be away from
the CentralBankDealersRange we just
need to know
what it is after the move has already
ensued so even if we get it wrong okay
I'm gonna play double tap against for a
moment say you don't get it right in
London but you're able to capitalize on
a continuation in NewYork
how far in
the future will price reach based on
IPDA and using the CentralBankDealersRange that's what this teaching will
give us
and just like we showed with the
previous slide
ideal scenarios are going to be seen
with no more than two Standard
Deviation usually that's about the the
bulk of buy and sell days you'll see
price go down many times just one
StandardDeviation but two is generally
the general rule of thumb but across the
board as a general thumb they generally
don't like to go beyond three Standard
Deviation
and we already assumed
the role for the use of four Standard
Deviation in the previous teaching
okay just a quick Brief Review because I
don't know when you're gonna watch
the lesson three in review so I'm going
to use these slides again because it's
Salient for this topic
when we look at the CentralBankDealersRange again
the range between two o'clock and eight
PM
that range is ideally best suited for
our use less than 40 Pips and again
preferably 20 to 30 Pips
we move to the sidelines and we do not
look to trade with the CentralBankDealersRange in our repertoire
when the range is greater than 40 Pips
and again we're focusing on
nailing down where the high or the day
on the low of the date may be formed
okay and we always look at the CentralBankDealersRange in terms of using
the spread of the wick to Wick high to
low range between 2 PM and 8 PM New
York time
and I like to look at the bodies
highest high in the form of open or
close and the lowest low in the form of
an open or close not the Wicks so I get
the range in the bodies but then I also
do it on the Wicks as well because you
want to do everything you see in this
teaching here you're going to do the
same thing using the Wicks but I'm
teaching it through the use of the
bodies because that's predominantly what
I go to first I get the ranges and
projections and measurements based on
the bodies of the candles
okay so now
now we get to the part where most of you
have been waiting for a long time to
learn this
and to be quite honest with you I'm not
sure why I'm doing it
it's one of those things that I've kept
for a long long time and I promised that
you would learn it in this mentorship so
if you are ever
in the sharing Spirit if you're ever in
the Robin Hood Mentality you know you
want to give to everyone else that
aren't a part of this mentorship
um this is one of those things you just
really really really want to keep to
yourself it's not common knowledge it's
not out there anywhere else believe me
when you start looking at it and seeing
it you'll it's
mind-boggling it really is mind-boggling
how precise you can get
but
we we showed the StandardDeviation and
the application of thereof okay and
obviously it looks like just grabbing
the best ones and doing that and there
it is it's as simple as that and it's
all pure hindsight but if you look at
what I want to show you in this teaching
and go back to the analysis during the
time when we are looking at the market
like this you'll see the levels that I
had given on the chart index they're all
there okay
so we're going to take a look at every
one of these examples with the exception
of the 58 pip CentralBankDealersRange because that's a NYX we don't do
anything for that particular day
but we will comment on that
when we get to that second example
okay so let's go out to a daily chart
and I'm going to ask you what do you see
here
okay I'm drawing your attention to a
specific level with that little trend
line Blue Line
and that's the segment of price action
that we're looking at in terms of those
examples
and highlight that little area in this
white box
okay so we're looking at this whole
entire reference point here
and again I'm going to count you to go
back to the time
when we were talking about the cable and
Analysis and all of the charts that were
shared
okay go back and look at that so none of
this stuff is cherry picking okay
so what we're doing is we're looking at
the marketplace using the PD array
Matrix and we're blending it with time
and price Theory so we're looking at if
the data ranges we're looking at PD
array Matrix are we in a premium
discount the market trades down in the
lower range of that white rectangle
until it hits a bullish order block
what I've done there is I've taken the
Sunday candle and the Monday candle
blending that small little Sunday candle
and Monday candle
into one candle blending the two bodies
together and I got a measurement of that
and I projected it across the chart and
you can actually go back and look at
your notes and look at the Forum and I
counsel you to download the charts every
day I do them because you can keep track
and see that I don't make any changes I
don't go back and re-edit them you get
them as I see it so that way you can
compare what I'm explaining to you here
was exactly outlined in terms of the PD
arrays specifically I even tell you
that's a mean threshold of a bull
shoulder block there
so
price hits that level
creates the first of three up candles
and now we're going to go into those
examples and break it down
okay folks
okay here we are we're at that point
where
this stuff starts to get really really
interesting
so
when we look at these examples okay this
is where the price has traded up into a
premium on the daily chart
and we did our
StandardDeviation
okay and
we see price that was on a daily chart
in a premium at this time
we have a
bullish candle right for the download
here that gives us a bearish order block
that low comes in at
125.93
the high comes in at
125.97 so it trades up into the body of
the bear shoulder block
StandardDeviation of two
price extends up to the Standard
Deviation
right to the PIP
and starts to trade off for the rest of
the day
when we have the StandardDeviation
arrived at
based on a PD array in other words we're
looking at a
premium PD array they are shorter block
price in a daily premium
hits it in London have a protractionary
state in the marketplace due to swing in
London
goes right to the PIP And Trades lower
the question is is how low will it go
well you have to look at the range that
is created by the CentralBankDealersRange protractionary state in other
words how much of a StandardDeviation
did we see
because that becomes the known range to
work with
and it becomes our multiplier as well
so when the market looks to fill the
numbers and I'll tell you what that
means when we get to it
we use this reference point here so it
has to actually the actual Standard
Deviation range
that we use for the CentralBankDealersRange and all the StandardDeviation it
uses to make the high or LOD
in London that becomes your measurement
Okay so
what we have here is the market showing
us a midnight
in NewYork candle vertical line and
then 1800 or 2 o'clock in the afternoon
NewYork time and again each day
midnight NewYork two o'clock in the
afternoon midnight NewYork two o'clock
in the afternoon midnight NewYork two
o'clock in the afternoon
okay and I'm going to give you the
London killZone
reference point now
and this is that Weekly I'm sorry daily
premium PD array here
so price trades up into it
and starts to sell off so in this time
element here this gives us our London
close time of the day so
this candle here starts it
this is the middle of the London Kill
Zone close
and we have this candle here right there
that creates the  the projected London
close
time window but then we have ultimately
two o'clock where we actually see the
close of
our highest point in other words usually
the higher low even when a really long
winded trending day two o'clock usually
caps the
higher LOD if we if we
continue through London close Killzone
or basically if we go past noon NewYork
time  we look forward to go to two
o'clock and dribble down or run up until
that that specific time of the day
so all of these days we don't have
anything on this day here because the
CentralBankDealersRange was 58 Pips
regardless if we used to Wix as a high
and low or if we use the body's high and
low it doesn't make a difference the
point is it's still too much of a
CentralBankDealersRange to use for
our projections in here so we have to
skip on this day here but we use other
tools which we'll explain in a moment
the daily bullish order block price
trades down into that on this big
CentralBankDealersRange day trades
down into the bullish order block here
and finds momentum to trade higher and
we have the scenario we would expect to
see price move higher on a bullish
discount PD array
and the same thing here continuing up
looking to close in
our gaps over here which we'll look at
in a moment
so when we have this range here price
point moves into a projectionary state
about two StandardDeviation what you
do is you take that range
and yes I do all this by hand okay so we
have our range
and just lay that on the bottom
of the CentralBankDealersRange and
you start layering layering them down
hold down control drag your
image away click on it and drag away
with the control button held down
right there
okay so we have
to blend two things now time and price
Theory so we're looking for this whole
range of two StandardDeviation
projected from the CentralBankDealersRange low but it's going to be a bearish
day so we have one StandardDeviation of
the total StandardDeviation used for
the CentralBankDealersRange to call
the HOD
so we have one of those Standard
Deviation to their StandardDeviation
three of their StandardDeviation why
AM I doing three is because price kept
going lower lower lower until we get to
the time of day right in here okay so
I'm going to draw
a vertical line
delineating the beginning and the end
of the killZone
we'll put it on the close rather so this
candle closes it at noon this is 11 and
it starts as early as 10 o'clock in New
York time
okay and we have this projected low
so I'm going to use this line here
and yes the charts will look a little
bit busy for a moment
and we'll project this out in time
Okay so
we could take profit here on this day
the low comes in at
124.76
with the close on that candle it stops
right at two StandardDeviation of the
CentralBankDealersRange right there
you see that
boom hits it okay yes it Wicks down a
little bit more and let you see it
a little bit more than that but not by
much
okay and now we're going to look at the
1800 which is the cap of the day
there's the low and there's our
projected low right here
124.40
we called 124 41 so I was off by one pit
okay so time wise we looked for it to
occur here
it just fell a little bit short but had
to go one more StandardDeviation
because it kept drifting lower so
there's nothing wrong with just taking
profits here and leaving something on
for the rest of the day because there's
a discount PD array of a bullish order
block down here that we saw on the
previous slide
that would be your objective but you can
take profits time of day wise here with
two StandardDeviation of the CentralBankDealersRange two Standard
Deviation used to make the high of the
day so again in summary we're taking the
total range used of all the Standard
Deviation one
two three accounting CentralBankDealersRange always
so we have three of them so we get a
mock-up of that range and then project
it from the low on Sell days is one two
three it gives you the  if the
projected DailyRange low
okay I'm going to take this off
okay and we can't do anything with this
one here
um we'll have to wait get new
information and the next day here we
have our criteria here where it's a
small enough range of CentralBankDealersRange we do one Standard
Deviation down
why are we going down one Standard
Deviation because we have the bullish
order blocks in here and an old bullet
order block back here
price trades down into it clears out
even the rejection block which would be
the bodies of the candle sweeps through
that in London one StandardDeviation
misses it by two Pips okay so this is
going to be a time where you just don't
get it exactly but it's still calm one
StandardDeviation so we get a range
okay of these two together
so what you do
I'll borrow this
okay I'm getting a measurement of that
total range
it's almost the same thing actually it's
pretty interesting
okay so we have one
two
okay two projected StandardDeviation
up
that gives us a projected High
and I'm going to tell you why I stopped
here
before you start thinking oh you're
cherry picking
okay so we have the projected High
called here notice that this Wick right
here goes through our projected idea of
where price should go
but this one stops right to the pit
here's our time when and when it starts
on this candle so it's a little bit
early one hour early making the
well not one hour early but in the nine
o'clock hour of NewYork time it made
the HOD then 10 o'clock it
made this candle's High
11 and then noon here
why did it go up to this level here
forget the time element because you're
never going to have that perfectly but
it just gives us a ballpark figure time
wise when they anticipate the move to
unfold but I want you to look back over
here we have a candle it makes a low and
the close comes off that low
by a little bit then this candle opens
trades up a little bit so all this buy
side delivery vacancy okay or void of
buy side delivery it's only sell side
delivery begins at this candle's low
okay at 125.26
so from this candle's High here
at
2503 to this candle's low
at 25.26
we have 23 Pips of range to close in
right out to this point here
so we can look at that
like this
here is the fair value Gap that needs to
be closed in it does it right there and
goes Just A fifth or two above it
closing in this fair value Gap from this
high
to this low so it closes that in
so there's a reasonable expectation for
us to take profit there because we want
to get out early anyway but that's why
it went to that price point using the PD
arrays okay so nothing's changed there's
no
home you know new Hocus Pocus it's all
stuff that you've learned but now we're
applying it with great deal of precision
and using time elements okay so we went
two StandardDeviation up if we were to
go three
if we went 3 up that would took us up to
the bear shoulder block but we were
getting close to the time window so
while we could have expected this to
occur
two is about right because we're going
to close in the fair value Gap as we
were running up here
and it came late in the day on NewYork
for London close overlap so that's why
we'd expect to see price Peter out at
that point
again here we have
two StandardDeviation down
it goes right to the PIP
so we get a measurement of this tire
range of two StandardDeviation for
that particular day
okay so we have our range defined
so you have that one
and two
okay so we have two potential Standard
Deviation up
and also when price trades down two
StandardDeviation what we're actually
seeing is it trades down to another
discount PD array
which is these three consecutive Down
Candles
all we're going to do is extend this
over and you'll see the overlap
boom
okay so price trades down hits it
the opening on this candle is 124.36 the
low on this candle is
124.36 precision
two StandardDeviation okay and as a
general rule of thumb I like to always
throw two on just to see what would line
up so on the first one we see price
could reach up to
this fair value Gap in here so this
candle
hi and this candle low we left a little
bit of
sell side delivery only so as a buy side
liquidity void that we can see it trade
up into it's more specifically this
candle not this one I'm sorry this
candle here
so we can look at that
frame that out
here
okay so in this day price trades up
here's the noon
close of London this candle right here
trades up closes in
to the bearish order block it goes
inside of the second Deviation so while
there still may be some range permitted
based on the projections it's the PD
arrays that call the shot okay just it's
not the magic of these projections these
projections will lead you to
an overlap of time and price so we're
looking at the extension of the range
two StandardDeviation measure that
projected above from the eight
consolidation of the CentralBankDealersRange High
we place that on there one Standard
Deviation that one alone would have been
enough and you could have took profits
right there
and that would be fine and just left
that little piece on there for the fair
value got The Fill in and let the rest
of the people chase that
the second one you can have a little
piece of one still
once it closes in the fair value Gap
again you would take another portion of
your trade-off and then see if it has
any room to trade higher
ultimately it never does but that's the
that's the way you'd use it in order to
read from the London close
Killzone when they cut lows Killzone
that includes killZone the Standard
Deviation range from the Central Bank
range per tractionary state in other
words how many StandardDeviation go up
that's your key okay that's the thing
that makes IPDA reach for it now it will
go those many blocks down until it
reaches the time of day where
we expect the range to cap that means
it's if it's a NewYork  session
reversal like we see here now we're not
using the range here because the Central
Bank dealer's range is too too extended
but price trades down into a NewYork
session reversal because it hits a daily
bullish order block
and then that's our weekly low and price
has a slightly bullish day intraday on
the next day and then we have our setup
going into the
rally on March 30th
trading down into a rejection blockable
shoulder block overlap and then two
StandardDeviation up Nails it now we
didn't get the exact
Range High in here but using the
fair value Gap in here and we've got you
real close two Pips away from it so you
can't argue about that that's sometimes
you're going to be right to the PIP
sometimes you'll be just short one or
two Pips and other times it'll be just
maybe five or six Pips above and there's
nothing wrong with leaving a little bit
of that on the table and if you're
looking for that always I'm not going to
be able to help you with that measure of
precision
so by blending these things like this
it gives us an overlap of Central Bank
dealers range projections okay and let
me remind you that the Precision really
is on the entry side of the low on the
BuyDays and the high on the Sell days
that's the StandardDeviation  tactic
now where this will get you in trouble
is you're going to try to apply the
StandardDeviation based on the range
between two o'clock in the afternoon and
8 PM NewYork time you're going to try
to do it every single day and you're
going to forget about the importance of
having a range between 20 and 30 Pips
for the CentralBankDealersRange it
has to be less than 40. and you have to
have a DirectionalBias remember we were
in a premium up here we saw a price
coming down to a discount PD array which
is the bullish order block recently
expected to bounce bounce it does okay
so to get into buy side
boom one StandardDeviation now I could
have done two StandardDeviation okay
and trade down below these Wicks could
have done that but it already hit this
order block and we found this low in
here the body's equal in here we swept
it didn't get quite down there no
problem big deal even if you missed this
move look at this one here you make up
for it the next day
is it a trade every single day no
that's what I'm trying to show you by
sitting down with you every single
trading day and using the things that
you've learned thus far in the order
that you've been learning them you can
see that it doesn't equate to getting
money every single day now some of you
are in here using other tools and using
things of your own  in your own
discovery of my tools and such and
you'll be able to find some setups
that's fine that's great but when we do
live sessions I don't want folks trying
to call out what they think is going to
happen unless I'm specifically asking
you because I'm trying to keep the
learning curve basically everyone in the
same mindset
because if I can hold you all
collectively as long as I can in that
mindset you'll hopefully learn in its
closest way possible step by step with
each other
and some of you are a little bit more
advanced because you've been using my
stuff a little bit longer than the
mentorship started but a lot of us are
in here are talking for the first time
and we're using the content you know in
a graduate modular State and this is the
way you learn it so by blending these
things again this has nothing to do with
Elliott wave it doesn't have anything of
supply and demand it's all interpanc
delivery okay so this is the science if
you will behind IPDA calling the daily
high and low please
please understand that this is something
that should not be out there on YouTube
if you see this on YouTube send me an
email at Inner Circle Trader gmail.com
tell me that's on there send me the link
and I will flag it and have YouTube take
it down none of you would have
permission none of you have permission
to post this anywhere and I certainly
don't want to post it on online video
hosting mediums or meet available to
other people so
it's just too good to be out there in
the public I debated whether or not I
wasn't even going to include this if
y'all would have kept it out you never
would have known it anyway but
you would have you would have missed how
I'm pretty much calling the highs and
lows when there's specific times of the
day and Times of the week and Times of
the month where it lines up this is how
I do it so hopefully you found this
insightful I'm sure some of you are
going to be nuts about it go through all
your charts and  this weekend will
probably be a very  light sleeping
week but I can assure you that this
isn't all there is we get a lot more
precise than this but there's some
things that you have to take in
consideration obviously if I gave this
on a YouTube video and mentioned  you
know all the things that we've learned
so far in the mentorship it still
wouldn't serve many people because they
would try to over use it they would try
to use it every single day they wouldn't
understand the PDA rate Matrix they
wouldn't understand the if the data
ranges they would just not have all the
insights that you have so
again this gets back to why it can't be
done in a video it can't be just one
video does it you have to have all the
stuff that's been taught thus far and
now you can see how they start to draw
together and there's some symmetry here
so now because we are understanding
these ranges we can take our Precision a
little bit more further and now start to
understand when we don't really want to
be taking specific day trades so now
instead of trading every single trading
day while I will be forced to try to do
it I will remind you based on these
rules that there is or is not the high
probability setup based on the Central
Bank dealers range being in an area of
discount or premium and
we're not in a Range that is conducive
in other words 2030 is ideal in terms of
Pips for the CentralBankDealersRange
if it's bigger than that we have a
harder time getting these measurements
okay so remember it goes back to Power
Three average DailyRange is about 100
Pips not always but generally and we
look for an average about 33 Pips for a
protractionary state in London it
doesn't have to do that it can be just
six Pips okay but generally we allow up
to 33 but if we have a central bank
deals range that's greater than 40 Pips
it usually messes up the synchronization
for the London open killZone so
hopefully you found this insightful
please do not share it please don't be
your best friend to somebody else and
give this out to someone keep it to your
close to your vest don't share it trust
me it's just way way too good to be out
there for everyone else to know you paid
for it be greedy with it there's nothing
wrong with that you earned it until next
lesson wish you good luck and good
training