welcome back folks
all right so we're doing a short little
market review
dollar Index euro dollar and s p and
NASDAQ futures
so dollar Index is our weekly chart here
you can see I mentioned this
last week is a a point of
consideration for a discount
and while it looks like it touched it it
was one pipette short of touching the
the high
which is the actual low of this
weekly candle here you can find that
with the week
represented by the date here okay
so far we're working up into this city
this is a sell side imbalance buy side
and efficiency
I'm watching how we trade in this area
right here
okay so if we watch
two price points that I'm keeping a
close eye on which is the consequent
encouragement of this candle's Wick
which is midpoint right here
and the same thing here
so midpoint of that Wick
extend those two out
I want you to do that in your own chart
okay and how we trade if at all
and either one of these
that will be interesting to me
[Music]
dollar Index daily chart
okay so we see you can got real close to
it there I didn't quite get to it and
then now we have pulled up into this
efficiency there's a small little
Gap this is actually a real liquidity
void where there's no actual trading
printed between these two respective
candles this candle's high neck candles
low
so it'll be interesting to see if it
wants to get up
to reprice into this area right here
that little Gap right there
if it stays open and starts to trade
lower
this can be something
that can stay open for a long time
you're a Dollar weekly chart
all right so we have the weekly volume
and balance which is
the difference between this candle's
closing price and this candle's opening
price while we did have this
candlesticks tail
and this candle sticks Wick
overlap one another in here but I have
drawn your attention to and this was
ahead of time so it's not just right now
we've talked about this for
also for several months actually but the
difference between those two price
points is that there is no body
no Candlestick body on this time frame
so the weekly candlestick
while we did trade down with the
candlesticks Wick and the candlesticks
tail up here
whenever a market shows an unwillingness
to drop a body
between two respective candlesticks
that is a volume and balance okay so I
dubbed as a volumet balance because that
time frame to be efficiently delivered
okay so the algorithm will refer back to
weekly time frame
there's an inefficiency here everyone
else would not see this as an
inefficiency because they see that it
traded back and forth in here
that's not efficient
so the draw on liquidity that we've been
looking for for months has finally
been delivered
okay so the high of the week we opened
traded up just to the high that
inefficiency
which is the weekly volume and balance
and then we traded down near the close
of this
volume of ounce on the low end so we had
the high end of it and the low end of it
and the close was just about right at
the load
so we traded up
meant the high of it
and then close back down
on the daily chart on the euro dollar
you can see how we did in fact deliver
here
and painted right back down over top of
that range from the low of the weekly
volume of balance up to the high and
then back down again
we had several targets
from July 9th
analysis video you can find it on
YouTube
and you can see this is where it began
before this Candlestick started Trading
we were looking for a move back down
into the weekly inversion Gap and then
draw to buy side which it did here and
then draw up into the weekly volume
balance so this right here completes a
rather
obvious
illustration of what my Concepts can do
for you what you're looking for in terms
of precision why the price should behave
a specific way
and right now
at this juncture
it's important for you to realize
because you're all probably thinking I
just watched this Pan Am
I watched it on my own chart I had the
annotations had the expectation to see
it deliver and it delivered
now what's the next move ICT what's the
next thing
it's really important that you
understand that we don't have to pick
the next move right now in fact it can
go both directions it can go higher the
trade up into this Fairway Gap or it can
dig deeper into this inefficiency here
this is a buy side and balance outside
an efficiency this is a sibi sell sign
imbalance beside inefficiency
either one of those can be treated to
because of the 50 50
likelihood
then we have to do what we have to drop
down below the daily chart
and be a day trader trade the intraday
sessions
the London Open Session
the New York open session
[Music]
all right we can see the hourly chart
here on euro dollar
trade through the buy side
came up found some support at the low
end of that Weekly volume of balance
then trade it all out to the high
then broke down
and aggressively return to the low of
the weekly volume imbalance
so on the upside
you want to have
this inefficiency
and
this inefficiency both of those are
in terms of the premium and or discount
respectively those are the two areas of
interest for me
I don't want to be overzealous and say
something up here
or something down here
because I don't have Sunday's opening
price yet
right now the time is a little bit after
four o'clock my local time so I'm
keeping my cards close to my vest this
week and I'm going to allow Monday's
Trading
to give me more insights about the
weekly range so it's okay for you to not
know because sometimes I don't know
I never know what it's going to do when
we open up on Sunday Sunday's opening
price is a mystery it's absolutely
unknowable let's put it that way so you
have to submit yourself to not knowing
what it is
and then watching and seeing how we
behave after that new week opening
evening s p
on the left hand side weekly chart
NASDAQ mini futures
weekly chart on the right
all right so I mentioned that this
inefficiency here would be a likely
culprit to draw up into we did see that
last week this was the initial one here
which we saw that trade to and then went
through it foreign
gap which is what we've outlined also we
had an interest in that
weekly chart on NASDAQ I mentioned this
is likely to be
the upside draw as well and we got that
delivered last week as well
and off the heels of the weekly
Ferry Gap here in the discount so it
sent price higher
and while again I'm not trying to call
the top of the marketplace I'm not
trying to pick a top
it's in an area where I think it's
reasonable to see it come back down into
this inefficiency here and over here
respectively for the s p down into here
now if
we take out the down closed candle
on the weekly basis if we take out that
low then
I would submit to the idea that we're
probably creating an inmate term high on
the weekly chart for s p
same thing here if we trade below
the down closed candle here on a closing
basis so this is important man it has to
be on a closing basis both s p and
NASDAQ if it were to close below this
candle's low
then I would likely assume that we are
creating an intermediate term High not
that it's the top not that it can't go
higher later on in the year it just
means for right now it would change
gears for me
and then I would likely look for lower
time frame
cell setups
and focus there until I was shown that
the market did in fact want to return
back to being bullish but right now
everything's still bullish nothing here
indicates there's a top nothing
indicates here that there's a top either
all right s p on the left hand side
daily chart we have a immediate
rebalance which is this candle here and
then the next down close candle and then
we opened traded up to the previous a
closed candle and then rejected that
so unless it takes out Friday's High
I'm looking for the likelihood of it
drawing back down into this
inefficiency here because we didn't
completely close it in see that
so it can trade down there and still be
bullish longer term it doesn't need to
change anything by doing that because
what we have here is a swing low
and trailed stop losses have been
brought right below that low
and we have a little bit of inefficiency
here between this candle is high and
this candle is low
so it could trade down there and still not upset anything
and essentially that's the midpoint of that lower inefficiency on the weekly chart
so I can trade down here quick below this close in this entirely even go
so far as to get down to CE from this Wick
and then I'd like to see this area down here stay open as a Breakaway Gap
so all of that changes if we trade on a
closing basis above Friday's High same
thing here on NASDAQ
we have
almost entirely closed in this fair
value Gap here but I'd like to see it
trade down into this area here into this
order block
so
I'm expecting
and anticipating
and for my own analysis predicting that
we would likely trade down more into
this inefficiency now if we gap down
create a gap opening trade up and then
go lower then obviously that might
require a little bit more
movement into this order block maybe
mean threshold
right in here
so it's a lot of wait and see
and it's always the case before we open up on Sunday
so I can have a lot of different scenarios that I would favor
or I would like to see or my concern would be around a specific
you know
scenario panning out and price on
Sunday's opening price going into
Monday's trading but all of that is just
I guess for the purpose of studying
because I don't trade on Sundays anymore
and because we are in an area where it could go either way
I have to force myself to go down into LTF to Day-Trade the sessions
so I'll be looking for inefficiencies\BSL\SSL for DOL and technically not have a bias intraday
it's an ant time frame on email the s p
okay you can see here on Sunday and
Monday of last week we rallied up
straight back down aggressive rally
higher and trade it up into that higher
inefficiency on the weekly chart
weekly volume imbalances what this says
and then we work lower
tray back up into a balanced price range
which is because of this singular up
candle which is a buy side balance
outside efficiency in this city which is
a singular candle cell sign imbalance
bison efficiency
these two areas here makes this a
balanced price range that's why we had
it rally up
and aggressively slammed lower
targeting the sell side and trading into
the Fairbank app here
right there
and then back up into that same balance
price range extend it to the right
boom
Rejects
all of this consolidation here in my
mind I'm thinking this is to
enticing for them and even this over
here is just too enticing for sell side
liquidity rate
so cell solid liquidity here and sell
side liquidity below these lows here
I would favor a run into that you know in
the first part of the week that's what I would like to see
but
I am again reminding you that we have
not yet opened for the new week yet so
Sunday's afternoons where we're at here
at the time of me making this recording
and later in the evening a few hours
from now we will see the opening
of the new week so
unless we get above this High here I think it wants a probe of lower
sell sign liquidity pools
NASDAQ e mini Futures 15-minute time
frame uh this one here I like the idea
of getting below this low and there's
that little bit of an inefficiency
okay so
um as long as we don't trade
Above This High here
it looks heavy
and I would favor a move to that cell
site and closing in this inefficiency
right there
it's interesting to see how we had that
little tiny little Fair bag at right
there it went right up into it and then
slammed it lower for the sell side below
here it's rather shallow
and I traded this on Friday
but the uh
the continuation lower is what I'm
interested in
and while I wouldn't be you know
typically afraid of
it running Above This short-term high
and then collapsing it's better that it
didn't do that because we have already
with the vision time frame we have a
really nice Market structure here
the fact that we went to a short-term
premium there to get into this fair
value Gap and breaker
so I would like to see a gap lower try
to fill a gap and
reach into this area here that's the
scenario I'm looking for for Nasdaq it
doesn't mean I'm going to be right don't
bet the farm on don't even try to take a
trade on it okay just observe it and
watch it I won't be Trading until we get
to Tuesday I want to use Monday's
trading to provide me a better backdrop
or Foundation to what I think the weekly
Candlestick is going to do because as of
right now my mode of thought going
forward for this particular trading week
is intraday only
no daily bias and that means we have to
trade intraday
volatility that means buy side or sell
side liquidity and or trading for
inefficiencies and that's it so
I know that's probably not which one
here because you just watched me to
deliver a really wonderful month of July
in terms of you know a big run for a
swing Trader model on a daily chart
but they don't set up every day they
don't set up every week and you have to
sit on your hands
and that's what we're counseling you to
do here today is this sit still relax
and let the next setup come to you and
Don't Force It
again as a reminder
this was just a review and I'm just
counseling you
I'm going very very slow with this new
week of trading and allowing Monday to
give me the bias for the week and so
I'll talk to you next time
be safe