okay folks welcome back this is the
fourth teaching of eight of the november
2016 content
for the ict mentorship
okay we're going to talk about
some anticipatory skill sets and one of
the skill sets that i teach
is using the monthly chart
but this teaching is going to be
specifically dealing with
using institutional order flow
to help you find new setups
when we look at the monthly chart
the first thing you remember is remind
yourself that the monthly charts are
only going to move
with a great deal of money behind
these price swings and retails i'm not
going to have it
the idea of seeing
big ranges on a monthly chart
that's going to be a
result of enormous amounts of buying or
selling interest by the smart money
again retail can't move
price so
if we can see where they're most likely
going to
place orders to buy or sell and we can
see on the monthly chart we stand to
make a great deal
of pips and we don't have to trade a
whole lot to do it
but i want you to think about the opens
the highs the close and the low
of every single candle
on
a monthly chart over the last
three months
every pair that you uh
that you have on your platform this is a
good study not to trade every single
pair but i want you to go back over
every pair you think is
of interest to you
and have the open high loan closed
delineated on a monthly chart over the
last three months so that would look
like this we're in november now
so here's october
september
august
and having those reference points
on your chart
and having those levels uh transposed
into your lower time frames they'll
bring a great deal clarity
now you may have a few overlapping
levels like this
chart we have a couple different opens
and closes that are real close to
proximity
that's okay
but i want you to find the most recent
down candle
that would be this one here
there you go
and then prior to this
down candle
what up candle exists above it
so much if this is the down candle you
got to go above its high
so its high is
if i can get it to show up
okay the high is 31.44 so we have to
have an up candle or an up close candle
that has at least
a low that's higher than
3144.
obviously it's right here
just that quick
we've delineated
a range on the monthly chart
now by itself you've done a great deal
already
but i know you don't believe it you have
to see it you need to have faith in it
so what we defined is the range in which
we're going to trade in
if i take these two reference points and
i'll drop them down into a weekly chart
okay by having it on a weekly chart we
can have a lot more information refined
and let's delineate
this month here
with the vertical line
on the month prior to it so now we have
a down candle
to the right
of this vertical red line
so we're looking at june this is june
having a down close
so we go into a daily chart i'm sorry
weekly chart okay
we have price still in the long term
consolidation many weeks going by here
and these two down candles here
price trades through it on this candle
here
so now we have activated two two down
candles as a bullish order block we have
upside movement here
it violates the two down candles so now
we can see
price return back down into it it would
be a bullish scenario
notice also that the monthly
candle at 130 70 we'll call it 130 80.
well let's round it to 130 80.
that's close enough for government work
price drops down into that a couple
different times
and you see price is expanded now the
upside is still
that monthly bearish order block
it's also
the beginning of the last three candles
that were up it's the same as this up
candle slow
you can see price and you can probably
already visualize it reaching for this
probably going into next uh week or the
week after
we'll probably see see more
continuation on the upside
we go into a daily chart
okay you can see the vertical lines
delineate each month
see
price dipping down into
that monthly
open that we rounded up to 130 80.
price responds aggressively off of that
and then we have
the beginning of this decline here in
october
and this is the reason why
and it sounds
like
hindsight
if you're watching this without having
the benefit of being a part of the live
sessions and watching the recordings
over the last last week
but we looked at 132.80 as a downside
objective
and the reason why that was objective
was based on these two down candles here
and the fact that we are looking for
higher prices relative to what's been
shown on
the monthly
okay
so we see price retrading back into this
down candle
multiple times right here on this one
and then ultimately
retreating down into the higher level
3280 level
right in here
and you can see price expanding on the
upside so we're looking for 138
big figure and potentially higher than
that
the takeaway is this if you look at your
monthly charts
okay
and you define where you're at presently
in the range
all you have to do is find the most
recent down candle and most recent up
candle and there's your range
if you get the market trade above a down
candle you wait for a return back to
that down candle to trade up into the
last up candle
if you have a market trade up into
a
up candle you find the last down candle
the most recent down candle which will
be over here that would be a range
for the downside
so we have still have
upside still to go
for
dollar cad on a monthly basis
let's look at this same example
of study on a
u.s japanese yen pair
okay we have the most recent
down candle here
and prior to this down candle you have
to have a candle that's higher than the
candle's high
which is
104 35
so above here
to the left where's the up candle it's
here
there's your range so between 106 28
and 103
26 so basically 300 pips
the idea as soon as this candle trades
above
the down candle's high
this down candle becomes a bullish order
block
so we can be a buyer at 103.26 or less
we drop into a weekly chart
here's price trading below 103
26 and again here on the us election
trading down into the bullish order
block
here we go into a daily chart
you can see the body of this down candle
it's larger than this one here
so this is the beginning of the bullish
order block
tear
and mean threshold of this down candle
would be about right here
and it's not even challenged at all here
even on the election
uh knee-jerk reaction
so price dips down into it here this
will be a buy
it starts to rally away then the next
candle opens on the election
trades down into
previous bullish order block this would
be another buy
and rallying away
we have old highs back here
and we have equal highs back here
on the
monthly chart this is the objective we
would be reaching up to and we've
already seen that happen with 300 pips
plus
choose kiwi dollar
[Music]
and go to a monthly
okay so we have
the last
down candle
here
and the most recent up candle
okay
and we've moved away from the last stop
candle
exercising this as a
bearish order block
we go down to a weekly
okay you see price trading up into bear
shoulder block it does trade through the
body of this candle but it's rather
sloppy right now
the downside objective is 69.83
so 6985
the bodies of these candles here
closed comes in at
70.05 so that would probably be where i
would be looking to cover
it's about 120 pips or so
still potential downside objective
personally on the side now i think it's
going to go down here
to 67.80
and on the daily time frame
you can see price has in fact already
moved
a good distance
now this is the bearish order block up
in here
so anything above that
price had reached up into we can refine
that into a lower level time frame
bearish overblock
see it trading it here
minimum expectation is to trade down to
here
the next one would be down here
so you're going to reach for that
and then below these lows
so we're using the monthly chart to give
us our bullish and bearish order blocks
and define our range and then we look
for lower time frames to get closer
to the market and refine our risk
use the higher time frame monthly chart
find the most recent up candle and most
recent down candle there's your range
define that range in terms of where the
most recent order flow has sent
price was it violating a down close or
down candle which
gives that
permission to become a bullish order
block
or has price broken
an up candle
by violating its low
which then activates that as a bearish
order block um you just simply look for
the the contrary and order block
on the monthly chart
and you take those levels and you find
them down until weekly into a daily and
down to an hourly chart and you can see
there's a plethora of opportunities to
to study with all these different pairs
and it gives you a context to actually
look into the marketplace with a
specific mindset not just waiting for a
neon sign to jump off at you and say
okay
well i wonder what i should do today
you'll know what levels to trade off of
relative to the monthly chart and it's
basically a top-down approach
that leads you right into trade setups
that you otherwise wouldn't know they
were there