for the month of november 2016
ict mentorship
we're talking about false tops and
bottom patterns as it relates to
classical head and shoulders
now head and shoulders pattern is
typically seen with a
price high
that trades in a small little
retracement then it creates a higher
high
and it retraces back
lower and it creates another lower
price peak or short-term high and then
connecting those three successive peaks
in price
we classically refer to that as the
neckline and classical support
resistance ideas are seen here where if
that neckline is broken
many times you'll see it retrace or pull
back up to that neckline and then sell
off again
in the form of
selecting targets you can measure the
range from the neckline up to the head
or the highest peak
and subtract that range from the
neckline once price breaks below it
and i'll give you a reasonable price
objective now the problem with this
pattern okay it's
because it's taught in all of our retail
books and such every trader out there
when they first get in their charts
they're always looking for these types
of patterns
but generally price will form these
genuinely at intermediate or long-term
highs only
and due to the low understanding of most
retail traders they tend to seek these
classic topping patterns on lower time
frames
and many times at a significant low in
price but they marry the pattern
the opposite is referred to as an
inverted head and shoulders pattern this
is a false pattern false bottom pattern
we're going to be teaching in here so
we're not really teaching these
classical patterns
uh they can be found on the internet i'm
not going to teach that but what i'm
actually going to tell you is how you
can capitalize on these patterns when
they appear in charts
and our higher time frame premise
indicates the opposite direction is
unfolding
but an inverted head and shoulders
pattern is
typically seen with a short-term low
that's met with a lower low
then it makes a higher short-term low
and you connect the highs that form
around those three successive lower lows
and we refer to that as the neckline
eventually should price trade above that
neckline classically you would expect a
pullback in price
or retrace it back down to the neckline
and then advance me up to the target and
the range from the neckline down to the
lowest low of those three lows
added to the neckline once the price
breaks through it that would give you a
reasonable upside objective now again
much in the same way generally price
will form these
genuinely at intermediate or long-term
lows
and again much like we said with the
regular classical head and shoulders
pattern due to the low understanding of
most retail traders they go into the
lower time frames and they start looking
for this classic modern pattern on lower
time frame charts
and many times at a significant high in
price
but much like you probably done when you
first started the trader you get these
textbooks and you get these ideas and
you go in you force
the
understanding of what you learned
out of the books into the charts so
therefore you learned about head and
shoulders patterns so therefore there
must be a head and shoulders pattern
right now so let's go in there and trade
it
and unfortunately it doesn't always
equate to profitability
uh i when i first started as a futures
trader this was one of the patterns that
were
really promoted hard because it's the
idea that you want to cut so high and
you want to catch a bottom and
picking tops and bottoms is one of the
worst games to play especially the new
trader because number one even seasoned
pros don't do that okay we don't we
don't pick tops and bottoms
we can trade with rather
impressive new accuracy in in catching
significant intermediate term lows and
short-term lows and highs but as it
relates to long-term tops and bottoms
i try to avoid that and i actually
promote the idea of doing the same thing
in your own trading try not to do that
but one of the coolest things i've
learned by going through institutional
order flow studies and watching how
interbank pricing is delivered
it allows me to go in and actually see
these patterns when they form in price
charts
if i have a
indication that the price is actually
going to go higher and i see a
head and shoulders pattern which would
be a false top
in my opinion but in the charts retail
will see that as a top forming
conversely looking at it inverted head
and shoulders which would be classically
viewed as a bullish pattern in price
if i see that happening when the market
is
actually bearish
i would be looking to go short
and
where
we see the
neckline let's go back to the standard
head and shoulders pattern
when you look at the neckline
what i see there is an opportunity to be
long once the neckline is broken on the
downside especially if we are in a
institutionally trained bullish
environment that means if we're in a
long term or immediate term low
and it forms a
successive three peaks
in price moving higher which would be
classically viewed as a head shoulders
pattern um chartist pure chartist would
see that as a
bearish indication especially new newbie
traders or less informed traders i like
seeing when price does that because to
me it's a retail trap
and marketing is actually uh designing
classical chart patterns in price where
you can actually
get tripped up thinking just because you
saw a head shortage formation and the
neckline's broken um when that neckline
is broken
i don't see that pullback as a
resuming lower or a new selling scenario
i see that as a turtle soup long that
took out two previous lows where the
clean lows were there i look at that as
a buying opportunity so i'll buy the
cell stops below those equal lows or
where the neckline is and then i'll look
for the head
or the highest peak to be violated and
i'll try to pair up my
long exits with the buy stops above the
highest high
in this pattern
and that would be my first objective
the inverted head shoulders i would do
the opposite if i'm looking for
price action to be bearish
as a higher time frame would indicate
and i see a low with a lower low and a
higher low which would be deemed as a
inverted head and shoulders i don't see
that as a bullish breakout above the
neckline i'm actually looking at that as
a run on buy stops
and i'm going to look to go short there
and not expect to see price go higher
but in fact blow out those equal highs
and then make a run for the cell stops
below what would be deemed as the head
on this pattern or would be the lowest
low and most recent price action
you can actually take your first profit
at the right shoulder on both these
patterns
respectively but let's take a look at a
couple chart examples and you can see
what this pattern looks like in price
okay folks we're looking at a daily
chart of british pound usd or cable
and i want you to take a look at this
down candle
right before the up move we've
consolidated for a while price came down
and hit that same order block right here
okay closed in
the
fair value gap between the high
to the midway point of the candle and
look at this candle right next to it
price came down and respected
that range
okay
right in here didn't go any farther than
that
and then on this day here
it's august 10th
we traded through the down candle
making this a bullish order block right
in here
so from this candle's high down to its
opening it becomes sensitive
to be a buyer
right there
and the high comes in at 1 55 46
so on this day here we trade down into
it on the 12th
of august 2015.
shaded right down into the body of that
down candle which is a bullish water
block
now that's bullish on a daily so let's
take a look at a hourly chart at that
same time on
august 12th
so here we have the market making a high
a higher high
and a lower high and we have two equal
lows in here so we have what
we have a head and shoulders pattern
retail traders are going to see that as
a selling scenario
so they're going to look for a break of
this neckline
and then take the range from the high
down to that neckline and subtract that
that will give them their objective for
going short
okay so we have that range here
and we can duplicate that and give
ourselves our downside objective for the
retail mining crowd
so retail is going to think this
breakdown here is going to lead them
down to 155 or thereabouts in this range
here so retail is going to expect
a range expansion
down to a low of
154.95
we do not expect that because on the
daily chart we're expecting the bullsh
order block to send prices higher so
while we see a in a regular head and
shoulders pattern which would be
classical bearishness
in the part of price action study
as it relates to institutional order
flow we're looking at the run below
these lows in here as they run on
sale stops
so we're looking at the market to go
below here to pair up orders to go long
for those individuals that want to have
a sell stop down here that's already
long their trailing stops loss is going
to be in the form of a sales stop
because the market moved most recently
has been higher
we see this move below these equal lows
as an opportunity to buy those sell
stops those willing sell stops or flood
the market when the market trades below
here so now we have a lot of liquidity
remember that market efficiency paradigm
we see liquidity here in the form of
going long and we're going to be looking
for
objective up here
to take profits
so we could be a buyer
at 155.50
and look for 5620
a move above this high
as our objective or 70 pips
the market runs one two three four more
times below that low gathering up the
cell stops and then expansion
which pairs up the buy stops above 5620
and ultimately you can see a nice little
little pool back here
okay so that's an objective
of using
the head and shoulders pattern
against
what retail would expect
and using higher time frame
institutional order flow on the daily
chart reading it as the banks would
let's go back out to that daily chart
you can see what it did as a result
and there's that expansion and it's not
much of a move but that you don't need
much of it we understand what you're
looking for okay we have another example
here this is the daily of the british
pound usds
the
down candle right before this big move
up
equal highs in here there would have
been buy stops above these highs
this rally up takes out those buy stops
and it comes all the way up and closes
in its range
all up here so this liquidity voids
closed in that's up candle
closes it in but more importantly these
stops were targeted
with this down candle that means that
this down candle was a bullish order
block which is used to break
the buy stops that were in the
marketplace here
so when price trades below it here when
price comes back up to it here we're
inside of a breaker that's a bearish
environment 153 45 to 153.50
in that area we're looking for a reason
to expect some kind of a
bearishness
but
there's going to be
on a lower time frame
retail will see patterns like this we
have a low
a lower low
higher low
this is an inverted head and shoulders
pattern
you draw your
neckline on
the chart
okay
that's the high up here
and we're going to draw what would be
considered the
inverted head and shoulders neckline
connecting
these two levels here and the difference
would be from the low up to this
neckline once we break above it
price trades above it here
neckline is broken
the stops below here would be would be
targeted
so selling up here on a break above the
neckline
not looking at that as bullishness and
return for
higher prices but looking for it to sell
off getting above there so we would look
for that run
to sell into the buy stops above this
high here and above this high here
that's why i would expect to see some
bears this year and then we would wait
for a run below these lows here it does
give a lot more than that here but
nonetheless it's not a bad little trade
uh 10 20 30 40 50 60 70
80 pips or more running them low over
here
let's go back out to the daily
okay we're going to look up at this high
up here
price trades up into it here
we're going to use the low of the last
up candle
right here and the body of the candle
you can see that it trades up into that
as well
and we're going to look up at the
18th
on
october
okay so we have here's the
15th
creating a
head and shoulders inverted so that
would be viewed as bullishness
so if we get above
that high we can be a seller
because we would expect those buy stops
to be viewed as breakout artists on in
inverted head and shoulders they're
going to see that as bullish pattern
we're going to look at it as a bearish
pattern we're going to be completely
opposite of that
now you can do two things you can use
this here or you can use the bodies of
the candles like i teach
where the most volume is so this is the
highest body of the candle so 5502 would
be a cell
if we get above it
price trades to it here so you can be a
seller above 5502
so 5502 is your
area being
bearish we do not look at that as a
breakout and then wait for a pullback
for new higher prices we're looking to
see it sell off and there's your entry
on
the buy stops at 55.02
and the neckline
i'm sorry the head down here
your objective would be to cover
below that low right here
and that happens
right there
and then again all through here gives
you another opportunity to cover
and ultimately uh runs one more time
above that 5502 level
for buy stops and then again below what
would be the head
plenty opportunity to get me handsome
profits
so again it's you look for the pattern
because retail will look for the pattern
but you're going to fade that pattern
based on what you see
on the higher time frames we look for
institutional overflow to justify why
this should be bearish up in here we
should be looking for reasons to be
selling
not buying and if we see inverted head
and shoulders patterns on the lower time
frames retail's gonna be all over that
looking for bullish you know upside
moves
and that's not what you see here at all
hopefully you found this one insightful
as well we're going to be attacking a
lot of the retail-minded classical chart
patterns throughout this ict mentorship
so uh this is just the beginning of two
that will fall victim to
institutional order flow until next time
wish you good luck and good trading