welcome back folks this is teaching
number seven of eight for the month of
November 2016 in the ICT mentorship
we're gonna be teaching trendline
Phantoms or false trend lines
and the first is going to be diagonal
trend line support
the priming is done by way of seeing the
market begin to make higher highs and
higher lows
the market appears to have an imaginary
diagonal line it seems to repel price
higher from
retail Traders will extend these
imaginary lines into the future and
attribute support theories to it
when price hits the extended imaginary
diagonal line connecting higher lows
retail traders buy it then
conversely diagonal trend line
resistance
this is primed in the thought processes
of retail Traders by seeing the market
begin to make hot
the market beginning to make lower highs
and lower lows
the market appears to have an imaginary
diagonal line it seems to propel price
lower from
retail Traders will extend these
imaginary lines into the future and
attribute resistance theories to them
when price hits the extended imaginary
diagonal line connecting lower highs
retail Traders short at that moment
okay trend line Theory now it's my
press it's
it's my perspective that there's no
basis on trend line theory in the form
of diagonal support or diagonal
resistance
and I believe it says basically an
opinion
um there's no statistical Edge that I've
been able to build with use of diagonal
support or resistance in the form of
trend lines
now I've been doing this for 24 years
coming up and just about the end of the
month we're actually producing this
video and I will have been a Trader for
24 years
and in 24 years I've done a lot of
things in analysis and I was
indoctrinated with trend lines when I
first started and to me it made perfect
sense because I could see it in the past
and you know all the books gave us
perfect examples where it all works but
when we try to use the trendline idea
you know which lows do you draw
connections to which highs do you draw
connections to and quickly all of a
sudden and you it's like well maybe this
isn't as easy as I thought it was
but does price have an awareness of the
point of trendline support
or does price have an awareness of the
point of trend line resistance I'll
submit to you that it does not
price has no awareness of your trend
line price doesn't respect what you have
on your charts price only respects where
the actual liquidity is in the
marketplace and because they can't see
you because you're too small
the marketplace sees where the large
pools of liquidity are that means in
buying interest and selling interest
that's already in the marketplace in the
form of protective cell stops protective
buy stops or new buy stocks for long
entries or new sell stops for selling
entries
that's the only thing that makes price
move and it's going to be hinged and
framed on the context of who
is in play right now what what smart
money entity has the control of the
marketplace at the moment is it going
higher based on their book being bullish
or is it going lower based on their book
being bearish and that's what this
mentorship teaches it gives you those
ideas to go into seeing where price is
most likely going to go and we don't
subscribe to down sloping trend lines or
up sloping trend lines to formulate
ideas in which we find support or
resistance based on that idea
do banks associate value or
prognostication on the basis of
trendline theory I'll submit to you no
they do not now for some that are in the
financial industry maybe you're working
at a bank maybe you have used them in
the past and you've had success I'm
telling you since the banks don't have
any association or prognostication
placed on valuing a trendline level on a
diagonal basis and the reason why is
because it's so subjective you are
associating future price movement to a
level that hasn't been traded to yet
you're doing it on the basis of
connecting two reference points in the
past that don't have any bearing on what
the future price is going to do has
nothing
that high that you connected to to a
lower high when you're looking for
resistance or down trending trend line
resistance that third time it supposedly
comes up to that line what makes you so
confident that it's going to go down at
that point
just because you drew the line on on
your chart
the the
Banks don't care what you're scribbling
all of your charts they don't care about
that they're not aware of it okay but
what they are aware of is sentiment that
shifts and builds around those levels
because it's going to be many times
being replicated on the fund level
funds will get beat up That's the basis
of trading large Traders are the prey
that's where the markets go they go for
their orders not for our little orders
not for our little liquidity okay but
because we've learned
to trade and herd
like the fund Traders
we all many times are casualties of that
war between smart money and large funds
that's the business model that goes on
large funds are cannibalized at
reversals but they're permitted to
facilitate long-term trends when the
markets are in that environment
but trend lines are not the key to it
is the very nature of trend lines flawed
at its core I will submit to you that
yes it is because it gives too many
dangling carrots in front of the
Trader's eyes thinking that okay this is
going to be an easy setup so therefore
let me go in here and sell out this
resistance trend line or let me buy it
this diagonal support trend line
it's not that easy folks but many times
our charts will paint these beautifully
disguised opportunities that are
impossibilities
knowing this
how can market makers capitalize on this
fallacy and price action
retail bullish trend line support
in periods when price is making higher
lows and higher highs the use of trend
line support will be adopted by retail
Traders
the influx of weak candid or less
informed money at an area or price level
provides liquidity for the market maker
the chart may appear bullish but the
underpinnings are in fact the opposite
the retail crowd will buy at a moment
when price will be devoid of support
price will collapse and leave the retail
Trader long withdraw down in the trade
when that third Touch of that uptrend
line is seen in price action many times
I get dialed in expecting the high that
forms between the low
at the second time it hits the trend
line and the third time it hits the
trend line that high in between I aim in
that high for a bare shorter block or I
will be allowing price to just briefly
poke its head above that high for a
turtle suit especially if the higher
time frame charts that I use for my
analysis indicate that we are not in a
bullish environment but the lower time
frames will many times paint these
beautifully Illustrated uptrend diagonal
support lines
so what I'm trying to do is I'm focusing
in on when the market maker sets their
traps for a sell scenario many times
that high in between the load it forms
if the second retouch of that trend line
and the third Touch of that trend line
the high in between there is going to be
a cell scenario that I'm aiming for in
that I'm looking for a bearish order
block or I'm looking for maybe sometimes
on a lower time frame I'm looking for a
breaker a bearish breaker where the
market has shown a willingness to Rally
up to take out an old high that's on a
lower time frame that may not be seen as
clear with that high in between point
number two and point number three
all I'm looking for is a reason to be
contrarian because if the trend line
looks so obvious to me I look at that as
a trap
retail Bears trend line resistance
in periods when price is making lower
lows and lower highs the use of trend
line resistance will be adopted by
retail Traders
the influx of weak candid are less
informed money at an area or price level
provides liquidity for the market maker
the chart may appear bearish but the
underpinnings are in fact the opposite
the retail crowd will sell at a moment
when the price will be devoid of
resistance
price will rally and leave the retail
Trader short withdraw down in the trade
between the high formed at Point number
two and point number three
the low in between those two points I'm
going to be aiming for a reason to be a
buyer down there because I I will submit
to you that if the higher time frames
are indicating that higher prices most
likely going to be in the near term and
we're trading a higher time frame
support levels based on order blocks or
institutional order flow
I'm looking for that low between High 2
and high 3. I'm looking for a bullish
order block at that low in between the
two points and while price may drop down
into that old low just by a little bit
but not getting down to the low
altogether
I will be looking for a bullish Order
Box to buy
or I will accept a break just below that
low for a turtle soup long entry or
basically a run on the cell stops many
times the market will break through
now a point of which I wanna draw a
attention to is the second point at
which you have that trend line
in other words that the first High you
you see and it comes down and makes a
lower high number two and it trades
lower and you think it's going back up
to make a a number three point High
that's lower or three times touching on
that downtrend when the market rallies
I'm actually going to be looking for a
move up into that second High because
that's where a lot of the buy stocks are
going to be residing
the same thing said just an opposite
when we're looking for that sell
scenario in bullish trend line support
retail's gonna be looking forward to go
higher I'm looking forward to go down
below Point number two that's where
everyone's stop loss is going to be
now when you think about like this trend
lines in the form of diagonal basis
support and resistance it's really a
toss-up
do you have confidence that the trend
line that you're drawing is going to
really Provide support or resistance
think about it it's really Associated
closely to flipping a coin
heads are going to be a buyer and guess
what tells you'd be a seller
you're back to the same equation of
chance and we do not trade with the
perspective of chance
when we trade we look at the marketplace
to provide clues
clues in which the smart money is going
to be utilizing
the liquidity that's made available for
willing or unwilling liquidity in the
form of the funds and uninformed money
you have to think like that liquidity
for product
prices delivered to engineer efficiency
for the smart money entities only
okay folks let's take a look at examples
here
okay I want to take a look at this
high right here
okay price has a nice run away from that
so that very nice animated term High
put an Impulse price swing moving lower
and we have
a gap in here fair value Gap from the
low of this candle to the high of this
candle there's only been down movement
with this candle's body
I'm going to highlight this whole area
in here
and we're going to reference the
the low of that candle
right here
Okay so
we're going to watch price as it trades
that's just a reactionary level that
we're gonna be waiting for in the future
so this is how we stalk the setup price
starts to Rally up
trades right into that 52 34 level right
there
that day it occurs
is December 11 2015.
okay over here on the right hand side
we have the 15 minute time frame
for December 11 2015.
and we're going to delineate that
same high
at 52.34
and you see price hitting it right here
and I want you to look at how this low
connected to this low here
projected out eventually has another
third time hitting it
okay so trend line followers and see
that as a potential continuation to go
higher finding some support here one two
three maybe a run up higher
problem is is we have
a daily
institutional reference pulling over
here
and we're in that area over here in this
whole shaded area we've closed that in
so we would be looking for the next area
of liquidity
and down here so we can look at this
range
from this Down Candles High
from this damn candle's High
up
to this Down Candles low
between this candle's high and this
candle is low it's only been one pass on
the upside so we're going to be looking
for price I want to come back down into
this candle is high in the form of
50 60. okay so 150 60 level
so we know there's a possibility to see
price want to drop lower based on
liquidity
we have trend lines in here that would
be reasonable in terms of what retail
would be drawing
expecting some bullish prices
let me show you what it may look like at
the time when it was forming
okay you have a Hello here they're
finding some support here old high back
here so they could reasonably expect to
see this to trade higher
problem is the only thing it's done
is moved back up into the last up candle
here which is a bearish order block
right there
so using the market efficiency paradigm
we don't see this as trendline support
we see this as a return up into a reason
to get short more and the market breaks
lower
Market trades down into a low right here
which we'll look at let me zoom out a
couple minutes
but we have a low here we have another
low here protecting that low out in time
okay we can see price coming down to
that third time does it make a bullet
scenario no it's only going up to the
last up candles Midway point or mean
threshold
so let's take a look at what that is
okay right in here equilibrium trading
rate that uh reference point we're gonna
be looking for price to come down and
close in this void this candle is low
here and this candle is high so in here
has a liquidity void
and we have
cell stops below this low here again
remembering that we're focusing on the
idea on the daily chart like a bank
would looking for 150 60 level
so up here we're looking at this Market
move higher
anything that was viewed as support on
diagonal basis on a trend line we're
going to look at that as suspect and
buyers are going to come in here in a
big influx
we're going to have wonderful
opportunities to be sellers to them
Market trades up into
[Music]
equilibrium one more time Pierce is the
high turtle soup
s off and it trades around one more time
down into this level in here so I'm
going to zoom out a little bit to a 30
minute chart you can see that
other trend line so we have a low here
extend out in time here's another low
and price comes down hits it here is
that a buy no it's only coming back up
into this last up candle bear shoulder
block cell here do not see this as a
bullish scenario because of trend lines
because we're expecting this area here
to promote selling
okay it's in an area which we're going
to be looking for a sell-off
price does in fact sell off
and you see the bearishness here it runs
back above old High
turtle soup
or Bear's order block
okay because we're using a higher time
frame setup over here you stop would
provide you an opportunity to put a stop
above and hold high back here
price accelerates goes through what
would be considered trend line support
and ultimately
down into the 150 60 level
right here
and as you can see it over here
so let's take a look at some
downtrending or bearish trend lines that
are actually buy scenarios
okay folks we have a nice run up here
two Down Candles right for the up move
okay so we have 143.85 where thereabouts
the opening price on the ears 143.84 so
we'll round it to 43.85
okay we have a down candle hits 43.85
so we're going to add 43.85 to our
lower time frame chart
so 43.85
we see price
trading down into it here hitting it one
more time
we have a high we have a lower high and
the third time price hits it here
we see this as a cell no we don't we see
it as a potential Turtle Soup long here
or a return back to bullish order block
so we could be a buyer at 43 85 or 43.90
on a limit or if we can get a fill at
43.80 or lower it's going to be a buyer
down here with the expectation that this
is a false trend line and
we would be looking for this High here
that's the second one so anyone would be
short all their protected buy stocks
will be above this high in here
price rallies away
comes out real close to this high end
here
one more retracement lower
back down into the last two Down Candles
here as a buying opportunity
again up here is where we'd be expecting
to see
the buy starts to be tagged
you can see that happening here
five stops is right there
you can see that happening here buy
stops hit right here
then
you'd be permitted to see lower prices
because we've seen the highs taken out
here
for the form of a buy stop read and then
now the liquidity below here would be
allowed to be tested
can you see that happening here
's another example we have a nice down
candle here bullish order Block it's
validated when the Scandal trades above
this down candle is high the very next
camera we trade up again in the third
candle you see it opens here and trades
down into the body of this down candle
the main threshold is approximately 144
big figure and the open comes in at
144.46 on this down candle so we have 46
pit range in here and the the day on
this candle is the 18th of May
of 2016.
we see the
18th of May here
okay and we see the high a lower high
can extend that out in time does the
price sell off here the little bit but
then it comes up Pops through one more
time so traders that even see this as a
downtrend that maybe have been broken
they may see this as a return back down
into it to be a buyer and they're wrong
there as well
also you may see a classic chart pattern
here that we haven't spoke about but
we're going to talk about it in this
mentorship as well
classic chart pattern triangle
and false breakout here they would have
been wrong even trading with that and
exploding up into one of the 146 big
figure now the reason why 146 big
figures is the last up candle in the
daily chart
and it closed in all these Down Candles
so intutional order flow you're going to
see price come up and close all that in
so it's only been delivered on the
downside all Down Candles price has to
be efficiently balanced by offering on
the buy side after it's been sold off
and been offered on the sell side price
to be efficiently delivered has to be
offered on the buy side so we see that
rally back up into that 146 big figure
and that's why it quickly ran up into
that level here but breaking
this idea of
these supposed
trend lines
that's not the key to it guys but we can
see when the trades are seeing these
retail fingerprints all over it
probabilities really shift in our favor
when we're doing the opposite of it and
we can also justify it with
institutional order flow and
institutional reference points on a
daily chart just like a bank would
so hopefully you enjoyed this teaching
go back through all your charts look at
some of the moves that's taken place and
go down to the lower time frames and
actually see how these trend lines are
really there as Phantoms and Retail
chases them and when they think they see
them
they're really not there and they end up
giving up The Ghost and their profits