in this section we're going to discuss
how prices move and who the players are
behind it when you understand how
traders make prices move then how you
need to think to generate consistent
results will start to become clear to
you okay where we're going now is that
is that I think what I said when we do
just before the break is that when you
guys understand the nature of price
movement and how any technical
methodology that's based on a
mathematical formula or a price pattern
interacts with that movement when you
understand that relationship how you
need to think will become self-evident
do you remember me saying that okay
this is the part that we're going into
right now okay in other words where you
understand just exactly how prices move
because what I found in doing these
workshops over the years that here I'm
I'm addressing a group of people who
trade and who and many cases have traded
for years and if you ask somebody
exactly how do prices get from one price
to the next they can't tell you they
don't know they don't know how it
happens and maybe you guys are I'm sure
you guys aren't that that group but well
you know we'll do what we'll go over it
just as a refresher okay we'll do it as
a kind of refresher no actually I
haven't I would address a group yet that
that there were very few people or if
anybody could tell you exactly how
prices move from one price level to the
next so for an example
okay if the last reported price that you
see on your screen of something is 10
how does it get to 11 what who's they
the market maker and market maker asked
12 okay
well no well okay it's at 10 how does it
get to 11 how does the price actually
move to 11
well more buyers but that okay that's
true but then again when you with that
demand okay
but when you look at 10 what you have is
you have offers at 11 and you have bids
at nine right everybody understands that
okay now there's only two ways that
anybody can make money in this business
there's only two possible ways no matter
what strategies you're employing no
matter how elaborate they are no matter
how simple they are you have to be able
to buy something at a low price and sell
it back at a higher price or sell
something at a high price and buy it
back at a lower price well we in
agreeance on that and would you also
agree that everyone that trades is
trading to make money in other words I'm
gonna say that there isn't anybody who
puts on a trade that does so knowingly
and consciously thinking it's going to
be a loser
in other words where they going to the
mark and say I my purpose is to lose
money okay you guys with me on this now
if the only way that you can make money
is to buy low and sell high or sell high
and buy low and the last price posted
price is 10 which represents the value
at that moment then what's low nine is
low and what's high 11 what's the only
way that it can get to 11
somebody somebody thinks 11
good price meaning that they have to buy
high relative to the last price right so
for an exist
so basically what this also means is
that that all the offers have to be
taken out at ten do they not anybody who
had an offer in at ten that wanted to
sell at ten will get filled and all
those offers have to be taken out for
the price to go to eleven correct
and of course and for the price to go to
twelve all the offers that exist that at
eleven have to be taken out so that
someone could actually bid the price up
to twelve for prices to move somebody
literally has to bid the barque it up or
for prices to go lower it means that
someone has to offer it lower now if the
only way that anyone can make money is
to buy low and sell high and sell high
and buy low why in the world would
anybody bid the market past the last
posted price conviction exactly
conviction in other words what you have
is a situation where on every trade
every trade that exists or a boat there
are two people on both sides of the
trade even in stocks there's even
someone who's selling a stock not like a
commodity where we're in a futures
contract or an options contract there's
two people on both sides of the trade
there's a buyer and there's a seller and
the next tick is going to make one of
them a winner and one of them a loser
right off the bat if you and I you and I
enter into a trade at ten okay we enter
into a trade at ten it means that you in
essence if you're the seller they'll say
you you sold them at ten and I bought
them at ten the next tick is going to
make one of us a winner and one of us a
loser if the next tick is nine the
amount of money that flows into your
account is coming directly out of mind
are you guys with me on this the next
tick is eleven the amount of money
flowing into my account is coming
directly out of your account okay so
basically what you have is you have two
diametrically opposed again to every
single trade every trade that is made
there are diametrically opposed Ivelisse
about what the few
sure is going to be so again I'm going
to say what would cause anybody to buy
high or sell low just conviction in
other words what you have is a situation
where if someone's willing to bid a
market up to the next highest price
basically what that person is doing is
that person is stepping out saying that
my conviction that the price is going to
go to 12 or beyond is so great that I am
willing to do the opposite of what I
need to do to make money think about
what I just said I am willing to do the
opposite of what I need to do to make
money because my conviction is so strong
that the next price will be 12 or 13
otherwise this person would wait if this
person thought the next price is going
to be 9 then they buy lower what they
thought was going to be 8 they'd buy low
they'd wait and buy lower whereas so
what happens is that the person who's
willing to bid a market up and take out
these offers at 10 take out all the
offers at 10 and bid it up to 11 has to
have a stronger conviction in the future
than the person who sold it to him at 11
because this person is creating price
movement is actually creating movement
and the person on the other side of the
trade is being passive because they're
doing exactly what they think they need
to do and that sell high relative to the
last price are you guys with me on this
okay everybody understand it now when I
ask you is there anybody in this room
who has purposefully bid up a market
there are there are some people who have
actually been a market up in other words
the people who've actually taken taken
the offers all the offers out at the
next highest price and bid it up do
people like that exist yes that so no we
are aware of the fact that there are
traders who have both who both have the
financial and the psychological
resources to actually purposefully bid
markets up or offer them lower we're
together on this right okay
so basically what you have is that all
price movement has to be a result of an
imbalance in the degree of conviction
between the traders who believe that
prices are going up and those who
believe that it's going down that is the
only way that prices move it doesn't
matter what the reasons are that people
tell you about why they did what they
did or it doesn't matter what the
reasons that you hear on CNBC or
whatever about where the market is and
why it went the way that it went
ultimately it all boils down to an
imbalance in conviction that's the only
way prices can move because the only way
they can move is for someone to actually
purposefully bid it up or offer it lower
and for them to do it there has to be
you know like like a sense of strength
in terms of energy in their belief that
the next tick is going to make them a
winner
okay so we're basically does everybody
understand everyone's with me on this
all price movement is a result of an
imbalance in conviction between the
buyers and the sellers every trade every
trade that's made there's somebody on
both sides of the trade that have
diametrically opposed
you're always having it with every
single trade there's always a clash
there's always a clash in wheels and a
clash and belief in terms of what the
next tick is going to be or what the
future holds we've got two people coming
entering into in a sense an agreement by
making a trade but both of those people
have diametrically opposed expectations
of the future and one of them is willing
to say hey you know what my expectation
is so great is so strong that I am
actually willing to do the opposite of
what I need to do to make money and get
a mark it up now there are traders who
will do that
I call them dynamic traders they are the
people that have like I said both the
financial and the psychological
resources to actually bid markets up
what the typical and what I'm going to
call everyone else passive technical
traders okay they've got dynamic traders
and passive technical traders what the
typical passive technical trader doesn't
really I'd say really not a where ever
think about is the fact that the only
way that they will find themselves in a
winning trade is by the actions of the
people who are willing to bid a market
up an offer will offer at lower that's
the only way that it happens in other
words when you and I get into a train I
am a passive technical trader by the way
I'm not one of these dynamic guys I
don't bid markets up an offer lower okay
that when you and I get into a trade at
this price right here let's say we got
to move ought at seven we're buyers at
seven what are we really saying when we
get into that trade bottom line what are
we saying based on the dynamics of what
I just explained we're saying that I
think that someone is going to come into
the market after E and buy at a worse
price and what I did
so that has such a strong conviction
that this market is going to go up that
that person is actually willing to buy
at a worse price than me to buy it eight
to buy it nine to buy it ten because if
there isn't anybody else that comes into
the market to take out all the offers at
eight take all the offers at nine take
out all the offers at ten that market
ain't going up and I'm not gonna be in a
winning trade you see the implications
are every single trade that we put on as
packed as passive technical traders we
are in fact obliged and dependent on
other people who are willing to do
something at a worse price than what
we've done it we did it at oh we will be
a winner are you guys following me on
this is it starting to put the idea of
trading into a different context that in
essence what you're really trading is
other people's perception of what is
high and what is low that any technical
indicator any price pattern that you
might trade any trade that you put on
you are basically trading other people's
perceptions of what is high and what is
low now when you think about how well
you might know other people's
perceptions you think about in that
context it might not make a lot of sense
to get so fixated on staying in a train
that isn't working it might be a little
easier to put in a stop and to say hey
you know what if they if these if people
aren't coming in to buy it a higher
price than me I'm gonna give them this
much room from here to here and if they
don't come in I'm out of this trade I
just go to the next one because that's
basically what you're doing is a trader
you are completely dependent on other
two other traders to make you a winner
now who are these dynamic traders who
are the people that are going to do this
and why
what hedge funds okay money managers in
the commodities arena
do you guys really know how like the
futures markets he was started in the
first place
or why'd they even exist
I know people probably exist because
there on the screen and it's part of the
platform but you know there's actually a
legitimate economic purpose for these
things and when you get to the
underlying and I would understand the
underlying reason for these markets
you'll understand why they trade the way
that they do and why prices move the way
that they do you know for an example
what you know what really what what what
happened in the past is that a for an
example if you had a farmer who you know
who planted their their their corn in
the spring and harvested the corn in the
fall what they were dependent on of
course was a lot of different factors
that they had no control of one of them
being the weather and one of them being
how much other how much other corn was
planted out throughout the country and
how much that corn would end up end up
in in the market in the fall in
relationship to what the demand was so
if there was a lot of corn and and and
let's say the demand remained relatively
constant the price of the corn would go
down and the farmer would lose money if
there wasn't a lot of corn and demand
would remain constant the price would go
up if there wasn't a lot of corn and for
some reason demand was really high and
the price would go up even further so
what you had is a situation where there
was a great deal of economic risk in
being a farmer or being anybody that
manufactured anything or abduch stuff
out of the ground like gold or silver or
manufactured electric motors that needed
copper or whatever goes into all the
products that we use so what what
evolved was a situation where the the
farmer and the and the manufacturer
let's say a bread that needed the flour
they would enter into what was called a
forward agreement meaning that they both
wanted the economic risks taken out of
their business they both wanted to be
able to make a profit they both wanted
you know to be able to have some sense
of certainty as to what prices might be
at some point in the future so for
example if if I'm a farmer and it cost
me $4 a bushel to plant my corn and
bring it to harvest or bring it to
market then for me to force me to make
some money I want at least five dollars
a bushel right
and if I'm the guy on the other end of
that trade or other end of that
transaction that wants to buy that corn
in the fall or wheat or whatever and I
want to know exactly how much I'm going
to have to pay for it so what ends up
happening is that if let's say it's it's
April or its it's March and the price of
corn is $4 a bushel you enter to a
forward agreement with with the with the
end user and they say hey you know what
I will deliver a million dollars of our
million bushels of corn or a hundred
thousand bushels of corn and say 450 a
bushel or whether a price they agreed on
five dollars a bushel regardless of what
the price of corn is in the fall so if
the price of corn in the fall happens to
be three dollars a bushel because
there's so much demand or because
there's because there's so much corn and
very little demand then the farmer
actually still got his price and let's
say five dollars a bushel but the but
the manufacturer ended up having to pay
two dollars a bushel more than what he
would have if he had waited and just
bought his corn on the open market in
the fall so in that sense he seemed to
lose on that transaction but then the
next year what ends up happening is that
there's very little corn or there's more
demand than what there is corn and the
price of corn ends up being seven
dollars a bushel and the farmer would
have made the seven dollars had he not
or entered into a ford agreement but
what ends up happening is he still made
his dollar bushel profit and the and the
end user ended up saving himself two
dollars a bushel so over the years all
this evens out well so then what
happened then is that exchanges in other
words instead of these these people
individually entering into these
transactions exchanges were developed so
in other words they had a central place
to come to and make these transactions
like the Chicago Board of Trade Chicago
Mercantile Exchange
well what ended up happening is that
when with the advent of exchanges which
you had of the situation where there
were people that were willing to take
the other sides of these trades that had
nothing to do with the actual process of
making bread or growing wheat or corn
they were called speculators and then
that's when futures are futures
contracts
came into being so what would happen is
that is that if I'm if I'm a farmer
instead of me having to make the
transaction directly with a with someone
who manufactures bread I could go to the
Chicago Board of Trade and sell my corn
or wheat in with a futures contract and
so if I'm selling it at four dollars a
bushel and so that means I'm long corn
this is where the long and the short
comes from I am long cash I'm long corn
and because I've got a crop and crop in
the ground and so if if I sell it at
four dollars a bushel on a futures
contract I think the equivalent number
of futures contracts and so if the price
of corn goes down but let's say the
price of corn goes up I've already
locked in well I'm gonna sell at five
dollars but I've locked in my dollar
bushel profit so if the price of corn
goes up what I've done is I'm short
futures I'm short the actual futures
contract I'm long the corn so I'm gonna
lose money on my futures contract
because as the price goes up I'm losing
money but I'm making money on my cash so
I'm making the equivalent amount of
money on my cash as well what I'm losing
on my futures so in any case it doesn't
matter what the market does the market
could go up the market can go down I've
locked in my dollar profit bushel but
dollar per bushel profit and the person
on the other side of that trade the
speculator if of course the market goes
up then the speculator is the one that
makes that two dollars a bushel profit
if it goes up to seven dollars a bushel
okay these guys with me on all this if
the price of course the price of of it
goes down then I'm losing money I'm
losing money on my cash crop but I'm
making money on my futures contract and
the speculator on the other side of the
contract is losing money because the
markets going down in other words the
speculator is just one-sided this the
farmers two-sided he is hedged that's
what's that's what's called a hedge now
what's interesting about all this is
that is that as these markets evolved
you will find that that the farmers
don't trade against each other
or the grain elevators or the people who
the commercials who actually are
involved with the production and
manufacture of anything they don't take
the other side of each other's trades
what they do is they want speculators to
take the other sides of their trades in
other words if I'm a if I'm a commercial
grain elevator I'm not going to be that
I'm another commercial grain elevators
not going to be taking the other side of
my trade because we're both going to be
doing the same thing okay if I'm a
farmer and I'm gonna sell sell my wheat
or sell my corn the guy the farmer down
the street who also trades isn't going
to be taking the other side of my trains
what what commercials and hedgers and
fund managers and all the people who are
really let's say professionals they have
become very very sophisticated at
finding ways of drawing the general
public into taking the other size of
their trades meaning in the point that
I'm making here is that they will
purposefully do things that will draw
the typical general public let's say the
general public into the other side of
their trades when in fact what they want
to do is the exact opposite for an
example let's if I'm if I'm a hedge fund
if I'm a hedge fund manager and I want
to and I'm long stocks or or it doesn't
really matter what it is I could be long
bonds I could be long a goal that could
be whatever it is and I want to and I
want to liquidate my position now I've
got a huge position meaning I've got a
cash position and I want to sell it if I
go into the market right now and sell my
entire position what do you think is
gonna happen to the price chances are
it's gonna go down I'm gonna I am
actually good at because of the volume
of my trades I am actually going to
drive the price down making my average
cost lower and lower I don't want to do
that I don't want a so for example if I
come into the market and I say hey you
know what I've got 10 million shares of
this and
not to sell what's going to end up
happening is that those 10 million
shares are going to end up taking out
all the bids all the way all the prices
down take out all the bids until you
find a spot where it can't take out
where the sides of the trade cannot take
out any more bids and the price
stabilizes okay so I'm thinking to
myself now what you get is you've got
these what I'm going to call like these
these hotshot hotshot kind of hardcore
traders where you know to make a name
for themselves because they're in a
they're in a big trading room and they
they compete amongst one another and
their bonuses depend on how well they do
what they're gonna be what if what if
they did something like this I'm looking
at a price chart let's just say they
could be Daly bars or whatever okay and
this is like a swing high swing low okay
now interestingly enough as we're
talking about this I want to make a
point about what does this what does
this price represent right here and what
does this price represent right here
what yeah we're going to call it
resistance but but but more from a
practical matter what does it represent
what's that ah yeah in other words there
wasn't no you're right he said he said
there's nobody believed is going to go
higher it represents there wasn't one
person in the whole world in the whole
world that was willing to bid it bid the
price one tick higher not one up to this
point there could be any number of
people who were willing to bid it higher
but it got to a certain price level and
there wasn't one person left in the
whole world that would bid it higher
this by the way is one of the reasons
why technical analysis works is because
the market has a memory this is why
technical analysis works the market has
because when the market came back down
he formed a swing low came back up to
this high there were people there were
people who made money by selling this
high there's a good chance those same
traders are gonna come back into the
market and do it again as well as there
are people who lost money by buying that
high because for every trade that was
made up to this last price there was a
buyer and a seller there was a trader on
the other end of the trade that sold
that bought that high
now when the market comes back again to
this to the same price level chances are
there will be an imbalance between the
buyers and the sellers just by the mere
fact that the people who made money are
going to be willing to trade it again
and come into the market maybe with with
a lot of ferocity and the traders who
lost money by buying that high are
probably not going to be willing to do
it again and so what you have is even
more of an imbalance that existed the
last time are you guys with me on this
okay well that's fine you can do that
however now I'm not gonna really get on
to the most I'm gonna do is get into
what we're just doing right now because
this is not you know this is not a
course in technical analysis I mean that
and it doesn't really matter anyway
because you guys are trading off on
mathematical formulas and and not doing
subjective trading so and this would
fall into the category of subjective
trading subjective trading also is is
the equivalent to like like who watches
Texas Hold'em tournaments I like on TV
anybody come on give me more of a show
of so so you've got so you've got
categories of development where we're
initially people when when they play
Texas Hold'em you play your cards and
then you get well enough and get good
enough of playing your cards but you
start doing is playing the people and
you get good enough you get so good that
you don't even have to play your cards
you need to look at your cards just play
the person that's the equivalents of
subjective trading okay what you're
doing is you're using a process of
deductive reasoning to determine who's
thinking what and what they're likely to
do okay and all the only reason I'm
giving you all this information and
making this point is so that you
understand
with no uncertain terms that there are
as a whole category of traders out there
people out there traders people who have
both the financial and the psychological
resources the bid markets up an offer
from lower and what's the point that I'm
making the point that I'm making is that
any particular technical methodology
that you use to determine a pattern is
present that gives you a higher
probability of one thing happening over
another until you can get into the minds
of the people who actually move prices
you will never know for sure what's
going to happen next the only people
that know for sure the people who are
willing to do it and that's what you've
got to get you got to burn that in your
brain you will never know for sure
what's going to happen next unless you
can read the minds of the people who are
going to do it and there are people who
will do it and they do it all the time
that's the only way you end up in a
winning trade most of the time when you
end up in a winning trade is because of
what these other dynamic traders are
doing so to convince you that there are
people who are willing to do this if I'm
a hedge fund manager and I've got to
unload if I've got to unload a huge
position and the market happens to be
sitting right here in relative to this
chart pattern how might I maximize my
profits what might I do now remember
I've got a sell I'm going to be a seller
but what might I do to make sure that I
get the best price what yeah drive it up
in other words I will do the opposite of
what I want to do to get a better price
and I will drive it up but how much risk
am i taking by doing that
well yeah I mean if I Drive the price up
by taking out these offers and then
bidding up taking out it off taking
other words I can look with with
depending on the kind of software I have
I can find out what depth the depth of
the market meaning that that you know
and I'm not saying these are hard hard
offers because people pull their offers
all the time but I can look at this I
can look at this hi and I say you know
what what if how much money might it
take for me to drive the market from
here to just pass these highs right here
how many offers do I have to take out to
do it just tally it up and see if you
want to spend the money because in
essence so how much risk you actually
taking see by by by driving it up what
you're doing is you're you're increasing
the asset value of your portfolio so in
that sense you're not taking any risk
you're actually making money if I if I
continue to drive the price up I am
actually making the trade that I made
down here winners every tick that I
drive the price up I'm making myself a
winner on the trades that I made at
lower prices to actually drive a price
up because you are making yourself a
winner at the prices that you know what
you bought out in lower prices if for an
example by me driving this price up it
draws other people into the market that
will help will it not because it creates
more of an imbalance now that's the real
thing what I want to do is I want to get
more buyers into the market and the
reason why I want to get more buyers
into the market is so somebody is there
to take the other side of my sell orders
because that's ultimately what I'm doing
here what I'm doing is I want to sell so
what I'm doing is creating a bigger pool
of orders to come into the market to I
could sell into so that I might my sell
orders don't drive the price down down
and so I will purposefully do the
opposite of what I want to do ultimately
with which back to my position now what
the reason why I'm selling has nothing
to do with this chart pattern absolutely
nothing to do with the chart pattern
itself I'm just using the chart pattern
as a means to maximize
my profits now what if I managed to
drive it up to resistance chances are
there's going to be a lot of selling
orders coming in that I'm gonna have to
compete with that's that's a risk that I
that's a risk that I'm taking here but
what if I can drive it a little past
that resistance what I'm gonna have is a
situation where all the people the other
traders who sold at this level right
here that came into the market because
it was approaching this previous high
they're gonna put their stops a little
bit above the market know what kind of
stops are they gonna be they're going to
be buy stops if they sold to get out at
a loss they have to be buyers if I can
drive the market to those buy stops I
have given myself an instant pool an
instant pool of orders to take the other
side of my trades and and get me out at
maximum profits this is typically what
you see in a chart pattern is a false
breakout because what will end up
happening is that as soon as my order
hits the market it's so large and and
then because there really weren't that
many other traders that we're willing to
bid continue to bid the market up
what'll do it it'll take out all the
bids and then drive the price right down
that's called a false breakout it's it's
being done at different different time
frames all of the time to do this you
have to have a large enough position so
that when you drive up your cost basis
it's incrementally small compared to
where you really are today and then as
you said you get up to either you do it
below that resistance hope you break
above and then you just dump your shares
right right thank you
now like I said this is well did anybody
ever wonder why like like you you have a
really strong bull market or a really
strong bear market and the market seems
to open up in the morning like in bull
markets that opens lower and bear market
opens higher let that happen well what's
the deal with that what do you think's
going on
you ever heard the term shaking out the
weak lungs and the weak shorts that's
what that's what that's what dynamic
traders are doing they're shaking out
the weak Long's in the weak shorts in
other words they're taking their spot
because what you have in a bull market
is you have you know people that feels
the markets going up because this is
this is a daily bar but if we made it an
intraday bar or whatever as a market is
going up they're buying people are
buying but they're not they're not like
really confident about what it is that
they're doing now in the morning before
the market opens there might not be that
many bids in other words if though after
the market opens they'll be more bids
that come into the market but before the
market opens there might not be that
many bids so what so if there aren't
what these dynamic traders did we'll do
to take advantage of this is they'll hit
those bids now in other words they'll
sell they'll sell into those bids drive
the market down and then when the market
opens up all of the weak longs meaning
people who aren't that confident well
will start to it will start to get a
little frightened and to get out of
their position what do they have to do
they have to sell and these other
dynamic traders will take the other side
of their sell orders to buy and increase
their position and the market goes right
straight back up all they did was shake
these guys out take their spot at lower
prices by by by forcing the market lower
on the open
isn't this an argument to have a Vig to
either not use let's talk no no no it is
not no I don't want to get I don't want
to get into user not you absolutely you
stops I'm not gonna no we're not gonna
get into that we're yes you can achill
passive technical traders in the
mechanical mode this is not in any way
saying that you should not use stops
absolutely it's a disastrous thing to do
not you stops okay because I'm not
saying that regardless of any of this
that you can't make money you I'm giving
all I'm doing is giving you examples
that there are people out there who will
drive prices up and offer them lower
that they have the psychological and
financial resources to do it and the
reason why I'm spending you know making
so much emphasis is that the passive
typically the passive typical passive
technical trader would never conceive of
actually bidding a market up and so as a
result it's very difficult for you to
think that anyone else can do it either
when the reality is that's the only way
in many cases you're gonna make money
and so the point that I'm making is that
what you you're trading off of a
mathematical formula literally you're
trading you're in this mathematical
formula what technical analysis does is
it gets into the collective mind of the
market in other words every tick every
uptick and every down tick is
information that information is
accumulated and mathematical principles
are applied to it there are there are
actual patterns that that that emerge
that repeat themselves over and over and
over again that you can identify with
mathematical formulas or with these
visual price patterns but the problem is
is that there's no mathematical formula
that can get into the mind of the
individual traders who actually are
driving prices up or offering a blower
but if you don't know that you somehow
or another if you happen to if you're
trading on a smaller time frame you're
trading on a smaller time frame and you
get a little a little pullback right
here okay and based on that pullback
your methodology says okay it's time to
buy and you do and but and you do it
just before this
fund manager comes in and starts driving
the price up see you're gonna think that
the reason why you won is because that
your mathematical formula told you what
was happening next and that was the
reason why it happened what I'm saying
to you now is that there almost isn't
any reason that you could come up with
whether you won or lost that would
correspond to what really happened in
the market you hear what I just said
there's almost no reason that you will
come up with to put on a trade that will
ever correspond with the actual reason
why the market went up or the market
went down other than the fact that there
was an imbalance and conviction between
buyers and sellers because the people
who do this will not tell you unless
it's in their best interest to do so
and the reason and the people who report
it in the news agencies they don't know
either they're making it up they make up
the reasons because they sound
reasonable they are paid to sound
reasonable and there's no way to verify
what it is that they say that's right
there's no there's no way the only
people who can do it are the people who
actually made the trades the only people
who know for sure what's gonna happen
next are the ones who are willing to
make it happen you see will put on a
trade and find ourselves in a lace
monster little winner here and think oh
man my methodology it is just fantastic
and then the next time you get the same
signal and then you don't get anything
not only then it's a loser you think oh
now you feel betrayed you think your
your your methodology let you down
your methodology wasn't designed to tell
you what's gonna happen next on a trade
by trade basis no technical methodology
is that's where your expectations are
not in line with the reality of the
situation that's why it's so easy to
make mistakes is because you're
expecting something from your
methodology that just doesn't exist it
just doesn't it never did
and a trade by trade basis they will
tell you what will happen let's say I
don't want to use their words to happen
next they'll tell you what will happen
over a series of trades on a percentage
basis this particular pattern will
emerge X number of times and when it
does there's a higher probability of
this happening than that if I limit my
risk when I take the trade and my
profits in my profit potential is at
least you know one or two or three times
greater than what I need the risk then
over a series of trades I will be a
consistent winner
that's what trading is all about guys is
the passive technical trader unless
you're doing this other stuff I just
said it right then and there I said it
all right then and there there was a guy
that I that I guy that came to me for
consultations several years ago he was a
it was really anything he was he was a
guy that yeah he was a guy that lost a
lot of people's money
he was basically what he was he he he
was actually he was really good an
analyst I should say really he was an
excellent an aspect as far as far as
Margaret analysis was concerned he's
probably one of the best analysts I'd
ever worked with but the problem is that
he had some really as far as executing
his trades and and let's put it this way
he was let's say on the arrogant side
and that's and that's and that's that's
being that's being nice
and so when he put on a trade he just
thought that that was it you know the
mark was gonna do what he thought I was
gonna do period so he was a kind of guy
who you know he he went through all of
his relatives money with trading
accounts and his friends and that sort
of thing and his getting the point was
really exasperated so he came to me for
consultations and basically after
listening to him I said hey you know
what why don't you do something get paid
for something that you're good at and
you know and stop trying to you know
stop losing other people's money and go
get a job as an analyst just get paid to
be an analyst not as a trader and so he
did he got a job with a with one of the
major clearing firms that's a Chicago
Board of Trade as one of their analysts
for their brokers and that sort of thing
and the president are they actually the
chairman of the board he was his son was
actually the president he
chairman had retired he was an old-time
grain trader soy bean trader and you
know made his money in the 40s and the
50s and that sort of thing
and and traded Pitts style trading in
other words it's something that I talked
about early this morning I'm not gonna
get into but in any case he didn't make
Direction related traits and so the so
he was really mystified with this with
the idea of technical analysis I mean he
really was he was literally mystified
with the idea that you could basically
predict prices based on chart patterns
and that sort of thing so he thought
well you know what I'm gonna sit down
with this guy and you know this this
star analyst here that we have in the
firm now and find out what this with
what this crap is all about basically
the way he thought about it and so he's
sitting down with him for a few days and
it got to a point where one day the the
soybean market was the soybean market
was was basically you know trading in a
range about the middle of a range
between what the analysts projected as
the high of the day not just the high
the high the day and the low of the day
okay and so the market drifted around
you know or you maybe did a little bit
of a coast to a test of the high and
it's coming down to the coming down to
the low and they're both sitting there
and they're both watching it right now
and the the chairman of the board the
soybean trader old scientist Lubbock
trader says ok so this is gonna be the
low of the day right here right guy said
yeah that's it gets that price it's the
low of the day low of the day and the
guy looked at me and said that's bull
and he picked up the phone which he had
a direct line to the soybean pit he said
sell 10 million beans at the market now
10 million beans is 2 thousand contracts
cuz they trained five thousand five
thousand bushel increments so he hit the
market at that moment with two thousand
sell orders okay which drove the
immediately drove the price down 10
cents which makes arisen is a million
dollar trade by the way you drive the
price of course of course if he got if
he'd have sold all of them at this price
and brought them all back at this price
but they were
he was there was an average price now
but from here to here is 10 million is a
million bucks on two thousand contracts
and then after the price dropped he you
know he looked at him and said hey if I
can do that anybody can do that if I can
do that
anybody can do it now think about the
implications of what I just said if you
remember back in that surveying that we
just took a little while ago and I said
it only takes one trader somewhere in
the world than a gate the positive
outcome of your edge oh gee what if
you're one of the people that bought
right here how many people did it take
to mess up your train just one just one
person that's all it's usually more than
one but that's all it takes is one you
guys starting to get the idea
this kind of stuff is going on all of
the time as a matter of fact when prices
move this is usually the reason why when
I was at Merrill Lynch I mean this I
mean you know and for many years even
when I was teaching teaching you know
material in the psychology of training I
didn't really include a lot of this
stuff because I just sort of took it for
granted that people understood it knew
it you know and the reason why I took it
for granted because I guess I learned it
so early in my trading career that it
just you know it was self-evident to me
but it was self-evident because here I
was at Merrill Lynch and and I had I had
access to a squawk box now our squawk
boxes were open phone lines to the
various pits in both Chicago and New
York meaning we had Merrill Lynch
representatives in each of those pits
that as buy and sell orders would come
in they would tell us who was buying and
who was selling what houses what
manufacturers what big accounts what big
traders if they could in other words if
they had if they had access to the
information they would tell us who was
buying you know and and and maybe who
was even taking the other side of their
orders if they could determine it so
it's like he had a very intimate it was
like you know you had this sort of
intimate connection with what was really
going on now at the same time when I was
doing my own technical analysis I would
do I would do my equations because we
didn't have computers back then of
course you can do that
the hewitt packard the handheld thing
but I didn't do that I did all my
equations on all my analysis on a
spreadsheet and I actually did all the
all the calculations by hand and I did
it on purpose that way so that I could
get an intimate sense of how the actual
mathematics of my signals in other words
actual calculations the multiplications
the divisions of subtractions you know
and what that what the final product was
in terms of a signal how it related to
the actual market movement and I found
that there was no relationship other
than the fact that it would identify
patterns where the signals would work
sometimes and you know sometimes they
wouldn't but the point is is that there
wasn't any relationship between this
fixed mathematical formula and the
people who were buying and selling at
that moment the reasons why they were
doing it
there was none at all
but not only that here's what really
shocked me is we had a TV monitors going
all the time and we had it on in Chicago
there was a local investment channel
channel 26 and it was very much like
CNBC now but it was a lot less
sophisticated and you know so we'd watch
as people would come on the show and and
with various you know you have various
interviews and that sort of thing and
I'm watching watching one morning and
there's this vice president from hind
hold which was now doesn't exist anymore
but they were one of the biggest hog and
and meat producers in the Midwest back
in the 80s and this hump this vice
president from hind hold is being
interviewed by you know the guy in
channel 26 and he's talking about how
you know how people got people got to
get into live hogs and pork bellies
because prices are going up and you know
and he's just going on and on about what
a great investment it is and and really
and here and this one happened quite
frequently by the way but this was just
an example and all the phones started
lighten up these are all the people in
the Chicago area the typical you know
the traders in the Chicago area then a
listener to this guy because I think I
say that because the phones are lighting
up and all the brokers are starting to
take orders to uh to buy bellies and buy
hogs and I don't think well you know
that was pretty a pretty impactful right
oh gee and then on squawk box guess
who's taken the other side of those
orders hein hold they needed somebody to
come in and take the other side of their
orders what is a mathematical formula
have to do with that now as it just so
happens if my math is working in a way
where I happen to get in at that moment
I end up in a winning trade well that's
great but that doesn't mean I could rely
it on the rely on it to do the same
thing the next time
okay explain hedging reverse auction in
a normal auction this I'll talk about
dynamic traders right now in a normal
auction what do people do in a normal
auction in other words of you're in in a
situation where where those things or
items are up for bid when you bid when
you're out bidding somebody what are you
doing you're limiting the competition
right in other words by bidding higher
your hopefully eliminating
anybody else who'll bid higher than you
hedgers and commercials and dynamic
traders create what I call a reverse
auction they'll bid a market up or offer
a lower to try to attract the public
into the market to take the other side
of their trait you guys with me on this
they will bid a market up or offer it
lower as a reverse auction that doesn't
mean that they want they you know they
could the market can go higher but
they're their immediate objective is
that if they're bidding it up it means
that they want to sell they just want
someone to take the other side of their
trades so they're actually creating a
reverse auction attracting people into
the market because as the market goes up
the people to think okay I'm going to be
missing out and and I've got the
assurance that I need that it's gonna
keep on going and so they get sucked
into this move and then and then they
slam them with a huge order now see I
had intimate contact with a hole that
Merrill Lynch not only that I mean cuz
because I knew the floor traders I knew
many of the floor traders who actually
created the movement that particular day
and there were a number of times where
the movement was significant and they
were fast markets and you know enough to
track the the media to the exchange and
you know when they put a microphone in
front of their front of their mouth and
you know and that I definitely they
definitely would say something that was
palatable to the public in other words
what was reasonable I can guarantee you
that the reason why they did what they
did during the day had nothing to do
with what they said nothing there was no
relationship whatsoever
go ahead I'll fully understand your
concept of the movement that's taking
place because of dynamic players and I
can understand how that would relate to
the commodity stock and stock options
market but can you have the same effect
and say the foreign currency market
where it's a much bigger market that's
traded worldwide it just depends on the
player absolutely you get a central bank
that starts that starts doing this
starts unloading something and then
they're gonna is going to have a major
impact on the market yes but you yeah
you've got basically what you have is a
situation where where this markets so
large it's so liquid that it would be
very difficult for individuals to have
any impact on it is that what you're
saying to me is that what you're well I
wasn't necessarily limiting it to
individuals I mean even a central bank
just on the world market could they have
that kind of an import it's what I call
the pebble in a pond effect okay they
might not have enough they might not
have enough impact initially okay
initially to do something okay to have
to have that meaningful making to create
that meaningful of a price move but
you've got a pebble in a pond which is
the way a lot of prices move anyway
because it's like what you've got to
drop a pebble in a pond well if it's you
know it creates waves does it not okay
and what I found is that especially with
floor traders and and and really the
kind of same the kind of same that the
same kind of dynamics work even even
with off the floor traders in the
general market itself I found that what
you had is that most floor traders did
not know what they were doing in the
sense that they didn't have a real good
reason for buying or selling at any
given moment other than the fact that
they were following the lead of other
people who thought they thought did have
an idea of what they're doing so what
ends up happening is that is that what
you've got is you've got the guy the
trader who's confident knows exactly
what he's doing why he wants to do it
and does it and then you've got you got
all the other guys who are let's say in
the pit okay who are closest to
this particular this guy might be on
this step right here who are closest to
this guy that will that will mimic what
he does and then what it does it starts
spreading out and that and that as as
word gets out okay the guys at the
farthest then end up getting you prices
that are that are greatly diminished in
relationship to this particular
individual but the point is is kind of
like the pebble in the pond a central
bank could create create the same thing
in other words initially a central bank
hitting the market with a huge order
might be absorbed but the fact that the
central bank is doing it will cause
other people to want to do it too and
therefore as a result of all the other
traders who pile on it creates a huge
move does that make sense okay
we're moving right along here okay
dynamic traders okay players they know
and understand the mindset and behavior
patterns of the crowd or herd they they
they basically refer to the general
public as the herd and they are the herd
masters okay they are the herd masters
whenever possible they will use that
knowledge to move prices in a way that
will extract the most amount of money
from the largest number of traders that
is their mission that is what they do
characteristic the passive technical
traders they're usually mystified by
price movement would that be a fair
characterization okay they wouldn't
think about trying to cause price
movement as a result they typically
can't conceive of anyone else doing it
either
they're typically drawn into trades
based on an opinion about the
attractiveness of the price or Stampede
it out because of fear the passive
technical traders objective is to find
himself in a winning trade without any
intent to move prices now think about
what you're doing you are trading in a
way where you want to find yourself in a
winning trade but absolutely wouldn't
even think about moving prices to do it
you're completely dependent on someone
else doing it for you to find himself in
a winning trade he's dependent on the
traders to be willing to either buy or
sell at a worse price in himself to
create
movement in his direction the typical
passive technical trader is expecting
other dynamic traders to make him a
winner when they usually have little or
no knowledge insight or understanding
about how dynamic traders operate would
that be fair the typical passive trader
does not realize it only takes one
dynamic trader somewhere in the world to
negate the positive outcome of his edge
is that a fair statement now does
anybody want to argue with the statement
anymore or and I'd say anybody did in
the first place but there are some
people who realize their hand and said
that that wasn't the case is there
anybody that that's not convinced about
this seriously I want to know and I'm
not we're not going to get into a fight
or anything but you know ok the
characteristics of technical analysis
now what we're going to do is we're
going to take what we now understand
about the nature of price movement and
look at the nature of technical analysis
to see to see what we got here okay see
how well it you know in meshes ok
technical indicators define identify and
organize market data the up and down
ticks and to understand a little
patterns are you guys with me on this
the patterns are observed observable
quantifiable meaning that can be
measured and repeat themselves with
statistical reliability and and really
and while I'm doing this and while we're
going through this I want you guys to
really keep in mind that that just
because I explained the the underlying
characteristics of dynamic traders and
people who can actually move the market
and do it and do it all the time in fact
when the markets moving they're the ones
who are doing it it's not you or I the
only time you or I move the market is
when there's an overabundance of market
orders coming into the market from
passive technical traders because the
market order does what okay if the last
forget in the last price is 10 we've got
nine and we've got 11 ok what's the
market the last price is 10 if I want to
buy the markets actually 11 isn't it
that's the market because that's where
the offers are the offers are at 11 so
that's where I'm going to get filled I'm
going to get filled at 11 well if
there's so many buy orders come mark
by orders coming into the market and all
the all the offers are taken out at
11:00 then that means the next price up
where there's offers are 12 and that's
what I'm going to get filled and if
there's so many more that got in before
me and this is real I mean it's really
an overabundance of buy orders and
relationship to the number of offers
that are that that exist then I might
get filled of 13 because that's the
market so that's the difference you've
got you've got an overabundance of
passive technical orders coming into the
market that will drive it up or you've
got dynamic traders who are doing it
purposefully and when they're doing it
purposefully I guarantee you they got
they got a good reason for it they know
what they're doing I'm not saying it
always works but they know what they're
doing and it doesn't mean that you can't
take advantage of it
it doesn't mean that you can't make a
consistent income even I'm you know a
really a really good consistent income
with your technical methodologies you
don't you don't even have to you don't
have to understand all these these
subtle dynamics or market or price
movement to be able to take advantage of
of it all you've got to do is be able to
trade your edge and follow your plan I
just want you understand that when you
understand what's going on you will will
be able to trade your plan because you
won't be putting so much emphasis on
things that don't have any relevance
like expecting this next trade to work
just because you got a signal is this
what drives the price up typically early
in the morning like on when the market
opens some popular stock all the market
all the orders come in or it goes down
and is that what creates this gap or
well I can't tell you the academia would
say what that's what happens I mean well
you can lose it that's why is it a log
jam right you can you can always break
it down to one fundamental reason the
only fun no the only reason that they're
really there is there's an imbalance in
between between buyers and sellers price
movement is always the result of an
imbalance because when there's balance
there's no movement
it's that simple right if there's
balance there's no movement prices do
not move when there's balance there has
to be an imbalance for people to bid it
up or offer a lower and if people aren't
actually bidding it up in this example
we don't see what the reason I can't
answer you exactly is because I don't
know if it's actually being bid up
purposefully by somebody or it's because
there's an overabundance of buy orders
and relationship to the amount of offers
that's what I don't know okay the
Payette the patterns basically measure
the collective mind of the market in
other words here then I should have and
I should have really emphasized this
word collective collective mind of the
market not the individual Minds the
collective mind meaning all of the
actions all of the beliefs all of the
agendas all of the objectives are built
into that next incremental price change
from eleven to twelve or from twelve to
thirteen it's all there and the only
thing that mathematical formulas can do
is actually measure that you know
measure the patterns that result from
that information it isn't getting the
information of the guy who actually bid
the market up by taking out all the
offers because he's got some specific
agenda about what he wants to do with
where he wants to see the prices go
because he's doing something has nothing
to do with any of this meaning your
technical methodology or anybody else's
he might be putting on a huge hedge
position based on some contract that he
has to deliver something three months
from now
so collective mind of the market
indicating when there is a higher
probability of one thing happening over
another represented as an edge so
because the patterns show up in every
timeframe technical analysis turns the
market into an unending stream of
opportunities to enrich ourselves these
patterns that the mathematical formulas
identify show up in every timeframe from
the smallest to the largest and as a
result if we learn how to think about
these patterns or edges appropriately it
will actually turn the market into an
unending stream to enrich ourselves but
not on a trade by trade basis but not on
a trade by trade basis but rather as a
percentage over a series of trades this
is big guys this is it right here this
is the holy grail of technical analysis
right here right now your technical
indicators will turn the market into an
unending stream of opportunity to enrich
yourself but not on a trade by trade
basis but rather as a percentage over a
series of trades that means you have to
learn how to think of probabilities you
may understand the concept of
probabilities it doesn't mean that you
can think that way I've worked with
traders in fact one guy came to one of
my workshops many years ago a hedge fund
manager reasonably successful you know
let's say reasonably because he made you
know that I was a 10 to 18% a year but
his indicators if he had followed them
the way you know the way they were
planned to be followed he could have
made anywhere from 60 to 70 percent a
year little frustrated came to a
workshop and then you know some some
consultations afterwards in one
particular situation where he said you
know he put in a trade a trade even
watching four months
finally got to his price level you know
he put the trade on and put a stop in
the market you know and the market
started approaching his stop and you
know he he got out he got out of the
trade early it market didn't hit a stop
he got out of the trade early and then
it just went just just fell to pieces
and because he was short and he you know
in his direction he wasn't in the trade
and he would have been someone who would
have said that he understood the nature
of probabilities because he majored in
it in college but it hasn't he did not
do the sufficient amount of work to
train his mind to think in probabilities
at a functional level there's a huge
difference you can't take it for granted
that because you understand the nature
of percentages that you can think that
way at a functional level it would be
you know like you could you can do I'll
do the analogy to technical analysis to
flipping a coin okay that if you if you
take an evenly weighted coin and flip it
a thousand times you've got a large
sample size there right the pattern that
will emerge with each thousand flip
sample size is a relatively even
distribution between heads and tails
maybe not quite 5050 but let's say forty
nine point two and you know of forty
nine point eight or something or
whatever there might be a little bit of
variance more variance there but in any
case that will be a pattern see that's a
pattern because it'll happen
every single time you flip the coin a
thousand times but within that thousand
flip sample size is there anyway since
you're going to get an even distribution
between heads and tails is there any way
that you can know for sure which
individual flip is going to be hands in
which individual flip is going to be
tails no you could get ten flips of
heads in a row
and be absolutely positive the next
one's going to be tails and it could
come up heads again and even though you
can have all these streaks of heads and
tails in the end they're still going to
come up 50/50 this is exactly the way
technical analysis works exactly when
you consider the diversity the diversity
of the market with all the different
players and all the different agendas
from people all over the world trying to
predict what will happen next would be
almost equivalent to sitting in front of
a slot machine and coming up with some
rational reason why you think that the
pattern that you're looking for is going
to come up on the next push of the
button
it wouldn't make a lot of sense would it
but the reason why it's we get fooled as
traders and we think of it in and not
this and not this probabilistic way is
because when we put on a trade we put on
a trade for a reason see reasons are
important in our lives
reasons are important we've put on a
trade for a reason and see the problem
is is that when the trade works we think
are we just naturally think our reason
was right what I'm trying to do here is
help you disconnect is disconnect any
reason that you put on a trade with the
reason why it actually moved because
like I said before there's almost never
a relationship there's almost never a
correlation and so the next time that
reason seems to appear in the market
we're gonna we're gonna do the same
thing thinking we'll get the same result
and then we don't we feel betrayed and
then the next time the reason comes up
we're gonna be a little hesitant you
might not put it on at all we'll try to
find additional reasons why this trade
will work well the reality is there
isn't any reason you're going to be able
to come up with it's going to assure you
of anything unless the reason you're
coming up with is you know the people
who are actually going to bid them hark
it up or offer a lower and they tell you
what they're gonna do and why ultimately
there's only one reason why markets why
prices move and what would that reason
be come on yeah an imbalance in
conviction that's the only and what
technical analysis does is it finds
patterns in that imbalance okay
technical analysis finds and patterns in
the imbalance where there's momentum in
a direction it's still not going to tell
you what's going to happen next
technical analysis doesn't nor can it
get into the minds of any particular
individual trader who has both the
financial and psychological resources to
either move prices or defend certain
price levels and traders will defend
price levels by the way there are
dynamic traders who will actually defend
a price is it reasonable to expect the
fix criteria that make up a mathematical
formula the sake to stay consistent with
a dynamic event that's in perpetual
motion on a trade by trade basis what's
the answer to that well what does the
answer come on no no it is not
reasonable no it is not
especially where that motion is being
caused by traitors all around the world
with different beliefs objectives and
agendas there was no way of determining
the intentions of all these traitors yet
the typical passive trader trades their
methodology as if they are being told
what those intentions are the
professionals do not you guys get that
the typical passive technical trader
trades their methodology as if they are
being told what their intentions are
whereas the professional does not and
why doesn't the professional because the
professional understands the underlying
dynamics of price movement and that
anybody could come into the market at
any time to do anything
there was another floor trader that I
work with who executed a trainers own
accountant in soybean market but also
also executed the orders for one at the
time one of the biggest soybean
producers in the world there was an
Italian firm that actually tried the
corn of the soybean market got thrown
off the Board of Trade but before that
happened you know there was many days
where you know they he would call you
know be in touch with the the head
traders at the Home Office and their
plotting out their strategy you know
like you know he told me one day you
know it's like like the whole strategy
for that day from the Home Office
traders the whole strategy was to spank
the locals at the Chicago Board of Trade
that wasn't only purpose that day they
were gonna suck the locals into a trade
and they were gonna try to wipe them out
this is that we're gonna spank the
locals today
now your mathematical pattern okay you
happen to get a buy signal ends up to be
a big winning trade you think it's
because because a couple of lines
crossed you know no matter what it is
you know with a stochastic sore Weis
trade or whatever doesn't really matter
it had absolutely nothing to do with the
reality of why the price is moved
nothing this is the primary
characteristic that separates the
professional from everyone else what I
just said right here