hello my name is Mark Douglas and I'm
the author of the discipline trader and
trading in the zone I've been a trading
coach since 1982 and over the years I've
worked with some of the industry's
biggest hedge fund and money managers as
well as some of the exchanges largest
floor traders I know that all of you
want to experience consistent results in
your trading
in other words you want to be able to
generate an income you can rely on
however one of the major obstacles and
trying to accomplish this objective is
the area of trade execution to produce a
consistent income a trader has to be
able to execute their trades without
making any errors or mistakes in other
words trading without hesitation
reservation or internal conflict
basically all of the errors we are
susceptible to a result of a lack of
confidence or more specifically trading
with fear well most people don't realize
is that trade without fear was actually
a learn a training skill a skill that
has to be cultivated and it's very
different it separates the professional
from the typical trader in this series
of DVDs I'm going to provide you with
the kind of insight understanding and
specific mental techniques you'll need
to learn to trade without fear so that
like the professional you can move in
and out of your trades the confidence
and ease that will allow you to take
full advantage of your wise trade or any
other trading methodology
[Music]
yeah good morning and also to how many
people came to the west coast or in that
in the West Coast time yeah is like the
the why straight people pick me up at
6:30 in the morning which was 4:30 in
the morning for me so I say that you
know when I say this is it we're here
for you and to ignore the cameras ignore
the environment I really mean it but at
the same time I want you guys to help me
a little bit okay it might take me a
little bit you know might take me a
little bit to get going because I'm not
used to doing presentations that you
know 6:30 in the morning my time or semi
for morning my time but anyway what
we're gonna do is we're gonna we're
gonna go through the process learning
how to think like a professional trainer
why would we want to learn how to think
like a professional anybody got any
ideas that make some money but you don't
have to think professional to make money
do you what does it even imply what does
it imply to to think like a professional
trader I mean let me ask you this how
many you guys have I don't know what
your what your trading experience have
been in terms of the number of years
you've been at it or you kind of give me
an idea of the demographics here of the
audience I mean how many people have
been trading for more two or three years
most everybody then then less than less
than two years kind of new people no
okay so we've got about half and half
what would it mean to guys to say well
let's think like a professional trainer
what's that
not thinking like an amateur ok that's
good but what are the implications of
the difference between a professional
and amatuer consistency there you go you
see you're at least a workshop right hey
consistency exactly in other words what
what that would imply is that is that if
I don't know if I'm a professional
trader and other words if I've aspired
to be a professional
it one of the implications would be that
that I can make consistent money because
if I'm trading in the mode of a
professional I could be a hedge fund
manager you know a professional edger
working for trading companies or just
having a full time job as a trader where
my income my sole income is derived as a
trader and be in that kind of a position
in order to be in a position where other
people are going to give you their money
or or give you their assets to be able
to you know make money for them it would
certainly imply that you can make
consistent money that there's a way for
you to let's say create an equity curve
that looks you know something like this
is that right
are you gonna give your money to
somebody with an equity curve that looks
like that I'm not saying that people
don't do it and I'm not saying that it
doesn't happen but I'm saying that if
I've aspired to be a professional trader
it means I must have learned something
that's different than the people who
can't do this there must be something
about about the way that I approach
training that allows me to do that and
believe me there is there's a lot but
that yeah basically and I don't know if
how many people in the room have have
either read trading on his own or the
disciplined trader got a few people so
so probably there so there's actually
most the people in the group by familiar
maybe even with me or my background at
all true or not yes or no see no right
okay so I'm gonna just give you a little
bit I'll give you more later on but I
started talking back 1978
and the first trade that I made I the
first trade I made was in potato
features at the Chicago Mercantile
Exchange which they don't even trade
potato futures anymore why pick potato
futures I have no idea I think that's
probably what my broker said I should be
trading maybe he said there was there
was an opportunity and potato futures in
any way I made money and of course you
know and just like most people who make
money there the first trade or the
second trade it's it's about as easy as
one could imagine and therefore you
think yourself oh my god why didn't I
learn about this a long time ago it
sounded I mean that sounds kind of
familiar right in terms of the thought
process and I went from trading potatoes
to trading gold to trading silver and my
I'd say my trading experience back then
was probably typical even to what it is
today with most people although you have
to keep in mind that the technology that
we had back then wasn't anything
anything like what you have available to
you right now today it still boggles my
mind when I think about the way we had
to trade 25 years ago almost 30 years
ago compared to what's available right
now I mean I've never I've always been
attracted more to trading commodities
than stocks as a matter of fact I've
never even traded stocks I'm always
traded commodities and options and and
it's just and I've never really never
really had the desire to Train on the
floor the exchange although I lived in
Chicago for 20 years it just it never
really appealed to me I don't know how
many people are familiar with the floor
or the or the or the trading pits but I
just thought it was an extremely harsh
environment and and not something that
you know not something that just like I
said it appealed to me but the kind of
trading platforms that you guys have
available to you today really truly
approximate what it would be like they
have a seat at the Chicago Board of
Trade or Chicago Mercantile Exchange and
and to trade at that level you have
instantaneous execution a
and it's like you can and you like you
can change your mind and not feel
humiliated or or or like you know
there's something wrong with you you put
in an order you can cancel it back you
know before before the advent of
electronic trading platforms we used to
have to call a broker now you think
about the time you made a decision to
put on a trade you think about the time
that it takes one to dial the phone for
someone to pick the phone up you know
how many times it has to ring and then
he gets on the other end of the line you
know you got your broker and then you
give your broker your order and then
you've got to deal with the fact that
does your book really approve of your
order in other words my good of anybody
proof is that we'll see I'm you know I
want to buy you know I want to buy three
gold contracts I said well you know some
of my biggest biggest customers are they
they just went short gold no not what
you gonna do with that information okay
or I've got you know X number of guys
that are that are on the other side of
that trade say well yeah if you want you
know what take the other side of their
trade I mean that's fine finally off
with the order in so it's like you know
so he could put the order in and then
you know you've got to wait for it you
got away for a fill I can't tell you how
many times that I put orders in the
market where they were limit orders
because they'd want to do a market order
as I didn't want to get the slippage of
a market order so you do a limit order
in and I'll limp it order market has to
change to guarantee guarantee to fill
the market has trade through your price
doesn't not how many times has the
market traded to your price okay just
write to your price if a buy order and
reversed and you didn't get built that's
very possible the problem when you're
doing it with a with a broker over the
phone is that is that that order goes
into the pit it goes to an executing
executing broker in the pit itself so
you've got a runner and and and and and
then the order got to go back to the
runner back to the farm bank back to the
broker and the broker calls you with a
fill you're talking several minutes now
what if you're in a situation in a fast
market where the market actually hit
your price you may have gotten filled
but you really don't know you don't want
to put a stop in the market because you
don't even know you're in or not and
Marcus screaming let's say even in your
favor and you'd like to take profits but
you still haven't got a fill back yet
you don't know if you're in the market
this is the kind of stuff we had to deal
with all the time
all the time it was a completely
different world not only that the only
information that we had available to us
was open high low and close that was it
open high low and close bars and we used
to have to get those unless we talk to
our broker and pestered them you know X
number of times a day you know if you
get it through the wall street journal'
used to have to keep our own daily
charts intraday stuff was just like
non-existent so so anyway I you know
that's I I started trading like that I
went through well I don't even remember
what my first trading account was I
think I was around $20,000 you know I
lost all of that and then you know saved
up some money and opened up another one
for around 15 you know lost all of that
and then we went to another broker and
I'm thinking this guy doesn't know what
he's doing and I'll find somebody who
does
and and then this is this is what really
really this is probably the reason I
mean standing here today was this
particular trade because because this
particular trade just it had a profound
impact on me in terms of in terms of how
it changed my life and what I was
willing to do to find out what this was
all about to find out really what does
it take to be a consistently successful
trader what does it take to really be
able to earn an income as a trader I was
I was long silver this would have been
back in right around 1980 or 1981 1980 I
think I was long silver at around 975 an
ounce and there was to 5,000 ounce
contracts at the Comex in other words I
was long ten thousand ounces of silver
at 975 an ounce and right after I got
into the market the market dropped about
20 cents on me to about 955 so I was
down $2,000 and my broker said well okay
you know here's what we're gonna do
instead of getting out
well-well we'll put you into a spread
and so what we'll do is we'll you're
long ten thousand ounces of silver in
New York will go short ten thousand
ounces of silver in Chicago because you
could trade Chicago silver at the
Chicago Board of Trade everybody with me
on this does want to make sure that you
guys are all with you know even though I
know many of your stock traders it's the
concept is the same okay so I'm long
10,000 and 975 he puts me short 10,000
at 9:55 in Chicago so I've got this
spread going on and then he said well
when the market goes back in your favor
we'll just take the short leg of the
spread off now keep in mind back then
you guys are you guys are what do you
typically pay for commissions even in
commodities or even I don't know what
you pay for stocks but but typically the
average Commission is about four to five
dollars around turn right that's what we
would expect to pay no what are you
paying less more round turn wow really
well you're in the Dow mitt you're in
the Dow Minnie what do you pay for the
Dow domini a lemon okay well anyway then
eleven okay well back then back in the
80s we were how much you think we were
paying back then come on give me guess
come on yeah
what yeah 125 about house 125 around
turn per contract so in other words we
to put this trade on cost me 250 bucks
okay when he put this one on right here
it cost me another 250 bucks and then he
said of course that when the market goes
back into my favor he'll take the short
leg of the spread off and you know I
should be all right so that's exactly
what the market did the market went back
up to you know right around the 975 area
he took the short leg of the spread off
and then the market immediately dropped
back down another 20 cents and put the
shirt this is a short leg of the spread
back on again so that's another 250
bucks okay plus he just locked in when
he took this off first of all he locked
in a 2,000 dollar loss by putting this
trade on when the market went back up to
975 and he took this off he locked in
another $2,000 loss and then when I went
back down again he put it put it back on
and locked in another $2,000 loss
now I'm down six thousand seven hundred
and fifty dollars okay and then of
course it happened two or three more
times now from from from the markets
perspective all I'm in all the markets
the silver markets just in a trading
range that's all it is I say it's just
in a trading range but but I don't
really I didn't know how to read chart
math chart patterns at the time it
didn't really understand what was going
on I was just listening to him
and so what he was doing is just taking
advantage of the fact that his going
back and forth between support and
resistance and and generating
commissions for himself okay that's that
was it that's that's basically he was
just he was just turning my account but
that's that's not the story okay that's
that's happened to a lot of people of
course it happens less now because we're
all responsible for the trades that we
put on all we have to do is click the
mouse button and it's not that much
money but here's here's the story is
that as these losses are as these losses
are mounting okay and I can't I can't
sleep and and and getting real stressed
out you know I I wake up one morning I
thought you know what this is it I just
can't take this anymore I just I just
can't take it
and so you know when I got to work I
called them and I said you know what
just get out of the whole damn thing I
just can't do this so just liquidate the
position does anybody remember the hunt
brother silver debacle it didn't there's
any but if I say the word limit up does
anybody understand what I mean by that
okay the exchanges will impose
artificial price limits of how much a
commodity or even stock for that matter
can fluctuate in any given day before
they stop trading so we don't have the
cut we don't have these kinds of moves
too much anymore but back in the 80s
limit moves were really quite common
they really were in other words what
would happen is this is that is that if
the market if the market went up let's
say I think in silver was 50 cents I
don't remember exactly what it was but
if the market went up by 50 cents they
would actually stop trading meaning if
the market was bid up to let's say in
this case ten dollars and 25 cents
trading would stop
in essence what that what this means is
that is that is that at 10:25 there were
no people there wasn't anybody in the
world
it wasn't Mikey but this is important
for later on there wasn't one person in
the world who was willing to sell silver
at 10:25 if it was a limit move
not one person and so what happens is
that the market the price will go up
seeking to find who will actually sell
so what and but what they but what the
exchanges didn't want his exchanges
didn't want there to be this is huge
fluctuation all in one day there might
have been sellers at 10:26 or there
might have been seller is that 11
dollars but you don't know that because
the exchange says we're gonna stop
trading at 10:25 you guys with me on
this okay so what happened is that I
don't think it happened more than maybe
a half an hour 45 minutes after I got
out the mark was trading right around
975 an ounce where silver went limit up
and went limit up was 30 days in a row
249 dollars an ounce to 49 dollars an
ounce
I was looking now now kita now thinking
I'll think about this okay now think
about being in this kind of a winning
trade now when we're in a winning trade
the market almost never go straight up
and it never go straight down there are
rare occasions of course like in this
case and when it does so that we're when
we're in a winning trade we have to
constantly be making decisions about
where we're gonna take profits and how
much heat we can take with the market
coming back against our position to say
well is this the time to take profits or
am I going to let it come back a little
bit further we're gonna come back a
little bit further against me because
well this is the nor is this normal
retracement or is this more significant
okay is this a little bit of a profit
taking retrace or the more significant I
get out now do we have more or left are
we gonna make new highs you got to be
making all these kinds of decisions and
it's very difficult as we all know right
see in this case I didn't have to be
making any decisions because the market
went limit up 30 days in a row boom boom
it was like wait go in I was out I just
got out like a half an hour before it
happened only the problem is I couldn't
even get back in because there wasn't
anybody willing to take the other side
of the buy orders on a limit move you
can't get back in so I sat back and
watched in a complete agony I mean yeah
I mean intense intense agony I'm not a
nice throw up but do you know it's like
maybe I almost did I don't know go ahead
you said you had five contracts no to to
just let you just take one off the table
that the other one run for another day
first of all Jerry you're you're
assuming that I knew that this was gonna
happen no I'm assuming that getting out
all at once takes you off takes you out
of the play completely Jerry have you
ever been in a situation we really lost
a ton of money and you just can't deal
with it anymore yeah I know I have
situation where I've been down a lot of
money I didn't lose because that's on
paper
no well commodities no with stocks
you're right with stocks it's
technically on paper with when you're
when you're in commodity is the money is
out of your account it's gone it's gone
at the end of the day okay it's not this
is not paper money this is real money
are you with me on that I am
understanding you okay so so so I wasn't
looking at at I wasn't looking at at you
know and like I said paper losses the
money was out of my account so I had had
enough I couldn't I couldn't take it
anymore so when you when you think about
it in that context when you just made up
your mind that I just can't deal with
this anymore it doesn't even occur to
you to get out in stages why would I get
out in stages when I when I've already
gone through a week and a half of this
back and forth and you know and it's
virtually wiped out my account because
by then I probably would have had to put
more money even for me to take just one
contract I'll leave one on I probably
would have had to put more money in the
account and I'm not there's what any
point in doing that but are you with me
on this idea I don't trade commodities
that's right other things in but the
concepts of
except it doesn't come out of my it's as
you said it's a paper trail yeah you
already all is who you won't stock you
on an asset and if you want to hold on
to that asset until it goes down to zero
that's fine okay your money is not
flowing in a sense money's flowing out
of your account but not in the same way
it is whether it a commodity yeah okay I
have to pay that money right now you're
just losing the value of an asset I
actually have to pay that money and it
comes out every single day go ahead and
go in to hand the microphone back to
that gentleman
another thing that can be of interest
here is at least from way I gathered you
was talking a while ago you really
weren't controlling this your broker was
doing the correct so even if you had
wanted to get out in stages your broker
was doing it saying hey here's what I'm
doing to you yeah pretty much yeah it's
like I didn't really I wasn't really in
control of the situation because they
didn't know what I was doing all I know
is that I was within let's say a half an
hour 45 minutes of just a monster trade
a monster trade yeah and like I said I
sat back and watched an agony as a
market went up to 49 dollars an ounce
I'm thinking myself I was like that
close to $400,000 on just two contracts
four hundred thousand dollars it's so
like I said when I first started telling
you this this really had a profound
impact on me it really did and I thought
to myself and at the time I was managing
a commercial casualty insurance agency
in the suburbs of Detroit not really you
know I thought that's what I wanted to
do I didn't really know what I want her
to do but you know I aspired to to
management I was very successful and you
know for at the time you know even back
then in you know the late 70s early 80s
what was making a six-figure income and
I was only in my early 30s so you know
it was I really had a lot of things
going for me but in you know after this
experience I thought to myself you know
and I got to figure out what's going on
here and I certainly wasn't going to be
able to do it in Michigan so I thought
you know what I'm going to Chicago
and that's what I did I went to Chicago
the first thing just thought you know
well if I'm gonna get into the business
Who am I gonna get into the business
with well back then there was Merrill
Lynch there's Dean Witter Smith Barney
you know and I thought were you gonna
who you gonna pick you pick Merrill
Lynch right okay so I went over the
Chicago Board of Trade they have an
office right there and right on the
second floor of the Chicago Board of
Trade
and they just so happened they had three
openings for trainee brokers and they
had over a thousand people applying for
it so how am I gonna how am I going to
be one of those three people I thought
well you know what I went back you know
I went back home I went to you know one
of the one of the bigger Merrill Lynch
offices in the Detroit area and I went
through the whole employment plan
employment process to fill new your eyes
myself with what it is that they
acquired to get a job and and and this
is what I think got me that job at the
Board of Trade is that they had an
aptitude test and there's a multi-page
application but on the back of the
application they had a they had a square
like this on you know and and they
wanted spontaneously while you're in the
you know while you're filling this
application out spontaneously what they
wanted you to do was to write like a
little mini essay about some
philosophical question before I went to
the Board of Trade and actually filled
out that application I spent two weeks
agonizing over every word we just to
make sure every word of that two or
three paragraphs that I wrote down was
completely perfect so that when I took
the hat I wrote down exactly what I'd
worked on and and I can imagine why they
hired me because if he thought that I
wrote that spontaneously in the moment
but hey this guy we got to have this guy
here we got to have this guy okay so I
did I got the job now think about this
now when I was working for the agency
the casualty agents commercial casualty
insurance I was as a matter of fact I
just signed a contract not more than
like three or four months before I
actually went to the went to work in
Chicago over a three-year period for
$360,000 and what Merrill Lynch was
offering me was $20,000 on a draw okay
in other words it was it was a you know
they're going to give you 20,000 but
it's a draw me and I got to pay a back
pay
not commissions now though if you can
imagine there wasn't one person in my
life not one person who thought that I
wasn't absolutely stark raving out of my
mind to give that up to go to Chicago to
do this so you know wasn't like I had a
lot of support you know and I wasn't
like I wasn't catching a lot of grief
from everybody that I knew about what it
was that it that I was doing so you can
imagine my horror you might as a good
word for it I mean because when I got to
Chicago I'm thinking why am I even doing
this I'm doing this because I'm going to
Chicago because because that's where the
traders are that's that's where the
people are who know who know what
they're doing
correct and then to get there to find
out that that is not the case that is
not the case at all that the brother
were 40 almost 50 brokers in the office
and none of them knew how to trade not
only did they not know how to trade I
mean they'd Merrill Lynch made
absolutely no bones about the fact that
we were not traders they spent no money
no time and completely discouraged us
from even learning how to trade we were
salesmen we were taught how to talk
about training we were taught how to
talk about investments we were taught
how to you know it's called dialing for
dollars to get on the phone and get
people to open up accounts and and the
and even though this was unspoken I'd
say the the underlying philosophy behind
the business was especially in the
commodity business I'm not talking about
the equities I'm not saying that that on
the equity side of the business that
there was that it wasn't more reputable
but but this was about as your reputable
as it could be because the underlying
philosophy that we operated from was all
commodity traders are terminal meaning
like they have a terminal illness it's
only a matter of time before then when I
say all commodity traders are terminal
and it is our job as a broker to make
them as comfortable as possible until
they expire
in other words to extract as much money
out of their account as you could until
they're gone and and and and even to
this day even to this day it just blows
me away to think that when I went I went
to a 30-day training class in Manhattan
and there were brokers from all over the
world probably about in 80 or 90 of us
and and the guy and and the person that
was the head of Merrill Lynch
commodities at the time his name was
John con Heaney and when he came in to
address our class and to this day I
don't know why he did this but he like
you said hi he started out and he
started out with these words the average
Merrill Lynch customer loses all their
money in six months and that was the
truth and commodities not equities
commodities and that was the truth that
was about what it was that's it took
about six months for people to lose
their account and and and you just like
I say just go to the next one so here
I'm I left this six-figure income to go
to Chicago to learn about this business
in this industry and here I'm in a
situation and it's like it was I guess
it was appalling absolutely appalling so
I thought well okay I'll make friends
with people on the floor they must know
what they're doing the floor traders the
floor traders know what they're doing
well I found out that wasn't necessarily
the case either now it doesn't mean that
the floor traders didn't know how to
make money but what this is and I'm not
going to get into this because we don't
have time but even though what you do is
called trading and what they do they
call trading the way in the mindset that
you have to have to make money couldn't
be further apart
even though they're both called trading
the typical local what I mean the person
who traded for their own account in the
pit or in the floor of the exchange the
way they made money almost they didn't
they didn't weren't trying to make
Direction related decisions in other
words it wasn't the kind of trading
where they actually they would find
themselves in winning trades that were
going in their favor but that's not the
reason why they put the trade on and
like I said I'm not going to get into
the specifics of dynamics of
does it take me too long to explain it
just doesn't necessary for right now all
I'm saying is that is that it just it's
it's a completely as a matter of fact
before I left Chicago and moved to to
Arizona I the Chicago Mercantile
Exchange asked me and I and I worked out
for all for a while for about six months
before I left asked me to put together a
program to help floor traders make the
transition from the floor to screen base
trading because it's very it's it's a
huge psychological leap it really is
it's a huge transition that that that
has to be made so what I'm saying is
that not knowing that before I got to
Chicago it was like here I'm in a
situation where where I really didn't
know anybody who really knew how to
trade or at least knew how to trade in
the sense of creating that consistency
that we're looking for it doesn't mean
that people couldn't make money people
are making money all the time it's just
that you know what's the point of making
money if you're you're susceptible to
giving it all back and all those if this
is your equity curve and all of a sudden
you're you're you're experiencing these
huge losses and huge drawdowns
not only is this certainly damaging
financially but it's also damaging
emotionally and it can be very difficult
to recover from these are what I call
the boom and Buster's okay you basically
had traders that fall into three
categories as far as equity curve is
concerned you've got your consistent
winners the people who have the traders
you've got your consistent winners now
that doesn't know it doesn't mean that
there aren't draw downs here okay but
what do you think these draw downs would
be a reflection of for the consistent
winners consistent winners take losing
trades all the time but their draw downs
are a reflection of what anybody got any
ideas yeah money manage money management
skills capital preservation okay these
are okay these are two good answers but
not the answer I'm looking for their
draw downs are simply a reflection of
the normal losses that any trading
methodology will incur there are there
is such a thing as normal
losses you don't have to write this down
because I'm just we're just starting to
scratch a certain we are going to go
into this and far more detail later on
so I mean if you guys want to write it
down that's fine but it really isn't
necessary okay normal losses that any
trading methodology will incur then
you've got people who who have who
learned something about how to trade who
acquire a good methodology where it is
possible based on that methodology to
experience consistent a consistent
income but your equity curve might look
more like this
most people who are experienced the
boom-and-bust cycles use the bus cycles
would say that something happened in the
market to cause this
what you're going to find out today is
that it is not the case even though it
may seem like it it is not the case
these are virtually always the result of
trading errors what I call trading
errors which we're going to go into in
detail later on one of the Oh just just
a I just for the gentleman the people a
few people back here that don't have any
idea of my background I'm gonna go a
little bit further in it and and just
I'm just gonna jump ahead for a second I
ended up ended up being a trading coach
and and working with I was trading coach
from probably about 17 years I don't
really do it do it much anymore I just
pretty much focus on my own trading but
but while I was especially in the you
know throughout the the eighties and and
most of the 90s I worked with a lot of
floor traders and wonderful I would talk
about boom and bust there there was one
of the floor traders I work with was
probably one of the five biggest bond
traders at the Chicago Board of Trade
and when I met him was in like around
May of 1992 and from January of 92 until
the time that I met him in May of 1992
he had her on this is key this is a guy
that just traded for himself he didn't
trade for a firm he just traded his own
account on the floor of the Chicago
Board of Trade in the bond pit he had 12
million dollars rolled in and out of his
account he had a particularly bad day
and he ran into somebody who attended
one of my workshops and say hey you
should go see this guy he called me we
had a few appointments didn't really go
anywhere and the next thing about a
month later I get a frantic call from
his wife who I hadn't even met didn't
even know who she was got a frantic call
from his wife that said you know they're
gonna lose her house if you know if if I
don't do something with him okay
he had had a particularly had another
bad real bad day so anyway I started
working with him in July of 1992 and
from July of 1992 until the end of the
year he ended up the year with with
almost six thousand six million dollars
now that may not seem like a lot
considering he had these swings but he'd
never finished he'd never finished a
year with more than I think around 700
650 or 700 thousand dollars so he had
just under six million dollars and so
then he went on vacation he happened to
take a book with him called the coming
collapse of the bond market and this
would have been in like December over
late December of 1992 early January of
93 and came back now if anybody
remembers the bond market back then it
rallied to rally to spectacular Heights
but in the meantime he'd read this to
come and collapse of the bond market so
he was going into the market every day
short ok and and pissing away the six
million dollars until he got to the
point where he had about two of it left
and and took him about I don't know
until maybe mid-february and and he was
so exasperated that he said hey you know
what I'm willing to do anything
okay now keeping my I'm willing to do
anything and he wasn't it wasn't lip
service it was real it was genuine it
was sincere and I said if you're willing
to do anything then here's what you have
to do what I've been working with him
what I noticed is that he was able to
stay focused really for not more than
about an hour a day now this guy loved
trading I mean he just loved being in
the pit he just loved every part of it
he just he just had the hardest time
tearing himself away but if you really
wanted to make consistent money then I I
felt that an hour a day was about it
because after an hour a day he started
losing his focus would start to diminish
and then he'd also start to get reckless
he was the kind of guy in this in this
here again this even kind of this is
very difficult for people to comprehend
but it was the absolute truth he he was
the kind of guy where when I was working
with him during
period you know in in in second half of
1992 where he would have a he'd have a
1/2 million dollar day winnings he'd
make a half million dollars but when he
called after he was out of the pit to
have his consultation you know he'd be
real angry with himself because he up
till about five minutes before the
clothes he was up a half a million
dollars and then he then he pissed away
about 175 of it so we really end up with
$325,000 for the day now this is just
like a normal guy like like us here in
this room with three hundred and twenty
five thousand dollars and this was not
an abnormal day but he's real angry with
himself because he pissed away that
hundred seventy five and then the next
day you know he'd do about the same
thing he'd make four hundred and and and
piss away maybe two at the close and
then the next day he'd make you know 350
and then piss away another 150 he's got
spectacular winds up until Friday but
this accumulated angry anger that that
he was building up throughout the week
Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday by
five time Friday rolled around you know
he'd lose a million and a half bucks and
then start to cycle all over again so
this so now it's like I'm saying you
know what especially as a floor trader
as a floor trader you really have to be
focused when you're trading at the level
that he traded at when you're trading
hundreds of sometimes thousands of
contracts if anybody knows anything
about the bond market we know that that
that one incremental price change in a
bond contract is thirty one dollars and
25 cents
okay you guys with me on this so this
would be a tick so in other words if the
bonds went went one one tick up and
you're long one contract you'd make
thirty one dollars and twenty five cents
if it went down one tick and you were
long one contract you just lost 30 $1.25
he would trade a thousand contracts at a
time that means one incremental tick
priced range was $31,000
31200 fifty bucks now if anybody's ever
watched the bonds move you know that it
can move 5 10 15 ticks like that not
only that there can be what's called
price of vacuums everybody are familiar
with a price vacuum you know what I mean
by price vacuum it means that if the
bond is if the bonds are at let's say
106 106 10 you guys are probably not
familiar with bond prices 106 10 that
was the last posted price that something
can happen and you're long something can
happen where there are there are no more
offers and the next posted price is 106
even that means the market went down 10
ticks without there being any trades
between 10 and even no trades at all
which means if you're long you just lost
in that instant 31,000 dollars and 25
cents on a thousand contracts this is
quite common so you really have to be
focused it would be like when you're
trading at this level I would I would
make an analogy it's almost like there's
a couple of analogies one it's like if
you're in an NBA playoff if the finals
it's the last game seven games it's all
it's seven game NBA Finals one minute
left
the score is tied the coach is going to
send somebody in who's really focused if
the coach thinks you're distracted and
you're not on your game you think you're
going to get in that game this is the
way you to be in these kind of
circumstances in the pit that's the kind
of mindset that you had to maintain
because even if you got you just even if
you were if you were distracted and
turned away
there could be bids and offers that
would have gotten you out of your trade
that all of a sudden dry up meaning when
guys are bidding an offering in the pit
they're using hand signals and there's
and they're telling you they want a
buyer they want to sell and how many and
there's there's a hundreds of guys all
around screaming now these bids are off
can dry up because when you have make
eye contact any point you say okay we've
got a trade and then you write your
trade down in a trading car turn Alison
electronic handheld handheld device but
otherwise you make a trade and then you
could be out of your trade and take your
profits when these kind of things happen
these price vacuums you know your you
could be in bad shape and just be a
matter of just just a momentary you look
away the guy that you were gonna use to
get out of your trade is gone now he put
his hands down oh I'm in I'm in trouble
well what I found is that is that he
could maintain his an ideal mindset for
about an hour a day and so that's why I
said if you're really sincere you if
you're really you really want to do you
can really do anything you can only
train an hour a day and he agreed to it
and he said what hour a day I said
doesn't it really won't matter and it
really didn't he was convinced initially
that what hour he went in would make a
big difference it really didn't make any
difference at all
he was so good as a matter of fact there
were other bond traders that I work with
that said that watching him trade would
have been the equivalent of like
watching Michael Jordan play basketball
he was that good and so he did he went
in just one hour a day and because he
knew that he only had that one hour he
was really focused and he was averaging
a hundred and seventy-five thousand
dollars for that one day or for that on
an average for that one hour per day
okay but that would be an example he
would be an example of an extreme boom
and Buster there kind of gonna kind of
have that concept down the brain about
boom and Buster's okay and then what you
have is you have the consistent losers
people whose equity curve looks like
that now just to get back to my
situation when I when I like I said when
I went to Chicago I'm thinking okay you
know I mean I've got quite a bit of
money I sold my interest in the agency
but at the same time I had a
pretty expensive lifestyle as you can
quite imagine I had a house in Michigan
that I had a girlfriend a very
high-maintenance girlfriend and and and
who to her to her two daughters were
living in and I had a very expensive
apartment in Chicago and a portion the
you know I just I had the life okay and
and you know I was I was going back and
forth every weekend to visit them so I'm
really my situation was I really I
couldn't maintain that kind of lifestyle
with the money that I had without making
without being successful as a trader and
that was a whole IDN e way i thought you
know okay I'll I'll make whatever
shortfall that you know I end up with as
a trader and interestingly enough I had
to have my trading account with another
brokerage firm secretly I couldn't train
through Merrill Lynch and there wasn't
anybody else in the office who traded
their own money I was the only unless
they were doing a secretly didn't tell
me I was the only person in the office
who was actually trading their own money
who actually traded period other than
putting on trades for their customers so
what ended up happening is that and
although part of this is that is that I
also had this I just I don't know I
can't really tell you why I knew this
just that I did I just it just made
sense to me it just never occurred to me
that trading was anything other than
about psychology I mean the first
trading book I ever bought was was
actually the very first book on trading
the only the first book that was devoted
it's a specifically trading psychology
which was Jake Bernstein's investors
quotient that came out in 1980 and there
were that many trading books of a leavin
available back then and that was the
first trading book that I didn't buy a
book on technical analysis I bought a
book on trading psychology so I was I
was not only
immersed in the concepts of trading
psychology virtually right from the very
beginning I was also keeping very
extensive journals of my thinking
process what was going on what I was
observing from other brokers in the you
know in the Merrill Lynch office as well
as what I was observing from interacting
with my customers and I noticed we were
all kind of all kind of you know
conforming to the same patterns the same
problems but just say that because I did
have you know I did have this kind of
foundation you know to understand that
that it was basically psychological in
nature because one of the things we're
going to talk about you and I get into
the skills section of this of the
presentation is that when you look at
trading skills it's like what kind of
skills are we talking about we're
talking about thinking like a
professional we're applying that the
skills are all mental in nature and they
are because when you really get right
down to it you really start to think
about it what physical skills are
necessary to trade but we're not talking
about a golf swing or a tennis racket or
any other kind of you know any other
kind of physical endeavor that that
we're that we're familiar with what kind
of skills we what does it take
physically to put on a trade the
mouse-click that's it your ability to
move the mouse and to click it on the
buyer cell button it's that simple and
as a result of it being that simple it's
easy to think that oh my god trading is
so easy it isn't as you will probably
know whether you've been added a long
time or even a little bit of time there
are some very sophisticated
psychological skills that you have to
acquire to get this kind of an equity
curve and and virtually all these skills
are founded in learning how to trade
without fear that's basically what this
whole workshops about is learning how to
trade without fear
because that's what's gonna screw you up
on virtually everything everything that
you can do wrong as a traitor is going
to be the result of what you're afraid
of and the effects that fear has on your
perception of market information so so
with my situation it's like here I'm
given all this up to go to Chicago to
learn how to trade to find out that the
only people who really knew how to trade
back then were were people that I didn't
have access to meaning there were there
were you know there were some big names
in the industry who never really took
the time or expended the effort to find
out exactly what it is that allowed them
to create a consistently rousing equity
curve what they would say is well yeah
you got to go with the flow the trend is
your friend cut your losses let your
profits run you know as all these all
these neat little phrases but it's like
who and I hell knew what that meant and
how to do it yeah it sounds great cut
your losses let your profits run huh you
know even cutting your losses it can be
extremely difficult to learn letting
your profits run can be 10 times more
difficult than learning how to cut your
profit cut cut your losses fact is one
of the most difficult things to to
acquire in terms of a skill is learning
how to let your profits run so it was
like all this was kind of building up
and my lifestyle was was draining it was
draining my money away and one of the
things that one of the things that that
I would say characterized me back then
if I was probably obsessive about
anything it was my credit it's like my
credit was my as far as I was concerned
it was like the most important thing in
life is to have flawless flawless credit
not just I mean flawless and here I'm in
a situation where I'm I am truly running
out of money
and my trading losses I didn't really it
wasn't really like I was losing a lot of
money trading because I'd really stopped
the hemorrhaging I wasn't trading in a
way where I was actually losing money
but I wasn't making any money and it's
like there was always this little voice
in the back of my brain you know coming
to the forefront of my consciousness and
I would say you know mark this ain't
adding up there's something wrong here
there's something there's something
wrong it's like it's not it's not adding
up and then I kind of shove it back
there and you know I'm like yeah it's
gonna be all right I'll figure it out
I'll figure it out it's gonna be all
right
eventually got to the point where I I
was literally out of money and the only
choice I had was to file bankruptcy
fortunately I was in a situation where I
had two residences one in Chicago in one
in Michigan and so I had a choice of
where I filed and of course I filed in
Michigan because if Merrill Lynch would
have found out they probably would have
fired me
it's a matter of fact nobody knew what
had happened ie nobody knew in Chicago
buddy that I knew in Chicago knew what
had happened
so I filed in Michigan and I'm thinking
and literally because of my attitudes
about credit I'm thinking if I've got to
do this I'm going to fall beneath the
cracks of society and never really
believe that I honestly God really did I
just didn't see how it's possible to
live after having have to after having
to do something like that and of course
you know what I found is that in when I
ended up I mean what I say in the
discipline trader and I don't really go
into a lot of detail on the disciplined
trader about this but just just to say
that what I ended up with was relaying I
had an apartment I had my bed in my TV
and and and and when I when I filed I
was still current on everything I was
even late one day on any my bills as a
matter of fact I even I even called you
know called the the finance company to
come and pick the car up but I was even
late a payment I said you know what I
can't do it anymore you're probably
gonna want it back anyway so you know it
was like come and pick it up and of
course they did and and the guys went
there's a funny story about that I
remember told anybody this but you guys
want to hear funny story about that
when the guy came to pick it up and so
I'm thinking you know because we were in
front of the apartment building and and
I'm thinking well if he's gonna pick
this up you know then I ought to get
some sort of receipt that it was in
perfect condition you know because I
don't know what the hell is gonna do to
it I'm you know yeah you mean I don't
know so it's like any guy wouldn't give
me a receipt saying that and so I
wouldn't give him the keys and so you
know so we called his boss and and I and
I heard I heard his boss on the other
end Alliance screaming at him get those
keys you know it's like yeah he said
something else I'm not gonna say yeah
for this brother for this you know for
this particular presentation but yeah I
was like you know they just you know
someone someone's willing to give you
the car or they don't even have to go
repossess it that's like you know hey
give him the receipt but in any case
what I realized I mean don't you think
about this it's like it's like when you
define yourself based on your
possessions you know just like anybody
that loses anything you know you've got
you've got an internal representation
and you've got an external
representation and now there was there
was a discrepancy between what was
outside I mean what was inside of me in
terms of the way that I defined myself
and you know so that has to be
reconciled and what I realized you know
in a dad didn't even really take that
long I don't remember how long it took
but it was like one I still had my job
at Merrill Lynch and so as a result I
mean it's like I'm starting thinking
okay well things are gonna be all right
I was in my worst fear I mean that was
my worst fear I mean with it with the
fear would creep up into the forefront
of my mind I was like you know that was
my worst fear now I'm in it and I'm
realizing that you know I think I'm
gonna be alright I'm healthy I can still
think I'm gonna I'm gonna be alright and
when I came to this realization that I'm
gonna be alright this is when things
change for me as a traitor and and this
is and this is the interesting part
about my situation that that most people
don't have the benefit of experiencing
there are two things one I had this
foundation of knowing that it was all
psychological anyway so I had all these
things that I that I'd been working on
up to that point and to when you tap out
as a traitor
I mean when you
really tap out you don't get to trade
anymore cuz you don't have any money
right but I was in a situation where I
still got to trade even though I was
working with other people's money I
still got to trade every day and so as a
result of experiencing my worst fears
coming to the realization that I'm gonna
be alright and then at the same time
being being in a position where I'm able
to interact with the market it was like
because I didn't have anything more to
lose I didn't it was like it was like
this the market completely changed for
me it was like I had these blinders on
that all of a sudden just came off
because the market was different because
I wasn't afraid anymore I was seeing the
same patterns over and over and over
again beforehand but I was seeing the
same patterns differently I was seeing
the same patterns from a let's say
relatively carefree state of mind and
that relatively carefree state of mind
allowed me to like say flow in and out
of my trades with an ease and
effortlessness that I would not have
been able to imagine beforehand and then
what happened is that I started making
consistent money for my customers and
there's even well there's one one really
was a matter of what one really good
good story where I mean there are a lot
of good stories that I can tell you
about my customers at Merrill Lynch but
in one case I inherited this guy who was
at the time was a head of the state of
Illinois mainframe computers and he was
from India and he had put together his
own trading program and he was using the
you know state computers to do it and so
and he had an account technically an
account with Merrill Lynch but it wasn't
funded because he had lost all his money
but he but he still had he still
maintained the account and so I
inherited him as a customer and he would
call me every day and he was just like
and all he would say to me was like I
pick up the phone he wouldn't say hi how
are you
here's a
give me data you know like give me the
high low and close there and you know so
we interacted like this for a long time
well he came up with his own day trading
system that that that eventually well
because he and I started working on it
together he had the he had the internal
program for it but he didn't have any
money management parameters for it so I
have about two or three months of
working with him on it we came up with
some really good money management
parameters and then all my customers
started trading it and and we were
making consistent money day after day
even to the point where Merrill Lynch
will starting to take notice you know
that that you know here we all hold this
whole customer because his customer
bases is making money and and he got to
the point where where he's thinking okay
all these people are now deriving this
benefit from my work I should be able to
do it too and he talked his wife into
letting him put five thousand dollars
into his account to fund his account now
I don't know what happened to him why I
mean I you know we've not like we had
personal discussion so I don't know why
he didn't have any money in his account
the guy was a maniac
it is like he got he put the money put
the money in his account and two days
later was all gone it was like he called
me up and say okay do this I said well
wait a second the system says to do this
no no no no no they don't care what the
system says this is what's going to
happen he didn't follow any of his own
rules
now here we had a track record we had a
legitimate track record bonafide real
money day after day he gets a few bucks
in his account and it's like he thinks
he knows where the markets going like I
said he was gone in two days and that
was it it was all over with because at
that point he you know he was done I
didn't get the system because it wasn't
in his computer mainframe computer at
the state of Illinois and and had no
more contact with him and shortly after
that ended up getting fired from Merrill
Lynch anyway because there was a like
one of these management consultants that
came in from New York and she was going
around the office talking all the
different brokers because of one or
whatever whatever was that they were
trying to find out
and she got to me and at that by that
time I was already writing the
disciplined trader and so and I just
like you know I started very exciting to
say hell yeah this is what I found out
this is what I've learned and her eyes
lit up saying this is exactly this is
exactly what we're looking for and she
was just we talked for probably about an
hour hour and a half and you she was all
excited and then she and then said I you
know I got to go tell you I don't say
his name
the office manager okay and she walked
away from me walked over the office
manager
ten minutes later ten minutes later he
came over said pack up your stuff and
get out right then and there right then
and there on the spot pack up your stuff
and get out so that's how I ended up
ended up actually being a trading coach
because by then just you know floor
trade because I'd made friends with
floor traders you know I was making
friends to find out how they trade that
sort of thing well they started coming
to me for advice even while I was at
Merrill Lynch and and because it's a
pretty small community you know the word
gets around especially when when you you
know people are really genuinely help
with with the kind of advice that you're
getting that you're giving them and I'd
you know and I'd help several for
traders turn their training around and
so what had happened is I started
getting hired by clearing firms what I
mean by clearing firms that to trade on
the floor of an exchange you have to you
have to clear your trades through a
financial institution and so you know
it's like you're it's these are traders
just like you they have their own
account but but what they have to do is
they have to clear their trades through
like I said one of the one of the major
clearing firms at the exchange well what
had happened what would happen is this
that it isn't like this now but back in
the back in the early 80s through the
mid 80s clearing firms were in some ways
like like almost like family operations
where where the people who owned the
clearing firms they knew all the all the
floor traders they were friends with
them they partied together you know
Christmases and holidays and that sort
of thing and so if one of the floor
traders would go debit we know what I
mean by go debit in other words you know
you have to trade it have to have a
positive
positive balance in your account well
the problem with floor trading is that
not again not today but back then when
you trade it on the floor you had to had
to record your trades on a trading card
so in other words of you and I are
entering into a trade where I'm going
along and you're going short what I
would do is is that we would we would
take our badge like the acronym of our
badge and and our Clearing House number
recorded on this card and how many
contracts we traded you let's say you're
short 10 and I'm long 10 and when the
price that that that we trade in a map
well those cards didn't have to be
turned in until the end of the day and
then they'd all get reconciled meaning
that between all the different trades
and all the all the traders well the
different clearing firms this will all
go into a central clearing operation to
find out which trades were you know to
find out whose long and whose short how
much money's coming out of whose account
and whether or not they were caught what
are called out trades meaning that you
thought you thought I said 10 and and I
thought we were doing it for a hundred
ok so now we've got a discrepancy in 90
trades these were called out trades it
had to be reconciled before the open of
the next day which is a whole nother
world now we're not in Gilmer now you're
not gonna get into it all but all I'm
saying is that all I'm saying is that is
that it would not be unusual for guys to
over trade during the day in the
clearing firm wouldn't even find out
about it until the end of the day for
example one of them one of the guys I
worked with at Merrill Lynch eventually
he was a mathematics professor a really
nice guy should not have been a trader
at all had absolutely I mean anyway more
than peas at the Chicago Mercantile
Exchange and he was a one lot trader
meaning you know just traded one
contract one in and out one contract and
and and eventually the forces inside of
him building up where he's frustrated
with the fact that he's you know I can't
make a living at it and he's just eating
and eating it out where one day he
snapped and this and this one lot trader
almost took down the clearing firm in
other words he's got like several
thousand snps on several thousand
contracts where other guys are into
those trades and and the markets going
against them so he almost took down a
clearing for him just just by himself so
what would happen is that is that
because guys would go debit meaning they
end up as they've lost me they're down
25 thousand or fifty or a hundred
thousand dollars the guy that owns a
clearing firm doesn't want to say hey
you can't trade until you pay this off
they'd want to let me go back into the
pit to work it to work it down
well after you know you've got four or
five of these troublesome or 15 of these
troublesome traders that are constantly
running debits you start to get a little
worried and so what they did is start
they hired me to work with these guys
most of the information most of the
insight let's say that that you'll find
in the disciplined trader and trading in
the zone came from me working with these
floor traders on a daily basis and it
was I'm laughing because obviously it
was quite it was quite trip working with
these guys because they are not like
they are not like you and me okay that's
that's that's really about the best I
can the best way I can describe it
without going into a lot of detail
they're not like you and me so anyway
you know this is kind of a maybe a long
drawn-out introduction to the fact that
what we're talking about here is that
you guys have a really wonderful trading
methodology where there is an enormous
amount of potential for you to be able
to make a consistent income from being
able to take full advantage of the
potential that this trading methodology
offers you but I would say that there's
probably it wouldn't be unfair for me to
say
it wouldn't be unfair for me to say that
there's probably what I'm going to call
the profit gap the gap between the
potential and your bottom line results
this is the potential and there's your
bottom line results most people think
that when they realize that this gap
exists that somehow learning more about
the markets is what's going to fill it
and what you're here today to learn is
that that is categorically not the case
you have to learn more about yourself
and how you interact with your trading
platform and the market to be able to
fill this gap there are psychological
skills involved then wise talk about
psychological skills well let's do we do
anybody think of an example of a
psychological skill this this this is
difficult I don't think you know I'm not
saying that you should have the answer
but well can you think of an analogy and
you know it may be in other parts of the
way we express ourselves that you can
think of what would be an example of a
psychological skill anger management
okay that good anybody else okay what
about a situation that was just anybody
watch will Milton here lately just it
was on I'm not a big tennis fan but I
just happen to be watching it and
because I knew that this I was doing
this this workshop here this is
something who really sticks on my mind
what's the difference between between
let's say oh here it doesn't even a
better example what's the difference
between a bath a pro basketball player
who can stand at the free-throw line and
hit 20 in a row
even 30 in a row where the thing about
the variables are fixed the line in the
basket and the distances they're all
fixed and they've got the motor skills
to be able to hit like I said 10 15 20
in a row but they get into a situation
where there's 1 second left and the
score is tied and this basket is going
to win the game
any chokes that's a cycle the guy that
doesn't choke it has a psychological
skill that the other one doesn't
trading without fear is a psychological
skill it is a skill that the
professionals have acquired and if they
have evolved beyond the typical mindset
or the kind of mindset that the typical
trader operates out of so when we're
talking about trading or thinking like a
pro that's exactly what I'm saying
I'm saying that you will evolve beyond
the typical mindset so that you can take
full advantage full admit this
represents if this line represents
potential that you can take the
potential of your methodology that you
can take full advantage of your
methodology because it has to do with
your state of mind