in this fourth section I will cover the
underlying dynamics of confidence and
fear so that you can build a framework
for understanding how to create a
carefree state of mind when you trade ok
the next section that we're going to get
into is exploring the dynamics of
confidence and fear in other words what
what was the from this morning and in
just a little while ago not so much a
little while ago especially from this
morning what's the primary problem why
why why do we have so much of a problem
or what creates the problem with the
tuna trade by trade perspective in other
words if I'm looking at the market if my
technical indicator gives me a signal to
buy right now
ok what's in a buy and if I'm not pre
defining my risk if I'm hesitating if
I'm jumping the gun if I'm you know if I
put my trade on and and and you know I
want to move my stop what is it that's
going on right now what's compelling me
to make these kinds of errors fear and
and what's behind the fear ok but that's
good but I want but yeah because you
don't want to get tapped into being
wrong losing missing out all that other
all that pain but remember I said what
was what was a universal characteristic
of all humanity
in terms of how we feel about our
expectations being fulfilled
well yeah but you all know where they
are but what I'm saying is that it's
because I'm expecting this trade to work
ok once you got you guys got to get this
ok the reason why I'm having a problem
is because I'm expecting this trade to
work this trade it's not because I'm
thinking that I've got a I've got a
series of trades remember the pattern
with the pattern within flipping the
coin the pattern is that if I've got an
edge well I'll give you another example
let's say that I've got a coin that's
waited waited
whether you're on the tail side so that
it's going to come up on a percentage
basis 65% of the time heads and I get
someone to take the other side of a bet
where I get to call the flip every time
what am I going to do am I gonna try to
determine win tails is going to that 35
percent of times tails is going to come
up
I'm gonna call heads every time that's a
pattern okay the way it relates here is
that I've got a technical methodology
that gives me winning trades let's say
65 percent of the time I don't know
which of those of the next 20 trades or
25 trades that come up I don't know
which ones are going to be the winners
and which ones are going to be the
losers if I'm going to trade my
methodology appropriately that really
obligates me to take every single trade
I can't be picking and choosing my
trades based on what I think is going to
happen because I hopefully I've already
established you don't know if you think
you know you're just making it up in
your own mind I'm gonna repeat that if
you think you know you're just making it
up is this is everybody alright with
what I just said
and so it obligates me to take every
single trade that comes up because I
don't know which ones are going to be
the winners and which ones are going to
be the losers it means that if I'm
having problems it's because I have a
certain expectation about this trade or
about this trade or about this one so
what if I'm expecting a random outcome
what if I change my expectations well I
feel differently about it if I change my
expectations while I feel differently
about it is there anybody in this room
do does anybody who trades look what I
ever it's been in this way I don't think
I've ever met anybody who trades who
hasn't at least gambled at some point in
their lives right what do you expect
when you put money into a slot machine
and push the button good one of those
that's was goodbye I like that what else
loud if every the same thing what are
you expecting really on this one
seriously what do you expect
yeah what do you know what you're
expecting you're expecting something to
happen right you're expecting the wheels
to turn you're expecting something to
show up now think about what I'm just
saying because you know what what I just
said is exactly what I expect when I put
on a trade I'm expecting something to
happen I don't know what but over a
series of trades if I do everything
right I'll make money because I'm
managing my expectations on each one of
these trades I'm managing my
expectations so that I do not have the
potential to define and interpret these
up-and-down ticks the information the
market gives me and some sort of
threatening or painful way because what
I'm going to tell you what are we
get into now is the effects of that when
you put money what's that what do you
mean how realistic go ahead no no take
the microphone how realistic is a 65%
win ratio on your methodology I'm not
understanding the question how realistic
is it well if you can't go by any
individual specific trade which you say
over 20 trades you can say you expect to
win 65% of the time correct that based
on past performance okay but then again
looking at over any individual 20 or 50
sample how realistic is maybe that's 65
percent saying that you are that's a
real number
I'll find out I don't know I don't know
how will I know how could I know I'll
find out that's why you trade in sample
sizes that are limited in other words I
don't make an assessment of how well
it's working until after the end of a
sample size if if at the end of a sample
size I get a high enough percentage of
winning trades than where I'm satisfied
then I'll take another sample size if I
don't then I'll find ways to tweak my
indicators to improve my results so for
you to say how realistic is it I have no
idea of knowing what's going to happen
in the future when you get right down to
it it is possible would it not be
possible for me to get in to start a
sample size that trade 1 and end up
where every single one of them was a
loser am I going to know that in advance
and see and that's where paper trading
is so critical is that by paper trading
you will get a realistic assessment as
to how well your edge works and people
have no problem paper trading don't
paper trade to find out if you know if
they're meant that they can you know
they can their methodology works and to
gain confidence in it it's the other
part that they won't they won't
participate in meaning that they won't
take that same take
take a similar exercise to see how well
their own psychology matches up to what
they need to do to be consistently
successful in other words to set up an
exercise paper training is an exercise
is it not it's an exercise in developing
skills and understanding your
methodology is it not so wouldn't it be
just as reasonable to set up an exercise
to learn how to execute properly so
you've managed your expectations what
what do you consider a proper sample
size 20 25 trades I don't think it has
to be more than that I really don't if
it's not working within 25 trades and do
this then there's something there's
something you have to change okay so
it's all about our expectations when I
put money into a slot machine I'm
expecting something to happen if it
comes up a loser do I get all worked up
about this this tapped me into my
accumulated emotional pain of every time
I've been wrong and lost in my life I
mean look at there there are there are
people who trade and and and and because
of their expectations make every error
in the book and can't make consistent
money and the reason why is because of
the regs like I said because their
expectations and yet if they put money
into a slot machine where essentially
the only difference between technical
trading and a slot machine is the fact
that with a slot machine you have to put
your money in first and then wait for a
pattern to emerge with technical trading
you have to wait for a pattern to emerge
and then technically put your money on
the line the problem is because the way
our minds think we think that because
the pattern emerged that somehow or
another it's giving us an edge on that
particular individual trade and there's
just no way of knowing that but over a
series of trades it does so it's like
technical analysis gives the individual
the the availability of being the casino
Finkle analysis lets you own the slot
machine because you've got the odds in
your favor the casino makes the slot
machine available to us because they've
got the odds in their favor but - but
derive the benefit of those odds you
have to be able to execute properly and
you have to think about this properly it
is just a numbers game based on the odds
that means that you can't put an
extraordinary a and it let's say next
and it's an extraordinary amount of
significance on each individual trade
because if you sat and played a slot
machine you wouldn't think anything of
it if you if you put you played a dollar
slot machine and you sat down with the
idea that you know what I got a hundred
bucks in my pocket
and you didn't win you know you might
have you know is it ten times in a row
you didn't win you're still you're still
gonna push the button because eventually
you think eventually I'm gonna hit
eventually I'm gonna hit so it's alright
you see it's alright same thing here
this trade didn't work well eventually
eventually I'll get a winner
this trade didn't work eventually I get
a winner this trade didn't work well
eventually I'll get a winner no I don't
know about this next one now that's
almost always the winner now if it turns
out that your methodology has diminished
and it's let's say in its capacity to
produce a winning percentage because the
underlying nature of the market is
changing in relationship to this fixed
formula then you know that's why you
trade in smaller sample sizes or a
sample size where you don't lose an
inordinate amount of money to find out
it's not working but you do this right
and you're the casino regardless of all
the dynamic traders regardless of all
this other stuff I'm talking about it
doesn't matter none of that stuff's
important as long as you understand the
underslung as you understand how the
underlying dynamics relates to the
formula so that you don't put and you
know an extraordinary amount of
significance on a formula that's just
giving you a pattern in collective
behavior not individual behavior and
it's individuals who move the market so
those individuals there can always
an individual or group of individuals
who come into the market that do
something that completely negates the
outcome of your pattern and that's
alright because there's no way to know
that in advance
it's alright when you look at it that
way then you won't get all worked up
then it's just a random outcome just
like a slot machine it's just a random
outcome because that's what you're
expecting you expect a random outcome
you've got a random outcome and there's
no emotional significance because here's
what happens when you don't look at it
this way let's take a typical trader
who's operating out of the for Fears
okay we got support we got resistance we
got a nice training range the markets
coming down to support okay now a
typical trader operating out of those
four fears the fear of being wrong the
fear of losing money missing out you
know depending on the intensity of these
fears and they give it a moment he might
have a hard time putting that trade on
right he's got a Bible pattern you know
all that happened here is that when the
market got an imbalance in conviction
remember all price movements a result of
an imbalance in conviction the markets
came down to this point right here there
wasn't one person in the world not one
now let's say that's not one person in
the world in the whole world that would
offer that would take out the bids to
offer this market one tick lower than
this price right here not one okay and
then all of a sudden there's an
imbalance in conviction where there are
more buy orders and sell orders it
drives the price up to here and the same
thing happens driving the price down to
here same thing happens here here now
it's coming back down that from my
perspective I'm looking at it like this
how much room do I have to give the
market to tell me that the people who
bought here and the people who bought
here are going to come back into the
market and do it again because right now
there's an imbalance and conviction on
the sell side that means that enough
orders buy orders have to come into the
market to absorb all the offers to
absorb all those offers with enough left
over to create upside movement do I have
any way of knowing whether or not
they're going to come in no I know but
the odds are in my favor at least I hope
they are in any case I'm willing to risk
a certain amount of distance from my
entry point to find out that's all of it
that's all it means to me if they don't
come in it means you know what the guys
that were bought here but it might be
out to lunch and that happens I am not
kidding you I know that for a fact I've
experienced it because I intimately knew
you know a lot of the big traders in
certain markets that would buy
by here and I'm thinking okay they're
coming back in and they were out to
lunch so hey where were you guys but to
the typical trader that doesn't think
this way what's going to happen if he
manages to get the trade on it's gonna
be because he thinks he's right because
he thinks he knows what's going to
happen next right and he's not gonna put
in a stop because to predefine his risk
how much money does they have to how
much room and dollar-wise how much room
a distance of the dollar value of this
distance that it has to give the market
and tell him that this trade is either
working or it's not or that to let it go
any further is it worth finding out
that's all it means to me but he's not
gonna think that way he's gonna think by
gathering evidence that this trade might
not work he might be talking himself out
of taking it and so by the time he
actually manages to get this get this
order in the market and buy somewhere in
here
he has convinced himself that he's right
now I remember I said earlier and I
think I just said it once so you might
not have gotten it that fear has an has
an effect on the way we perceive
information when we're in a state of
mind of fear we are perceiving
information in a threatening way in
other words we're having an expectation
of pain remember I said that to
experience emotional pain there's two
kinds of pain physical pain and
emotional pain emotional pain requires
an interpretation the up and down ticks
that the market offers us are not
inherently pleasurable or painful by
their nature there is such a thing as
painful information
I mean painful from the environments
perspective if the environment if
someone is someone's hurling insults at
you their intent is to cause you
emotional pain but that doesn't mean
you're going to experience the emotional
pain unless you interpret it that way if
they're hurling insults at you and a
foreign language you don't have the
slightest idea about what they're saying
you may look to you like they're saying
something isn't so nice but then again
you don't have you don't know what the
words are and so what do you feel
nothing the interpretations come from
our beliefs the interpretations come
from our mental framework in other words
the pains already inside of us all the
words are doing is tapping us into it
once we learn how to manage our
interpretations we can manage the way
that we feel we can actually determine
how we feel in our own state of mind so
this trader he's operating out of a fear
of being wrong
so like I said he convinces himself that
he's right that's the way you get the
trade on so let's say the market
now I said that fear causes us to focus
on their focus on the object of our fear
so that we end up creating the very
experience we're trying to avoid this
trader is trying to avoid being wrong
now we have self protective mechanisms
there they can work at an unconscious
level there are mechanisms inside of us
that will protect us from information
that we perceive as threatening it
causes what was typically referred to as
perceptual blindness where there are
things going on around us that we cannot
perceive even though we have the ability
to perceive it but we're being blinded
from it if I'm afraid of being wrong
what of the information that the market
is making available to me what am I
going to focus my attention on the up
ticks of the down ticks you're right the
up ticks not the down ticks meaning that
what I will do is I will place an
inordinate amount of significance and
although the way my mind will
automatically weigh this information in
terms of what's significant and what
isn't it will give more significance to
the up ticks than the down ticks because
every time I get an uptick it will be
taking me out of my pain I'll say oh
it's finally all over and then we'll get
more down ticks and then we get a couple
up ticks and say oh it's finally all
over in other words what my mind is
doing to protect me is saying that these
few up ticks are far more significant
than all these down ticks now do I have
the ability to recognize a trend in
other words being able to define and
recognize the trend is one of the most
fundamental characteristics of learning
technical analysis a trend is a high
series of higher highs and higher lows
or lower highs and lower lows but in
this moment a might be able to recognize
this as a trend no because I'm too
focused on getting myself out of the
pain which means that I'm focused on
these up ticks now our trader is
operating both out of a fear of being
wrong and a fear of losing money now
what ends up happening is this is that
if this if this word
present all the negative energy inside
of his mind of what it means to be wrong
there's also negative energy inside of
his mind about what it means to lose and
as the market was further and further
against his position his belief about
losing will start to gain more and more
significance and start to rise to the
forefront of his consciousness and make
itself known make its presence known
until finally he gets to a point where
he cannot stand losing one more dollar
and that one more dollar in essence is
when the pain of losing one more dollar
is one degree greater than the pain of
admitting that he's wrong in other words
when this pain is greater than that
pained by one degree he'll get out of
the trade that's when he'll admit that
it's a losing trade and get out you guys
with me on this
now he would say that the market did
this to him but what I'm saying is that
is blatantly not the case his fear did
that to him he created the very
experience he was trying to avoid he was
trying to avoid being wrong and he made
himself wrong and ultimately this was
always a spot with the market you know
where the market does that anyway you
guys with me on this okay now this
trader gets out of this trade right here
he looks back at this chart pattern and
he why did I just go short why didn't I
just go short the ability to recognize
this as a downtrend
let's say he was blinded from his
ability to recognize us as a downtrend
the distinction existed inside of his
mind in other words he can actually make
the distinction of what a downtrend is
but in that moment while he was in that
trade he was blinded to his own
distinctions because he was operating
out of a trade by trade mentality he was
operating I would say he was operating
out of a trade by trade mentality this
trade took on the significance of life
or death
just like any any other trade that he
puts on does and to be a consistently
successful trader it ain't gonna happen
if you think that way the pros don't
think that way determine your risk
either works or it doesn't and win go to
the next trade determine your risk the
work sort of doesn't go to the next
trade that that's all it is that's the
whole game
now let's say that this doesn't happen
but this happens but say instead of it
going against them at the market does
this now what ticks do you think he's
gonna be focused on the upper the down
ticks the mark is doing exactly what he
wants by the way now the market is doing
exactly what he wants and what ticks do
you think he's gonna be focused on out
of down ticks and why the down ticks
because he's been in too many times the
trades in the market has taken away his
profits and so he plays an inordinate
amount of significance on every down
tick and in essence ends up doing what
leaving money on the table so what he
does is let's say he gets out right here
so he cuts his profit shorts and lets
his losses run in Chicago vernacular
this is called like this is called
shooting like an elephant and eating
like a bird
I hope that now if this trader had a
belief in a random outcome that he
didn't have to know what was going to
happen next to make money what do you
have these problems what would he be
expecting if he had a belief in a random
outcome that there was just a random
distribution between wins and losses and
then he give him a set of variables that
define his edge if he believed that if
he believed that only took one trader
somewhere in the world to negate the
positive outcome of his edge if you
believe that no matter what reason he
thinks he has for putting on that trade
that the reason why it works or it
doesn't work will almost never correlate
to the actual reason that he conjured up
if he believed all these things how
would he be handling this come on how
would he be handling it tell me okay
when he got into the trade he's going to
say that okay when it reaches this level
right here I'm gonna get out if it goes
down to this level down here I'm gonna
get out now he may have ended up leaving
some money on the table but at least
he's going to be in that percentage that
he had already predetermined it's going
to create him to be a winning percentage
of trades would he have the same be
saddled with the same emotional problems
that he had if he if he was operating
out of a fear of being wrong or losing
money no no because you didn't have any
emotion in the trade it's saying hey
it's following my predetermined plan
that I have in place and it either works
or doesn't right that's right because I
trade from a series of trades
perspective I don't know what each
individual trade is going to do
this is the way the pros do it by the
way this is thinking like a pro you want
to make consistent money this is what
you gonna have to think otherwise you
already know what the problems are
trading will take on a take on a quality
of being
exasperated because you can see the
potential and it seems like you're
always just that just like that close
I'm getting it and you never get there
how we feel our state of mind in any
given situation is always real and the
absolute truth now I want you to make a
distinction here and any given moment
we're in a state of mind state of mind
could be any number of things we have a
lot of ways to define states of mind we
could be a state of mind of like sits
satisfaction dissatisfaction happiness
joy fear terror these are all states of
mind confidence in the state of mind as
a state of mind confidence when I'm
confident I feel I feel compelled to
step into a situation compels to thrust
me forward into an experience of course
if I'm fearful then what am i doing I'm
pulling back because I feel threatened
in some way I'm perceiving the
information that's available in that
moment as threatening but you've got to
remember for me to perceive it that way
it means I'm interpreting it that way
here's where people get real mixed up
about this sort of thing is that the
state of mind that we experience in any
given moment as always the absolute
truth you can't deny the fact if I'm if
I'm feeling fearful right now that I'm
that I'm feeling fearful that's just the
way that it is I'm in that state of mind
the particular interpretation that got
me into that state of mind however could
be completely dysfunctional the guys
with me on this the interpretation that
comes from what we believe could be
completely dysfunctional
you see as passive technical traders if
we believe that somehow or another our
methodology is telling us what's going
to happen next
on any particular trade the reason why
we're having problems is because that is
a dysfunctional belief it was never true
now the states of mind that result from
that belief are real so for an example
if I put on a trade and it turns out to
be a winner I think that I'm right
and as a result I feel great if I put on
a trade and I think that I lose well
then I feel like crap because I was
wrong the reality is neither one was
really true because when you win you
weren't right and when you're wrong you
weren't wrong because whatever reason
you had to put on the trade in the first
place again had almost no correlation to
what actually happened with the market
in other words why the market did what
it did you just happen to put on a trade
at that time that worked and all
technical patterns do technical
indicators I mean pen price patterns is
get you into a situation where there's a
likelihood a likelihood a likelihood
that when you get into that trade it'll
work that's all they were ever
represented to be understand I'm saying
that's all they were ever represented to
be I'm not saying they don't get you
know screwed up somehow in terms of the
way people represent them but that's
basically that's all basically they ever
they ever were it's not on a trade by
trade basis now we're gonna get into the
last part of it we're we're heading down
the homestretch guys heading down to the
homestretch
are we all right up to this point as far
as anybody have any questions about the
fear and confidence and the
relationships that we're talking about
that what we're talking about is the
fact that we've got it if we want to we
want to think like a pro so that we can
experience the kind of results that the
pros get which are consistent it means
that we have to change our perspective
from trade by trade to a series of
trades does anybody have any questions
about that and why that's essential so
if you know that why do we have to go to
a series of trades perspective why
well hold on one second sir
you're taking all the fear out of and
you know that through a series you'll be
right more the times and you will be
wrong and you take all the fear out of
it and just work on that basis without
any emotion correct no and why isn't
there any emotion when you take give me
specifically why you think there's no
emotion well you're doing it out more of
a mathematical concept and not I think
it's gonna do this you're taking to see
they're gonna be right or it's gonna be
wrong and you either walk away or stay
in it I want you to use words
expectations and your in your answer
okay I don't have any expectations it's
either gonna work or it's not yeah
another words this particular trade you
don't know what you think something's
gonna happen but you don't know what
when you when you put money a slot
machine and push the button you think
something's gonna happen but you don't
know what and if it comes out to be the
putt jackpot well hey your dad feels
great you're surprised right when I put
on a trade I feel the same way literally
I don't know I don't have to know I just
have to do what I need to do to make
money I can on a consistent basis which
means I have to take every one of these
trades I can't pick and choose the only
reason why I'd pick and choose is
because I think I'm right so when you
change your perspective from a trade by
trade to a series of trades it
automatically manages your expectations
in a positive way I'm gonna set this up
for you as an exercise in a little bit
okay but but I just want to make sure
where anybody else have any questions
about any of this so you know you so in
other words what so what we're doing at
this what are we doing at this point
down so so you know where you want to go
right so do we know where we want to go
we want to get to a point where we are
actually changing the way that we think
when you walked in here this morning you
didn't think like a pro did you now you
have some idea of what it means to think
like a pro right come on yes or no come
on guys give me some response okay how
we gonna get there now we might
understand it how we gonna get there
well
paper trading yeah well yeah sort of but
yeah I didn't you know I'm not saying
you just have the answer and I say we
got to have a way to get there right we
have to but we have to have a series of
steps to be able to get to this
particular mindset because what we're
really talking about here is we're
talking about changing the way that we
think now that can have some profound
implications right no one seems to like
to change the way that they think most
traders have to go through the process
remember this morning the thread that
the common thread between all traders
who end up you know being you know being
really successful is that they end up
having to lose one or more fortunes of
what they defined as a fortune to get to
that point it's because the process of
losing caused them to change the way
that they think about trading now do you
want to do this the hard way or do you
want to do it the easy way okay I'm
getting some response here good the easy
way right we want to do it the easy way
so this is what this is all about now
this is what the last part of the
workshop is about is about doing it the
easy way what's that right there you go
how do we change well that's a good
question right that's a real good one
how do we change a lot of theories a lot
of techniques about a lot of theories a
lot of theories on techniques as far as
I'm concerned change is really a
function of well you can break down to a
series of steps and really change is
really a function of desire when you get
right down remember how we took price
movement and boiled it down and
distilled it down to simply what price
movement all price movement is a
function of what imbalance and
conviction between buyers and sellers
all change is a function of desire
if the desire is there you'll find a way
to facilitate the change and it really
doesn't matter what the technique is
honest to god it really doesn't I'll
give you an example right here probably
the one of the most extreme examples I
could come up with you could by the way
this what I'm gonna read you right now I
got off a guy who and you can go google
this kid and find out more about him
yourself okay but as I read this to you
keep in mind how this kid accomplished
this because the scientists that that
investigate this they don't know they
can't figure it out to me it's easy the
kids desire was so intense that he
managed to find a way this is Lincoln
Nebraska
Bryce Mellon is a whiz at video games
such as Mortal Kombat who is anybody
familiar Mortal Kombat I'm not into
video games though well not those video
games anyway Mortal Kombat okay I've got
some people this is a tough game yeah
challenging okay in that regard the 17
year old and he's a little older now
this was a couple years ago in that
regard the 17 year old isn't much
different from so many others his age
except for one thing
he's blind and as Eve and as he easily
dispatched foes who took him on recently
at a Lincoln gaming center the affable
and smiling bright smiling Bryce
remained humble I can't say that I'm a
superhero we said working the controller
like an extension of his body I can be
beat those bold enough to challenge him
weren't so lucky one by one while
playing Soul Calibur - which is another
game their video characters were
decapitated eviscerated and without
mercy bye-bye Bryce's on-screen
alter-ego I'm getting bored Bryce said
and just as he won game after game blind
since birth
when his optic nerve didn't connect
because of LIBOR disease Brice honed his
video skills over the years through
patient and not so patient playing
memorizing key joystick operations and
moves in certain games while asking lots
of questions paying particular attention
to audio cues he worked his way up from
games such as space invaders and
asteroids into modern combat games I
guess I don't know how I do it really
Bryce said as he continued playing while
facing away from the screen facing away
from the screen it's beyond me that's
what I'm just quoting him Bryce knows
this much he started playing at home and
he was about seven he enjoyed playing he
enjoyed trying to play but he wasn't
very good at first said his father Larry
but he just kept trying he broke a lot
of controllers when the questions of
broken controllers comes up Bryce
flashes a smile in just shrugs I used to
have quite a temporary said me and
controllers didn't get along very well
now they're just now we get along just
fine
while playing Soul Calibur - Bryce
worked his way through the introductory
screens with ease knowing exactly what
to click to start the game he wanted he
rarely asked for help once the game
started he didn't need any help how do I
move an exasperated ponent Ryan O'Banion
asked while doing battle which his
character was frozen in place you can't
Bryce answered before finishing him off
that's what happens it's why I don't
play him O'Banion's said after his blood
spattered character's corpse vanishes
from the screen now Bryce became so how
Bryce became so good as a mystery to his
father he just sat there and he tried
and tried until he got it right Larry
melon said he can't ever complain to me
or anyone else about how hard it was
Bryce hangs out any chance he gets at
the dogtags gaming center in Lincoln
opened last month every now and then
someone will come in and think that he
can't that he that he can beat the bot
that he that he can beat the blanket
that attitude doesn't faze Brian I'm
challenge I challenge I'll challenge
them maybe if I feel like a challenge
you said displaying and Infectious
confidence i freak people out by playing
by playing facing backwards there's
nothing like there's nothing he likes
better than playing video games he would
be a senior in high school next year
after graduation he plans a year off
because he wants a break from school
and when he goes to college he wants to
study what else in video game design
this is just an extreme example but I
think a really good one that all change
is a function of desire if you want it
bad enough you'll find a way to do it if
you want to be able to think of
probabilities because you want to be
consistently successful you will find a
way to do it I'm going to give you ways
but what I'm saying is that you will
find a way if you don't then it's that
simple you won't it's like almost every
what might the traders when I was doing
coaching the traders that I worked with
fell into the two basic categories and
there almost wasn't anybody in between
the first category would be traders who
are already consistently successful they
already knew how to win and what they
wanted was fine tuning so they'd go to a
trading coach like myself to find ways
to find some really creative ways let's
say to fine tune fine-tune themselves
where they can actually make more money
than what they were already making and
then the other category was desperation
and I'll do anything
they all do anything the everyone in
between no way and even they all do
anything wasn't always sincere sometimes
it was just lip service
change is also a function of the degree
to which we change is also a function of
the clarity of your intent in other
words you could have the desire but your
intent has to be really clear because
when you think about the whole concept
of changing which are really saying is
that I'm willing to let go of a certain
portion of my identity in a way of some
part of myself that you know I obviously
operate it out up for X number of years
or months or whatever put it maybe put a
lot of energy into and you got to be
willing to let that go is it even
possible to change a belief how about it
is it possible to change a belief I mean
it happens all the time does it not is
there anybody in the room who did not
grow up by this is this is just a simple
example a simple illustration is there
anybody in the room who did not grow up
with it with a belief in Santa Claus
that most everybody did just an example
if you believed at some point in your
life in Santa Claus where's that belief
now what happened to it what happened to
that portion of your identity because if
we are all children if we're all four
and five years old and someone knocked
on that door and said Santa Claus is out
in the lobby we'd probably be jumping
over each other to get over there to get
there right and it was that belief the
energy inside of that belief would
compel us to express ourselves in a
particular way
a way that was consistent with the
belief if I believed in Santa Claus and
someone said and gave me information
said Santa Clauses in the lobby I'm
gonna be I'm gonna be jumping over these
tables to get there as a four-year-old
now as an adult someone knocked on the
door and said Santa Claus in the lobby
I'm sure I just took just ignore me
where did the my belief in Santa Claus
go what happened to it
yeah I don't know the underlie mean
really I don't I can't say that I know
the underlying dynamics of how that
energy got transformed but I can say it
doesn't exist inside of my mental
environment any longer in a way that
would compel me to express myself like I
did believe in Santa Claus and noble
words there's no more energy there I can
remember when I did believe it I could
say to myself oh yeah there was you know
there was something there's something or
maybe there's something there even now
but not enough to say not enough for me
to go running out into the lobby you can
say before you walked in here that you
might have had a real strong belief that
whatever you use to determine your edge
gave you that edge on a trade by trade
basis in other words I wouldn't be
putting on this trade if I didn't think
I was right now you can say to yourself
are you willing to let that go the only
way you're going to be willing to let it
go to even generate the desire to let it
go is if you're really clear about your
intent hopefully I've given you enough
insight to be really clear about your
intent as to why you might want to let
this go because it's just going to
create frustration if you like trading
on a random basis then great then stay
on a trade by trade basis then trade
randomly because it is fun you'll win
you'll have winning streaks but I can
assure you I can't assure you without a
shadow of a doubt that you trade
randomly and you are setting yourself up
for catastrophic losses because anything
you do could result in a win and most of
the things people end up doing are just
the kind of things that set themselves
up for catastrophic loss because
inappropriate you are reinforcing
inappropriate behaviors on a train when
you trade randomly on a trade by trade
basis you are reinforcing inappropriate
behaviors those inappropriate behaviors
namely are not predefined in your risk
is the biggest one you get into a trade
you don't predefined your risk and you
win you're going to do it again you're
going to do it again until you get hit
with it without with
huge loss and sometimes those are really
hard to recover from in fact for most
people they're almost impossible not you
can't it's just that you don't have the
resources for nor do they have the the
desire the inclination to do it they
just walk away are you
relatively clear about why you would
want to do this why you'd want to go
from a trade by trade to a series of
trades perspective sincerity say you
need to desire you need the clarity and
you need the sincerity
it can't be lip service it has to be
real it has to be authentic as a matter
of fact I'm going to say to you that
based on my experience if you're clear
if the desire is there its genuine the
clarity of your purpose is there it son
conflicted and so the sincerity is there
it will virtually happen automatically
that is the technique for change what
most people the problem is is that with
most people it takes pasta it takes
usually a series let's say it takes
using various techniques that are
available that have been you know that
have been created and thought up that
over a period of years they finally get
to the point where they're come they had
the the real desire they have the
clarity and the real sincerity is there
and once all those are in place the
change happens automatically and they
would think that it happened over a
period of years using techniques but the
reality is it just clicked into that
just finally the whole thing clicked
into that that one point where it's all
there like the cut that like the straw
that broke the camel's back I mean a
good example would be about what I'm
talking about in terms of how clear you
have to be in some cases because some of
the energy that you want to move out in
terms of a conflicting or dysfunctional
belief it could be really strong energy
I mean you know there could be pretty
substantial when you think about it I
mean there are traders that I worked
with many years ago especially that
we're really I mean hard hard-core
technicians I mean these are really
hardcore guys that just you know I'm not
even gonna mention the techniques they
use but you know it's like well I gave
like Elliott Wave casualties I mean
there were there were guys that were
just you know there's a time in the in
the late 80s and early 90s where a lot
of my off the floor traders were what I
call Elliott Wave casualties and you
know because these are guys would just
you know who love to analyze and you
know when you start with it you start
when they start understanding the
difference between analysis and
execution and also the underlying
dynamics of the market it's like it's
like they had to get to a point where
the realization that they'd spent ten
years or eight years and thousands or
tens of thousands of dollars on analysis
and workshops and seminars when I mean
when none of it was there very little of
it was really necessary I mean they had
to get reconciled all that stuff and
that wasn't an easy thing to do that was
an easy thing to let go of it wasn't an
easy thing to say okay it was alright
you know though I know what I need to
know now and you know but how do you
know what real clarity of intent is
imagine yourself being held underwater
and as your air starts to run out second
by second it gets to the point where you
believe that if you don't get a breath
of air
right now you're gonna drown that is a
point at which every fiber of your
mental being is aligned is aligned 100%
with your desire for that next breath of
air there's no conflict there's no
hesitation there isn't anything that
argues inside of you for anything else
other than that next breath of air if
you want to make money bad enough in
other words if you want to be want to be
able to make the kind of income that you
can rely on as a trader then your desire
to switch to this series of trades
approach has to be greater than any
resistance that you might have to stay
in a trade by train approach does this
make sense
degree of conviction I just basically
gave you that to the you know the how
much energy is behind your desire energy
moves prices in the market I mean what
moves prices an imbalance in conviction
what its conviction imply conviction
implies energy energy I am NOT going to
bid a price up to a next highest level
unless I think I know what the hell I'm
doing and that I can at the market I can
make the market go further or someone
else is going to come in and help me out
I have to have conviction to do the
opposite of what it takes to make money
meaning by high instead of by low or
sell low instead of sell high
my conviction in the future has to be
greater than the guy on the other side
of the trade conviction moves prices
conviction will move energy inside your
mental environment
focus thought will move energy out of
dysfunction bullet dysfunctional beliefs
and that's basically what we're talking
about we're talking about clarity of
intent desire that is focused thought
you know exactly where you want to go
you want to get to the point where you
believe that there's a random
distribution between wins and losses
that anything can happen that you don't
need to know what's going to happen next
to make money and that's the big one I
don't need to know what's going to
happen next to make money if you
understand the benefits of installing
those beliefs inside your mental
environment as a core component of your
trading personality then you will find a
way to do it I'm gonna give you away but
self-discipline self-discipline I define
as as simply making a conscious
commitment to pay attention to what you
are thinking saying or doing in
relationship to what you're trying to
accomplish in any given moment in other
words if for an example I have a goal or
a desire or an objective a desire to
transform myself into someone who could
think like a professional trader someone
who thinks in a series of trades
perspective someone who believes in the
random distribution between wins and
losses in my series and I and I also
know that you know I I may have any
number of conflicting beliefs that I've
acquired over the years that say
otherwise but say you know even though
I'm aware of the benefits of this
there's all these other beliefs that say
this isn't true this is not who this is
not who I am this is who I am right here
this guy okay yeah he seems to be making
a lot of sense up here but you know
something this is who I am you want to
transform yourself into someone who
thinks this you can use self discipline
as a technique which is simply my
objective is a think in a series of
trades perspective start monitoring your
thoughts your words or your actions to
see that they're consistent with
what it is that you want to accomplish
and then simply purposefully refocus
when you find out that you're doing
saying doing or thinking something
that's opposite or not not consistent
with what you desire and just constantly
refocus eventually get to the point
where you are that person a real good
example of employing self discipline is
back in the late 70s I decided I want to
become a runner and I can't tell you why
I could I don't remember the reason why
I just got it my brain that I want to do
it now back when I was a kid in high
school in college I was very active
played a lot of sports but in the you
know from that point on my lifestyle was
such that I ended up becoming somewhat
of a slug and I say a slug just you know
I watched a lot of my primary vocation
of them working was watching TV and so
when I decided that you know I wanted to
become a runner you know what I do I
went out and Rand could I found out that
I couldn't I mean him I said couldn't
and I literally couldn't I was shocked
and astounded that's how hot a shape I
was I couldn't run two blocks and so you
know I went out the next day you really
could run two blocks again oh my god and
then I didn't run again for probably six
months and so so when I ran again at
least had enough enough desire to compel
me to run more than a couple of days and
and something in and I found something
out is that is that I was amazed how
fast I how fast your body adapts and
improves and so that gave me a lot of
encouragement because you know I ran a
couple of times I ran the third and
fourth time and it's like I ran so much
further like the fourth you know what's
third or fourth time I'm thinking that
gave me a lot of encouragement to think
okay I can do this and so I set this
goal for myself that this was like in
May I remember in May of 1979 or 1778 I
really don't remember anyway but I set
this goal for myself that I wanted to be
able to run five miles by the end of the
summer and at the time it seemed
insurmountable it really did it didn't
seem like it was even remotely possible
to me
but I thought that was my goal and so I
went out and being kind of a methodical
person I
out and I bought a journal a running
Journal and a stopwatch and of course
the running shoes and all this kind of
good stuff and so I set out to set up to
just start running and immediately ran
into a set of obstacles and those
obstacles had to do with like it wasn't
a part of my identity because every time
I said okay I'm gonna go and go running
well can't we go run well what do you
think happened all these conflicting and
competing thoughts flooded my brain like
okay it's too hot it's too cold I ran
three or four days ago nobody I know
none of my friends are doing this you
know my crane and the biggest one of
course was I'll go after this program
and of course I never went so I would
say that out of all the times that I
when I said I am going I want to run I
would say that I managed to actually get
my shoes on and get out the door maybe
30% of the time okay and and but that
30% of time I was like I was improving
okay
and and you know and I was actually
getting further and further and getting
encouraged but at but I realized as as
as I could run foot run further and
further like I was up to a mile maybe or
a mile a quarter or something because I
feel III marked it all off in terms of
like every half mile kind of thing of
the course that I did so I realized that
that I was getting so enthused over the
fact that I was even getting that far
that I thought I needed a mechanism to
get the five miles because I thought I'd
quit well I mean I thought I quit is
that if I got the two miles that was so
far beyond what I thought I could ever
do anyway that what would compel me to
go to five and so I don't know why I
thought that way but that's what I did I
really did
so I established what I called the five
mile rule and the five mile rule was if
I managed to get through all my
conflicting and competing thoughts and
if I managed to get through those and
actually get my shoes on and get outside
and take one step forward that I had to
always run at least one step further
than I did the time before and
knew what that was because I kept the
journal I knew exactly where I stopped
so my rule was I always had to go I
could go more than one step but I had to
be at least one step and what I found
and this was really interesting because
what I found is that there was a
threshold there was a certain threshold
point at which in which you know all the
conflicting and competing thoughts went
away and it was like there I just became
I became a runner it was like I didn't
have to I didn't have to force myself to
go out and run anymore I actually felt
compelled to run and in a sense what I
did was create a new sense of identity
like some people might call it a habit
or whatever I just call her a new sense
of identity I actually established a
belief that said I established a belief
that said I am a runner that's who I am
you see it's like it's like it was
people then my friends and family they
all thought that I was really
disciplined because see because that's
what I say about that most people think
discipline is a personality
characteristic I don't define it that
way at all I've defined it is simply a
technique for change because when we see
somebody doing something that we can't
do that we'd like to do but we have a
problem with it we just naturally think
that they have the same kind of problems
and that they're being disciplined and
doing it and that's not the case at all
if you're doing something effortlessly
it's because it's who you are there was
a threshold point like I said where
we're all the conflicting energy just
completely dissipated and instead of me
having to say consciously say to myself
oh I'm gonna go out and run I actually
felt compelled to run then I got no I
got to the five miles and then I got to
the point where I was running so much
that I actually had to establish a
corollary belief to learn how to listen
to my body because there were days where
my body was basically saying hey this is
not a good day
and give yourself a rest and that had to
be alright but for a while it wasn't
because when you start injuring yourself
then you know you're overdoing it so I
actually had to establish a belief that
it was all right not to run so it went
from went from conflicting and competing
thoughts to this is who I am and now
it's effortless completely effortless
there's there's no conflict at all
that's what you're going to have to
learn well that's what you're going to
learn how to do with your trading you're
going to learn how to put on a sample
size of trades where it becomes
completely effortless where there's no
conflicting you're competing thoughts
about what it is that you're doing and
why you're doing it it wouldn't even
occur to you not to make it wouldn't
even occur to you to make the kind of
mistakes that you typically make now
that's what you want to do you want to
get to the point where it doesn't even
occur to you it doesn't even enter your
brain does everybody understand that
example
like I said when you when you realize
that you're not appropriately focused on
your objective meaning you notice that
you're either thinking saying or doing
something that's inconsistent with what
you're trying to accomplish
you deliberately refocus your attention
on the object of your goal just do the
best you can okay so so basically like I
said this whole section this last
section is is giving you steps and
techniques for evolving into a
professional traders mindset so what you
want to do is you want to resolve
andalusia yourself my desire is to be a
certain way so that I can make a
consistent income from my training
something I can rely on so I resolved to
stop analyzing or trying to figure out
if the current opportunity to put on a
trade is going to work resolved to stop
doing that and when you find yourself
doing it consciously we focus your
thoughts that analyzing is not
beneficial in any way as the passive
technical trader you are dependent on
other the behavior of the traders to
make you you make your trade a winner
and you are using a mathematical formula
or price pattern to predict what they
will do math formulas or price patterns
don't know the intentions objectives or
reasons why the individual traders who
are capable of moving prices behave the
way they do as a result you will almost
never know the real reason why any
particular trade worked or not there's
nothing to analyze there's just nothing
to analyze nothing there was a back in
back when I was in you know commercial
casualty sales there was a sales course
that I bought by zigzagging everybody
but I was the executor is okay and there
was a part of this part of this sales
course where Zig Ziglar talking about
the exact right moment to ask a closing
question to close the sale and you know
and I said he and and you know who's
trying to get people to understand when
that right moment is and when you know
where you're at that right moment Zig
Ziglar pause and there was silence and
then he screamed shut up
he screams out much louder than that
shut up the first person who talks to
loses in other words when you ask that
closing question as a salesman shut up
and don't say a word because if he said
the first one who talks lose and that
was a truth that worked I found when I
felt compelled to talk before he did I
didn't get the sale and when I was able
to keep my mouth shut and let them talk
first I did what I'm saying to you is
that when you get a signal from your
methodology stop thinking there's
nothing to think about there's nothing
to think about
do you understand why I said that just
put on the train there's absolutely
nothing to think about
just put the train on
so you resolved to stop analyzing okay I
resolve I'm gonna I'm gonna analyze
anymore when I get a signal I'm gonna
stop thinking resolve to learn the skill
of trading without fear
in other words manager expectations by
discarding the trade by trade approach
in a favor of a series of trades
approaches what we've been talking about
for the last half an hour the pitfalls
of a trade by trade perspective anything
you do for any reason can result in a
winning trade the problem is many of the
things that you could do that results in
a winning trade could reinforce trading
behaviors that could lead to a
catastrophic loss losing streaks can
usually cause one's attitude to
deteriorate into a negative spiral when
you trade and trade by trade perspective
from a trade by trade perspective you
are making a choice to pick what you
think is an edge out of all the other
possible trades you could have picked in
essence you are saying I am picking this
trade because I think it's going to work
when you trade in a trade by trade
perspective you can't help but think you
know it's going to happen next because
you are picking trades that you only
picking trades that you think are going
to work and therefore you your
expectations automatically will not be
in line with the realities of the market
from its perspective is therefore have a
threat will have the potential to define
and interpret market information in a
threatening way therefore causing your
perception of that information be all
out of whack and you're gonna end up
trading in very things you want to avoid
which is lose and make money or losing
and and be wrong you guys with me on
this the reality is that a rational
level you don't know if any trade is
going to work because you never know for
sure who's participating and what their
intent is you're guessing see you know
what you know what traders is an
educated guess this is what we do as
traders edge got an edge you cated guess
that means probabilities you're making
an educated guess you've got the
probabilities in your favor that's all
we're doing here
with a specific expectation of the
outcome any market information that
doesn't conform to what you expect will
be perceived as threatening you will be
trading with fear if you win you think
you're right and if you lose you think
you're wrong in either case you'll be
setting yourself up to make a trading
err on the next trade just think about
what I just said regardless of what
happens if you're right or you've even
or if you're wrong in either case you're
setting yourself up to make a trading
error on the next trade because our
minds have the natural tendency to
connect the past with the present if the
trade was a winner
in other words if you're training in a
trade by trade perspective and you think
you were right because you won in other
words whatever reason you use the market
seemed to validate that reason we know
now that that just is not the case if
the trade was a winner we're susceptible
to on the next trade not pre defining
the risk well the last one was a winner
I knew for that reason I knew what was
happening therefore the risk doesn't
exist not letting ourselves get stopped
out of a loser jumping the gun because
you're anticipating the signal over
trading our position sighs not booking
any profits because you think it's gonna
go on forever is this making sense to
everybody if the trade was a loser
you're susceptible to not pre defying
the risk because you're gonna gather all
the information that's necessary to make
sure it's not gonna be a loser this time
otherwise I wouldn't be putting it on
right you're gonna analyze it to death
you're gonna hesitate get in late or not
get in at all take profits too soon or
revenge trading by not booking any
profits in other words whatever the
markets giving you ain't enough I gotta
have more the last trade was a loser I
gotta have more
the benefits of a series of trains
perspective you know exactly what
behavior serve your purpose and what
behaviors do not you cannot trade in a
series of trades perspective with a
trading plan and not know exactly what
behaviors will serve your purpose and
what behaviors will not because
everything is planned out you either
fall in your plan and you're not but the
point is everything is planned you are
not picking individual trades therefore
no one trade has any more or any less
significance than the other the next
trade this trade they're all just trades
none of them have any more or any less
significance you will gain a sense of
freedom to flow in and out of your
trades without conflict because you are
not living or dying on the outcome of
any particular trade by reducing the
number of variables you will be learning
what works and what doesn't by truly
accepting that the outcome of this trade
can be different than whatever happened
the last time you are positively
managing your expectations now think
about what I just said by truly
accepting what does it mean to truly
accept it means that there's no other
part of your identity or consciousness
that isn't conflict with accepting the
fact genuinely accepting the fact that
this trade could have a different
outcome than the last one
if this laughs the last trade was a
winner it means that this trade could
have a different outcome it could be a
loser
if the last trade was a loser it means
that this trade could have a different
outcome it could be a winner you see our
minds don't feel like there's anything
wrong with you by thinking in the
previous way because our minds are wired
to think that way our minds are
literally wired to connect the two
that's why it's so difficult for many
people to break through into this into
this ability to think in probabilities
and to break into the this threshold of
consistency is because we're working in
some cases against natural wiring it is
natural for our minds to say if this is
what happened the last time if the
circumstances are identical or similar
this time then the same
things going to happen what I'm saying
to you is that you have to you have to
you have to step into an exercise where
you consciously disconnect the two in
other words your whole purpose is to
disconnect this now moment from what
happened the last time because there is
no connection the reality is there's no
connection that's the truth you just
can't let your mind think that there is
a connection there is no connection
between what's going between the outcome
of this now moment opportunity with what
happened the last time even though the
variables that are getting you into this
trade or identifying this opportunity
are identical that creates quite a
paradox for our brains okay that's why
people can understand the nature of
probabilities they can understand them
but they can't function from that
perspective you have to train your mind
to function from that perspective that's
what separates everyone from the pros
okay you have to train your mind to
disconnect don't let yourself think that
there's any connection between now and
what happened the last time because the
reality is there is none there really
it's it I don't care how identical it
looks
you can use the same mathematical
formulas and and and and criteria and
those formulas that apply to market data
and come up with these patterns but I
guarantee you the traders that are
operating in the market now are not the
same traders identically at least not
the same traders as the ones that
operated the last time therefore there's
no possible way that there could be a
connection between now and then there's
no possible way
when you disconnect when you make that
disconnection okay you won't perceive
market information as threatening you'll
eliminate the potential to make a
trading error and you will be aspiring
to trade without fear in a carefree
state of mind now that you understand
that your technical methodology does not
tell you what will happen next on a
trade by trade basis in this section I
will take you through a step-by-step
process that will integrate the
principles of consistency as a
functional part of your trading
personality up to this point we've
talked about how we get into this
mindset about resolving to think in
certain ways but this is this is
learning how to disconnect in other
words learning how to circumvent that
natural mechanism in our mind that
automatically connects things connect
similar events this now moment
opportunity there's not more an event
with something that's in our mind as a
memory if there's enough so you know if
there's enough similarity there it'll
it'll tap us into a state of mind that's
identical to our memories as opposed to
what might be available in the now
moment which may be very different then
you know may very different than what we
think that it is I mean that's where you
know that's where we have relationship
problems communication problems you know
it's like it's this this this this
connect mechanism really does cause us a
lot of problems it really does because
in many cases a lot of the pain and
heartache that we feel in our lives is
not connected at all with what's really
happening in that moment but you
wouldn't be able to convince ourselves
or no one would be able to convince us
or wouldnt be able to convince ourselves
that what we weren't experiencing in
that moment wasn't real because what we
were experiencing was the energy it was
the the fear the confidence the
dissatisfaction the betrayal you know
the energy of it is is real that you
can't say this is not what's happening
but the problem is that the
interpretation of the information that
tapped us into the state of mind and the
connection that our mind automatically
may
from this moment to some memory in the
past could be like I said completely
erroneous we knew when you look at when
you look at the very nature of the
universe and the way it exists there is
no possible way that any moment could
ever duplicate itself no two moments are
ever alike ever and could never be
because if you just look at it if you
look at physical reality is constructed
of atoms and molecules and those atoms
and molecules are in constant motion
they are in constant motion for two
moments to ever duplicate themselves it
means that all the atoms of all the
molecules would have to be in the exact
same spot they were in some previous
moment right now and ain't going to
happen so when you really get right down
to it every moment is really unique
every moment in the environment is
really unique but our minds don't
process information that way every
moment in the market is genuinely and
truly unique but our minds don't process
it that way we have to train our minds
to process it that way if we want to
make ourselves the casino if we want to
put ourselves in the situation where we
are the casino then we've got to get our
minds to process information in a
different way Richard have had a comment
that I thought was really good we tend
to associate with a winning trade or a
losing trade that when we do suffer a
loss oh we tend to think of ourselves as
a loser instead of that is just a trade
that turned out a loss right and when we
so when we do get a winning trade we
think well I'm a winner
so you get caught up in the emotion of
it instead of looking at it
that was a bad trade this was a good
trade it has nothing to do with whether
or not you're a win or a loser
Richard have you ever played the slots
no never
well yes why couldn't you say yes like
not anymore because no say no did I say
have you ever played the slots yes sir
okay
when when the tumblers didn't come up
with any kind of a jackpot did you think
of yourself as a loser
no why because I know that the slot
machine is rigged against me well okay
but did you think there's any
possibility of ever winning
I absolutely because I did get some
virtually ended up with an empty pocket
but in other words you you you walked
into it with a belief that on any
particular time that you push the button
that there's a random outcome correct
you knew that right and so therefore you
didn't think of yourself as a loser
correct not have you ever thought of
yourself as a loser when he had a losing
trade yes and what would be the reason
because I lost no because you didn't
because you didn't believe that there
was a random outcome right if you
believed if someone told you from the
very beginning that that whatever
outcomes that you experienced from any
methodology that you picked to define an
edge were random would you be thinking
about this completely differently makes
a big difference yeah so nobody wouldn't
have the same emotional problems that
that you might have with the kind of
errors and and and and everything else
that goes along with trading with fear
if someone would have just said to you
you know what there's a random outcome
now even though it's a pattern and it
doesn't make sense and it creates a
paradox for our minds we've got a
pattern that produces a random outcome
if you believed that there was a random
outcome where would the emotions come
from they would go they would certainly
diminish it well there wouldn't be I
don't think they'd be anywhere at all
with anyway yes no I'm saying if you
just right from the very start
what would you have to associate with if
it's a random outcome that you know that
you're not wrong right great so there
wouldn't be anything to associate the
outcome with any kind of interpretation
that that could end up causing you to
feel some sort of emotional pain you're
right
all we're trying to do is get to that
place now even though you've had all
this backlog of experience telling you
otherwise that's where we want to get to
how are we going to get there we're
going to create an exercise nor the five
mile rule okay we're going to do we're
going to do the five mile rule
in a training exercise why are we going
to do the exercise remember we have to
be have to have clarity of intent what
is our desire our desire is to become a
consistently successful trader one where
I can I can generate an income I can
rely on okay and so we are going to
actually trade for a new reason we're
going to stay focused in the process of
trading as opposed to the outcome the
typical trader is obsessed with the
outcome of a trade the professional
trader is focused in the process of
trading and letting the outcomes take
care of themselves as a matter of fact
the best traders that I've ever
encountered love the process of trading
the typical trader on the other hand
either has no awareness of the actual
process of trading or really doesn't
like the process of trading but they're
addicted to or obsessed with the outcome
so you have to make up your mind and
everyone in this room at some point in
their lives for some reason has decided
to make up their mind about something
and when you have you've got results
everyone has I know everyone has had
that experience you've made up your mind
with so much desire so much clarity of
intent and and with with absolute
sincerity that you've got the desired
result so I'm saying that if you make up
your mind to trade for a new reason the
reason is the acquisition of skills as
opposed to the outcome or how much money
you're making you will acquire those
skills and then you'll find that the
outcomes just take care of themselves
if you've paper traded or tested your
methodology to the point where you have
confidence that you have something that
can generate consistent results then you
can do this exercise if you haven't then
you're going to have to do that first
you're going to have to you're going to
have to plan your trades in other words
you're going to have to take your
methodology and determine a given set of
rigid variables because what we're going
to do is set up a training exercise with
just a simple twenty five trade or
twenty trade sample size in other words
what you're going to say is that I am
willing to invest in the development of
these skills the skill of learning to
trade without fear learning to think in
probabilities because when you learn to
think of probability as a fear will go
away and so what I essentially have to
do is convince myself I have to step in
to purposefully step into an experience
where I am convinced where I literally
convinced myself that these principles
are true now they sound true to you they
might resonate as the truth but you have
to keep in mind that you might have a
backlog of of any number of experiences
that that would support beliefs that
would argue otherwise because I could
say to you that if I set up or you set
up an exercise where you said okay I've
got a particular set of variables that
when they appear in the market that is
my edge and that my edge will produce
let's say even 60% winning trades and
you don't even have to have 60% you're
gonna have 50% and still make consistent
money as long as what you have to risk
to find out if it works is you know a
third or a half of what you normally get
when the front when the trade does work
in terms of profits but if we set this
exercise up so that there aren't that
there's no wiggle room there is no
wiggle room what I mean by wiggle room
is that the variables the criteria that
you use are absolutely rigid black and
white
they either they're either present or
they are not that's the only decision
you have to make are the in other words
if you do it and you do it in terms of
lights whatever lights you're going to
use whatever timeframe the lights you're
going to use in whatever timeframe they
are either on or they're not and if
they're on you are obligated to take the
trade and what you're going to say to
yourself is that in this whatever
whatever criteria or a plan that you set
up is I am NOT going to take just the
next trade I am going to take the next
twenty trades I'm going you are
committing yourself to taking the next
twenty trades of the occurrence of your
edge you will know in advance based on
testing and paper trading exactly the
optimum amount that you have to risk in
other words what your risk is on each
trade it is not going to be a very it's
not going to be a varying amount it's
going to be a specific amount whether
it's in terms of dollars or distance
there will be a specific amount so that
you know exactly how much each trade is
going to possibly potentially could cost
you and it should really be set up as a
rigid profit profit potential - in other
words I don't want you making subjective
decisions it's about how far how far
you're gonna let the market go in your
favour
so if you can you can get a set of
variables well let's say you even two to
one or even one to have to want one and
a half to one meaning that that if I
have to risk one point of something even
if it's let's say in stocks of it I have
to risk a dollar to make that that my
particular my particular set of
variables my entry variables will get me
into a trade where if I risk a buck I'll
get two dollars sixty percent of the
time or fifty percent of the time then
that's what you do you do do two to one
there are trading methodologies that can
be even the opposite you can even go
two to one here meaning you could risk
two to get one but in these cases the
trade has to be the trade has to be 80
or 90 percent correct you could do it
any percentage as you want as long as it
is fixed there is no regal wiggle room
there is no subjective decision-making
what so ever am i really clear about
this
there is no subjective decision-making
whatsoever go ahead the big things in
expectancy are in trading with risk
reward ratio is you don't know which
trade is going to be the winning trade
correct and typically you you try to let
your winning trade get stopped out on
your winning trades but what you're
saying to us for this exercise is that
we take a fixed stop understand the
fixed risk but a fix essential profit
stop you know what if you can set it up
as a trailing stop if you can set your
trailing stops up four you're not making
any kind of the subjective decision you
can do that too long if you're
sophisticated enough to do that then yes
okay most most traders in these
situations are not that's why I make it
real easy okay as long as long as it's
as long as you're not making any
decisions so in other words what you're
saying is that if the market goes X
number of points in my favor I move my
my trailing stop up to a certain
percentage below where the market is
right now and you don't move that unless
you get stopped out it moves up another
gradient or whatever and another one I
think standard like deviation beyond
yeah okay whatever you're using okay
yeah if you can if you can if you could
do that that's fine
I just want it I just want all the very
old variables to be completely and
absolutely fixed okay and then you've
fixed all these variables and so you say
to yourself I'm going to take the next
20 trades not just the next one but the
next 20 no matter what
no matter what now that means that you
have to be prepared based on the amount
that you have to risk you have to be
prepared to take 20 losses in a row the
likelihood of that happening are is
about as remote as getting 20 wins in a
row
but the point is is that the dollar
value of the risk of each trade
multiplied by 20 you have to be able to
afford so you've got to set it up that
way you've got to set it up so that you
can afford the dollar value of the risk
of taking 20 losing trades in a row
because your so what you're saying to
yourself if taking the risk of taking
the 20 trades in a row losing 20 trades
in a row based on the amount of shares
that you trade so for example if if the
standard amount of shares that you trade
would say that you know but if I had
lost 20 trades in a row based on how
much I've got a risk is going to be
$5,000 you say to yourself you know what
I don't want to spend $5,000 on this
then don't but say I'm willing truly
willing to spend let's say $1,000 then
set it up where the the amount of
contracts or shares that you trade
correspond to adding each one up where
it comes up to $1,000 even if it means
is trading 10 shares at a time go down
to a level where it's you're completely
comfortable with the dollar value you
have to be completely comfortable and
then when you get an occurrence of your
edge put the trade on and see what
happens and if it turns out the booty
would be a winner you think oh hey yeah
mark Douglas a good take this this is
alright okay yeah so this one turns out
to be a winner and maybe this one turns
out to be a winner and maybe well this
one's a loser you think okay I can
handle that and this one's a loser oh
and this one's a loser now we've got
three losers in a row I have rarely met
a trader who doesn't have a problem with
the next trade after three losers in a
row
you you you made the commitment to take
every single trade when the next one
comes up and your mind is screaming no
it's a loser remember how our minds are
wired to think our minds are wired to
think that way but that is not the truth
the truth is your methodology the
mathematical formula does not know what
the outcome of that trade is going to be
and neither do you
you've got to take it any way you can
see and when these occurrences when you
can when you purposefully put yourself
into a situation where you're
confronting these conflicting beliefs
because that's what's rearing its head
this is any different than me saying I
want to go run and then and then you
know after that program or it's too cold
it's too hot it's raining whatever it's
the exact same thing you put the trade
on anyway and it turns out to be a
winner you are you are convincing
yourself that you don't know what's
going to happen next because you created
an experience that directly that wasn't
that directly it can counter dix what
you thought was true you actually
created an experience that directly
countered NYX what you thought was true
and the more of these you run into and
the more times you do it
all of a sudden you're not thinking the
old way anymore
you are truly and genuinely learning how
to think in probabilities you are
integrating thinking of probabilities as
a core part of your training personality
you may understand the nature of
probabilities but now you're being able
to function from a probabilistic
perspective because what you're going to
do is you're going to do this exercise
until you can do it flawlessly you are
going to do this exercise and you do the
first one and if you don't execute your
trades completely flawlessly then do it
again now at the end of
sample size if you don't like the
outcome if you don't like the results
meaning the amount of money that you
made or even loss for that matter
because that's possible
you don't like the bottom line you can
tweak your variables you just can't do
it in the middle of a sample size if you
want to change your variables at the end
of a sample size you're free to do it
you cannot do it in the middle of one
cannot absolutely cannot you will keep
doing this exercise until when what what
well
yes but there's something else I want to
get until when Wendy when you how do you
know that you're how do you know you've
arrived how do you know you've actually
arrived that you've changed that's right
you can just there's no conflicting
energy anymore it doesn't occur to you
to not do it it doesn't even end of your
brain you don't even get the thought you
get a signal you put on the train
you get a signal you put on the train
it's like then then it's who you are you
guys with me on this
you you managed to actually work through
all that conflicting energy and you've
changed you're a different person
because the competing and conflicted for
conflicting thoughts don't even enter
your consciousness they're not there
anymore because it's not who you are
anymore
any questions about this this is making
sense to everybody if you're really
sincere about wanting to generate a
consistent income you'll do this
exercise and if you're not you won't and
you might not be ready to and that's
alright whenever you're ready you'll do
it
but this will work this will work one
second because you are actively stepping
into an experience where your desire is
to change the way that you think instead
of avoiding the confrontation you are
actually embracing the confrontation big
difference you are embracing the
confrontation because the more that you
embrace it the faster it dissipates go
ahead can you speak a little bit about
their going from paper trading to real
money I know there's a difference and
you would say you were trying a new
strategy or something that you you were
tweaking you would do paper first and
what would you would you consider I mean
if you you would you look at each trades
and if you executed it flawlessly and
and you say you generated money and then
you went to the real money how would you
decide I guess if you lost money to
match my own question here in other
words what would you expect the
transition to be well that's going to
depend on the individual one you're
always going to want a paper trade if
you've got a new set of variables that
you're working with you're always going
to want to paper trade it to the point
where you're confident that that you've
got you can get good results
that doesn't mean you can execute good
results it means that the potential is
there you want to know the potential is
there correct once you know that the
potential is there then you move see the
paper trading partners only to find out
what variables in the market work and
relationship to you know like like
market movement in relationship to the
formula okay now we're working on our
brain okay that's that's the first step
the second step is that is that do I
think in a way that's consistent that I
can extract the maximum potential out of
the methodology that means executed
flawlessly so so what you do is you set
this exercise up in a way that will
dictate it is how much you're
comfortable with if you how much you're
comfortable with the dollar amount of
losing every turn every every single
trade that's how you know how to set it
up that's really key it really is it
means that if you
have to trade one share and you know if
that's all you're comfortable with with
losing based on the dollar value of how
much you have to risk on each trade
that's based on your analysis by the way
then do it do and then and then when
you're cut when you can execute one
share flawlessly over a sample size or
one or two sample sizes then go to ten
shares and see how you do it if you
can't do ten shares comfortably and
flawlessly go back to five you're just
building skills if you stay if you get
your mind out of the out of out of the
money out of the outcome part and focus
on building the skills once those skills
are there you're gonna make all the
money you want that makes sense doesn't
it do this exercise and you won't
believe how things will change until you
actually change and it's just like it'll
be they'll be amazing do the exercise so
there anybody else have any questions
about how to set this exercise up how
long how long you going to do the
exercise if you set it up and do it how
long you gonna do it what's the criteria
I understand how many 20 trades sample
sizes are 25 trade sample size exercises
are you gonna do that's right so there's
no conflicting and competing thoughts
good until you can do it flawlessly to
this until you can do it until it's like
it just a part of who you are it
wouldn't occur to you not to do anything
other than what your rules say it just
wouldn't even occur to you it doesn't
even doesn't even enter your brain
and I guarantee you at that point you
will be thinking in probabilities you
will be trading without fear you will be
trading from a carefree state of mind
that's the payoff
you'll be thinking like a pro
so you want to resolve to focus your
efforts on developing specific trading
skills and consistent profits will
naturally flow as a byproduct of the
mastery of these skills the most
successful traders love the process of
trading whereas a typical trader usually
ignores the process because he's
obsessively focused on the outcome on
these traders that keep saying you know
do the process and you till you do it
perfectly right what are some of tech
Falls I mean when I trade I don't really
think that I'm doing too much wrong so
one curious what all can go wrong on a
trade other than tidying it in wrong all
the things that like all the errors that
I that I mentioned earlier like in turn
up redefining hurry if you're not doing
stuff wrong that's fine you know that's
don't don't don't more it don't that
stuff yeah yeah if you're doing a haul
right and you're doing fine okay I don't
want to give you the impression that
that there has to be anything more there
it's you know
okay resolved to commit the five
fundamental truths about the nature of
training as core beliefs of your trading
personality those five fundamental
truths are anything can happen is that
true or not every moment is unique is
that true okay an edge is nothing more
than an indication of a higher
probability of one thing happening over
another okay is there a random
distribution between wins and losses on
any given set of variables that define
an edge yes absolutely do we need to
know what's going to happen next to
produce a consistent income no you see
so if you find yourself as you're doing
this exercise you know with conflicting
and competing thoughts pay attention to
what you're thinking pay attention to
what you're about to do as a result of
what you're thinking and then refocus on
what you want to believe I want to
believe that anything can happen that
there's a random distribution that I
don't need to know and just stay focused
on on these particular beliefs and do
the best you can and keep on doing it
until it just becomes a part of who you
are it's the right you're absolutely
right it's like a meditation that's
right your mantra put them up on your
wall or by your computer screen
because they're all true continually
really resolved to continually reinforce
a belief in your ability to be a
consistently successful trader by
adopting the traders Creed by the way
these two things are in the discipline
training in the zone what I just though
the five fundamental truths and the
traders Creed are both in training in
the zone the traders Creed I am a
consistent winner in other words
remember the belief that I put up that I
am a runner never that I said when I
actually became a runner that that
belief compelled me to express myself in
a way that was consistent with that
belief well what we want to do is
install a belief that says I am a
consistent winner and the subset beliefs
that you have to have to make this true
will automatically compel you to act or
behave in a way that's consistent with
that belief why are you a consistent
winner because I objectively identify my
edges objectively meaning no
rationalizations justifications are
building cases I know what criteria
defines my edge and it's either present
or it's not I predefined the risk of
every trade wouldn't even think about
getting into a train without doing that
now that doesn't mean because who
brought that up earlier no he's not here
right now that doesn't mean that I
always put a stop in the market but I
trade subjectively that doesn't mean I
actually enter a stop but I guarantee
you that whatever price I picked as my
wrist point I never violate not getting
out at that price the market hits my
price I get out that doesn't mean I've
entered a stop in the market beforehand
but I can do that I don't have a problem
with that it wouldn't even occur to me
not to do otherwise
I'm a consistent winner because I
completely accept the risk I'm willing
to scale back or let go of the edge
meaning I am completely free of conflict
about the amount of money I'm willing to
spend to find out if this trade is going
to work if you're not completely sure or
let's say completely without conflict
about the amount of money that it could
take to find out this trade is going to
work and scale back to a level that
you're comfortable but the important
thing is participate even if you have to
scale back again so like I said one
share at least you're participating at a
level where you've got some money at
risk I act on my edges without
reservation or hesitation I am a
consistent winner because I act on my
edges without reservation or hesitation
I'm a consistent winner because I
continually monitor my susceptibility to
making trading errors
how do I do that I keep journals
I pay myself as the market makes money
available to me I subscribe to a
philosophy of scaling out of positions I
like to divide my position up into
fractions and scale out and quarters or
thirds that way I'm continually making
myself a winner as the market makes
money available I'm extracting money out
of the market because I don't know how
far the markets gonna go in my favour
and what I have is I usually have at
least a quarter or a third on in case it
just does something that you know I
could have never anticipated and by the
time I've got just the last third on or
last quarter on anyway and you know I've
got I've got a trailing stop or you know
at least my place in my mind where I get
out if it retraces back to back tonight
you know not far beyond my entry point
anyway that from that point on and the
last one I never violate these
principles of success what do you think
guys any questions get them now go ahead
do you ever scale in no I didn't know a
lot of lot of traders who do I just I
just don't that's things I don't wanna
say that because I don't doesn't mean
that that I that I don't think it's fine
I just don't have a particular
methodology right scale and that's all I
get in all at once
anything else here's a chance to get on
the DVD come on
don't miss out what's that well we'll
know about that why what do you mean
that do you think well what do you yeah
you don't have to eat you can get to a
you can get to a go ahead yeah never
violate that's the never is it that they
said never say never well you know let's
put it this way you can you can at least
aspire to never violate to violate the
principle yeah that's good but that's a
good point yeah yeah you're making
you're making a good point you really
are I appreciate that you can aspire to
never violate these principles of
success
anything else
let's call it a day
[Music]