Well, the profile would be the following Monday
consolidation Ok this is like an amd
in a broader fractal weekly
accumulation this would be the manipulation
of this low to this High Ok and what we
would be looking for here is the turn so
that it begins its expansion Ok an
accumulation then  an
upward manipulation Tuesday maximum of the week hide of
the week Ok this Hi we would hope that it
is not taken that the entire structure is respected
and we would look for the previs week and low Ok
this like like
this would be the profile that what the
shortenme the  shorten discipline who
are the ones looking for One Kill
are practically looking for the
weekly profile This is the key to ong you look for
the weekly profile you look for where
the maximum low
of the week is likely to form and you look for the objectives that it
would achieve if it were in  the
correct direction in this case because in
a hypothetical case, being bearish, if a
bearish mind were to develop weekly, our Target is the
previews,
we take the last movement of Vela's bodies,
the bulish movement, which was the one that
formed the High of the week
and we project it  to match
the previews Look Joshua here I'm not
taking the highs because it doesn't match the one it
matches me below if I take the
High low and it's okay it's not bad to
do it like this
but since we want a more
achievable goal for example
maybe this  This size is
problematic, for example, where
the two is
towards the previews weekly Love, it may
be problematic in this area as such. That
is, if you have your Take profit in the
two deviations. Imagine that you say,
it's not that I take profits in both
expressions.  always and I put my Take
profit there then you put your Take profit
here but our Target or
high time frame objective of Price as such is the
Imagine that price begins to expand
bearishly it
reaches the previs weekly low and does not reach
your two deviations it reaches the previous one
but  not the deviations then Here you
start to have some setbacks, a
setback to internal is an example Ok
then you no longer managed to pay at the
lowest points
which would be below the previews
weekly low Ok for waiting for the two
deviations that's why it's  What I say is that the
best thing is always to make them match. If
I take Vela bodies, for example, there
are Vela bodies, because
practically at two deviations
you are already paying yourself and at 2.5 if he gives it to you,
by then you have already paid yourself
in the  two deviations
OK But now deviation 2 is closer,
which is where we commonly have
setbacks. So now you have two
objectives where you can pay yourself and I am talking
about achievable objectives Well, that is
theidea,
not to do pirouettes or twists but
simply the closest thing to reaching
[Music]
[Applause]