14:40 what does that number mean to you
for most of you probably doesn't mean
anything at all but you live it every
single day that's the number of minutes
you know 24 hour span of time now most
of you are anticipating some super slide
devilishly named concept or technique to
be released in some ICT video next and I
am here just to kind of like remind you
that are new to this or maybe that
certain person that's been here for
months or maybe years they just can't
find a way to make time if you're
developing trailer this is gonna mean
much more to you because you haven't
been met with the challenges of seeing
where Trading is gonna fit in your life
every single 24 hour span of time can be
broken down into modular components time
management as a trader as a developing
trader a student of the markets is
absolutely paramount because you can
spend a lot of your time doing the wrong
things and doing them at the wrong time
and doing much more than that's
reasonably expected to have a
progressive developmental curve
I want you to think about that 24 hour
span of time and if we were to break it
up into individual components in the
scale 15 minute increments each one of
these boxes would represent one
15-minute span of time out of a 24 hour
period
every four squares across would be
representative of a full one hour span
of time the entire length from top to
bottom would represent 24 hours of time
so with 24 hours at our disposal each
day we're left with the challenge of how
we're going to spend it now for some of
you most of that time is already made up
and it's outside of your hands in terms
of controlling where it is and what
you'll be doing at those specific times
of the day as a trader if you are I'm
using my quotations with fingers blessed
to have the opportunity to be a
full-time trader and deriving your
income from the markets themselves you
are given the freedom to determine where
and when you're going to do your
business hours however for a developing
trader you're plagued with the normal
realistic well pitfalls and barriers of
having a job a family and a life there's
a lot that's been talked about by
mentors teachers educators and such
about trading buy here sell here
you know don't put your stop-loss here
don't use this indicator use that
indicator don't listen to that guy
listen to this guy but far too little
has been spent on how to efficiently use
your time not only as a student but also
as a trader so I want to do a two part
series and this is the
first part but right now I just want you
to take a moment and think how have you
spent the last 24 hours
could you go back through your 24 hour
span of time and fill in each one of
these 15 minute incremental blocks with
what you were doing now it doesn't have
to be a long list or an expose of what
it is and who you're with and what you
were doing exactly but if we made
generalized categories sleep work play
family time food dressing if we kept it
to those simple categories could you go
back for your 24 hour time and law what
you were doing at that specific time of
day if the first block or row represents
1:00 a.m. that first row would be
representative 1:00 a.m. to the next
block of 2:00 a.m. the midpoint of this
grid would be noontime in the afternoon
and then 12:00 a.m. will be the bottom
so it represented the entire 24-hour
span of time I gave the responsibility
of one of my students to fill in their
general day what what they do on the
regular okay and this is actually a new
student so it's not someone that's been
trading for a while or knows how to
trade this is someone that has just
recently came under my tutelage so I
knew I had the opportunity to really get
a ear to the rails if you will
perspective of what the new developing
trader is doing with their time and this
is what they filled in now take a moment
and take in take all this in for every
block there's something recorded for
what they were doing at that specific
time and that duration of time
you can see the multitude is spent
between work and sleep and you also
notice there's a lot of time spent
watching television I'm going to state
this and it'll probably be debated
amongst you all if we were all in a room
it would be a great deal of agreement or
disagreement with what I'm gonna say and
I'm just giving you my opinion no you're
not
obviously held to that as a you have to
do this to succeed
there's the plenty of avenues and
approaches to doing trading or
developing as a trader that would lead
to success it doesn't have to come under
the wings of ICT but I felt inspired by
a few of the new students that just came
under the June enrollment and their
concern is is how are they to manage
their time to be efficient and still be
a active participant of their family and
I guess the best way to do that would be
to like I'm doing here
and I think all of my students
collectively both in the free mentorship
content areas of my forum and under the
private mentorship group those
individuals would I think benefit from a
study like this because it's a practical
it's not a get in here and buy here or
get in here and sell here you're worried
about what the charge of telling you
right now because if you don't master or
control what you're doing with your time
it doesn't matter what you're buying or
selling
you're gonna lose money you're gonna be
worrying about not being able to be
somewhere when you're supposed to be or
you're gonna be focusing on studying
things that aren't really something to
be concerned with at the moment so why
am I doing this particular study I want
every one going into this new week with
this in mind and I think that if you
submit to this exercise it'll be rather
illuminating for most of you you'll see
where you're spending the majority of
your time
and where you have opportunity where
most of the time I have folks say that I
have a lot of content there's a lot of
things to read there's a lot of things
to watch and a lot of things to study
where should I find the time or where
can I find the time I should say to do
all that and every one of us no matter
what you're doing you have time all you
need is one block out of all these
blocks here to represent a 24 hour span
of time you really only need one of them
now if you spend those 15 minutes with a
undisturbed focus really spending just a
small segment of your day number one
it's practical everyone has a life
everyone has a family everyone has
responsibilities some of us have jobs
some of us has businesses some of us
have job search because we're between
jobs so those things are real you have
to make time for them obviously but
there are still opportunities in every
24 hour period of time that everyone
could make time to learn how to do this
do you need a full hour every day no
absolutely not I think if there is an
ideal time representative of what I
think a normal progressive development
curve in terms of how much time per day
I think 30 minutes is Right anything
more than 30 minutes each day is number
one you're not going to retain the
things that you're looking at you're
entertaining yourself so no matter what
you're studying I think that the
workload of everyone's standard day work
family commuting to work commuting back
home from work eating you know doing all
those things and then digesting the TV
which i think is the worst way of
spending anybody's time because you're
being programmed you're programmed to
think the way they want you to think the
media is always doing some kind of
program a that's why it's called TV
programs so if you can find a way to be
honest don't
how to sugarcoat it no one's gonna see
this okay but I'm gonna give you a
template you look at the bottom of this
video in the description there'll be a
link and click on it's a PDF file and
it's a blank worksheet okay and they'll
give you the opportunity to fill in each
day what you did with your time for each
15-minute incremental segment of that
24-hour span Monday through Friday and
Saturday and Sunday 7200 7200 that's how
many minutes there are between Monday
and Friday every single person that has
a job a responsibility a family someone
that's depending on them is spending
those 7,200 hours
pining and working and slaving and
sacrificing those minutes for someone
else's benefit 72 minutes each week
Monday through Friday every one of us
has to spend those 7200 minutes doing
something now
for most of you there was 7200 minutes
are being spent sacrificing your time
for wages you're submitting yourself to
time in exchange for money you're going
to work to benefit someone else's
pockets fulfilling their dreams and
you're just making ends meet
and sometimes they're not meeting which
is reason why you're at a website or
channel like this one because you're
looking to someone else to help you make
those ends meet and find a way outside
of that rat-race 7200 minutes every week
Monday through Friday this is what the
generalized perspective is of the
student that submitted to this whole
process for me all we did was basically
did the same thing every single day he
has set things that they eat every
Monday every Tuesday every Wednesday
Thursday or Friday the things that are
being prepared for dinner or pretty much
predetermined it's a routine folks all
around the world have some measure of a
routine they go through the motions
you're gonna waste a lot of time if you
just go through the motions you're never
gonna leave the rat race if you're stuck
in this rut it's very easy for every one
of us to wake up go through the daily
grind of what's expected of us what's
being demanded of us and we put our
wants and our dreams and our desires
aside because it's distracting getting
away from what we have to do but just
like when you have to go to work you
have a set time you have to report to
work you have set break times
lunch maybe you have 15-minute breaks
around the 10 o'clock hour or the 2
o'clock hour but they're scheduled there
are times that are allotted for you to
be doing or not doing something and when
you subscribe to the idea of working for
a particular company or an employer you
are submitting to that time schedule now
outside of that schedule you have to be
a good steward with your time you have
to take those moments that are available
to you where they are elective the
things that you can do with your own
time now the problem with this own time
definition is some of us have family
some of us have children spouses we have
recreational team sports bowling leagues
pool leagues you have to go to your
lodge things of that nature they also
fall into their own category of allotted
time you're being expected to spend your
time at this function at this amount of
time for this duration of time then you
have wasted time what is wasted time
in my opinion and again this is simply
my perspective on it
I believe that sleep is a wasted amount
of time because you can get away with a
far more amount of time then most people
feel they have to have TV is an absolute
waste of time if you go through this
exercise and you fill in your blocks be
honest if you spend time watching
television record it as such if you have
your special programs that you have to
watch record it and be honest at the end
of the week when you go through all of
the things you've done you're gonna find
that you're spending again most of your
time sleeping and working for someone
else now you're looking at that sleep
time to rest so that way you're prepared
for the amount of time you spend for
work that work is what you submitted to
for an exchange of your time for wages
I'm not saying that that's not required
because most most of us really you have
to have some employment to some degree
okay either you're running your own
company or you're submitting your time
for someone else bottom line is you're
doing it okay and if you have thought
about trading for a living you're really
trying to earn a job you're trying to
learn to earn from a job that you make
your own schedule for but it's still a
job you still have to perform to eat so
if you don't have that in the forefront
of your mind okay cuz a lot of students
come to me with this fairy tale in mind
that it's gonna be magical and it's not
magical and many times it's a lot more
work because you are the one in control
but you start that control with this
time management if you don't identify
where you're wasting your time
you got viously you're not gonna have
any time to devote to development and
study all you're looking for is 150
and block one to start and then
gradually grow into a 30 minute saying a
time for study just because I have a
video that may be an hour long doesn't
mean you have to sit and digest the
entire thing you have to be a good
steward of your time you to spend your
time efficiently spending it in such a
way where the time that you're spending
with the information not only are you
digesting the information but you're
also retaining it because if you're not
retaining it what good is it it's of no
use to you some of you are zoning out
right now thinking this is not a video
for you and that's fine but I'm speaking
to the ones that are really taking this
development cycle serious because if
you're going to invest your time in
yourself it's well it's practical and
responsible for you as the person
seeking to make a positive change to be
sober-minded
about what you're doing with the most
valuable thing in existence to you it's
not money it's not your family it's time
because without time you can't make
money and you can't spend time with your
family think about it the most important
valuable commodity that every one of us
have and not enough of it is time this
individual spends his Monday through
Friday doing this very routine day in
and day out they want to escape this my
question to this particular student was
are they willing to give up all that TV
time because if you take one of those
rows of TV out and replace it with
exercise you'll you'll need and you'll
find that you need far less sleep for
someone that doesn't exercise actively
that they exercise they're gonna think
that they need more sleep time because
they're gonna be more tired the opposite
is true because the sleep that you end
up taking on after you exercise is much
more beneficial to you so the time that
you're asleep your body does all of its
repairs it gets adequate amount at rest
and you can get up and do your name
normal day to day grind you do not need
eight hours of sleep I had one student
come to me and say oh you know I have to
have ten hours of sleep or I just can't
function I asked if the exercises and
the answer was no and what's their diet
McDonald's and Burger King okay you're
poisoning your body and you're not
exercising it so you're going to feel
like you need more sleep because you're
not fueling your body with the proper
amount of exercise stretching
flexibility these are all things that
should be scheduled into your day now
for some of you that have a work
schedule that may be very close to what
you're saying here you're probably
thinking this is know has nothing to do
with trading but it does it absolutely
does because if you are not in the
proper state of mind with a healthy body
that's well rested but not over rested
and you're budgeting your time
efficiently number one you're not gonna
be distracted in your study time because
your son needs to go to that soccer
practice or your wife needs to spend
that amount of time with you and go to
dinner or you have to have that doctor
visit with your your pet you have to
have all these things allotted for now
just because there are a lot of four and
you plan for them it doesn't mean that
it's always gonna fit inside those
little perfect 15-minute blocks
sometimes it eats into another block
sometimes you can finish things although
earlier I want you to use the blocks as
the closest representation of that
amount of time in 15-minute increments
if you do it and you're honest part two
of this series I'm going to teach
how you can use the time more
efficiently and what I think is a
realistic developmental curve for new
students then what's what's a new
student someone that's been with me in
less than one year okay cuz the first
year you're gonna dabble you're gonna
look at videos and gonna daydream about
well I could do this and do that and
you're gonna look at something like do
want a video Papa a Fibonacci and draw
or X I'm a rectangle or something on the
on the chart and you're play around how
to figure out what I've been doing or
your demo trade to see what would happen
and you're wasting time your first year
with me you just don't know what you're
doing once you get to the degree of
seriousness that's required and it's
usually about a year you get tired of
looking at everybody else's stuff and
you see things in mind that keep popping
up in your charts because of hooky with
very generic things that are transparent
price action you can see it things that
take place in the London session you've
seen those things well those learning
sessions they operate on a schedule but
just because that schedule is blocked
out for a specific amount of time that
we call one an open doesn't mean that
you have to be there the entire loan in
open session when you have that 7200
minutes in front of you the motivation
is you're doing everything will know
7,200 minutes to spend your twenty eight
eighty two thousand eight hundred and
eighty minutes that's what everyone
works for Monday through Friday not to
do this they want to take those two
thousand eight hundred eighty minutes
and spend it with something like this
the students submitted to me what their
Saturday and Sunday generally is
comprised of as you can see the play
time majority and it's sleep
a couple commutes to and fro some family
time but notice how much family time in
comparison to sleep and play play is
their time doing their own thing now
that could be representative of going
out and having drinks it could be out
dancing it could be you know doing
whatever adults do with their own time I
didn't ask for the specifics okay but it
was apart from family okay so the
commutes to and fro they recorded it the
time they took that get prepared
dressing showering and such all those
types of things are being recorded here
but notice how Saturday and Sunday are
almost perfectly the same in fact they
are the same if you look at it so
they're doing the same things on
Saturday and Sunday they made time
obviously for an app that appears
towards the middle the the afternoon it
looks like it's a preparation for their
night ahead now this doesn't seem like
someone that is going to be well rested
for the Monday grind because you have
all that play time they've been wasting
they could have been resting now doesn't
mean sleeping it could be doing things
allowing the body to prepare to unwind
how many times have you spent your
weekend where you should be resting
enjoying the time away from work you
feel like you need another weekend just
to get prepared for Monday that's not
because you've worked hard it's because
you have not allowed yourself to
discharge which is one of those things
that you have to learn to do that means
not doing anything that's gonna
stimulate you psychologically not gonna
stimulate you physically you have to
have a period of time to rest that means
do not
sitting still doing nothing stagnant it
just means you are doing very little to
overexert yourself mentally
psychologically emotionally or
physically so you have to have some
period of time to just relax and be
settled you have to schedule that now
some of you probably aren't Christians
and don't believe in the Bible that's
fine I'm not here to preach but it's
taught in the word that we should have
one day of rest I know that's not you by
chance it's it's proper actually if you
have a day where you just relax and
spend time resting doing very little
work
don't try to exert yourself don't put
too many time demands on your day
most people subscribe to the view that
sunday is the right thing it doesn't
have to be Sunday but if you have a job
Saturday or Sunday is a good day to do
it but I don't think that it should be
one or the other but there should be a
day where you have no Chuck no chart
time no reading time about the markets
you need to be completely segregated
from it no ICT videos no looking on
Twitter no none of those types of things
and you need to be apart from it because
most of my inspiration have come by way
of times where I've been away from all
of you been away from my private
mentorship students and didn't look at
charts didn't look at you know Twitter
myself no social media and I get ideas
about teaching or a specific solution to
some students sticking point will come
to me you know I'm not actively looking
for it just jumps in my head I would be
distracted if I did not have my time
allotted for rest now rest is again is
not sleep I do a lot of meditation I do
a lot of stretching and to me I think
those are my two best times outside of
Bible study but if you look at the
periods of time that you wait
doing things that you really don't
benefit from and no one else has
anything from either they are just
consuming your time what are you looking
forward to this coming weekend where
your 2880 minutes are gonna be devoured
by what are you gonna do is it a
particular sporting event is it a bar
scene is it a recreational venture with
the family are you going away is it a
vacation
is it a extended weekend type thing
whatever it is that's gonna be in your
mind Monday through Friday you know
every time you feel like you want to
walk out of your job and quit those
things are gonna pop up as a deterrent
well just like you've done for your job
because you hate it well I shouldn't say
there are some people that follow me
that love their job even though they can
imagine themselves being profitable as a
trader they don't want to leave it and
it's great but trust me it's a minority
group they're the motivational factors
and rigidness to discipline of sticking
to that grind of going to work for very
little in exchange for your time for
money you have constantly built
reminders of why you have to keep going
back there that torture okay comes with
it by way of a reward in sense of it's a
wage and it pays for the things that
feed your family you have to down
associate that same measure of
importance to your study when you
schedule your 15-minute walk you have to
submit to that do it in over a period of
time how much time it's all dependable
and when you can make more time and when
you feel inspired to do so but I don't
think more than 30 minutes a day is
asking too much of anyone and I think
anything more than 30 minutes when
you're new it's just really bloody
wasting time okay so when you watch a
video for me it shouldn't be viewed as
you know sitcom
entertainment don't don't look at like
that put in 30 minutes
get what you can get out of the 30
minutes and turn the video off if you
got to come back to it to die you die
just the rest of it then do so but I
think that the worst thing new students
do is try to plow in and watch every
entire video in every series and think
that themselves that they now know what
I'm talking about and that's the reason
why people struggle because there's too
many things to learn too many things to
learn and you're trying to cram it all
in like someone that went through school
all all the entire semester you didn't
pay attention to the teacher at all but
the night before the test you're trying
to cram and it never works out and
that's the same type of effect that new
students do they go in they they're
fascinated they see things they learn
things and they can you know more or
less relate to the things I'm saying but
they over exert themselves and allow too
much information in one time it's like
drinking from a firehose and you can't
do it okay I'm not saying I'm a mental
giant I'm not saying you're not mentally
adequate to do it I'm just being
realistic
there's too many things for you to
properly digest and retain with the
information and this is actually going
to the mentorship students as well just
because you have access to the entire
month's content doesn't mean that you
should just plow through it all in one
weekend because you're not going to
retain it you're absolutely not going to
retain it you should go through at your
own pace but you should do it in a sober
minded approach don't try to do too many
things because it'll be just like this
here play play play play play and that
doesn't mean play an ICT video just
because you have more time away from
your work doesn't mean gorge yourself
with ICT content because you're not
going to grow from that you just watch a
video spend about 30 minutes to that you
know in terms of time and then spend
your time elsewhere
trust me while you're working and when
you break times and you commute times
you'll spend time thinking about it
you'll be motivated because you have
scheduled the amount of time - 15 or 30
minutes of study time each day but
you're found saying well this is gonna
make it harder and longer for me to get
better at it no it's not it's absolutely
not you're going to keep the intended
motivational level and inspiration in
your development such as a new student
by limiting how much time you spend with
it the time you spend with it will be
much more enrichment it'll be much more
engaging and you'll find that you're
retaining more and it's not overwhelming
you don't have to rush at this and I
can't say it enough to say it so many
times but people think I'm just I'm
speaking in the sense that it's
counterproductive for them but I have
done this with thousands of people
thousands of people and I'm telling you
the ones that always gorge themselves
with the content they never get it any
faster in fact they're the ones that
email me saying I'm struggling or I just
can't get it I watch all these videos i
watch it from the time I get up and I'm
telling them you're doing too much but
they won't listen they think I'm trying
to keep something from them it's not
what I'm doing I'm actually trying to
help you but you're not listening so if
you have a coach if you have a mentor
and they're trying to teach you listen
this is one of the best ways for you to
improve in everything your time
management I get asked a lot of times
what is it that keeps me going I'm
always apparently awake I'm always
always online to some degree everyone
asks you do I ever sleep and I sleep I
sleep in increments of four hours and
then I do two hours in naps and I
schedule them and it's not a set
schedule my say my sleep schedule
rotates and I start my day when I wake
up from my four hour sleep schedule
whenever that is for that particular day
I schedule it and I do everything around
that four hours if I'm gonna be doing
any kind of trading if I'm gonna be
doing any kind of errands
spending my time with my family if I'm
spending time with my children if I have
to take my kids somewhere or if I have
to take my dogs to that or anything like
that I plan it outside of that four-hour
block of sleep and then I do two sets of
napping I don't do a block of two hours
I do like a 1 hour nap and then maybe
I'll catnap in two cycles of 30 minutes
but it's throughout the day because I
don't have a job I can place sleep where
I can schedule sleep I don't need to
have eight hours of sleep in fact if I
ever have a four hour a full night of
normal sleep that everyone else requires
I would feel sick because it's too much
sleep so I'm not advocating for you all
to go to work on four hours sleep that's
not what I'm suggesting here I'm the
saying that I get asked that a lot and I
use a four hour sleep schedule and I
don't feel really rundown at all unless
I do a whole lot and I do like 24 hour
or 36 hour runs with teaching and things
and preparing things which I've done and
it's not healthy to do on a regular
basis but I don't feel that it's hurting
me because it's not always happening but
I don't require a lot of sleep that's my
point
okay and when you get to the point where
you no longer have to work and you can
do this on your own you're gonna find it
you don't need that much sleep either
because I'm not stressing about things
that normal people are stressing about
don't worry if it's stressed as I have
is if my wife wants me to do something
I'm gonna be able to do everything else
I have to do outside of what she
requires of me or my children okay so I
have all those same problems that you
experience yourself but I have the
freedom to plan all my other stuff
around it whereas your job gets in your
way you have to be again a good steward
of your time and by doing so you're
gonna find at your days far less
stressful because you've made time for
things and you're also going to filter
out the things that waste your time see
you're gonna be surprised once you go
through this and you record everything
out what your
doing what your time is in terrible a
terrible amount of time being wasted see
you'll look back maybe before you let
your head down on your pillow or make
you free close your eyes and go to sleep
and you'll think you know I didn't think
I did anything today I feel like I've
wasted today you know that's probably
true
ninety-nine percent of time it's gonna
be something that everyone would agree
on if they were to go through the entire
process of looking at what you did with
your day but when you live your life
like this and you plan out those things
that make you an efficient productive
person you're gonna filter out the
things that waste your time you're going
to focus your time and energy and
efforts more economical and efficiently
when they're in front of you you're
gonna know what those things are by
their measure of importance and priority
obviously wages and earnings is going to
be top of the list then it's family time
and then sleep you know some of you
it'll probably be work sleep and then
family or in other groups that are more
selfish you'll think that it's sleep
work I'll get there when I get there and
then you're in recreational time and
family comes the distant last so I'm not
judging anyone here I'm just stating
that I think that if you go through this
exercise this week run down each
individual day and fill in the blocks
and you'll see at the end of the week
and do the weekend to Saturday and
Sunday I'll do a part two to this and
show you how a development cycle could
be done and still have all the
requirements of normal sleep go to work
do all your normal things okay so I'm
actually using someone behind the scenes
there's a real person behind all this
so the the insights I'm sharing with
this individual is being basically
shared openly known obviously for
privacy sake I can't say it's this
person or that person and if they want
to say on Twitter it's them and that's
you go right ahead but I'm not doing
that
because I have privacy requirements
being expected of me as you know it's a
business owner so
just know that there is a benefit to
doing this and it absolutely has a
bearing on your success as a developing
trader because if you don't do these
things you're gonna waste your time
you're gonna be emotional about things
why why would you be emotional because
you didn't get the things you needed
done notice what happens when you sit
down with your demo account right now
and you have your job you have your
family when you're mad and you're
fighting with your family members or
you're fighting about something at work
and you're angry your work first thing
you do when you get home is put on a
demo trade think about it go back to the
videos I started with 2010 average Joe
needs some kind of release okay you will
not feel those impulses if you get
control of your time see that's what
you're fearing you're going nuts right
now because you're running out of it
every single day you're losing time now
the beginning of wisdom is to count the
number of your days and I agree with
that but you have time today's not
promised and tomorrow's not promised to
anyone but you still have to occupy you
have to do what you have to do what is
it yet to do you got to get control of
things what's the thing you can control
your time that's the only thing you can
control you can't control the markets
you can't control how your spouse is
gonna react
you can't control what your spout your
your spouse's employer there's another
factor that you may be a catalyst for
your inspiration that leads a rat race
because you you need to wages and that
spouse is getting harassed or overworked
and not appreciated not compensated
enough maybe you're not trying to lose
your job right away maybe you're just
trying to replace your spouse's job and
that's a pressure on you all these
things are things that's going to
motivate you do the wrong thing because
you're being emotional about it
why because you're running out of time
time is what you're afraid of you're not
afraid of losing money no one's afraid
of losing money that's not what you're
afraid of you're not afraid of failure
either you're afraid of your
I'm being wasted some of you probably I
turn this video off because you saw
don't waste your time some of you are
getting ready to hit that button to turn
it off guess you thought it was a waste
of your time it has nothing to do with
trading but it does it absolutely does
the best trading books out there would
talk about this if they knew what they
were doing the traders that call
themselves authors and educators if they
understood this element they would teach
it I'm trying to do that for you I'm
trying to highlight the thing that is
the biggest barrier to development in
anything not just trading anything is
mismanagement of time I have a highly
routine and disciplined approach to time
management
I don't always meet my time windows
because things could pop up but for the
most part I get more things done in one
day than the average person would ever
remotely consider doing at all because I
live my life like this everything's a
15-minute block of time to me and I
visualize my next 24 hours to 48 hours
in this manner I schedule my sleep with
the things that have to be anchored to a
specific time and then I put my sleep
and me time in between all those things
now you can't do that because you have a
job and I understand that you have
responsibilities but you still have time
to devote to learning this craft but you
have to be a good steward with your time
and you got to be responsible with it
filter out the things that are gonna be
a distraction focus on the things you
have to do at the time
what's the task at hand what am I
expected to do right now and do that and
I promise you if you do these things you
will have much more enthusiasm much more
energy because you won't be stressing
stress is a very
big burn on calories it's a big
impediment to your health and it's
routed to time everyone wants to have
more time you can't get any more than 24
hours have a day you can't but you can
more efficiently run your time in this
24 hours you don't need a lot of sleep
as much as you may think you do you
don't you sleep many times more because
you don't want to be awake during the
stressful hours people that are propped
up by their own enthusiasm and
motivation don't want to sleep because
it's wasted time when you're depressed
you have anxiety those things will make
you sleepy maybe you're depressed that's
the reason why you have in the feel that
desire to sleep more than you need but
generally it's because of exercise the
lack thereof and poor nutrition because
if you live your life principally
oriented on doing things in a positive
light that means caring about yourself
being motivated to stay healthy rest
properly not over rest and be
disciplined about your time you will not
worry about time and it by taking that
big barrier up you know being successful
and making it an ally because right now
you think time is and its adversary it's
not an adversary it's a resource that
you have plenty of you have more time
than you need but you have to allow
yourself time to develop and don't rush
it 2880 minutes is your weekend now this
I think is time where you can devote a
little bit more than at 15 or 30 minute
period but throughout the Monday through
Friday timescale nothing more than 30
minutes I think is needed on the weekend
no more than 2 hours 2 hours is
sufficient amount of time to be
developed me devoting to divulging into
the ICT libraries or any other
kilo doesn't have this have to be mine
it could be anything but two hours I
think is about right because again
anything more than that you're not gonna
retain it it's like that two hour-long
mini mini series movies that people are
putting out sometimes your attention
span is just like I want to smoothie to
end kind of like what you're feeling
right now at this video come on get to
the end of it two hours on the weekend
each day 15 minutes to start Monday
through Friday or 30 minutes at maximum
Monday through Friday you have to have a
balance and you have enough when your
plate Monday through Friday with work
and family and your normal date of a
daily routine to squeeze ICT in there
any more than that everyone has to
submit to this to some degree in the
beginning but your goal is in through
all this you need to find a way to
perceive time like this all you need is
one block in any one of those specific
elements of time in a 24-hour period one
day per week think about that now
you have Monday through Friday in front
of you to do very very well
you only need one 15-minute block out of
one day at this entire week to do well
part two we'll talk about how you can do
that until then I want you have a very
productive week don't try to do anything
else out of your normal routine record
everything with the PDF file that's a
test in the description below in this
video click on that PDF file print it
out and go through the whole entire week
Monday through Sunday and I'll have
another video on next Monday night part
2 of this series and I'll talk about how
you can do more productive things with
your time and the minimum that's
required to get maximum effort
have small requirements of time until
next time I wish you good luck and good
trading