focus it's a lot of things that we look
at on the charts a lot of things that
are promoted by educators and authors
gurus and mentors but what specifically
should you be focusing on
the last video I gave you an outline to
work with in terms of filling in your
complete Monday through Sunday week in
15-minute increments so every block on
this grid here represents one 15-minute
time frame hopefully you've done that
and you've seen just about how much
wasted time you put into other things
that aren't most likely going to do
anything for you into power Minh or
enrichment or just to improve so we're
gonna focus primarily on taking this
work week and focusing in on specific
times in a day and what is it you're
supposed to be focusing on and studying
as a forex trader I try to promote the
idea thinking of the 24 hour day in
these four incremental cycles there's an
London session which comprises of the
European and London open which is what I
refer to as the ICT learning up and kill
zone it typically includes Frankfurt and
all the way into the London lunch New
York open or as I refer to it as the New
York open kill zone the London closed
Asia or I refer to it as the Asian kills
them no matter what you do / repression
or a job or whatever it is you're gonna
have to find something in these four
specific times of the day to focus on
another problem I've seen over the years
as an educator is my students typically
want to go in and do everything they
want to be the master of the London
session they want to be a master of the
New York session they want to trade that
London clothes and they want to trade
Asia as well because more is better
right
well it's not in fact as a speculator
the less you can do the better because
less is more when it comes to
speculation the common misnomer is if
you look at the opportunities throughout
the day even if you understand the time
windows that's created by liquidity as
shown here you can quickly talk yourself
into doing a lot more than what's
necessary and you become an action hound
i fallen victim to this when I first
started trading Forex it was a rather
busy time for foreign exchange so that
ranges were you know pretty large so it
made me feel like I could do a lot more
and I abandoned what I knew in the
futures market which is basically the
same thing that goes on in the Forex
well back then we had open outcry only
and then when everything went to
electronic trading then everything was
pretty much what we see in terms of my
ICT Forex content but a lot of the roles
that I used with trading currency
futures were applicable to Forex the
overnight trading I wasn't as refined as
I am today because I focus primarily on
the opening of the open outcry pits for
the currency markets as the futures
exchange is opened so you're going to
have to get to the decision point for
yourself as to which one you're going to
focus on now you may be a student and
you have not found your way into your
career yet okay or your temporary career
you're going to be a full-time trader
eventually and whatever you're doing now
is a student that made transition into
something else based on your employment
after you get out of school
okay Worf has a break in your your
schooling you'd be like a summer break
or whatever your opportunities will
probably be more open to other times of
the day I
we recommend you try to pick just one
okay and the one that you should pick is
the one that's the most comfortable for
your family life and your job you do not
want to make things harder for yourself
by picking a time of day to trade or
study that's going to be conflicting
with your personal and work life there's
a balance that has to be made and I can
tell you for the last 20 plus years it's
been a struggle sometimes for me to
balance five kids a wife two dogs my own
personal wants and desires that do what
I want to do with my friends and my
personal time so you have to use that
grid to make a schedule for your family
time if you have a job obviously you
have to schedule that but outside of
that you want to put your family in
first two things you want to do with
your family the things that they've
asked of you you have to make time
available for them if you do not do that
trading is going to be very very
stressful because number one your
children your spouse they're gonna
interrupt you when you're looking at the
charts or trying to trade if they are
home at the time now if you're looking
to trade the month and open or the New
York session and it's throwing the
school session time then probably your
spouse may be working or she could make
herself or he can make himself scarce
while you do what you got to do and the
kids are at school let me close the same
type of thing at least I'm referring to
those in the North American States at
least as it goes with my time zone which
is relatively the same as New York time
but you have to balance that and there's
so many variables there it's up to you
to decide which one's going to be
applicable for you now I know that
primarily especially those I've studied
my free tutorials they want to be in the
London session because it offers the
most volatility and it gives you the
biggest portion of the range of a daily
range it's not necessary
to do that okay so I try to teach like I
taught when it first stepped out as a
Forex mentor 2010 fight primarily just
dealing with Forex were willing students
that you'd only you only need 25 pips a
week that's it
now what I'm gonna show you here tonight
is how you can get that one set up okay
based on a time of day and you can get
those 25 pips for a week
it may take you two trades or three
trades if there's a opportunity where
you don't get your full pool as far as
your target and you have to do another
trade maybe it's a losing trade you have
to take another one to recoup that and
get your balance that you're aiming for
but it's far easier to make a low end
objective between Monday and Friday than
it is to try to get 150 pips or 200 pips
you don't have enough range in the
weekly range to be able to do that
consistently if you don't know what
you're doing and you're rushing and
you're not really focusing so what I
teach is folks should be focusing on a
very low end objective something that
can be obtained rather easy now I say
that with quotations okay I'm not saying
that a new trade is going to step in the
market and easily find 25 pips that's
not going to happen there's some things
you have to learn about yourself and you
have to learn about the market place but
they're very generic things like we're
going to talk about tonight and you've
seen many times what I'm going to refer
to but I want you to really think about
in terms of an exercise because as I
mentioned in the first video in this
series and there's only two parts this
is the last part on this specific series
I mentioned that as a new trader you
shouldn't be doing anything more than
thirty minutes a day in terms of your
study so that means whatever video
you're watching it needs to be thirty
minutes of that only and stop because it
gives you an opportunity to reflect on
what you're learning and it builds
anticipation about your next study
session you don't want to be burnt out
you don't be
boring yourself because I have a
tendency to go on and on and drone about
things that are rather dry but they're
important but if you don't retain them
and that's why it's important to go back
over my videos because the number one
repeating Tennant is that folks get more
information out of the videos by
watching on multiple times because
they're rather boring ok is that the
content is very dry what makes it
exciting and that's what I'm kind of
gonna ring in tonight with this volume
is what you're supposed to be doing in
those study moments ok your 15 minute
block of study time or 30 minute block
of study time you have to find that time
within those 24 hours that's up to you I
can't do that for you because your life
and your your job and whatever that goes
on in your personal life are gonna
dictate where that's available but
whatever you do try to be consistent
about it that way you have something to
look forward to throughout the day until
you get to that study moment and then
you can focus and then you'd limit your
time set an alarm for your start time to
do it and set a ending time so that way
you are forcing yourself to be rigid and
disciplined you only spend this much
time and your study and then leave it
alone your spouse and your children even
not so much your children because
they're not gonna really appreciate what
you're doing and the balancing act is
required with all this but your spouse
will certainly respect that because I
can tell you I have had a lot of
arguments over the years with my spouse
about how much time I devote to this and
to teaching and making videos and
tutorials and notes and all those types
of things in answering email it's been a
lot of work for me as an educator well
that's not the same workload that you'll
have as a developing trader sometimes it
will feel like that because if you have
not scheduled your family time outside
of your work time made time for them
that way when you are alone with your
charts they don't feel cheated because
even if they aren't saying anything
gentlemen you'll know what I'm talking
about
mostly here the look your spouse will
get
when they look in over your shoulder and
you look over at them and here you are
sitting in front of charts again it's
like you're with a mistress okay and you
know what I'm talking about that look
they give you you're doing that again or
you're on there for you know for two
long time when you're gonna spend time
with us or with me particularly so it's
not something that you know is unique to
me okay anyone that spends any time with
the market it tends to be a very cruel
lover and by that I mean it's it demands
your time it demands your attention and
your focus so while it's necessary to
give that to it okay and I'm personally
giving personification to the
marketplace a lot in my references to it
but I want you to feel like it's someone
that could get you in trouble okay it's
the friend that if you allow that
friendship to go too far it becomes a
problem okay you you overstep your
boundaries so you have to keep things in
balance you gotta keep things in check
and keep things in a list of priority
obviously I'll let you guys argue which
one's am more important whether it read
the job or your family I would venture
to say if you don't have funds you know
your your jobs pretty much you know
first because you need funds to take
care of your family and then family is
second and then your free time is
bounced with whatever you do outside of
there's two matric consumers of your
time and again apart from sleep so you
want to have your focus on what you're
doing with your family be very specific
with your time budget your time with
them and then let your spouse and your
children know when you're going to be
involved with the market that way they
don't disturb you they respect your time
doing it and if you keep it in a real
modest amount of time each day it won't
be hard for them to give you that
opportunity to do that now this way
while you're thinking that that fifteen
or thirty minute block of study time is
far too little time it's not going to be
because you'll be much more efficiently
using that time
because you're not going to be stressing
about being interrupted or feeling
guilty about why you're doing it what is
your family and spouse what are they
thinking about what you're doing because
last thing you want to do is having that
over top of your your shoulder if you
will you're whispering in your ear you
know you know when you're done with this
you your spouse is going to have an
attitude or your children's going to
have their feelings hurt because you
didn't spend time with them doing
whatever it is you were supposed to be
doing in their eyes so this way you've
budgeted your time in that 24 hour block
of time which makes a day this way you
have no guilt you have no distractions
and your time is completely and utterly
devoted to the marketplace so that way
the things that you're doing while
they're not a lot of time itself with 30
minutes of time of study it is quality
time so you don't want to spend a great
deal of time with the time that you do
spend you want to spend it without
distraction so if you're gonna be
focusing on Asia okay I want to build an
idea of realism and kind of give you
expectation if you will of what you
should be doing each day okay so when
you're studying again I'm speaking from
this perspective that you've already
went through my free tutorials so
therefore you're not gorging yourself
with videos every day or hours upon
hours what should you be focusing on as
a student that has already gone through
the free content what you should be
focusing on for Asia beach day this is
what you want to be basically doing okay
it's an exercise of logging past price
action now I learned everything that I
teach and I use in the marketplace by
doing this very thing here so do not
discount it don't think that it's a
waste of time because I'm telling you
you gain so much experience by doing it
and by having a record of it and keeping
a study journal keeping each day on one
or two pairs if you want to be crazy
about it if you do this you will be
doing a 30-minute block of time each day
doing it if you want to do the majors
like all the dollar pairs anything it's
coupled with a dollar it'll take you a
good 30 minute 20 or 30 minutes to do it
but Trivedi's do like one or two pairs
and really spend some quality time
studying it and all sessions you know
whatever session that you're you're
focusing on that one particular is the
only one you're looking at now if you
want to add more for completeness sake
and obviously you can use the other
remaining three sessions of the day so
Lawrence if you're looking at London as
your specific time of day you'll be
studying you can add the New York London
clothes and the Asian session as bonuses
if you will and I'll kind of give you an
example what that looks like with this
whole presentation tonight but the
unique portions of a day if you're gonna
be focusing on as an example here say
Asia if that's going to be the time of
day that you have available for study
then this is what you'll do okay so
obviously looking at this chart like
this it doesn't mean too much it looks
rather random and that's typical okay
but over time if you start applying the
ideas that I teach in my free tutorials
the clarity will come and you can see
things that normally aren't observable
by the retail trader as you can see here
by adding the vertical lines delineating
the asian session going into the new
york time in new york of midnight and
identifying order blocks and where sell
stop liquidity pools are and aiming for
those specific things after the market
runs up to a very clear bearish order
block now what you're doing is is you're
teaching yourself to see this in
hindsight you want to have at least
three months worth of a study journal
filled with every single day Monday
through Friday with at least one
specific currency pair okay by doing
this you'll be
go back and look at these unique
examples every single time you want to
look at them it's like having all of
that three-month experience looking at
that specific time of day now imagine
doing that for 12 months if you do that
and you continuously do it as a
developing trader and a well-groomed
trader I do all of my sessions like this
with the fiber and cable it's in my own
unique study journal I keep my own
charts doctored up with all these types
of things and it keeps things in my mind
when I'm looking at price action
something will inherently be jogged in
my memory when I see a specific element
on price action narrowing live trading
if I'm looking at the charts during a
specific time of day like New York and
London if I see something that's acting
you know it may not be apparent on my
chart
because a lot of times I'll go back to a
naked chart when I'm watching because I
don't want to go in with any
preconceived ideas about what should
happen okay if I I'm unsure about the
market place I want to go back to a
clean slate if you will and have a blank
chart but many times my mind they'll be
reminding myself of things I've had
recently noted in my journal okay and
this is what a journal entry looked like
for me for Asian session okay so this is
what my chart looked like for this
particular day so I'm showing you what
my charts look like right now as they go
into my journal now there's a lot of
other things obviously the mentorship
would know about that are also added to
this but from a free tutorial standpoint
this is all free tutorial level content
but don't be discouraged thinking oh
well he's holding things back and I'm
not gonna have enough information and do
anything it's not true because you can
do a lot with the free tutorials but you
have to be very very disciplined and you
have to do a lot of work and you
discover things by trial and error by
doing it through the free tutorials with
the mentorship I kind of like show you
what to avoid and do specifically and
look for this and don't do that
okay that type of thing but there's two
avenues you guys can choose to you know
take whatever path you want I'm talking
for the free student in these lessons
okay so my asian session notes for euro
dollar today look like this okay you
know without the inclusion of all the
mentorship stuff this is sufficient okay
you can see that there has been a clear
bearish order block price broke down
moved back up - it's sold off here then
we went into consolidation which is
typical for the Asian session the market
runs above a short term high in here
back into the order block here and also
goes to the extreme end of this last up
close candle here now these are
15-minute time frames so you could argue
and say well you know these are very
very minor time frames therefore the
candlesticks shouldn't be that important
or significant but they are significant
and they are influential when you apply
the time factor okay so time of day is
very important we know that this time of
day is typically a consolidation portion
of the day so if you're going to trade
in Asia it's very very important your
your objective for pips are gonna be
drastically reduced okay there's gonna
be times when the asian session really
tears off and just starts to run but
generally and this is why you want to do
this you'll see that the normal
characteristic for this time of day is
it's very quiet so therefore you have to
have a very low-end pip objective if
you're gonna be trading this or studying
it but price goes up hits the order
block runs down and goes below the low
here whereas else top liquidity people
would be resting and you see that
reaching into it right here okay and
then look at the nice little reaction
after that now it's not a lot of hips
it's not a lot of movement but it's very
very consistent if you look at the
action Monday through Friday for three
months looking at one particular
currency pair
you will start to see these repeating
characteristics that are very generic
and do not you know random okay as I
have here facetiously placed on that
little rectangle what I'm highlighting
there is the actual Asian session
killzone as i define it so the setup
would be seen here it trades up in the
bearish order block and then runs for
the cells that look pretty cool
all right out of the scalping modules
that I gave for my youtube channel you
can find them on my website at the inner
circle trader.com
just join the forum it's free it doesn't
cost you join a thing there and you can
keep a running collection of all my
YouTube videos there it's all for your
enjoyment and edification but for those
individuals that are not focusing on
Asia during your time of study you may
be looking for London okay so when
London is defined as shown here we will
be looking at past data every single day
and you want to note the portions of
price action that would be seen for the
London open kill zone for that this is
what you would see here okay you have an
initial high so we think that the market
is going to expand higher run that old
high out so there'd be buy stops resting
above that and I'm highlighting here the
London open kill zone and what's missing
here why would make that a specific
price point to be a buy look very
closely and you'll see an ICT bullish
breaker okay we had all these lows over
here very clean level you know that Liz
it's candy land for cell stops price
trades lower clears all the stops and
goes above this high trades back down
into during the London open kill zone
okay you
would be your my right in here aiming
for the bye stops as they run on
liquidity so your opportunity would be
buying here on the bullish breaker
without wrong gonna buy stuff and that's
all you would necessarily look for for
the London open kill zone and your day
would be done but for those individuals
that are just studying it looking for
case studies every single day to build
up a experience reference over a period
of time is ongoing your chart would look
like this okay this is how I have my
chart for today and obviously it's very
informative insightful when you have it
like this because it builds a lot of
understanding about what is being
reacted off of in price action now again
you want to have these every single
trading day okay it's not important to
trade now if you're learning you do not
trade you don't even put demo trades on
this is how you learn you do this every
single day you log it Monday through
Friday and then on the weekends when you
have more study time as I shown in the
first video when you have about an hour
or so or a couple hours so that you can
devote to then you can spend time going
back over the previous week what price
did out reacted and how each individual
day dovetailed into the next day
the kind of Monday trade into Tuesday
and having Tuesday trade into Wednesday
and Wednesday into Thursday and what
relationships Thursday and Monday half
or Tuesday and Thursday what
relationships were there for that or
Friday was there any kind of a
retracement or a high or low formed any
specific day and you want to make notes
on that during the weekend go back in
the old charts like for instance this
one here I may make references on this
chart on Saturday when I go back and go
through all my data for the week that
I've collected this is what I'm doing it
on now I use a 15-minute time frame
because it gives me a lot of intraday
price action and it refines my fractals
into a really small element of time now
I don't like to do it on a 5-minute
chart because it's too much
noisy timeframe and obviously one
minutes is ridiculous so I'm not
interested there but I do a lot of my
notations on a 15-minute time frame now
if there's times when the element behind
the setup is more closely seen or
clearly seen rather by way of an hourly
chart I'll include an hourly chart
perspective but still nonetheless most
of my notations will be on the 15 at a
time frame okay now again looking at
like this doesn't mean much to people
that have this fascination with
indicators because you want to have
oversold you wanna have moving averages
meant these you Bollinger Bands all
kinds of variations of the theme because
it looks smart looks technical and again
all those things don't do anything to
make price move catered distractions I
know what elements in price and time are
going to be influential I know it
because I've done this exercise for
decades you will learn the same way if
you do this if you don't do these types
of things you're actually cheating
yourself because you're not teaching
yourself how to be a price action trader
you're going to be wasting a lot of your
time and what you want to be doing with
your time is focusing on what's happened
in the past because if you study that
and you see it over and over and over
again it's like anything remember when
you were in grade school and you were
learning math at least for me it was we
had to do flashcards okay I did would
hold up
you know simple arithmetic patterns or
problems like what's two plus four and
on the back of the card it would be an
answer six and the person would hold the
card up flash it to you and you give
your answer and if you're right they big
flash and say you can get you're wrong
or right rather so this same element of
repetition doing it every single day in
your own notations in your own words
you're creating the chart so that way
your subconscious is remembering it it's
recording it you're building up your
sensitivity to it because you keep
seeing it over and over and over again
in your notations and in your
and then at the end of the week on the
weekend you're referring to it again
three months of doing this which are
actually doing is you're building a
responsiveness a sensitivity to these
characteristics that are uniquely
specific to these times of the day
that's why it's important whatever one
you're going to choose you need to stick
to that one and don't try to do more
than that okay for those even more
formally you know used to seeing my
content have been using it for a while
and have been profitable with it then
obviously you can do more sessions of
the day and include that in your journal
but as a developing trader that you're
new to my content or you tried it in the
past and it didn't didn't hit with you
and now you're coming back to me this is
the way you want to study it
okay put three months into doing this
and I'm promising you it will transform
your perception about price action and
it will refine you as a better trader
now again you may study the limit
session and eventually come to the
conclusion that it's not a time frame
for you maybe you thought it was going
to be a good session for you but the
next session the New York session ends
up becoming a more appropriate time of
day again to the untrained eye looks
like random price action it's not giving
you any kind of insights here what you
want to do is just go back Monday
through Friday your particular pair of
choice or two pairs but primarily you
want to pick one you're going to be a
specialist in go back and add all your
details okay and what you want to do is
you want to basically try to explain
with the benefit of hindsight what took
place with ICT concepts if you do this
again every single day Monday through
Friday for three months for one
particular session time of day in this
case it's New York if you do this again
you will build a far vast far more vast
understanding about the characteristics
about that time of day then doing
anything else
it's not risking any money it's not
building an excitement or enthusiasm
about making money and it doesn't build
fear about losing it okay what you're
doing is you're teaching yourself in an
element in an environment where you're
not focusing on the money you're
focusing on the process this is the
process I get a lot of questions even by
people that are in my mentorship
it's month four okay or during month
seven and they're saying you know I
don't really know what I'm supposed to
be doing right now
sure you do I've given you lots of
exercises and thing to focusing on but
they want to go into the markets and
start trading right away okay and they
have not submitted to the process the
process is you learn 12 months of core
content then you go into a demo account
for six months minimum applying things
like I'm showing you here going in
taking notes on charts and building an
experience library in your mind
I can't transpose my experience into
anyone I would love to be able to do
that but I can't so the way you get that
experience and the way you submit to the
process and to time this is what you do
you draw the notations on your chart and
you go through the process every single
day whether you've taken a trade or say
we go fast forward into time say you've
been active in the marketplace and
you've been using the concepts and
you're making money but you take a
losing trade now obviously you want to
log what you did wrong and don't beat
yourself up about what you've done
don't use emotional descriptors or
adjectives in your new commentary you
don't want to beat yourself up and you
want to focus on the things you did well
and use descriptors and adjectives that
are positive around that that way your
subconscious doesn't link these
experiences to negative and then they
become a barrier to your trading because
your subconscious will remind you that
the last time you took a trade it was
painful and you'll be wrestling
internally about it you won't realize
you're doing it but
it's very powerful our mind is very very
powerful so if we have these examples of
no emotion in our study journal it kind
of like fills in that void that would
have been painful because we've taken a
loss maybe we go back in and draw out
what took place and then now you filled
in that gap with a positive element and
it masks that negative element that you
took a loss you don't want to focus on
the law so you don't want to focus on
the monetary pain okay you want to
figure out what you did wrong and what
took place in the marketplace and you
learn from that all of my best lessons
come by way of losing okay and then I go
back in at the end of the day I look at
what I've seen in the marketplace and I
mapped out like I show here this is my
actual chart again today for your $1.00
for the New York session with this
information here now I didn't know you
see you seen when I did you know today I
was long on Eurodollar
but this is what was a result later on
the day the market went to 11721 maybe
New York reversal and then traded lower
and that didn't reverse entirely on a
day from the high and make a lower low
or trade below the open but it did have
a reversal they offered up a pretty good
opportunity you can see the intraday
high here initially that set up our New
York session by it ran the buy stops
here and caused the turtle soup sell the
opportunity was between selling it here
above the old high and reaching for the
cell stops below here as it seemed
trading below it there okay so the
opportunity was in between here for a
New York session
market reversal profile now you're gonna
find many times at the New York session
by having this done every single day
predominantly you're gonna find the New
York session is a continuation of a
London session now there's going to be
factors that you'll learn by doing this
when the session will be a continuation
or when it will be a reversal now I'm
not teaching you that here because
mentorship stuff but I promise you if
you do enough of this you'll find one or
two specific criterias that will allow
you to anticipate when a market reversal
profile should come nothing's perfect
even in the mentorship there's nothing
perfect but it's more insight and more
experience by doing this if you don't do
it you're cheating yourself and you're
robbing yourself of valuable experience
that you just you can't beat it I mean
you can sit down if you have a day off
of work and you can go back literally
over a couple weeks and do this okay and
build in a great deal of history in your
study journal but in the beginning you
don't want to do that you just start
fresh with today or yesterday and build
your study journal up and you'll be on
your way for those that can't do the New
York open or London open or Asia an
opportunity can be seen by using the
London closed now London closed again is
another day time of day rather it's
similar to that of the Asian session
it's very low in terms of volatility
does have some quirky characteristics to
it but from for the most part it usually
has the the capping effect of the daily
range moving from a make a chart to more
notations this is how I internalize what
took place for London clothes you can
see here the rectangle is highlighting
the London clothes killzone as I define
it market trades up into a bearish
quarter block seen here trades up to it
here and it attacks the cell stops below
here and you reach this back down into
the ICT bullish breaker here trades down
exactly to the very low to the pip okay
and for those students of support
resistance if you like that trades back
down to the old high here
but specifically how we pick real
support/resistance is based on
institutional order flow and reading
price action and the best way of doing
that is studying my ICT breaker pattern
beautiful reaction off of that once it
trades down to the lowest end of the
breaker and pulls off that low and
starts going to consolidation now again
because this is a type of pattern in the
day that's very low volatility generally
the characteristic is going to require
your adherence to expecting or look for
very low in pip objectives not like that
you would see in London session or New
York session which brings us to if you'd
be focusing on the London session you
can anticipate a realistic 20 to 30 pips
on the london session many times you can
get more than that but I build in this
expectation as a developing trigger so
that way if you are actively demo
trading it this is what you should be
aiming for this is your first profit
objective if you hold on for the rest of
the day obviously you can do that but in
London you're gonna be looking to take
profits at 20 or 30 pips scale your risk
is as low as you can but still keep the
trade open you don't want to choke or
strangle the trade but you want to pay
yourself when you can get it 20 or 30
pips in London okay because you could
reach you very well could read London
wrong you're trading the New York
session
realistically 20 pips for that time of
day
Londyn close 10 to 15 pips now there's
some of you're thinking of 10 steps
that's not even worth it well what if
you did 10 pips every single day it's 50
pips a week I'm looking for 50 to 75
pips a week I'm telling you if you
understand this factor of trading with
using a 50 hip objective for the week
you have no problem finding those 50
pips if you are flexible and you are
eventually trading for a living you can
do a session in the London session if
you miss it or if you get it wrong you
can hopefully recoup it in the New York
session and go flat for the day or if
you made your money back and you see a
very strong set up in London close you
can get your 10 pips for the day or
maybe 15 pips and if you're doing that
it leaves only a balance of thirty five
pips if you got 15 for London closed 50
- 15 you got thirty five pips the rest
of the week to make it and you've made
your net 50 pips eventually when you're
treating saying I'm $1 per point or pip
that's a good week 50 pips is a very
handsome week I don't know where you're
from but you know that's a good living
and finally Asia another tunnel day
where 10 to 15 pips is realistic in
terms of a pip haul or objective if you
are going to be trading Asia I have to
say this you will find many times it's
not going to give you a setup that is as
consistent as the New York and London
also in your notes you should have
typically Asia or London clothes gives
the better setup so in other words if
Asia is really really quiet and it
doesn't give you a set up means
generally that lemon close that same day
will give it to you in contrast if Asia
gives you a very nice move that
typically means that London close will
be quiet later on in the day okay so
what I want you to take away from this
video is a way of balancing your time
targeting specific times of the day for
study budgeting and being a good steward
with your time and also balancing your
family life and your sleep time and your
work time but you only need to focus on
one of these a day not every single one
of them don't sneak one while you're
working okay or while you're at dinner
with your family
looking at your smartphone don't do that
because number one it's not fair to them
it's not fair to you because you're
distracted and you shouldn't be doing
two things at one time you can't keep
your money in the forefront of your mind
and still be respecting and spending
quality time with your family it can't
you can't have it so you're gonna have
to pick what time of day you're doing
what and then stick to that and if you
do that I promise you it won't be
perfect I promise you you will still
lose money I promise you that you still
will probably get in arguments with your
spouse and your kids will be
disappointed because you'll still do
something when they would rather be
doing something else with you at that
time but if you show them your results
over time they will be more likely to
see things like your hopefully wanting
them to and allowing you to do what
you're trying to do and you're
passionate about dealing right now which
is speculation for a living and if you
do this type of skill set and practice
and exercise and being disciplined about
budgeting your time and managing your
time efficiently you'll be well on your
way to reaching that objective and until
next time I wish you good luck and good
trading