all right folks welcome back this is
volume three of the energy trader market
maker series
in this volume i'll be teaching on
market structure key levels
and smt
all right we're going to assume that
when you're doing your
qualitative analysis that means we've
already gone through all the
quantitative we're assuming the market
price is up here
and your analysis suggests that there is
a move likely to ensue
that takes us down to a key level
low now these key level lows can be
weekly lows old highs of
entire time frame like four hour daily
or monthly or weekly
they could be
the top of an old trading range
there's multiple ideas that could be
used for a key level but what makes it a
key level
is it's on a monthly weekly
daily or four hour less importance
and significance place on the four hour
predominantly the higher time frame
daily
weekly and monthly now these
levels are important what makes them key
is because they're used by
large fund traders in their analysis
they're not really
going into these 15-minute time frames
one-hour charts and things like that
their analysis is predominantly linked
and founded on the monthly weekly and
daily time frames because
the volume that they work in and out of
the marketplace
requires them to be trading on those
time frames because they don't have the
luxury like you and i to get in and
trade on one minute charts
five minute chart 15 minute intraday
so the idea is we're expecting
where the market is now to trade down to
this level
and then a reaction should ensue
now your choice as a trader is if we're
here and you think it's going down here
to set up a move
to go later higher you can be a trader
from this point here
down or wait till it gets to this level
and then try to trade the bounce i'm
gonna leave that to you
to decide because a mentor should not
try to press everyone into a mode
it isn't a one mode fits all it's a
approach to understanding how price is
delivered and then you as a trader
find a strategy or a
process that allows you to engage price
action without you feeling like you have
to
meet the same expectations that someone
else is doing
so as the market trades down inside this
price swing
there's multiple opportunities in the
form of
swing trading short term trading day
trading scalping
and you can trade on both sides of the
marketplace but predominantly
the larger position and or more
risk can be assumed on the short side
whereas going long maybe scalping
something like that
counter trend to this expectation in the
marketplace
you'll use a lot less leverage and try
to be much more nimble
you know what your objectives will be
much more smaller
than that of if you were trying to trade
in line with this movement here
once it trades at this level here you
would expect higher prices and you can
trade obviously
with the majority of your leverage on
the long side
and any scalping or short-term trades
against this idea should be done so
with very low leverage and very
term price objectives now let this image
burn in
so that way when we transition to the
market maker buy model
it's this idea we have in mind here okay
market price is here we're expecting a
trade down to a key level
and then rally up
now these lows can form
two different ways you can start by
coming down
come off that short term low and then
make a lower low
creating the ultimate low in this price
swing here
and then price running higher this sets
up
a ict breaker where we have a low high
lower low once it breaks that short term
high in the middle
if it trades back down into that we
could be a buyer somewhere over here to
capture another continuation on the
upside
conversely there is another formation
you can see
where it trades down
it comes off the low and turns with a
higher low
and starts to trade higher this one here
i like to see this form only if
there is a smt divergence
that would be in a market that's closely
correlated to the one i'm looking at
here for the analysis
and what do i mean by that well let's
assume that this is the euro dollar
and i expected your dollar to trade from
its market price down to a key low
and then trade higher at this low
if i see euro making the low and then a
higher low
at the same time pound dollar is making
a
low and then a lower low that's an smt
divergence
okay smart money technique or smart
money total i never really settled on
the letter t
what it would stand for it was always
interchangeably used as
smart money technique or smart money
tool it's just simply a divergence
between
closely correlated assets or markets
what this indicates is there's a strong
disparity between
what the algorithm is pricing in for one
currency
versus another the theory i operate
under is
all boats rise with the tide and
if we're expecting higher prices in euro
it goes without saying that we should
reasonably expect
pound dollar to rally as well unless
there's other factors that are
outside the scope of this teaching that
would
negate that but for the majority of the
time in a general rule of thumb
all foreign currencies should be
rallying together and falling
dollar seen with that instance
here if we have a low a higher low in
euro
and cable goes low lower low that's
indicating that the algorithm is not
wanting to take
euro dollar to a lower low like it did
with cable or british pound versus us
dollar
and that crack in correlation many times
signifies a a
timing aspect that would be confirmation
to expecting this level down here being
significant
or key that leads to an upward price
swing later
okay with that idea in mind usually the
market will be in some
measure of consolidation i like to see
some kind of a short-term trading range
and it is very subjective this part okay
what is a trading range or a
consolidation
where price is having several candles
not two
not three not four but it just stays in
an
area over a prolonged period of time how
much time michael
it's all relative to the time frame
you're looking at if you're looking at a
15 minute time frame it could be
i don't know maybe 10 candles or more
and i'm just giving you a rough idea
because experience is going to guide you
on how
many candles really make up a
consolidation
studying price especially if you're a
new student this is going to seem too
vague and i had this complaint before
when i was teaching on baby pips as soon
as i
started to introduce an idea you know
right away they expect to have
the understanding entirely from one
lesson and you have to have
something of a comprehensive study
approach to what i'm teaching because
it's not simple but it is simple once
you understand all the moving parts
so from a modular standpoint when i say
that the market is usually in some kind
of a short-term consolidation
it could be you know consolidation on
one time frame but just simply two or
three candles on another
time frame that would be higher up so
it's all relative to
what you're expecting in terms of the
market price if it's
on a five-minute chart the consolidation
may look a lot longer
in terms of duration versus if you look
at it from a four-hour chart
it's all within one candle and you don't
even see a consolidation
but for the sake of continuity let's
just assume that we understand there's a
short-term consolidation here
i'll be giving you an example here so
that way you're not left with
too much vagueness so the market will
leave this consolidation
and inside this decline we wait for
another area of either
retracement back to the original
consolidation which it does
not have to do okay it does not need to
do this
this is kind of like what the
white golf theory folks will look for
there's lots of times where it just
doesn't do that
and that's why i don't teach why golf
that's why what i'm teaching here is not
wake off
so as the market drops down i allow
in my analysis the potential to return
back to the original consolidation but
if it does i need to see a very sharp
rejection there it can't just come back
to the original consolidation low
and then hang around for a little while
it needs to come back up there and then
break
i like it even better if it tries to
make an attempt to get back to the
original consolidation
low okay and fail to get there and then
breaks hard
i really like that because that
indicates a very heavy market
and it's likely to continue going lower
but either or
the next short-term consolidation and
this doesn't usually last as long as the
original consolidation up here
so what we're looking as a consolidation
a market that breaks lower
that maybe trades up to here and if it
does
we'll look for a sharp decline
if it doesn't and just goes right into
another area of consolidation
it usually will set up like an optimal
trade entry and if you're new to this
channel or
you're just watching this video for the
first time i have
a plethora of videos that teaches my
optimal trade entry pattern
it's very simple little pattern it
repeats every single day it repeats on
every single time frame
you just need to know what you're
looking for and why it should be forming
there
and this is really the point of this
lesson
is where in market structure should
things occur
and how do we interpret it and how we
anticipate it
so in this area here usually you're
going to see an optimal trade entry
short
it'll be a low retracement back up
into a bearish order block and then
slams lower
or it could be a low short term high and
then a higher short term high that runs
out
short term buy stops then it sells off
so
either one of those instances will allow
for
me to take a trade going short because
remember i'm waiting for some level down
here i've indicated
at the beginning of this discussion that
i think it's going to trade down too
or i'm watching price and i'm not really
engaging price i'm just
monitoring it and practicing and reading
price and i anticipate some measure of
selling
in this area or i'm watching price so
that way
it just keeps me closer to the
marketplace and i'm practicing either
with a paper trade or a demo trade or
i'm illustrating something with my
my teachings and lessons i'm just
anticipating whether i'm engaging or not
another price leg
lower and when it comes should it come
we're waiting for some kind of expansion
lower and
sometimes we'll get a secondary level of
distribution which will be another
either optimal trade entry cell
or a short-term high that's ran out with
a higher short-term high
and then leads to another level of lower
prices
until we get into that area where we
expect that key level to be reached
this is where the market goes into
smart money reversal okay usually it
will form
the same way as outlined in the price
swing where it will create a low
a lower low and then look for a breaker
or it goes
low high or low and if it
occurs like that again using
the inter market relationships i
mentioned earlier if it creates a low
with a higher low
versus one definitive load that takes
out a previous short term low
in other words the diagram i outlined
when it was just that big
blue v giving you a rough depiction of a
price swing the little animations i put
in
at the low those are the only two things
that can happen
that's it so how they trade
and form in price leads to what process
you look for next
i'm not really interested in
a market that will give me a dull
flat blunt-ended low i'll avoid that
at all costs i'll avoid that because
that means i'm gonna have to wait
because we could be seeing just another
level of distribution
that leads to another break lower and
then i'll revisit the analysis
at a later time but if we see price
trade higher
we're going to assume that the smart
money has accumulated loans in here
they are not pushing price up when they
go long by the way
we're seeing price trade down to this
level and then
it kind of like spends a little bit of
time down here not a lot
and certainly nowhere near the length of
time that the original consolidation
looks like
very short term little consolidation and
the algorithm keeps price
in that range okay so it's a small
little dealing range it works in and
then it'll reprice
if smart money traders do not buy
they miss that move so they'll have to
wait for a low-risk buy
that usually will happen over here in
the small little
consolidation which will form in what in
the form of a optimal trade entry
by or a low
and then a short term lower low that
takes out buy stops and then rallies
remember when i taught in the previous
lesson in this series that usually right
before
significant price advances higher some
little short term lows taken out for
stop raids
and they assume those positions when the
stops are taken their sell stops flood
the market with
selling so that way counterparties that
understand what the algorithm is about
to do with price sending it higher
they'll buy those sell stops and they'll
be positioned for
a rally higher we would expect price to
trade higher until we get to another
level of accumulation
so what we've already seen here is
consolidating
and accumulation of shorts
accumulate more shorts accumulate more
shorts in this area
you may only get one area of
distribution and then it trades down to
the smartment reversal
where they distribute their shorts
down here so they're going to buy
to sellers at a low price and
everything they assumed over here should
be hopefully
offloaded here some of it here and some
of it here
so their heavy positions are entered
here some of it's taken off in profit
here
some of it's taken off in profit here
and here
or they'll go short here
add more here add more here and dump it
all off here
so there's two ways for them to engage
price
and work within this market maker buy
model
the longs that they assume here they may
not get them all on and not to
add more here and then add more here
because
as price is rallying up it's going to be
targeting the original consolidation
until it targets the buy stops above
this relative
equal high or consolidation all those
buy stops will be the target
of all of this so if you're looking at
price and you think that it's going to
trade lower to go higher
the original consolidation aim there
you might have a higher time frame
target some somewhere beyond that
but initially study all old price data
price swings and
you'll see this phenomena is occurring
and
you don't have to have all the
complications
that are introduced with retail concepts
i mean this might seem
too vague and it may seem an over
simplistic approach to describing
something
but i promise you go into charts and
study it you'll see this very thing
unfolding it happens on all time frames
and it happens on buy and sell this is a
market maker buy model
where they're taking price down not the
traders
the algorithm all the algorithms are
working together
it takes price down then allows traders
that know what to anticipate
to onboard here and then they take it in
scalings here
and here and finally the last bit of a
run it's in a hurry
to get above here and this is a complete
market maker buy model
this is unique to me this is something
that i introduced uh years and years ago
and there's been some subtleties you
know
people adding like off to it trying to
make it look like it's white golf it's
not like golf
it's very specific things and elements
that are over here
have to agree with over here and vice
versa
and again that's outside the scope of
this teaching but just know that there's
logic that is very precise it's
extremely precision oriented
but this general idea here will serve
you well as a
road map for studying price swings
now conversely we can look at price
doing the opposite where this is a ict
market maker sell model
we're going to assume that the market
price is down here and we think that the
price is going to go up to some
key high again that could be
running out of old high it could be
trading to an
old high and just falling short of it
because we don't think it's going to go
higher
it could be trading back into an optimal
trade entry so
and there's all kinds of things that
would be
outlining this as a key level but what
makes it key again
is it's a monthly weekly or daily level
and at the lowest four hour but again
i'm only
throwing the four hour out there as just
an extra
side note because predominantly the
levels are going to be key because
they're on this
top higher time frame daily weekly and
monthly
so as the market trades higher and runs
into that
you could be a participant in buying
that up or
studying it as it rallies up into that
key level and then the expectation of
lower prices
if it materializes this whole fractal
okay our price swing is what we're
trying to strip down to its
basic components okay what elements
occur inside this entire price range
that's what we're highlighting here with
the models
the high can form obviously with the
higher high
and then breaking down which sets up a
potential bearish ict
breaker which would be over here
somewhere but the high
and then higher high forming this high
this is what i like to see i'm more
confident with
this pattern but conversely
if we're looking at it where we have a
high and a failed higher high
and then it breaks here this is only
significant and
a market structure break if we have
inter-market relationship
confirmation again let's assume for a
moment that this is british pound versus
us dollar
and british pound versus us dollar makes
a high and a
short term lower high and then breaks
down
this is ideally a breaking market
structure on cable or pound dollar
if euro dollar makes a high low
higher high and then it breaks down
because that would be a
correlated pair smt divergence smart
money technique or smart money total
because what that is indicating is that
cable was
underlyingly weak from an algorithmic
standpoint
it was unable to make a higher high
where euro was
and i'm speaking hypothetically
obviously but that's how i would use
this lower high formation
so in other words if i think it's likely
to form a lower high then my
attention will go to a correlated market
like
again if this is assuming pound dollar
i'm going to be really watching euro
dollar and i want to see and if
this is occurring here in cable i want
to see and almost demand
that it's a higher high in euro now if
it creates
a higher high in cable and it creates a
higher high in euro
that means we might not be really
topping yet and i'll have to wait for
more information or a real
strong breakdown then i can get back in
sync and trade with it later on as
you'll see
all right again the assumption is we're
at a market price down here it could be
trading
in relatively cool lows or consolidation
and it leaves the consolidation
at this point again the same it could
come back to the original consolidation
high
but it doesn't have to
we're waiting for it to rally up into
another area where it creates an optimal
trade entry
long or it creates a short-term low and
then another short-term low that's lower
than it
it takes out cell stops and then we
anticipate higher prices rallying higher
until we get to another level of
accumulation so each one of these
levels over here is accumulation and
another point of advancement on the
outside until we get to
our key level where we anticipate smart
money reversal
okay so smart money reversal occurs
with some measure of consolidation not a
lot
okay but we're we're anticipating
expecting
the algorithm to kind of like hold up
there for a little while what's a little
while michael
again it's all relative to the time
frame you're studying because if this is
a five minute chart
it's not going to spend 20 candles in a
five-minute interval
up in this area you know what i'm saying
like it's it's going to be very
short-lived
whereas if we were on a four-hour chart
and we're seeing this pattern
and we're looking at a five-minute chart
then it's going to probably look like a
whole lot of candles
so it's all relative to what you're what
you're looking at through what time
frame
and again the way you learn how to do
this and
get better at reading what i'm
suggesting here is you look at old data
the back testing and studying of old
data every successful trader
every single one whether they come
through my camp or on their own or
wherever else they went through it
they're always going to be better and
versed
because of their own study the time they
spend looking at old data
and studying those price swings because
those things repeat
that element from rallying here up to
some key level
and then expecting it to trade lower it
will have all these
elements to it they might look slightly
different each time but they generally
have the same repeating themes
after there's a smart money reversal we
expect price to trade and break lower
until we get to another level over here
where we would see another optimal tread
entry cell
so it would be a blow a retracement back
in
maybe to a bearish order block and then
a displacement lower
until we get to another level of
distribution
now in here it could be the optimum
transfer cell or it could be
a short-term high and a higher
short-term high
and then break down same thing here
it could be an optimal trade entry cell
or a little retracement creates a
short-term high
starts to go lower and runs up one more
time takes that out the question you're
probably asking is when does it do that
when will it do that in an optimal
transit like for instance if you took a
trade
thinking it's an optimal trade entry
cell here or here
how do you know that it's not going to
be one of those trades where it takes
out
the short-term high that you went into
going short
and you get stopped out that's going to
happen i can't promise that you're going
to
you know walk through this marketplace
without having those cuts and scratches
and bruises
you might break a bone or two okay
you're going to lose some money
but let's assume for a moment you're
taking an optimal treat energy short
here this goes for the same thing i just
mentioned
on the market buy model this is a market
maker cell model just reverse everything
i'm saying here
for for the other one if
you take an optimal trade entry cell
here and it starts to go down and then
runs up and takes you
out of the trade then what you can do
is put a sell stop below the short-term
load that's formed thus far
and if the market goes down there it
could take you right into the market
sure and if it's going to do what we're
expecting here it probably isn't going
to do a short-term high a short-term
high it's higher then a short-term
height is higher
that's unlikely can it happen yes so
rare
it's probably never going to happen but
it can
so there's no reason for you to fear
being knocked out or kicked out of the
marketplace and take a loss because if
your
analysis is correct then
you're probably still going to capture
some move and overcome that drawdown
you've taken here
and if you get this other opportunity
over here and you have to stop around
here
chances are you're probably not going to
get a stop run here it'll probably just
be the optimum trading entry run
right from a bearish order block down
and it usually will be aggressive and
quick
to get down to the low of the original
consolidation where
cell stops are resting so this is the
elements to
a market maker cell model and again for
someone new
for someone that has not been looking at
price charts for a long time
this is going to look too elementary too
simple too big too well
it's not really showing me anything i'm
not really grasping it
but i promise if you go through your old
charts and look at a price swing say on
a four-hour chart
that does basically something like this
and then you study it from a 15 or five
minute chart and you'll see
this general idea
all right so let's go over to the
british pound and if you've been
following along
in recent weeks
the discussion on pound dollar
i gave you guys in this very series too
but let's take it back a little bit
let's assume that we're looking at this
level over here it's a daily chart it's
a relative equal low so you know what's
resting below that cell stops
and we're trading right here so we're
looking at this high
below and we retraced in and we look
like we're about to
break lower we have relative equal lows
in here so saw stops there
lots of cell stops there so we would
expect to see price trade down there so
this is a key level
ultimately price does cascade lower
all of this here my students and
mentorship we knew about this we
outlined this talked about before it
happened
and the market has now at this point
traded cell stops accumulated longs
and then we have these relative equal
highs okay in the last lesson in this
series
i talked about how this is the next draw
in liquidity
and the market trades up into that
on thursday of the week of this
production and today's friday
so the market trades up and we've
completed
a accumulation of sell stops and a
distribution to buy stops
smart money buy sell stops and sells to
buy stops
okay so we can use all this information
here
for the weekly range to get to our
objective on weekly pip objectives
let's assume that's this is that
area where we were looking for the buy
stops and this is where the old low was
on the daily chart where the sell stops
were
look what we have here the market's
consolidating
it leaves the consolidation but why does
it come back up here
it doesn't need to so it's better for it
not to do that and we have what we have
the level of distribution here because
we have what
optimal trade entry sells off
another level here optimal trade entry
sells off trades below that old relative
equal low on the daily chart it's that
blue level
on the daily chart there's equal lows
those sell stops are being absorbed
here the algorithm holds price in this
little consolidation
allowing smart money to accumulate
their buying does not send price up
it that's not how this works i know you
have books and they have authors and
teachers and want to be mentors that
tell you
that the buying sends price up like this
it does not
how many times have you seen people
saying oh yeah we bought this
and i bought i'm long i'm long
everybody's long everybody was long in
bitcoin
before 20 000 back in several years ago
and i called the top on that but
everybody was buying
but this still didn't send price higher
it went the other way
because these markets are manipulated
they're controlled folks i know it
doesn't feel good to hear that it
doesn't feel
warm and fuzzy because it feels like man
i really don't have a chance no in fact
you really do have a chance
if you understand how these markets are
manipulated you
follow suit with what the algorithm will
do you're not going to always know
i don't always know i know a lot i know
lots of times when it's going to do
specific things and i know when it's not
likely to do the things that i would
normally expect and i avoid trading
but in this instance here the market's
consolidating
allowing smart money to accumulate longs
once it takes off here they can't
they can't enter they've already missed
that opportunity so they're gonna have
to wait for some new level of
accumulation
we have a low a high optimal trade entry
in here
rallies up we have another level here
from this
low to this low that's optimal trade
entry because you have a high
low higher low boom
rally trades up consolidates
rallies again and then drops down takes
out that short term low
we talked about this in the previous
discussion or volume
and it accumulates and goes higher
the algorithm is driving price up here
it's not
the buyers okay it's not the buyers
the question is this if it was just the
buying pressure
why didn't it run from here all up to
break out above here because that's what
we were aiming for
why didn't run from here right above
here in one shot why is it doing all
this consolidation
i mean think about it if the buyers are
really controlling price
and in retail traders coming behind and
they buy it later chasing price
why doesn't all that translate into just
singular price runs
where it just goes in one shot because
that's not how the markets
look okay it's not how it works folks
all of these lows here are critical as
we'll talk about
in later discussions that are outside
this
video but nonetheless we're looking at
how price
trades down into levels that take out
short-term lows
short-term loans were taken here in
rallies short-term low was here
it took it out and then it rallies
short-term low here
trades down below it and then on fmc
fomc right there
it wipes it out one more time and then
rallies then it takes out
this level here which will be critical
later in other
videos in this series it ultimately
takes out all the buy stops
above this relative equal high and or
original consolidation
so this is a market maker by model this
was
what i hinged the analysis on in this
video series live as we were walking
through this week with you
and my mentorship students knew about
this as well
the bias why i was looking for what i
was looking for what i was expecting
in cable it's based on what i'm showing
you here
now there's a lot more things than
teaching mentorship students
that aren't going to be included in this
series obviously
and you can get upset and be mad or you
can say you know what
i appreciate what you're showing me here
this is enough you can make
lots and lots of money with this okay
lots of you don't need a job
you can win ftmos and you can do all
these funded account
contests and get funded using what i'm
teaching you on this youtube channel
you do not need to buy mentorship
i'm not offering seats to it anymore
that
area is closed down but this
is something you can study on your own
and go into your charts
and see what i'm showing you here
repeats over and over and over again and
in 2022
after march because i'm gonna take a
month off i'm going to be more
active on the youtube channel and i'll
be teaching a lot
of these types of things real time so
that way you'll be able to see over my
shoulder
what i think is going to happen and i'm
going to just use
what you've been introduced in this
youtube channel and you're going to see
how
quickly and easily you can hit the
ground running and find consistency
and i'll be like a little bit of a guide
through youtube doing that
now we're going to talk about smt smart
money tool or smart money technique
when we're down below these relative eco
lows on
british pound we're expecting price to
accumulate those sale stops but how do
we know
that that's really going on how can we
trust that
well bring in the dollar the dixie
dxy is being overlaid on the
pound dollar chart and on trading view
you can see that the dollar index went a
little bit higher than this short term
high there
at the same time
pound dollar was unable to go lower than
its previous low
now think if the dollar is going higher
pounds should be going lower but if
pound is going higher dollar should be
going lower
vice versa but if you look for times
when there should be
a key level influencing price
this is when you go to smt now i taught
smt on baby pips like 10 years ago
and everybody took that
and ran with it and tried to make smt
occur
on all time frames every time they
wanted to get a trade
they're looking for it you only consider
using smt
which is a divergence between correlated
or inversely correlated markets
if you're looking at the dollar index
against the pound or if you look at the
dollar index versus the euro or
the dollar index versus the australian
okay that's a usdx smt divergence or
dollar
smt if you're looking at
correlated pairs that are like
euro and cable or like let's say this
way euro dollar
comparing its lows to pound dollar
that is a correlated pair smt divergence
if you see them
break their correlation in other words
this is a breaking correlation
this high with a higher high on dollars
should have been seen with a low and a
lower low on cable
but notice what's happening this right
here
is how the algorithm tips off
the traders that are in the know
we already know going below those wealth
of equal lows that their cell stops down
and it's probably going to go down there
accumulate and go higher that's
likely but how do we really know and
trust that's going to happen
the dollar index gives us the insight
the x-ray view if you will
where it went high higher high
low failed lower low so it's
telling the traders without really
broadcasting it
that okay cable's gonna start going
higher because it failed
to make that lower low where the dollar
made the higher high
so this is smt divergence higher high
higher low this is occurring at the same
time
we're below those daily equal lows and
we're expecting price to go higher
anyway and all this does is confirm
smt is not a timing tool it's a
confirmation tool
okay it confirms something that you were
already expecting anyway
and this is why a lot of folks that
learned from me on baby pips
thought that oh smt doesn't work it
doesn't work because i tried to look for
here and there
and it failed here it failed there you
don't go into your charts looking for
divergence between highs and lows that's
not
what you're doing you have to have logic
and some measure of a
narrative behind what it is you're
looking for otherwise the divergence
could
be there momentarily and then completely
evaporate
and then what you trade on you trade it
on the basis of like an indicator
and this is not an indicator when it's
done correctly because i'm comparing the
price of one
benchmark currency the dollar versus
another currency pair
and they should be mirroring one another
okay
so if this is high or high this should
be low or low if it doesn't do that
that to me indicates as a cracking
correlation therefore it's tipping off
algorithmically this is the signal it
sends
it's not oh it went down and there was
not enough sellers to send it lower
that's not what that
is it also isn't a low and there's too
many buyers to let it go down
it's not that either i'm telling you
what it is
i'm telling you exactly what it is and
majority of you aren't going to agree
with it because you know
you probably read 14 books okay or
watched a couple videos on somebody
else's youtube channel
and they swear up and down that it's
this and it's that and they
maybe have exotic cars that they're
leasing and they're trying to convince
you
with stacks of money they're carrying
around with them all the time going on
trips
go into a chart okay and use these
things i'm teaching you okay and study
like that
and you'll learn far more than any book
out there is going to give you because
most of the books that's being written
now
are just bleeding information from what
i'm giving you here on this youtube
channel or for my mentorship
and that's the truth and if it sounds
arrogant i'm sorry if it sounds arrogant
i'm not trying to be arrogant
i'm just telling you if you're going to
learn how to do this you need to learn
it from the source
and that's me i'm going to show you how
to use this stuff and make money with it
real money not demo dollars that i teach
through for compliance reasons because
i'm not licensed to give you trade
advice
but i promise you this if you learn this
stuff
and you get good with a demo account
what separates
the ability for you to do the same thing
in a demo account in a live account
fear and greed and i have
modules in this youtube channel to help
you conquer that also
so there's no reason for you not to be
making money there's no reason for you
not to be passing
a funded account challenge so that way
you can get out here and start making
money because times are going to start
to get real tough soon folks
real tough and if you're relying on your
job
i'm telling you you are setting yourself
up for failure
i could be your best friend and all you
got to do is a pad
and pen sit down take notes and study
and experience will guide you i'm going
to put you in the right place
in studying but all that work is on you
you have to do all this stuff you have
to study it and go through example after
example of hindsight data
and then you train yourself to see these
things
you don't go in looking for divergence
because that's the same thing as a
student that
trades with retail logic will look at an
rsi and say okay
it's going higher and higher but look at
this rsi it's diverging variously
and they try to go short and they get
their clock cleaned
and just keeps on going higher
it doesn't make a difference what
indicator you slap on that chart
they're all going to flash bare signals
okay because it's
measuring mathematically a number of
bars in the past
and by default it's going to be
going lower and people don't understand
that because they're not they're not
versed in basic math okay there's simple
things
that you're being tricked by but because
they show example after example that
doing this or that in the past
then you go into thinking okay well i
believe
that this is going to happen because
i've seen it in the book four or five
times
never seen the author trading with it
never seen the author doing it with a
live account
never seeing them show you in live
market conditions
you don't see those things but they have
cherry picked hindsight examples
where they're talking about the left
side of the chart all the time
i did this series i did this series
again for youtube but i used
real market action real analysis
to deliver it
how better can you expect from a mentor
to be able to do it outline it i signed
my name on it where i thought cable was
going to go
and here it is i did it on a week during
fomc
and i even traded fomc i put the trade
on my
telegram it's there you can see it
and it went up and traded and i did a
one shot one kill set up with that
all of that with this logic here
better view of what i'm referring to
here is smt divergence
on the right hand side it's the chart of
the pound dollar and the left-hand side
it's the dollar index
here's that higher high in its own chart
and then here's that higher low on its
independent chart on cable
so these two price points are
correlated to these two price points
this
should have went to a lower low than
this one it didn't
but because it didn't do that and were
below those relatively cool lows
on the daily chart on cable this was
accumulation of longs
the algorithm is signaling to interbank
traders this is
going to go higher not because of buying
and selling pressure
deficiencies but because it's being
controlled and manipulated
don't take my word for it i don't want
you to believe me
i don't want you to believe me at all
about what i'm showing here i want you
to go into the charts
and study it with this premise in mind
go into it looking to disprove what i'm
saying
and you're going to shock yourself
because it's there it's been there all
this time
and until i started talking about it no
one paid any attention to it
so until we talk next time be safe