foreign
all right folks welcome back
for those that don't know this is me
doing a
revamp of an old 2014
video series i did by the same title
mark maker series i did 12 videos
in that series and i was long-winded in
most of those
installments so with the backdrop of
all of the supportive studies on this
youtube channel
it's been my
interest to revisit that series and kind
of like polish it up a little bit
and with that perspective in mind
hopefully i'll be able to deliver
something that's
much more meaningful and impactful to
your trading
especially for those that have been with
me for a long time
uh newer students to have acquired over
the
last six months or so may be
impressed by the level of
insight that this series will bring them
but i also want to begin with something
that is important to know
there's a lot of market maker
buzzwords that are making the rounds on
youtube
on instagram all over social media
facebook
telegram everywhere and
the bulk of what you're seeing
regurgitated
actually came from this series here
or it came from my 1996 lecture nights
which
again
many people have taken pieces
of what i've taught over almost the last
three decades
and tried to come up with their own
little interpretation
and all of them have been found wanting
it's my goal here to try to
present this in a manner that is
concise succinct and to the point as
best as i possibly can and not
try to gloss over too much and make it
of no use
so while i won't have 12 videos
i am going to go through that series and
pull out everything and put them
in the proper context the proper order
so that way everything that should have
been
understood and more because this is a
revamp of it
hopefully will be delivered by me in
these five videos
this first volume is understanding the
macro
all right before we get into the nuts
and bolts of all this
who is the market maker now obviously
i'm saying that with
my tongue and cheek but who is it
who is the market maker
well the central banks are the producer
of currency prices
and are the market maker
central banks establish and manage a
country's currency price
at all times both autonomously and
manually
currency prices are 100 controlled and
manipulated
by central banks
investment bank dealers goldman sachs
ubs city or
brokers are not
market makers now they're commonly
calling themselves
i'm a market maker i'm an ex-market
maker at goldman sachs i'm an ex-market
maker at ubs i'm an ex-market maker at
credit twist all these guys are dealers
okay or ladies indifference through the
women
they're not market makers okay if we're
talking about
the currency markets forex the central
bank
is the market maker everybody deals
and trades and exchanges on their
product
their product is the price of the
commodity or currency
they make that price buyers and sellers
do not make that price
we only exchange at the price fee that's
given to us
dealers and brokers do business with the
price fees set and delivered by central
banks
dealers and or brokers do not set or
control currency prices
central banks are not following retail
indicators or flawed
retail logic examples being they do not
and the algorithms do not consider why
golf
harmonic elliott wave vsa or volume
spread analysis
supply and demand zones etc no matter
what it is
that you may subscribe to as a trader
none of that is considered when the
central bank algorithms
deliver price reprice or hold in
consolidation
it's just the facts
central banks employ high-tech
algorithms to deliver currency price
fees
and they do not run on supply and demand
i'm going to repeat this one central
banks
employ high-tech algorithms to deliver
currency price feeds
and they do not not
not okay and let me press it so many
times
it's important you understand this that
supply and demand
has no bearing on the delivery of
currency prices period
now with all that said let's dive deep
understand the macro now when you're
considering market maker concepts
real market maker concepts you have to
start with quantitative analysis
okay a quantitative analysis is
something that's
statistical it's measurable it's not
subjective
it's not left for interpretation like
looking at a trend
is a trend still bullish or is it
bearish you ask
20 different traders on multiple
different time frames
they're all going to come with with a
different interpretation of whether it's
bullish or bearish
okay that's subjective that's
qualitative
okay we'll get into qualitative analysis
but for now
we have to start with quantitative
analysis and that means
something that is measurable it's
statistical
and it's not up for interpretation it's
pretty much straightforward
when you're doing quantitative analysis
you're asking essentially the first
question being what should the market be
experiencing at the present
like right now when you're sitting down
in front of your charts what are you
expecting
price to be experiencing in terms of
bullish or bearish is the market bullish
or bearish
you have to have a way of determining
that
how do you get that information what
derives
that answer or whether it's bullish or
bearish
so where do you find that information
well the first is global interest rates
now this address here is just an
additional link
but if you go to
www.globalhyphenrates.com
it'll take you through very simple
prompts on the
page that link specifically though you
want to bookmark that one
okay and whenever you do your
quantitative analysis you can refer to
the global rates
and the other being commitment of
traders and you can find that
on barchart.com now these are just
suggested
websites that if you google and you do
some
your own leg work you may find that
there are other
websites out there that you're more
inclined to
use or warm up to these are just simple
generic websites that will provide the
information for you
for free you don't need to subscribe to
anybody's service
you don't need to be a part of any
specific platform this information is
100 percent free
it's just a click and research and
that's it
the global interest rates are the
quote-unquote
fundamental driver that sets the tone
for
long-term macro price movement
the commitment of traders shows you a
visual representation
of what smart money is doing and how
they're positioned
periodically now by blending these two
elements it gives you a real
measurable and quantitative perspective
on what smart money is doing or
in this case what market makers are
interpreting
price on a long-term basis
that's how you start with the question
of what's bullish what's bearish
notice i'm not talking about trend lines
i'm not talking about moving averages
i'm not looking for any of those types
of things this is what
interbank traders concern themselves
with this is what they're looking at
how do you plan your analysis well by
looking at these two specific
points of interest you're going to come
up with a buy
program or a cell program very simple
now what does that really mean though
well let's go further
when you go to barchart.com we're going
to assume that we're going to be pulling
up
a currency and we'll use japanese yen
here as an example
you're going to see that they have a
select commodity tab when you click that
tab the drop down menu will appear you
scroll down to currencies and you pick
the currency that you're
interested in studying in this case
we're gonna use
japanese yen you click on that
your browser will take you to this page
here what you're looking for
is every one of these particular
lines aren't necessarily one that you're
going to be
picking the top you're going to be
looking for the one that has the highest
open interest
so it's the line directly underneath
this one the top one
is cash you can't plot the commitment of
traders
data on a cash chart you got to use a
futures chart
so the highest open interest rate now is
the september contract for 2021
and you can see the open interest is 196
469 contracts that means that's the open
interest
or available open interest that's in
that particular
contract month after september's
contract expires
because we're talking about futures here
it would roll over to december 2021
and the open interest would rise from
958 to whatever the highest open
interest would be
before it expires and then once december
2021 expires
it would roll over to march 2022 where
it only has six
in the open interest slot now that would
only increase
considerably after the december contract
starts the midway point of its life
cycle
when you have this page here you would
be clicking obviously on the second one
which is september 2021
once that occurs this is the page it
would take you to
and look at the upper left hand corner
where it says interactive
chart you would click that link at this
point here
and it would give you this chart once
you're on this chart
you're going to go to the little tab
that says
plus study when you click on that you're
going to
see an option to put in an indicator
okay when i say that
i understand that we're not looking at
something like an rsi or a stochastic or
a cci
none of that stuff is useful okay you
don't need any of that
but the commitment of traders you're
going to type that out commitment
traders and by the time you put in
com it'll offer that as the option
you just click on it and then once you
click on it it'll open up this little
window
you're going to click on the little
eyeball next to small specs
and that'll put a line through it and
then you'll click
the add button when you do that
you'll get the commitment traders graph
applied to your chart it'll post it on
the bottom of the chart
you can toggle to the top of the chart
or leave it at the bottom
historically it's always been seen
underneath price
charts but we'll get to that in a minute
the other link i gave you is
globalhyphenrates.com
and once you go to that website and you
click on interest rates and
you know the central bank's breakdown or
summary of current interest rates
page will open up this is basically what
it looks like
now each one of these columns
are active in the way that if you click
on it it'll sort it like a spreadsheet
now if you click on the country or
region it will put it in alphabetical
order
if you click on current rate it'll do it
from high to low or low to high vice
versa
or if you want to know which one's
changing direction
for going up or going down you can
toggle that and it'll list it
by that way as well or you can
do a search on how the rate was
previously and when the last time that
rate was changed at the central bank
level
for now the only thing i want you to
focus on is
toggling clicking this
and then sorting them by high to low
okay so or low to high doesn't make a
difference
but you want it in a
list that increases or decreases so that
way you can find things rather
quickly now there are some countries in
here that i'm not interested in
for instance the israeli interest rate
i'm not interested in trading that i'm
not
interested in the polish interest rate
i'm not interested
in the czech interest rate or the
hungarian interest rate
what i'm looking for is like the majors
like the swiss franc
the japanese yen
european interest rate from the ecb
bridge pound for great britain
obviously the fed from united states
canada's bank rate new zealand's bank
rate
so it's basically the majors all right
so
australia is another one in here it's
the australian dollar
so you have all the majors in here and
what their respective
current interest rate is
now when you're looking at the interest
rates
you want to toggle them obviously
however you want to sort them
you want to sort them by specific
country you can click on this and it'll
toggle all the
countries by alphabetical orders that
way you can find the
majors that are coupled with the dollar
or a cross of your choice
quicker that way and then visually go
right over to where the interest rate is
at the moment
now i'm going to talk to you about
interest rate differentials
what is an interest rate differential
well it's the difference obviously
between
one country's interest rate versus
another and why is that important
well the importance is that on a central
bank level
and an interbank level large flows
seek yield and that means that they're
always
looking for a rate of return
now would you rather be in a country
that has an interest rate of five
percent
or would you rather be in a country that
has an interest rate of
two percent in other words you have the
ability to make five percent
or two percent which one would you put
your money in
well hopefully you would be considering
the five percent
well large flows and large
interest and yield and speculation they
think the same way
so how do you get the information on
which country has the highest yield this
list right here
and obviously as a foreign exchange
trader that you're aspiring to be or
maybe you are you're just not finding
consistency this will give you
the foundation to finding real markets
that are
really engineered to go a particular
direction
but you have to look for something
specific
and that's the differential so it's not
enough to simply look for a
high yielding interest rate country
you need to find a high interest rate
yielding countries currency
and couple it with a weak currency
for example if you look at japan right
here okay the japanese interest rate
for the central bank of japan its
interest rate is negative
point one zero
now in this list if we found a currency
that has a high
yielding interest rate relative to that
negative 0.10
from japan we'll look at the fed's
current interest rate at 0.25 percent
so there's a differential between the
two
the higher interest rate is with the fed
or the american dollar
versus the japanese yen
meaning the differential is positive
for dollar and negative for yen
now since we have that fundamental
backdrop
on the interest rate front we know now
we can go into
the commitment of traders chart and
we're looking at the dollar index now
typically i don't really like to put
the commitment traders graph on the
dollar index
and the reason why is because many times
it could look
like this where it doesn't really give
you a whole lot of information in this
format now there's a way to
obviously change this and draw more
information from it but majority time it
looks like this
and it won't give you the movement above
the zero basis line now the zero basis
line
what we're interested in is the red line
that's the commercials the commercials
we'll just
call them the central banks okay
when they go above the zero line that
doesn't necessarily mean
it's a buy and
just because they're below the zero
basis line
doesn't mean that the dollar index is
going to go down
what we're looking for is a combination
of interest rate differential
and the highest
long position net long or
lowest net short position held by the
commercials
now since we're looking at the dollar
index and we're thinking in terms of it
being a
higher interest rate which is
you know it's really not that high of an
interest rate it's only a quarter
percent
but in relationship and contrast to the
rate of the bank of japan
being negative point one zero
dollar has the better interest rate so
what we're looking for is a time when
the dollar has
the commercials being above the zero
line
we see that here in the latter portions
of 2020
in december into january notice that the
red line is higher than it's ever been
in the past few years so they're net
long here
higher than they have been in recent
time at this moment
in the chart now this by itself is
bullish
only if we see the opposite with the
japanese yen
because remember what we're doing is
we're matching up a strong fundamental
interest rate differential against
a weak interest rate differential
that being dollar versus yen so if we
take a look at the yen
you can see as we crossing from december
into january 2021
the commercials have never been this net
short in order they're thinking that
it's overbought and it's likely to go
down at this point right there
so anytime in the past in this chart
they've never been as bearish or below
the zero line
as they were right here and
by itself it doesn't mean anything you
want to see a
break in market structure and if you
look at this swing low right there
you see a low with a higher load to the
left and a higher load to the right
many of you to understand market
structure would be looking at this low
being broken and that's the market
structure break
for you that's not what it is for me
this is a
swing low the highest of all these
candles
up here until it finally broke down this
being broken there is a market structure
shift or break from me
once this occurs then all of the
understanding of this outline for you
where
it's bearish for yen bullish
for dollar and the interest rate
differential will now kick in
then the algorithms will start to
reprice
yen lower and dollar higher or
consolidate dollar
presently we've been seeing dollar
consolidated but yen has been allowed to
reprice lower
so how's that translate to a 4x chart
well here we have the dollar yen because
when we're pairing the weaker against
the stronger using these differentials
the two currencies are dollar and yen
so the pair name is dollar yen
and that's what we're employing here for
the charting purposes the chart is
plotted
on the basis of us dollars versus
japanese yen
and we're using the stronger fed rate
versus the weaker
japanese rate so this translates into
expectations that it would be bullish
for this chart because dollar should be
going up
while yen drops and it would be
basically bearish yen thus
dollar yen should be expected to rally
higher
and we obviously see that here here's
december
crossing into january short term high
broken so then we have a break in market
structure now the algorithm will reprice
dollar higher against yen and that's
what you see here
now this is not a small move folks this
is pretty significant
but this in itself is the basis to
understanding how to find
markets that should be moving in one
direction
but you're doing it in a way that is
done like an interbank trader
it's not some willy-nilly guy that puts
tdi
indicators on his chart calling all
kinds of moving averages
and chasing price we're looking for
real measurable and quantitative means
of determining what these markets are
going to do it's not hypothetical
it's not subjective it's
very specific things that you're looking
for
and you go in looking for these types of
moves to be
the foundation to majority of your
trades now if you trade in this
direction
and you're buying you can be a
short-term trader being a buyer you can
be a day trader
you can be a scalper you can be a
position trader
swing trader every facet of
trading disciplines can be employed by
being bullish on
dollar yen
okay now we're going to be looking at
the interest rate differential
in the cad yen this is going to be a
case study for it
so we're going to be looking again at
the japanese yen
which is a weak interest rate negative
0.10 and the canadian dollar has a
interest rate the same of what we
referred to in the dollar index it has
the same rate
so right away you should know that it
should be bullish canadian dollar
bearish japanese yen but we have to go
behind the scenes and go do a
quantitative
analysis on what the actual positions
are by the smart money because the
commitment traders gives us a graphic
depiction
of their real trading of their real
positions
it's not just well this should be
bullish
or this should be bearish okay that's
the
precursor the interest rate differential
is the precursor
it doesn't mean just because one
interest rate is higher than the other
that the chart is going to be anytime
you sit down in front of it
it's a good buy or a good sell relative
to that differential
you need to know that that is just the
fundamental backdrop or underpinnings in
the marketplace
then you have to wait for smart money to
position themselves
then once that's there the algorithm
will reprice
all right we're looking at the canadian
dollar futures market this is the
september 2021 contract
on barchart.com and this is the symbol
you would use to see it
okay and plotting the commitment of
traders
now if you recall back on the
globalrates.com or globalhyphenrates.com
website when we were looking at canadian
dollar you probably didn't
notice it since i didn't mention it i
apologize but if you
go back to that list or rewind the video
rewatch it or whatever
you'll see that in march of 2020
it showed that it dropped
about half a percent from 0.75
down to 0.25 percent so it's a quarter
percent
from three quarters of percent so
the interest rate actually dropped a
half percent
in march of 2020 just from
looking at it from face value some would
say oh that's not good
because the interest rates are dropping
it doesn't make a difference here
because what we're looking at is the
differential
0.25 is still better than negative 0.10
so when we look at march here
this deep dive down in price
it happens around the same time that the
interest rate announcement comes out
and even though the interest rate
dropped a half a percent
it's still a positive interest rate
versus a negative interest rate that's
seen in japan
so right in here when price is
consolidating look what's occurring here
we have a big buildup of net long
positions by the commercials they're
above the zero line so they're bullish
okay so they're bullish at the time
when the interest rate differential is
positive for canadian negative for yen
later on as we get into the end of 2020
we move from bullish to negative below
the zero level
this swing down doesn't change it being
bullish
it just means that we're in a strong
trend and these relative equal highs up
here
and some of you that are new to think
that this isn't equal it's relative
okay it's we'd look for this to be taken
out
okay in other words there's a lot of buy
stops up there just like this
is relatively equal highs but it didn't
take long for it to get
above that there but from a long-term
perspective and this
we're focusing on this high here
should be challenged and we've seen it
here
now i know some of you may be new to me
and this might seem like well this is
obvious to talk about it in hindsight
but i promise you
this stuff repeats all the time every
three months
every six months every nine months every
year okay
it works all the time but we're in
a year that followed a really
weird year because of all the illness
related things and i'm not going to say
anything more than that
but even with that this information
still
fairs out moves so we have a net long
position here
that's bullish at a time when the
interest rate has dropped
so since 2016 the negative rate on japan
hasn't been changed so we had a change
in the interest rate on the
looney or the
canadian dollar so that rate
dropped a half percent but still
remained positive
rate in contrast to what japan's rate is
negative 0.10
so we have the real positioning of the
smart money being bullish
at a time after the interest rate
announcement
and even with this drop down below the
zero line here
all that indicates is we're in a strong
trend and now they're just hedging
into until we get to this really extreme
net
short position here where that's where
the market tops out
after it runs this high and it runs the
end of its seasonal tendency and i will
count you to go back through
recent videos and again the time of this
recording
is july 26 2021
so in recent weeks or within a month or
so
i taught a lesson on seasonal tendencies
and actually talk about canadian dollar
and how the seasonal tendency for
canadian dollar
is specific around
a time of year and if you look at what
we see here
it's delivered exactly like i outlined
even in that video there
but that's for another time another
discussion let's move over to
the japanese yen again we've already
seen the chart
but we're referring to it again
so we're bearish here
and just crossing over doesn't change it
from being bearish to bullish it just
means that
the trend is strong and now they're
hedging in
as it's dropping down they're buying
into those lower lows because they sold
short up here
and to get out of the short how you have
to get out of it you have to buy it back
and that's all we're seeing here is the
smart money is buying back their heavy
net short positions from up here so
let's take a look at what that
translates to
in terms of a forex chart so the
interest rate differential on cad
yen is seen here so in november the
summer time period
you can see a market structure break
here it comes back down and starts to
rally up
and follows that underlyingly bullish
canadian dollar
bearish japanese yen and the market
rallies up
and has a significant price run of over
1200 points
so that's a significant run in price
so you can be again in any of this run
up here you could be a day trader
you can be a short-term trader you can
be a swing trader a position trader
but these large moves are what the
interbank traders
from the central bank level okay there
will be people that say
central banks don't trade no
they employ people to trade for them
they speculate
they're trying to make money in every
avenue okay they have their tentacles in
everything okay so it's not a stretch of
the imagination
to if they're going to control price and
they basically run
the whole store
who's going to police them
no bun there's never been an audit on
any central bank
you're never going to tell them they can
or can't do something
it's their game it's their role it's
their casino and they can do whatever
they want
and if they control it they have the
inside edge
they have the advantage okay so you can
be mad
you can fold your arms and hiss and
say this is unfair or you can say well
this is how they do it
and i'm going to operate like this this
is the closest that you're going to get
to it
and it works it's
extremely powerful information the
insight that it gives you
really puts you on the right side of the
marketplace and it's not just
a one-day bias it's
long-term now i don't get in positions
and hold them
from a low like in november
2020 all the way up to a high of june i
don't trade that way
and the reason why is i don't have the
patience
to do that because i'm like a dog
chasing cars
i can see a one-minute chart a
five-minute chart a 15-minute chart a
one-hour chart and see
dozens of trades all week long and if i
have a trade on
like this my personality is short term
specialized in doing in and out surgical
strikes that because i can change my
mind a lot
and i'm not saying that's a good thing
i'm just saying i've matched my personal
personality with a mode of trading that
fits
and suits me which is crucial for your
trading
but don't let that be an invitation for
you to mimic
me because some of you may be excellent
long-term position traders that you're
very committed to an idea and it takes a
lot for you to change your mind that's
the personality
characteristic that's meant for
long-term position training
but if you don't have those
characteristics and you're trying to do
it
it's like it's very miserable because
you're gonna feel like you can't you
can't do it
okay you're gonna be wanting to change
your mind all the time every little
fluctuation is gonna make you wanna
change your mind to get out of the trade
and a swing trader has a little bit
less patience than a position trader
but more patients than a short-term
trader day trader or scalper
and some of you have those
characteristics and
others are thinking well you know i like
to be in for
a week maybe three or four days and then
get out that's short-term trader
if you have less patience than that
you're probably a day trader at heart
and the way you would use this
information
is from the crossover here when we had a
market structure break
and it starts to rally again every
bullish day in here is a day where
you're trying to capture
intraday price moves a day trade
and down days may be a day that you take
a loss or you sit on your hands and wait
for a new setup
and scalping you would
put more on your trades that were in the
bullish side of things
and trade a whole lot less leverage when
you're shorting
in a move that's fundamentally
driven like this i'm not saying you
can't make money shorting in moves
that run up like this but my question is
why would you want to do that
when everything is predisposed to go
higher
okay so hopefully this first installment
has got your gears turning
and it gives you a little bit of clarity
about
the mystery that makes these markets
move around
we're going to dive a little bit deeper
into what makes these things
gyrate and go to where they want to
eventually get to
in volume 2 until then be safe