foreign
all right folks welcome back this is
volume two of the continuing series of
five parts for the ict
market maker series this installment
will be focusing primarily on
foundations to institutional order flow
and understanding liquidity
alright so when we're considering what
the
large institutions are doing and how to
operate and engage in
the foreign exchange market the premise
i want to begin my trading with
and my analysis with on the weekend is
what i think the weekly charts going to
do
and that's what we're showing here is a
weekly chart of the british pound versus
us dollar
every candle in this chart represents
the highest and lowest
price for an individual weekly range
and i sit down on my weekly chart and
look for areas that are
obvious okay what i mean by obvious
years ago i taught that if you find a
level that's too clean
okay and it's just too straight edge
chances are it's probably going to get
swept
what do i mean by that well if you look
at this
area right here
notice how this candle goes to that low
the body stops here the body stops here
it doesn't really have any kind of
jagged end or bottom to it
just real smooth and clean just like
this high
and this high has a relatively clean
level up there and these two candles
here have a really nice clean
level to it and these right here
pretty much the same thing but
my eye jumps to these levels the
significance about these levels
is that below this level here
is sell stops traders that went along
here
they had stop loss orders to protect
that long in the form of cell stops
so this level in here
is saturated with willing participants
that want to sell
at the market because their belief is if
it goes below this
level here they're probably wrong in
their long
idea and they want to get out before it
causes them to lose more money
conversely there are traders that will
see this level as support and if it
breaks
their idea is well support's broken so
it's probably bearish and they want to
go short
so how do you go short you sell so
the function of the liquidity that rests
below these
smooth or clean equal lows
is cell side in nature so it's
sell stops or sell side liquidity
the market last week at the time of this
recording it is
july 27 2021
and the market trades down last week
and sweeps below these clean
candles okay so this area here
gets attacked and notice it comes off
that
low and closes here on the week
the week at present of this recording
we opened here has small little movement
below the opening of
the week and then we had this movement
higher
now prior to this candle closing
up here we didn't really know
if it's going to go down there and
continue
going lower or if it's going to reverse
that's not necessary
to find profitability and consistent
setups all we're looking for
is runs on liquidity okay so
you have to know where the draw on
liquidity is and that's what i'm showing
you here this is what you're looking for
areas that are too clean that may
draw price up into them or down into
them
so just the opposite of what we saw down
here
what would be resting above these
relative equal highs
buy stops anyone that was short how well
trader
protect his bearish position with a buy
stop
so any movement above here that would
trigger buy stops on shorts and or
some traders that see this as resistance
if it breaks that they would see it as
what
resistance broke and therefore bullish
so this is the closest draw on liquidity
that's opposing
this so when we started the week here
we opened traded down just a little bit
and started the trade higher
where is it likely to go right above
these highs
doesn't mean it will absolutely do it
but this is what we do
we look for areas where the draw on
liquidity acts like a magnet
okay imagine how this
candle is gravitating towards this level
here
to attack and absorb the liquidity
which rests in the form of buy stops
which is opposite of what we saw down
here
so the buy stops here are the near-term
draw on liquidity so
institutional order flow for the week
should be bullish until we get up into
this area
at that moment we have to reassess
everything continuation if it's
likely or reversal if it's likely or
just consolidation
but we don't need to know that right now
that
starts the week here with the likelihood
of running up into this area
so the inability for a price to make a
significant price run lower is the tip
off that we're going to see
institutional overflow or bias
or trend or momentum to the upside until
we get into this area right here
for the purpose of attacking this buy
side
liquidity pool for the buy stops
so if you zoom in here i want you to
think about the weekly range
in the context that the open
and decline from the opening price
anywhere in this area close to the
opening price
or below it is ideal for going
long this is the cheapest it's likely to
get
and the closest you can buy around that
opening price
the better as we get closer and closer
to this area up here
the idea of probability or low risk
starts to dissipate because we have the
likelihood that this could retrace back
in
this range now the time this recording
it's only
tuesday evening in my local time on the
east coast of
the united states but
it could very easily continue and trade
well beyond
these levels here into wednesday and
thursday
maybe even friday i don't need to know
that
the premise starts with we're down here
we came off the low after taking stops
it's probably going to make a run for
this area up here for liquidity
so the ideal scenario is if i'm thinking
that that means the weekly range
is likely to be bullish or at least i'm
outlining it as that so for my
qualitative analysis
this is what i'm doing remember in the
first volume we did quantitative
analysis where there were
measures that were data oriented
this is a little bit more subjective so
that's why it's qualitative
and the idea is if i'm bullish for the
week
i'm expecting monday and tuesday and
early parts of wednesday
to be bullish until we get to an area
where the draw on liquidity
is reached
we're going to drop down to a daily
chart here you can see
monday's trading this is the candle for
the entire range of trading on monday
july 26 2021
and then tuesday's trading daily range
for july 27
2021 and notice how monday we had a nice
little
rally higher and on tuesday we opened
here
and then we traded down into this candle
right there
this candle is what i teach as a bullish
order block
the market's already bullish or the
underlying narrative
is bullish and we had a confirmation to
market wants to go higher
on monday it trades higher on tuesday we
trade
down into that level the opening price
hits it trades off of that
rallies back through and makes a higher
high
than that of on monday remember the
candle opens here
and then trades down this is a judas
swing
retail traders get caught up in that on
a lower time frame they think it's
bearish and they start selling short
and then when it hits a higher time
frame level like this that's key
or significant it'll reverse and start
to trade higher and it catches them off
guard
some of you have probably noticed that i
posted a trade
or result of a trade that i did today in
british pound
versus us dollar this very market
i'm showing you the framework in context
because i knew i was teaching this today
in the second volume of this teaching
series so i'm teaching you
on the level of my youtube content and
everyone's familiar with my
concept of the order block through this
youtube channel
using the bias that
suggests that this is likely to reach up
into
these buy stops
so anticipating its continuation into
wednesday
to attack this now does it need to do it
no because i've already been profitable
on the entry and management of tuesday's
trading
dropping down to an hourly chart that
blue line
i used on the daily chart to identify
the bullish order block level
is now green here okay so i don't want
to trip you up i just want to have a
contrast because of the time frame this
level is that same
bullish order block level on the daily
just transposed to the hourly chart
notice how the hourly chart trades down
hits it and rebounds
and starts to trade higher this is that
area where the buy stops are this level
and higher
is where those buy stops reside
so it's drawing price up there
zooming in here you can see again this
is the
daily bullish order block level and i
want you to look closer
think about what i was showing you on
the weekly chart there's clean levels
well there's singular candle lows and
highs
or swing point highs and swing point
lows or swing lows and swing highs
depending on how you want to say it they
have stops
of and below those as well
this candle right here is a case in
point
we have a swing low a single candle that
has a higher
low to the right and a higher low to the
left one single candle there that swing
low
is going to be seen as a short term
swing low where sell stops are sitting
right below that
because the markets rallied up it
consolidated rallied again
and when it's up in here all in this
consolidation those that bought down
here or even over here
they have their stop loss trail right
below that low
and the market drops down to take those
participants out
and then rallies why is it going down
there to accumulate
sell stops why are they attacking the
sales dots because this is attacking
participants that are willing to sell at
a lower price
lower than what when it was up here
institutional traders will not buy up
here they're going to wait for it to
drop down
to attack a very deep discounted price
and pool of liquidity of sellers that
want to sell at a cheap
price because they trade their stop loss
up there
so these sell stops flood the market
with sell orders
and smart money buys them at the market
so it goes right in here and buys them
so this is called pairing of orders the
market hits this
and then price rallies
now this is that same swing low zoomed
in
but i'm drawing your attention to these
consecutive down closed candles because
this is a bullish order block
the high to the opening price now why
not the entire range
like a supply and demand zone would be
well this is not supply and demand
so it's the high down to the opening
price
extend it out in time and the market
drops down into that that's a bullish
order block
and it's taking out cell stops
so a high probability order block is
when it takes out stops and returns down
to
the order block itself not every down
closed candle is a bull shoulder block
and not
every up close candle is a bare shoulder
block but if you are in a context
that is bullish as i've outlined here
and clearly proven i was trading
with this bias today
the underlying pinnings of the market is
it's bullish
so therefore down close candles to have
a market move away from it
and has a swing low just above it like
we do here
that's a confluence of specific things
that make it high probability for the
other block
the order block is the consecutive down
closed candles
all three of them make up the order
block but the sensitive price point is
the high
and the opening so you can be a buyer at
this high
or at the opening price the easiest one
is using the high and allowing your
stock to absorb
any adverse price movement against you
that would if it was going to go back
into
say the opening price you have to
consider
that when you're placing your stop so
how how does that affect your trade well
when you're starting out without
lowering any
time frame beyond the 15 time frame here
you can be buying at the high and use
the
low of all the consecutive down closed
candles your stop loss needs to be just
below that
now you may look at this and say oh no
that's too much of a stop well
that's all relative in the beginning
it's good for you to try to trade like
that
because you don't want to be trying to
be too precise because many times
the market will slice and dice you if
you're trying to be too finicky about
your
entries and your stops it can be very
easy for the marketplace to take your
two pip stop loss three pip stop loss
it can do it okay because the broker has
the
right and freedom to do that and
they will i'm not saying you can't use a
very small ultra
tight stop loss but doing it as
consistently
over and over and over again uh the
broker will just widen the spread and
take you out
and there's nothing you can do about it
so
to repeat a bullish order block that's
high probability is when the market's
already predisposed to go higher
it's shown a willingness to go higher
and leave this area here
and we have a short term low so it has
stops
in a bullish market and it trades down
below that level here and into
consecutive down closed candles so you
would be buying at the high
plus the spread and your stop will be
below this
low right there and that would be your
underlying
risk does the market stay there very
long once it trades into it no
leaves it consolidates rallies again
comes back down into another order block
here trades lower
accumulates and rallies again trades one
more time retracement and then blasts
off
and attacks all the buy stops that were
resting above these
clean highs
notice also before the market starts to
rally
it generally takes out some short-term
swing low
this low took out this swing low
each time there's a dynamic rally higher
this swing low was taken out by this
swing low and it rallies higher
this swing low is taken out by that
swing low not by much but it's all it
takes
and then it starts to move higher so
when there's a run on liquidity
that's opposed to the underlying
direction in other words
if we're bullish on a market like this
get comfortable with the market reaching
underneath lows and stop
thinking that it's going to be breaking
down entirely or reversing
most of the time you're going to find
that it's taking those cell stops out
and absorbing them to offer smart money
buying opportunities at deep discount
prices
finally we're looking at price on monday
and today
tuesday and i want you to notice how the
market does what
it creates the low in london which is
exactly what i teach on my youtube
channel
and then a continuation in new york
session
on tuesday it creates the low of the day
and a continuation in new york and it
rallies up
it's consolidating in here and where
does the liquidity reside
again this blue line is that weekly
line i drew out that was a clean level
where the buy stops are
so the market's most likely going to
draw up into that 139 big figure
139 10 and the institutional level 139
could potentially be traded too as well
to make sure it really sweeps out
all those buy stops now what's the
vested interest for the market to
send price that high because smart money
has bought
down here they bought down here
and they bought down here where do they
want to get out
at a high price who's willing to buy it
from them at a high price the buy stops
resting just above
that level here i noted on the weekly
chart
so we covered several things in here
foundations to institutional order flow
how do we frame that we look for the
weekly range we look for clean levels
very clean levels your eyes need to be
trained to look for them and the easiest
way to do that is go through back
logging and look at old historical price
moves
and mark them up on your chart that
historical study will train your eye and
activate your reticular activating
system
and that means when you see something
over and over again it makes you
sensitive to it so that way
you will start to anticipate it when you
see familiar patterns in live price
action
and it makes you better at reading the
tape reading the tape is to simply
understand what the market's doing live
or what's about to do next okay so
hopefully you found something
in this that was helpful and insightful
and i'll talk to you in the next
installment
be safe