oh
all right folks welcome back this is
volume four a continuing series of five
parts
on the inner circle trader market maker
series
i'm gonna be teaching time and price
theory
all right keeping in sync with our
present market conditions and what has
transpired this week in
pound dollar no better way to learn how
to do something than to
apply it to a chart that's actually
trading and you watch unfold this week
we have the hourly chart here on british
pound versus us dollar
and with all the things that were
mentioned covered in the previous
volumes of this series if you haven't
watched obviously
part one two and three of the series
then you should not be watching this
video yet because it's kind of
requirement before you get to this
but the backdrop behind it is we've had
smt diversions
down here we've cleared out daily
cell stops so we've accumulated we have
a market maker buy model underway
and if that's what you're expecting and
your analysis leads to
a run above these relative equal highs
and above the original consolidation
here in the market maker buy model
let's incorporate the elements of time
and price
so now i have the daily dividers on and
how i did this in case you're wondering
if you're new
all i did was create a vertical line and
dropped it on
the zero zero level
on the time axis down here that's going
to be
midnight new york time if you have your
time
it's important that you have your chart
set to new york local time
that'll make understanding what i teach
easy to follow along because your charts
will look like mine
and also you'll be looking at through
the lens of the algorithm
so new york midnight time
is delineated each day so we're looking
at obviously today's
trading in friday thursday's trading
wednesdays trading
tuesday and then finally monday's
trading of this week
now when you're looking at this go back
and
look at your notes and we've outlined
how
this week of trading july 26 2021
to july 30th 2021 was bullish
four pound dollar i made the case for
why it was bullish
i pointed to where it was going to go
how it was going to trade there and we
have it here
now in hindsight so if you look at
each individual day as
one-fifth of the weekly range each of
these days have specific characteristics
that are
repeating in nature now they're not
always exactly the same
each week but what i'm going to teach
you here i've
covered in other lessons in this youtube
channel
but for continuity sake and kind of like
bring everything that you should have
collected along your
journey through all my videos here
we're looking at the delivery of the
weekly range and if we're bullish
the expectation is that there's a 70
percent
chance that the low of the week
is going to form on monday
tuesday or by wednesday's new york
session now right away you're probably
thinking oh that's
that's a pretty wide envelope of time
you got a lot of ways to you get it
wrong
well consider what we have here we have
monday's trading
we're already in a consolidation and we
left the consolidation
so is it likely to come back down
and go below this low here when it's
already taken out a low
there remember what i've taught you so
far in this series
before price movements that are
directionally driven
typically opposing stop losses
will be taken and then price will be
allowed to deliver
in your expected direction in layman's
terms
if you're bullish look for swing lows to
get traded below
and then it starts to move higher short
term low
trades below it then it starts to trade
higher okay
each day of this week was
predominantly bullish until we get to
friday obviously that ends the week
so if we look at a open high low close
perspective of the week we see the week
opening here
small little movement lower creating the
low of the week on monday
a retracement and a buying opportunity
on tuesday a retracement buying
opportunity on wednesday
and then thursday creating a short-term
high of the week
and then friday we went just above the
thursday high but not by much
and then we traded off the high and
we're probably going to close
anywhere between 139 20 and 139 big
figure
okay so going back to what i mentioned
here and what i've taught in other
lessons on this youtube channel is that
we want to be buying on monday
tuesday and at the best case scenario if
we missed buying opportunities on monday
and tuesday
we want to try to buy on wednesday in
the new york session okay
but we'll talk more about other things
that were factors
this week as we go into the series in
part five but
for now i want to bring in the opening
price each day
here at midnight so we have this opening
price here extended out in time
how far is this going out it's just
showing until 10 a.m
you can take it out till 11 a.m which
basically is the heart of london close
so the idea is if you're bullish you
want to be buying at or below
or very close to the opening price
each day we see it trade below the
opening price and rallies up
day here opens and trades down all
through london
and then rallies higher on the day
opening price here
we initially start to go higher but then
we trade down below it
and then we have another whip saw below
the low here on fomc
and then trades higher and then on
thursday we're not incorporating the
opening price on thursday and this is
for your notes make sure you
write this down we're only looking for
the influence
of the opening price and buying below or
at it
in a bullish expected week on monday
tuesday and wednesday
thursday and friday they tend to create
the opposite end of the weekly range
okay so try not to be looking to be a
buyer on thursday
try not to be a buyer on friday with the
weekly range expectation if you do that
you're going to miss trades yes but by
far and large you're going to protect
yourself
by avoiding being a buyer in a market
move it's already been moving
okay obviously there's going to be days
where it just continues on thursday and
then friday really explodes even higher
i've seen it happen in my own trading
i've missed pretty big moves on friday
but i generally keep a small piece on as
i
illustrated this week with trading the
fomc
day so i bought on this day i bought on
this day here
and i recorded and shared the fmc trade
and put it on my telegram channel
you can see that and left a small piece
on it got me out at 139.50 on a limit so
you can design this
any way you want you can create a model
where you get in
on a tuesday after you've seen monday
prove that it's wanting to go higher and
then trades down below some short-term
low
picks up the stops and we have optimal
trade entry here
and you can be a buyer there and
basically allow money to trade without
you
or if you're hardcore and you're in
consolidation like this and you think
you are in a
move where it's here and you start to go
higher rate from monday's beginning of
trading
then obviously you can put a small
little position on there
and then consider maybe taking a larger
position once you have a better
confirmation of the weekly range
unfolding to the upside and a
retracement down
as a new student or a new trader when
you see a day like this
and most of you probably have one in
five minute charts up on your chart
you see this decline like it's heart
stopping
especially if you don't have any
experience you're thinking there's no
way i could be a buyer or that
well we have relative equal highs the
bottom line is it's going down to pick
up the sell stops
flood the market with sell stops
allowing smart money to buy those sell
stops
and then it takes off and goes higher
each day or this week
between monday and wednesday is offered
a buying opportunity
to get us above our target that was
established for the weekly range
was trading above here for the buy stops
so let's strip this down and go a little
bit closer
so we're zoomed in on an hourly chart
you can see here's monday's trading
tuesday's trading sweeping below that
short term low there
and rallying and we drop down here on
fomc wednesday
it starts to come down and give us a
buying opportunity here but then on
fomc two o'clock in the afternoon new
york time
the market whips down knocking out
traders that would have already
trailed their stop loss right below that
low it gets
tagged and then it runs aggressively
higher above that
original consolidation which is that red
line here so above that red line
is our buy stops that we were aiming for
that i started teaching you about in
earlier parts of the series
in the earlier portion of the week
then ultimately we trade creating a
short-term high on thursday
slightly higher on friday and then
profit-taking
model kicks in and you can see it
returning back to
that original consolidation
study the relationship of the opening
price at midnight in new york time
and how buying below that opening price
is ideal this is where smart money
accumulates longs
this is where smart money accumulates
longs and this is where smart money
accumulates longs
they distribute their longs on thursday
and friday if it offers higher prices
and then you expect price to come off
that and trade back down into the range
which is the highest high formed
intra-week
to the low and we're seeing that here
now if you look at it on a 15-minute
time frame
i'm going to incorporate day of week and
time of day
here's that opening price at midnight
the market trades down creating the low
in london
rallies comes back down in for an
optimal trade entry
if you don't know what optimal trade
entry is there is lots of videos on this
youtube channel
and you can study and find out what that
is it's a really simple pattern repeats
all the time
so it creates an awful tradition right
there you can be a buyer there
and then trades back down again we have
a short term low here
and a short term low here and this low
is during
new york open so short term low here
to high down in and taking out a short
term low
what's occurring they're taking out
short term stops right below here
and optimal trade entry rallies in new
york and continues higher
the next day the market trades back down
into the range that was established
in the previous day this right here is
the reason why
most of the time i'm leaving monday's
trading to
everyone else because if i establish
along here
and it starts to rally up i may make the
mistake of
trailing my stop-loss up to here and
then they take it on tuesday and then i
gotta go back in and reposition myself
so i wanna study on monday what they do
and then
on tuesday generally that's my action
day
and you can see there's a lot more
animation in price on tuesday
but look what they do they drop it down
into london creating the low of the day
taking out this short term low again the
previous day
and if you look at the low to high
you're getting optimal trade entry there
the key is ote or optimal trade entry
is associated with time of day
a kill zone these little hyphenated
segments of annotation on the charts
london is delineated by 2 a.m to 5 a.m
new york time so again if you're setting
your time on trading view to
local new york time always set it to
that no matter what
location you are in the world always
look at trading view
through the lens of new york period
if you do that everything i teach you
will make perfect sense you won't be
confused
but london kill zone is two o'clock in
the morning to five a.m
new york is seven a.m to ten a.m
and if you want to use the new york
session time
not the new york kill zone the new york
session time is 8 30 in the morning till
11 a.m new york time
but each turning point that occurs at
these kill zones
sets up a really nice run in price see
that little short term low right there
it trades down below it and takes off
so we're seeing this element of time
which is also associated with the day of
the week because
day of the week is still an element of
time
it's a it's a calendar reference point
to time
it's a block of time that we call
monday tuesday wednesday and so forth
so the element of time and price is
important because
you need to focus and expect your
analysis
to be rooted on the first element which
is time
the markets will not generally give you
setups that pan out
between these two windows
there'll be a quiet little period even
though we have a nice run in here
sometimes that will occur
most of the time it won't be like that
it'll be consolidation
and then after running close you get
these consolidations like this
this is like dead time again same here
dead time same here dead time
so we're looking to engage if we're
bullish like we were
teaching in this series pound dollars
bullish
monday creates the low of the week
tuesday creates a buying opportunity
new york on wednesday nice buying
opportunity but you have to have a wide
stop
and if you get stopped out here you can
use
obviously other approaches to getting
involved
with the marketplace with fomc but i'm
going to teach you
and remind you that you should not be
trying to trade fomc if you're a
developing student
because it's too much of a whipsaw and
you're going to get caught up with the
short-term volatility
and you're going to be more paralyzed by
fear even with a demo account
and left confused than that of if you
just simply study it from the sidelines
and don't engage it at all
okay but the element of time is the
first
crucial factor to reading price
price when it gets to these levels
that we look for below the opening price
okay what price is important below the
opening price
what time of day during london open this
these are buying opportunities here
this low trading below this low is a
reference in terms of
price by itself doesn't mean anything
sometimes you can see a short term low
like this
we have these lows here all three of
them one two three look at this we went
down below it
so that's one of those times where ict
talks about oh this is when
we went below the lows and expect price
to blast off
no because we're inside of a time window
that's not
important it's not salient to the
underlying
bias because it's dead the
time when the algorithm is sitting still
it's going to just
mark time it's all it's doing going
sideways just like it does here
and like it does here okay so the
element of time
is crucial because that's when the
market will
start to spool that means the market
will start unraveling
in one direction or another just start
shooting off into a specific direction
aiming for a particular price but
when you're looking for price to behave
a certain way
it needs to be inside of one of these
kill zones for the highest probability
after running close each day you should
train yourself to anticipate
consolidation unless we get something
like fomc
days which is obviously you know this is
something that is not an every week
instance but you need to be looking at
your academic calendar because if you
don't
you'll be caught off guard with these
types of events and
either want to be protecting yourself by
not being in the marketplace or taking
considerable amount of your position off
ahead of it
so that way if it does reverse on you
you've paid yourself
but time is the first element keying up
on
monday tuesday or wednesday for your
trading now this is a bearish week
same thing we'd be expecting a high to
form on monday tuesday or wednesday by
new york session
but after wednesday's new york session
probabilities start to fall off
precipitously about catching
shorts or trying to nail the high the
day when you're in bearish market
environments
this week we're going to stick with the
narrative that we've outlined initially
is that this week was bullish we've
outlined why
i gave you examples on telegram
and i showed you the fruits of it
using this information this little
exclamation point is just highlighting
the release of fomc data
okay this is two o'clock in the
afternoon new york time
expect the volatility and even though we
had
the run below these lows here and start
the rally up this is classic fomc
this is exactly what non-farm payroll
does generally too
so if this was 8 30 in the morning on
friday on non-farm payroll
this is what you would expect to see on
non-farm payroll if you're in an
underlyingly bullish market
same scenario so i'm but i digress
so looking at this from the element of
time and price
we know how to group an expectation
and perception of analysis when we look
at
time we know there's so there should be
something occurring
but we have to anticipate that something
rooting it to the bias what's the bias
do we think the weekly range is going to
be higher or lower
we don't care about that weekly closing
price i don't care where it's going to
close
where is the volatility going to send
price mostly higher
or mostly lower over the course of the
days of this week
if i'm thinking bullish i'm going to be
focusing on monday tuesday and wednesday
because i know the algorithm generally
presents the
really choice setups if it's bullish to
be a buyer on monday tuesday and or
wednesday but
by wednesday's new york session now
because wednesday had a high volatility
news driver with fomc at two o'clock in
the afternoon
that gives us a little bit more energy
likely
after two o'clock on fmc's release
and we see that happen here and it rolls
over into thursday's trading and
so on but knowing
where you should be trying to buy if
you're bullish you're trying to get
below the opening price at midnight
that's that's a threshold
that makes your trade higher in
probability
doesn't guarantee profitability it just
means it's higher probability
that you're buying a really cheap market
and you're buying it when smart money
buys it
you're looking at prices that trade
either to an optimal trade entry to an
order block or runs out
stops if we're bullish
when you're trading your your plan okay
you have to have plan right
the plan is every time you create a
short term low
notice to see if it does a run below
that while you're bullish
inside of one of these kill zones
relative equal lows you see that you
trade down below that
in london and below the opening price by
itself that's a buy
now you probably won't trust that
because you want to have indicators you
want to have moving averages
you want to have all these other things
that you put your faith in
all that faith that you established on
retail logic
and indicators and harmonic this and
supply zone that
just reappropriate those
faith tendencies only what i'm showing
you here because this is the truth
it's not about me okay it's not it's not
true because michael says it
it's true because this is the truth and
i'm just the
sounding board for it okay once you
understand this
and you start studying it like this
you're gonna see
it's always been there always
but these three days and this element of
time
that is crucial and what price where's
the price
factor in price is when you're taking
out stops returning to an order block or
an optimal trade entry
that's it there's three little things
there okay three little things that you
need to worry about
and not all three form at the same time
so you need not worry about well how do
i know if it's going to do this and how
do i know if it's going to do that
well look at you have a low here forming
and then it trades down below it again
that might be what you're waiting for
for your model you may not want to trade
older blocks you may not want to trade
optimal trade entries
you just want to see a low and then wait
and see if it runs below that low
during london at a time when we're
bullish on a tuesday
or wednesday and you could be a buyer
there expect price to rally up to
10 o'clock to noon which is london close
and that's usually when it's the
opposite end of the daily range don't
take my word for it go through your
charts and study it
that's what the algorithm will generally
try to do
on mondays tuesdays and wednesdays when
the market is
predominantly bullish for the week
now obviously if there's an objective
that we're looking for on the week and
it hits it on tuesday okay so we
bullish on monday and tuesday it rallies
up say it went above
that red line which is that that buy
stop
liquidity pool that i've outlined
earlier in this series
and say it ran through that 20 30 pips
that would mean we have the potential
for the market to go into consolidation
the rest of the week or have a deep
retracement
whereas we see on tuesday we didn't get
to the high yet and sweep those stops
yet
on wednesday we didn't get to it until
here after fmc
but did it do it convincingly above no
it just went
really lightly above shallow shallow run
right there
and then later in the day when nobody's
really paying attention
it starts to rally straight on up
so you gotta factor the element of price
for where you think price is going to
reach for
so time and price theory you're blending
these things together to come up with a
narrative that you want to follow and
you want to see if price is sticking
to that narrative that you've outlined
or
scenario i guess it would be a better
analogy you're creating a scenario where
you think
based on these times of the day and
these days of the week
and the logic that this market's likely
to go higher to where
that weekly by stop liquidity pool
i've outlined in this series that we've
been harping on
every time we had a video
we're watching how all these things come
together to give
us a narrative that is delivering in
price
and nothing here's random it's exactly
how it should be
if it's bullish when should it create a
low to go higher
in one of these if not all of them
london and new york kill zones
just look at the chart right here these
windows of
time i taught this over 10 years ago
for free right on baby pips taught it
and they still worked today they were
working before i taught it
they're going to keep working okay the
reason why is because the flows that
come in
at that time of the day creates the
opportunity
for the algorithm to move around the
flows or buying volume and selling
volume
is not moving price the algorithm
is operating on the time window it knows
the
trading volume increases then it's not a
derivative
of okay lots of buyers are coming in so
i'm gonna
start seeing price go higher because of
that no that's not what it is
and i don't care who told you otherwise
it's not what's going on
these markets are absolutely manipulated
controlled
period the
the state of a country's economy
and the solvency of a central bank
is not going to be put in the hands okay
of
reddit i mean if everybody around the
world said hey look
here's what we're going to do we're all
going to buy the british pound
and we're going to keep buying and no
matter what
you really think that's going to be the
catalyst for the british pound to go up
and keep on going up
no matter what no way
but if you read social media today
that's what they want you to believe
that stocks are going to go to the moon
because
a handful of people on reddit are buying
it that's not
what these markets are doing okay these
are
the commodity these are the products
of a central bank their business is to
control
everything everything
and we as traders will never absolutely
never ever ever push price higher or
lower
because of buying and selling pressure
it's not going to happen
if they don't want to go higher it
doesn't matter how many people buy it
it isn't going higher that's it
so on the latter part of the week you
can see here on
wednesday's fmc we rolled into
thursday's trading
nice little optimal trade entry here on
london sticking to the theme
and we ran up 80 pips above
the 139 big figure the 139 10 level is
where that bicep liquidity pool was
basically linked to on the weekly chart
so we went 70 pips
above that that's a pretty good run and
here it is
we're on thursday in new york session
and then finally
london close creates the high the day
starts to drift lower
and then finally one more pump up in
london
on friday running just a little bit
above thursday's high
and then we have a breakdown and we'll
look at that on a five minute chart
but we'll look at that when we get into
the last part of the series
but each day has signatures that it
follows responds to in terms of time
and price it's not
something that is random it's
fitting specific logic that
has been taught in this youtube channel
i can't take
over 100 some different videos and
compress it into one
video and say this is all the moving
parts all at one time
but everything i'm showing you here has
been amplified in other teachings
introduced obviously in teachings and
also
shown by example and now here it is
again
being shown to you where it's still
working we're going to take a closer
look
into lower time frames in the final
volume on this
series until then be safe