welcome back folks this is lesson seven
of the ICT day trading model
high probability day trade setups
okay what makes day trades high
probability
the highest importance is placed on the
HTF daily and or four hour
Direction
when daily and or four hour direction is
bullish
use previous days low to high for
retracement entries
use previous days NewYork session low
to high
retracement entries
use previous days low
for Sell stop raid to accumulate lungs
focusing on the anticipated move from
HTF discount to premium PD
arrays
when daily and or four hour direction is
bearish
use previous days high to low for
retracement entries use previous day's
NewYork session high to low for
retracement entries
use previous days high for buy stop rate
accumulate shorts
focusing on the anticipated move from
the HTF premium to
Discount PD arrays
when we're looking for a high
probability day trades what we're really
focusing on is where's the next most
likely Direction higher or lower
and off of what level and trading up to
what level for a profit
there's several swings that you need to
be aware of obviously the previous day
is high and low
the previous days NewYork session
range from high to low that means the
sessions highest high and the lowest low
during the NewYork trading hours
there's also one that's not listed here
but I want you to think about
what's the highest high and the lowest
low
during the London session
that means the London
high in the London low
for the Elena Killzone
then also looking at the London high or
low
to the low or high contrary to it in
other words the total range from the
London session extreme whether it be
high or low
to the lower high prior to the NewYork
session beginning
so between
NewYork opening
what's the extreme on the range for that
day in London is it high or low relative
to the beginning of NewYork session
that range also is important
when we look through price and we find
the opportunities to be a day trader
you're looking for the similar things
we've went over on a HTF
charts just on a lower time frame
nothing that you see in the lower time
frame is going to be any different from
what we've outlined from what we've seen
in the daily or weekly or monthly
every example
that's being outlined here for framing a
high probability setup
this is not the Panacea list okay this
is this is not going to be every
possible scenario
these are the criterias that I look for
each trading day when the conditions are
ripe so in other words I've done my
due diligence if you will from the
HTF and I've arrived at
what I believe is the most probable
Direction
on a HTF chart
and then what I'll look for is if I'm
bullish I want to look for the range
from London's extreme high or low to
that which
the opposite extreme higher low would be
prior to NewYork so whatever the range
is from London
to right before NewYork opening
that's important I want to measure that
range if I'm bearish
that range is going to help me find the
next trading day
retracement up
during that protractionary state that
move up is going to be a retracement
into that London session range from
London going into the beginning of New
York
I'll also measure the NewYork session
range high and low
that also many times will give me the
setup that's framed for the next day's
higher low it'll be retracement inside
that range
I'll look for the previous days high and
low
to look for stop rates
generally you're going to see those
scenarios occur when there is
an end to a most recent move in other
words if we've seen several days go up
it's going to go up into a premium array
and it's probably going to trade above
an old High
I'll look for a buy stock run there and
then go short the next day
vice versa
if the Market's been trading lower and
it trades down to a discount PD array
I'll look for the market to trade down
below a previous day's low
I'll buy the sell stops
and I'll use that as a day trade
daily and four hour when we use those
independently or in concert with one
another to build our bearish or bullish
ideas
what we're looking for is the price
analysis of seeing is price supporting
bullishness are the is it bouncing off
of bull shoulder blocks is it rejecting
old lows and and showing them
willingness to go higher is it filling
in gaps below us and then rallying
those ideas are the first things that we
look for and then are we seeing
short-term premium arrays violating
if that's occurring then it's bullish
institutional workflows is bullish and
the opposite is said in Reverse when
you're bearish
when do I look to buy for day trades
ideally in seasonal periods of the year
but it's not required but ideally it has
to make the list in here because this is
the high probability series
when the current quarter or new quarter
is expected to be bullish
after the daily chart has reacted
positively on a discount PD array it
could be a bull shorter block any of the
discount arrays that's known to You by
The pdra Matrix
when price has a clear
unobscured path to an opposing premium
array in other words it's very easily
seen what it would reach for above you
presently
if you can't see it very easily
it's probably not going to be a high
probability setup
the ideal days of the week buying are
Monday Tuesday and Wednesday
you will refer to the central bank
dealers range and determine if it's less
than 40 Pips ideally
and we're going to demand that the Asian
range is in a 20 pip range or less ahead
of Frankfurt opening
buying between 2 AM and 4 AM NewYork
time we're going to be seeking the low
of the day
we're going to be buying it one to two
StandardDeviation of the Central Bank
dealers range and or Asian range coupled
with a discount PD array
time frame we're going to execute on is
a 15 and or a five minute chart
now where do I look to buy for day
trades
I like buying Under the Asian range plus
five Pips for the spread
I like looking for fair value gaps below
a short-term low from the previous days
NewYork session in other words after
NewYork opens up
I'm looking for short-term lows that
form going into the close at the start
of a new day Zero GMT I look back in the
previous day's range in the NewYork
session generally you're going to find a
low
and if we can drop down into that in
London
I'll look for those Sell stops to be
triggered and then I'll go along from
that but it has to overlap with other
things CentralBankDealersRange Asian
range there's ideas
also has to be in time of day
London open Killzone
little shorter block that resides below
a short term low
either in the previous day or intraday
today
in other words it could be a short-term
little intraday load it formed and then
it trades lower than that into a bullish
or a block that's a very very strong
condition when the overall picture is
bullish
I would be buying in that scenario
during London
if I'm very bullish I'll trade long at
one StandardDeviation
below
the CentralBankDealersRange or Asian
range
and any discount PD array overlap while
in the London killZone
inside the protraction lower
post 12 AM to 2 AM with IPDA
in other words it's trading down I'm
going to be looking to go long during
that Judah swing and again it has to be
an overlap with a discount PD array
feeling a liquidity void that completes
under a short-term low
all right so we saw on the second setup
fair value Gap it could be a larger gap
which would be basically a liquidity
void that would be completed or filled
in
below a short-term loan so what we're
doing so we're really trying to buy
below lows
looking to accumulate sell stop
liquidity that we can buy from
if after Rally post 12 AM NewYork time
buy the first retracement into a 15 and
or
five minute bullish order block similar
to what I'm saying here is if we have
rallied right after midnight
we didn't see any drop down or
protraction a state that would put us
into a discount
if it's been riding straight up
if you get into the two o'clock to four
o'clock time period today well then kill
zone sweet spot if you will
I'll buy the first rejection down until
a bullish order block on a 5 or 15
minute basis
one or two StandardDeviation in the
Asian range
coupled with discount PD array in other
words I'm looking for two for one
StandardDeviation drops of the Asian
range total range damn
and it's going to be overlapping with a
discount PD array so I'm blending those
two
if a short term low is taken out twice
but there has been no upside
protractionary state in other words we
haven't seen the market go up first and
then go down twice the second time in
that condition it's probably going to
keep on going lower but if it has not
seen any protractionary move on the
upside or due to swing up
we go down for a low and then one more
time blow out that low I'll buy that as
a turtle suit
now what I've outlined here
are my favorite setups these are the
conditions and you have to find them in
examples
I could show you examples but
nonetheless
that's not going to help you
these are the Frameworks I look for in
other words if I see these types of
scenarios unfold generally these are the
ones that typically get into my thought
process I'm looking for certain things
to line up certain some type of play or
for instance if we were a sports team
okay and the coach has a Playbook and he
likes certain  plays that he makes his
players go through well these are the
scenarios I love when it comes to
trading the London open
these are my like toolbox or consistency
these types of Trades form several times
a week
if you look for a few of them and
understand what they what they are when
the Market's bullish
we've shown willingness of respect to
daily discount PD array
one of these criteria are going to meet
every London session out there will have
something in this list that forms now I
already know what you're going to think
wow Michael this is a lot which one do I
pick well if you study them they all
don't have the same characteristics
it depends on what the Market's
providing you
so when you're watching 12 AM NewYork
time we're watching to see which
scenario unfolds
remember we're looking for that initial
drop down ideally
but if it doesn't happen we have one
condition here where it says if it
rallies straight from 12 AM
when we get to 2 AM we're going to buy
the first retracement into a 15 or five
minute order block boom it's over
so you got every scenario that I would
be looking for for a living open loan
placing stop losses in a buy for day
trades
whatever you do
and whatever you use for your initial
stop loss do not rush moving it I
already know what you're trying to do
you want to get to break even plus five
plus twenty forget that in day trading
in London because you can get a double
pass they can come back and knock you
out and you'll miss the entire move
leave your stop at initial until you get
to at least
40 to 50 of the DailyRange if you can
get that in London then bring it to
break even but anything prior to that
don't do it
if you're trading in Central Bank
dealers range overlap with a PD array
the stop has to be 30 Pips under your
entry
if you're trading a run under the Asian
range in other words what we're doing is
we're watching price trade down below
the Asian range it might be one Standard
Deviation might go a half a state  one
full StandardDeviation anything below
an H in range low
your stop needs to be 40 Pips below your
entry
if you're trading any sell stop raid
30 Pips under the low
of the entry you're using
all right you're going to use the low
as your primary entry point that low
you're going to try to enter below that
your stop has to be 30 Pips below that
low
if you're trading the first retracement
into a bull shoulder block
you have to be 10 Pips under the lowest
LOD
if you're trading the second return for
sell stops in other words we've had
move lower and then it moves lower one
more time takes out the Sell stops your
stuff has to be below that 30 Pips
again that one is if you don't see any
move right away after midnight if it's
only been a straight down move then it
goes down one more time blows at the
load that's formed initially
your stop has to be 30 Pips below that
if you're buying that as a turtle suit
if you're trading any other setup not
described above what you're gonna be
using is 50 of the average DailyRange
of the last five days subtracted from
the Asian range low
assume you have a 100 pip average daily
range for the last five days what you're
going to do is take 50 Pips minus
the Asian range low whatever that price
is that's what your stop loss has to be
taking profits in buy day trades
foreign
you're always going to try to take
something off and gain at 20 to 30 Pips
always do this in London
you're gonna look to scale something off
every two StandardDeviation of the
Asian range or Central Bank dealers
range yes I said it requires you to see
two StandardDeviation before you take
the next level profit that means after
your first 20 to 30 Pips
you're going to wait for two Standard
Deviation of the Asian range or Central
Bank dealers range then you take
something off again
foreign
take something off at the previous day's
High plus 5 to 15 Pips
because you could end up in a turtle
soup scenario and it could retrace on
you
take something off at 50 of the price
range you're trading in on a 60 Minute
basis in other words inside the range
where are we at if we rally up
inside that range remember equilibrium
could be an impactful level so you want
to take something off there as well
because it could reverse on you
take or have had taken 60 to 80 percent
off
at five day average DailyRange
projections always do this so in other
words basically if you've not taken off
anything except for the first 20 30 Pips
you didn't do anything for two Standard
Deviation of the Asian range or Central
Bank dealerships because maybe it didn't
do that maybe it hasn't fulfilled that
maybe you haven't done anything with a
previous day's High hasn't traded there
yet
and maybe you haven't  seen a 50 range
in the last 60 Minutes  price action
then you have to consider average daily
range the last five days you need to be
taking at least 60 to 80 off at that
point
always do this and then you can leave a
little portion on to see if you're going
to get more juice out of that lemon and
hold for a later portion of the day
if trading higher than the previous
trading week take something off there
because you can get a turtle soups in
there in that environment
if trading higher than a previous month
is high take something off there
in time of day scale out
something
at or just above the five o'clock hour
NewYork time
in time of day you want to scale out a
short-term High prior to the 7 AM New
York open knowing let me outline this
again these are time date specific you
want to take some profit
when it's bullish and you've been
rallying
whatever that short-term High that's
forming prior to 7 AM that means
there's going to be a short-term little
rally going into seven o'clock
whatever that high is as it's rallying
you want to take something off there
because NewYork could be a reversal
in time of day
look to scale out between 10 AM and 11
AM NewYork time during the rally so in
other words whenever price is moving up
at 10 AM that leg in price higher you
want to be exiting and taking something
out as it's rallying up
ideally any of the above scenarios
coupled with a PD array in a premium
basis
now obviously you're probably saying
well Michael I only did too many so I
can only afford to do that how can I
take this many
portions off you can't
but if you look at it again study it not
all these conditions can be present
but you want to look for the ones that
may potentially be there for you
you can go through this list
and look at your trade as you get ready
to take it and see right away if any of
these are going to be potential
candidates
but you have to take profits on these
rules that's how I do it this is the
reason why I do it and when you see me
taking positions and scaling them off
these this is the criteria I'm using
When I Look to short day trades
ideally in seasonal bearish periods of
the year but it's not required
when the current quarter or new quarter
is expected bearish
after the daily chart has reacted
positively on a premium PD array
when price has a clear unobstructed path
to an opposing discount array
the ideal days of the week shorting are
Monday Tuesday and Wednesday
refer to the CentralBankDealersRange
and determine if it's less than 40 Pips
ideally
demand the Asian range to be in a 20-fit
range or less ahead of the Frankfurt
opening
that's basically one o'clock in the
morning NewYork Times
early morning
shorting between 2 AM and 4 AM New
York Times seeking the HOD
generally I'm looking to sell one to two
StandardDeviation of the Central Bank
dealers range and or Asian range coupled
with a premium PD array
time frame to execute on is either 5 or
15 minute time frame
where do I look to short day trades
I like to run above the Asian range at
least five Pips above it I want to be
selling short there
a fair value Gap above a short-term high
from the previous day's NewYork session
there's going to be buy stops above that
I'll look to sell that as it rallies
above that in NewYork session
bearish order block above a short-term
High either previous day or today in
other words if there's a bullish order
block that resides in price action and
there's a short-term High just below
that we haven't rated yet as soon as we
trade above that short-term high and
into that very shorter block
if it does that during London session
I'll go short there
if I'm very bearish one Standard
Deviation with any premium PD array in
the open killZone I can trade on that
inside the protraction higher post 12 AM
midnight NewYork time to 2 AM NewYork
time
with a PD array or a premium PDA rate
specifically that's enough for me so
basically I'm looking at a Judah swing
that occurs right from Midnight going up
into 2 AM it can happen prior
to 2 AM but generally you want to see
that move right after 12 AM up it
trades into a premium PD array that's
enough to get short
filling a liquidity void that completes
above a short-term High
if after
the drop post 12 AM
going to sell the first retracement into
a 15 or 5 minute bearish order block
one to two StandardDeviation in the
Asian range coupled with a premium PD
array I can sell that
and if short-term high is taken out
twice with no initial downside
I'll sell that as a turtle soup
placing stop losses in short day trades
whenever you use the initial stop loss
obviously don't be in a rush to move
that we've said that in the buy sides
the same thing here for shorting
if you're trading the Central Bank
dealers range overlap with a PDA
stop must be 30 Pips above
your entry
if you're trading a run above the Asian
Range High the stop has to be 40 Pips if
you're trading any buy stock rate
your stop has to be 30 Pips above the
high or your entry
if you're trading the first retracement
into a bearish order block your stop has
to be 10 Pips above the highest high of
the day
if you're trading the second return for
buy stops or basically a turtle suit and
we have not seen an immediate rally
lower in price after midnight
your stuff has to be 30 Pips above the
highest HOD
if you're trading any other setup not
described above use 50 of the average
DailyRange of the last five days added
to the Asian Range High
taking profits in short day trades
always try to take something off and
gain at 20 to 30 Pips always
look to scale something off every two
StandardDeviation in the Asian range
or CentralBankDealersRange
take something off at the previous day's
low minus 5 to 15 Pips
take something off at the 50 range or
equilibrium of the price range you are
trading inside of on a 60 Minute chart
take or have taken sixty to eighty
percent off at the average DailyRange
of the last five days do this always
if trading lower than the previous
trading week's low take something off
there you could have a reversal or
rejection
if trading lower than the previous
month's low again this could be a
potential reversal so you want to take
something off there
in time of day
scale out something at or prior to 5 AM
NewYork time
in time of day scale out a short-term
low prior to 7 AM NewYork open in
other words NewYork open could be
reversal or generally a retracement into
the 820 CME opening so you want to be
seeing profit taking some measure
portion come off as profit as it's
accelerating lower ahead of 7 AM
in time of day scale out at 10 AM to 11
AM NewYork time while price is still
declining
ideally any of the above scenarios
coupled with a premium PD array now
obviously I've given you
several instances and circumstances and
and outlines for
the probable
plan of action
whether you're entering whether you're
taking profit where you're using your
stop at these are my general rules of
operation this is what I generally look
for these are the things I do how I
manage position what I'm doing initially
with the with the stops where I'm
looking to take profits at the ones that
I did not incorporate here were
obviously  been taught in other places
so I didn't have to rehash or put in
filler
any projection on the FIB 127 168 and
the
100 percent
symmetrical price swing or 100 move
measured move those ideas couple with
any of these as well really amplifies
for profit taking
this lesson obviously
I don't want to see it on YouTube and if
it ends up on YouTube I'll have it
pulled down but
the
the lesson itself I could pretty much
show this on
baby Pips and nobody would understand
what it's talking about so  that's the
reason why I went through a great deal
of information in January and all the
way up to now because you know all the
elements that's being described here or
you should know them because you've
studied all the previous months
the criteria and the Rules of Engagement
that's being explained and outlined for
both sides of buying and selling
not every single one of these are going
to be
usable you can't use every single one of
them they're not going to be applicable
to every trade that you're in so don't
think because there's a laundry list of
things and scenarios here not all of
them are going to be able to be applied
to your trade but knowing what they are
in advance and outline form here you can
already see how you can look to see if
it's going to be a probable scenario for
your particular trade idea
you may not be trading anywhere near a
weekly low
monthly low so they may not even be any
consideration at all
you probably already took something off
at 20 to 30 Pips and it hasn't much
moved beyond that going into 5 AM your
time so you wouldn't consider that
either
the scaling out ahead of 7 AM
maybe you have taken 20 or 30 Pips
already in London and then it went
you know
the whole full average DailyRange all
during London
you you're not going to take something
ahead of 7am on that because you've
already taken something based on average
daily ratings being fulfilled
looking at
the scenarios that would potentially
paint out here and also for the entries
again not all of them will be applicable
so don't freak out because it seems like
a whole lot and yes you're being
challenged I promised you in the latter
lessons you're going to have to think
you have to think for yourself you have
to have rules you have to look for these
types of things yourself in the charts
they all won't be there
so you're not having to look through all
these things to to whittle down to what
you should be doing for your trade
all of the criteria that's been listed
here for the setups the buys the sells
where your stop loss is there are
specific rules for all of that I have
specific outlined scenarios in this
teaching that if you stick to them
you'll do everything that I do on a week
by week basis when I'm Trading
so
yes it requires you to think yes it's a
little bit of work but is it worth it
absolutely and until next time wish you
good luck and good Trading