well good morning folks
it is a good morning
it won't be in about uh 19 minutes or so
retail Traders are going to get smoked
CPI numbers due out this morning it is
important that you try not to uh
get ahead of that because it can be
somewhat destructive if you're incorrect
in your assumptions or your analysis
and I stand in in the sidelines of this
report I I've been burned by many times
so
we're gonna take a look at the es and
quick pass through
euro dollar and cable in the dollar
Index we'll take a look at NASDAQ we'll
take a look at the Dell futures
and we'll peek at Gold
okay so that's what's on
tap for this morning I want to talk a
little bit about the
where setups form how you can trust
the principles I'm teaching but we're
going to watch CPI live
so it's important you also understand
that
anything I tell you today
should be viewed
from the safety of a laboratory
experiment that means you're not even
trying to trade a demo
you're not even
tempted at all to take any trade based
on what I'm going to tell you today I'm
not
I will not
I'm not going to come back later on say
you want to do so and so here's what I
did because I'm going to be here right
here live with you
so let's take a quick look at
let's start with the dollar Index
okay and it's
she'll run a weekly chart
and we're at the bottom of that Gap in
here let me
zoom in there's a whole lot of
annotations in here from
our recent discussions pertaining to
dollar
so this this Gap in here
originally we treated that as an
inversion Gap
come down and act as
support to take us up into our premium
arrays
we have since worked lower back inside
this
Gap and I mentioned in the last
commentary
that I want to see if it wants to go
outside of this
and then treat this shaded area here
as resistance okay so so far we've came
down and we respected the the low of it
I'll drop down into a daily I'll try to
get through this pretty quick because I
only have a few minutes before CPI comes
out
okay so we have somewhat of a small
little
remaining Gap here with in order block
so I'm going to note that here
so I'll be watching that going into the
rest of this week
I don't like the color
it does not mean okay does not mean for
you to go in here and assume that dollar
is going to sell off right away because
I see these buttons there I want to see
if CPI supports this this idea so that's
why I tell you don't stand ahead or get
in front of the CPI number because it
can be very
one-sided it could smoke you easily your
stop loss will not protect you
it won't have any protective
characteristics at all because price can
Gap right on through
and the liquidity is pulled okay
believing there's a lot of people out
there that want to trade it
but
Brokers liquidity providers they pull
the liquidity
they don't let you connect Okay so
because of that you want to stand aside
let the initial
I guess uh chaos hit the marketplace
let the victims start bleeding and then
once the impact crater has been created
then you go around you look around for
the easy targets you know who's who's
left that could be uh taken out with
either short-term liquidity runs or runs
to inefficiencies so we we treat that
surge in price action by the CPI number
as a means of creating that first
initial shock like imagine right now the
the surface of a pond real smooth
mirror-like
and then CPI is going to be like a
boulder being dropped in the middle of
it and that first splash
we don't want to be harmed by that and I
don't want any of you my students
being harmed by that but once that
occurs there's lots of new ripples
and every
advancing outward moving circle from
that impact
or all opportunities and each one of
them are respective to their specific
time frame so there's setups that are
forming all the time across all
different
one minute second charts 15 minute
charts there's all kinds of
opportunities and whatever one suits you
is the one that's for you
but I want to see if it wants to get
below this then treat this as resistance
and start to gravitate towards this I'm
not suggesting it we'll do it on one
Fell Swoop today but obviously it can do
that because this type of Market driver
that can create those types of runs but
I want to see does it want to get down
into here and then
reprice to this inefficiency between
these candles hi and this candle is low
more specifically the opening price of
this down close Candle on the daily
chart
and
let's go over to euro
all right in similar fashion we have a
very shorter block here very small
little Gap
here I'm going to show you the the tooth
level so you can see there's a
separation it's not much but it's there
okay so this order block
so reaching up into this down closed
candles range
repricing to the separation between
these two candles so this candle beneath
my cursor that candle is low
and this candle is high okay the candle
right above my cursor that candle is
high okay that small little inefficiency
I want to see does CPI lend well
to it wanting to get up into that area
it's a small little pool of liquidity in
the form of buy stops that will be
resting about this you don't need any
kind of Market map
um
and Mark of what's it
ugh they escaped me I mean there's lots
of resources out there that are trying
to show you where supposed orders are
resting whatever you don't need any of
that okay book map I think that's what
it's called
um book math if you're listening it's no
offense to you I'm just suggesting that
you know there are ways of doing what
you make available visually which is
great in the beginning I probably would
have used something like that but if you
study price action naked you'll see you
know above swing highs and short-term
highs and lows
um there's obvious stops in liquidity
and when the market has moved away from
this Gap here
traded above the short term High here
relative equal highs so I want to see
does it have a willingness to use the
CPI number to expand into this direction
now if we take out this low here
and very specific
get below the consequent encroachment of
this Wick
why this one because the difference
between the candles open and close on
this one inside of the Gap this one over
here
it left
that Fairway got here there was a change
in the state of delivery right there
so if we get through the consequent
encouragement of this Wick
that to me spells bearishness on euro
dollar and dollar might surprise to the
upside but as long as that does not
happen
I'm looking for this order block
in this guy now
for the slow folks
I did not give you a two scenario I'm
going to come back in here I'm right I'm
telling you what I'm looking for because
I don't know at the time at the very
time we're sitting here live I don't
know if I knew I'd be Trading
it's CPI I have no idea what they're
going to do and CPI is one of those
events like fomc rate announcements
which we'll have tomorrow
this week is littered with landmines so
I teach my students if you have a week
like this you want to try to get
yourself on Monday
and Monday was a pretty good day
if you want to see a review of how I
took yesterday's uh trade and thumbs up
this live stream and it'll inspire me to
do a secondary video later in the
afternoon we'll do a review and I'll
walk you through what I did and how I
saw it in all business but for now we're
focusing on the CPI so I'm looking for
evidence to support a bias for the rest
of the week
so it'll give me insight to see how they
use this data manual intervention
is where the quote-unquote powers that
be you call them market makers
they are
the
the folks are in charge of how far these
markets will go when they'll move
and what price is going to be period it
has nothing to do with your buying and
selling pressure all of our gimmicks all
of our order blocks all of our supply
and demand harmonic patterns none of
that matters when they step in
they will literally reprice to another
price level and it doesn't matter
what Carnage is Created from that so
that's the reason why I'm telling you
that this type of Market driver CPI is
dangerous
you can't trust even my own Concepts in
front of a move like this because
it can roll right over top of it
and I have been very candid about how I
get many times this very CPI number
wrong it's only very few times I've been
able to publicly call it and be correct
so I want you to respect the measure of
risk do not look at anything I'm saying
today as a little nudge to say here
here's our secret little handshake go
take this straight please don't do that
okay if you're right it was luck
I promise you on a day like today with
CPI if you make money it's luck
that's the only time luck exists when
it's a complete uncertainty and you just
happen to be on the side that worked
so I don't trade with luck I don't rely
on luck I I don't have that in in my
uh
expressions for trading it's it's it
doesn't exist you make the results and
skill set and experience dictate that so
that's what I'm looking for I favor this
right now so that way you understand
what's going on but if I'm wrong
where do where do I concede and say I'm
wrong and then I look at the market from
the opposite end as I mentioned it needs
to get below the consequent correction
of this week because that's where the
state of delivering changed
inside this Gap inside of seeing us run
higher we've taken them a pool of
liquidity out here
and we went a little bit higher but
these are relative equal highs I don't
know if they're using that right there
and then CPI sinks us and they make
aggressive runs for sell side below here
I I don't know so it's important for you
to understand that there are times where
your analysis your experience your model
will be silent
it does not mean it's broken it doesn't
mean that they changed the algorithm it
just means that you have to sit still
and you have to exercise discipline and
self-control and wait for the market to
give you your setup
you're not trying to be like a crack
fiend okay out there with your crack
pipe every single day trying to smoke
Pips and and points in these markets
because it's moving around
you just got to sit still okay
so that's the two things I'm looking for
for
fiber I'll take a quick peek at cable
all right cable I believe this is nice
came down inside this
by side of balance outside efficiency
which is a FVG but it's in a
buy side imbalance also an efficiency it
trades down to it here and then look at
the reaction so far today so I want to
see us return back up into this
Gap I'll show you in a second where
that's anchored
it's on a weekly chart I apologize let
me go back up to that
so that's that inefficiency right there
so I want to see does it return back
into that if it does it has unfinished
business all in here
that's assuming obviously if the dollar
falls off
let's go back into it daily
so far really Cable's been just hanging
around this large consolidation
not a whole lot of activity even though
we came down into this Gap
and traded into it and showed initial
willingness they want to go higher
we have to overcome this
okay so let's show that in perspective
so it's gonna have to make a real
meaningful move outside of that
that range here I'm keeping it faint
like that you might want to use a dark
color but the the real level I'm trying
to be interested in is here so if we
trade above it fall short and come back
down to Middle
of this inefficiency that would be
consequently encroachment in the form of
potential support so if we run up fail
to get to here
that shaded area like run above and come
back down
the lower time frames might give us an
idea after CPI that would be something I
would look for it's not a trade idea
it's just something I'm running certain
terms of scenarios what do I look for
what would I wait for after CPI if you
don't trade ahead of CPI ICT what are
you looking for after CPI what are those
types of things it's those these things
here I'm trying to outline to you
and let's take a quick look at NQ
we are looking at the September delivery
contract month now it's symbol U so
nqu2023
I saw a guy post a tweet to me saying he
was looking for NQ q q is the month code
for August and August is not a delivery
month for index features it's only March
which is H
June which is M September which is U and
Z for December there's only four
contract delivery months for indexes so
or indices I should say
all right so here is the
term
here is the weekly view on NQ
and like I said this was the performer
on the upside the strongest one and it
has delivered so
and drop down to it daily
all right this one here
only experience speaking here okay
um because we have a great announcement
fomc really afternoon tomorrow and
Wednesday and we have the CPI number
this morning which will be out in about
four minutes or so a little less than
four minutes I gotta hurry up uh this
sell side
looks suspect even though we had a
really nice run up in here
um
I just feel like they're gonna make an
attempt to get into this this week will
it be today or tomorrow I don't know
but this looks too clean way way way too
clean and
even if it went down there that would
upset folks thinking that it's topped
and then to me if it went down below
that and rallied and create another
short-term inefficiency that would be
bullish that could continue going higher
this would upset those individuals that
see this as support or real good area to
Trail stop losses below that
um BS real quick
foreign
I don't I don't see the same thing there
but if NQ draws down there that s p
would want to follow suit
I'm not trying to pick the top I'm the
same CPI I look at that number that
comes out as a means of trying to smash
anyone that's profitable
it can in some instances be used to
continue or capitulate and move that
means something that's already in a
movement like this it could accelerate
and add the last piece of it
so again that's the reason why I'm not
getting ahead of it and trying to trade
and then the Dow
this one here I favor or run Above This
High here
I think that would be something to
expect because it's been the the sixth
sister of all three indices NASDAQ I
told you would be the leader our Focus
has been teaching through the price
delivery of e-mini s p
and the Dow I use it as a barometer like
I use the dollar Index I don't trade the
dollar Index but I use it as a risk on
risk off
for comparative studies and relative
strength studies for
the indices I use the dial so for like
dial Theory smt diversions is six sister
Concepts those types of things I I lean
on the Dow for that purpose we have a
little bit of an inefficiency right in
here so we could if we're going to drop
initially on CPI it could go down there
and then make a run up into that that
would be a scenario I would watch and
see if it manifests today and it's not a
trade idea so please don't take that as
such
quickly go back into es we'll drop into
a lower time frame oops Soldier gold
sorry real quick let me see if I can
hold on
uh gold
um
I don't know
there you go I've gone to my head I
would say it's going to run
or the sell side below here
there you go that's what I think I'm
probably wrong please don't trade it
okay but I I wouldn't touch this at all
yes it's dropped down to a 15 minute
time frame
smaller Gap in here
buy side rests above here
so 30 seconds or so
everybody that's
you know trade is going to regret having
been
in it
and everybody that gets lucky you're
posted on social media and offer signals
per purchase
so here's where our sell side is I'm
going to try to keep the annotations
like this focus on my viewpoints sell
sides here buy side here inefficiency
it's rate if I can get down here before
it pops off
so you want to trade CPI do you
so I ran up and hit our survey gut I was
talking about ran through it a little
bit that's okay what's this mean
threshold of here then swept the sell
side now buy sides next
okay just a quick look at NASDAQ
so it's taken its South Side here then
ran for buy side
down
we're at 15 minute time frame
quick look at the daily on the dial
yeah I like this high
so would I ever have a wick like this
I'll measure the midpoint which is
consequent encroachment
that would be first objective and then I
want to see if it wants to get above
here because I could be wrong because it
may use this initial uh pump
to feed into that and tomorrow's read
announcement do something completely
opposed to what I've outlined and not
even come up here but I I think that
this is a likely draw on down
okay
I know I hear you bitching let me go
over here
there you go sorry
thank you I know
I was uh going through charts
and a few of you like to buried me about
not having the title bear I don't know
I don't know how they get untoggled I
don't
I don't usually mess with it
so we've had buy side here and sell side
taken
uh the initial draw let's go into a
moment chart
All in One Moment in one minute
the market opened here ran up just a
little bit above
the FVG then slam down the
take cell side and then in the same
minute one candle close up here after
running up the buy side so in one minute
look how much the market has traversed
now do you believe that you're going to
be nimble enough to trade in that when
the liquidity is already pulled anyway
your broker's not going to let you trade
that
okay you're not going to see these guys
out there that put a buy order and a
sell order unless they're running their
white list fake broker they're running
on their own scam those orders will get
filled because it's not really happening
but in the real Market none of that
works okay you're not going to be
allowed to be trading it it will not let
you fill so
as much as I love having fun and ripping
other people and I can take a good
ribbing too it's important that when it
matters when real discussions about risk
and money and the potential loss of it
I don't sugarcoat any of that so I'm
telling you if anybody's out there
showing you examples where they get
filled and they got a really good entry
here and they got out here that's total
grade A okay they didn't get
filled they didn't trade it and anybody
tells you otherwise okay the man they do
that and show you broker statements log
into their broker's account and show you
not mt4 or mt5 account because that's
too a reputable broker
sorry but that that's just the facts
okay
I consider myself a little bit better
than the average bear and I don't
believe I can make my stuff work even in
these environments because it's highly
manipulated like you are absolutely up
against a brick wall and you can't you
won't be permitted period
because it moves so fast
Brokers can take because they ebook a
lot of people they could be wrong by
happenstance
and over leveraging Larry that can be in
there doing big big moves and get lucky
they have to they have to pay that out
because of the the fierceness and
velocity of how fast it moves around
you know it's that's just that's how the
business Works folks I mean you can be
mad about it or just understand that's
what takes place and respect it it's
okay I'm not going to play in that
sandbox I'll wait
so
this is literally a 50 50 now because
it's
it's taken both sides of the liquidity
after I drew your attention to
working off the Fairway Gap I mentioned
first now
the takeaway in this is I want you to
think about how we were looking at the
buy side and the sell side
forget right
forget being wrong forget profitability
think
okay think about this
all of the movement that took place thus
far
was all inside of a one minute basis or
two minutes
that's it
so all of this movement from here and
here
that happened in
oblinko nine
you would not have the the ability
if you didn't have limit orders in that
could be filled not that they would be
you wouldn't have the ability to adjust
or to comprehend what it is that you
should be doing next
especially if you're a new student or a
new Trader you have no idea what you're
doing
you have no idea where you would measure
a willingness to see continuation up or
down
maybe you didn't even know where these
pools of liquidity were before I
mentioned them
so if you don't know those things why
would you even Gamble
on this report that's coming out
or that's that came out six minutes or
so ago
it's important not to see these things
and see how much it moved and think to
yourself if I would have got a piece of
that that's not that kind of move
okay that's that's not what this is this
is a trap
this is a very
difficult thing to convey to to new
Traders or new students because they
think somebody absolutely bought the low
down here or in this area and then sold
it up here they believed that and I'm
telling you that didn't happen
if it happened they'll gladly go into
their broker account and log in live log
into it with their password blocked out
that's fine but go in there and show
their time and date and their time and
sales
Phils
on a reputable broker you're not going
to see that okay believe me folks if I
could do that in this report I would be
doing it every month every time it would
do it I would do that just to show you
you know this is the way it is
but I'm telling you up front because I
want to protect you
that this type of Market driver is
essentially
risking ruin
but we can identify and use it like I
teach to use the non-farm payroll okay
nonpartum payroll I don't trade that
report
you can trade after
the non-farm payroll report you can
trade after the CPI number
but ahead of it
no because you know you have no idea you
have no idea I have no idea
where it's going to go on their CPI
number
so what makes you think you do as a
green horn someone to just start a
couple months watching some videos from
me some yahoo that teaches with a demo
account you think you're going to be
able to beat this
no
don't do that you're going to create
Scar Tissue so what I did this morning I
outlined how to focus on what to look
for and what you would study
and in a minute or less
Drew out here's where the buy side is
why did I call this out look at the the
idea of it not wanting to go higher so
retail sees this as what strong
resistance
say they can be short in their mind
and the stop losses would be above these
highs here
in the form of buy stops that's what we
call buy side liquidity
I took you over here to the relative
equal lows what's going to be resting
below that sell stops which is why we
call that sell side liquidity
both sides of the marketplace are always
in contention for high impact news
drivers like CPI rate announcements
non-farm payroll those types of things
anytime you see in your lower time frame
charts
these smooth edges like this very very
smooth relative equal lows very very
smooth relative equal highs they are
going to be made Jagged meaning it's
going to rip through it like it does
over here so now they're not so smooth
already now if this this whole movement
down here
was a function
to offset
any positions or interest
because it controls sentiment as well
with orders resting below here
down here
I'm sorry up here rather down here where
to go the uh looking at the relative
equal highs the market ran for those as
well and then what has it done since
it's staying in between those two pools
of liquidity but what did it do first it
went right to the FVG I
mentioned overshot it by a little bit
which is understandable
given the nature of this report that
came out and then inside of all this
move it dropped down now you can't see
it like this so if I if I'm in a one
minute chart
here's the 830 candle it opens trades up
it looks like it completely rolls right
on through it
but
we saw momentarily before it ran up
higher it ran up to it here and stopped
right in here it stopped and then moved
lower
then came all the way back up and
overlapped the entire run and then went
to the buy saw
it to you owner
30 second chart here
opens rallies up drops down still
15 second chart
there's the move right there that's what
it looked like
it opened
ran up
this came to this big green candle here
didn't exist yet
watch the video okay when the live
stream code I don't know if I can you
rewind my
live streams I don't think I've disabled
that you should be able to rewind it and
then tap the live Tab and left hand
corner taking refactor where I'm at in
line but you can watch it where it opens
it trades up creates that short-term
High there then it runs for the sell
side
and then all in the same one minute
candle it opens here on this 15 second
candle and then runs for the buy side
then
now we're hanging around in here
so I think we could make a potential run
higher
to take out this high
this run down here looks a little
aggressive it feels like they went down
there
fastest
and then this
movement here this is a lot of that uh
run break retest go short I think
Traders are trying to go short from the
retail perspective and they would want
to reach up into this Wick here I would
observe and study with that idea in mind
that would look like this
it's not a trade folks it's just this is
what you're doing when you're reading
the tape it gives you experience
watching price action where you don't
push the button even in a demo you get a
feel for what price is likely to do you
spend a lot of time doing that
if
if I would have done that in the
beginning I would have spared myself
years of drawing down blowing accounts
and it would have been a lot faster for
me to find consistency so here's the
love I'm referring to
4407 and then 4405 even that's the
midpoint of this Gap here
okay so watch and see if they want to
draw up into that
uh the main takeaway what I was saying
was even in this fast Market move
the FVG I mentioned and the
liquidity pools it went to the fair Bay
Gap then dropped to the sell side then
ran for the buy side so the takeaway
would be even in that speed
okay of within one minute
the very levels that I gave you the
algorithm referred to immediately
in a way in a speed and a velocity that
even I can't participate in it so
the takeaway is for you to see that
they're even in this recklessness
that looks like chaos and just
Carnage
it's still being controlled
but it's being controlled in a way where
it's going to move a lot
in a short span of time but you're not
being permitted to profit during it
that's that's what I'm trying to convey
to you it's an illusion these types of
moves are the very things that draw
people into wanting to trade because
they think they can get in here and take
these trades and make your 20 30 Handles
in a minute
over leveraged and get a five figure
withdrawal so
don't fall for that trap
it's very very important you don't fall
for that trap
okay there's uh
they run into our consequent
Correctional mentioned they would draw
too
that's enough to pay your bills right
there folks
I know it doesn't seem like it's all
that sexy but that little mood right
there that's what a high frequency
trading algorithm does
it trades on that type of little move
hundreds of times per session
now look at the reaction of that
just that little move right there that
in itself is a high frequency trading
algorithm entry
it moves back and forth there's
algorithms that
trade one-sided they stay in a buy model
for buys or going along and there's
other high frequency trading algorithms
that trade on the sell side it's a sell
side model so it's only going short when
it's offering the opportunity to do so
and then you have a
a Model A high frequency trading
algorithm that simply goes all over the
place it takes whatever volatility is
available at the time and it runs up
down up down up down up down that's the
stuff because I get asked all the time
what is it that you won't teach us
it's that
I'm not allowed to teach you that I'm
not going to teach that but I have
demonstrated it before in the past and
yeah I'm very candid about saying I'm
not going to teach that part to you
but you instead of saying look at how
much you've already taught and look how
much the impact has been for other
people they're making real money with it
now
um
the point of appreciation
is lost because
you forget everything I've already
shared openly and works amazingly well
and because I say I can't do something
like I can't folks I can't literally I
cannot I'm not permitted to do it
I would love to do it trust me I get
real close as close as I can and this
the students that really really really
want to know it they think that I hidden
it in my teachings I I did not
okay I did not teach anything like that
I'm not allowed to do it but you don't
need that all you need to do is find one
little multiplier one little thing that
gives you a setup
one little thing that gives you a reason
to engage the marketplace measure risk
Define it
that means know where your stop should
be
and then where you should take profits
partial and where you think term this is
where's your best case exit
sometimes my trades don't go to full
Terminus because I'm illustrating either
a
point of not needing to be 100 accurate
so that way it encourages you as my
students or sometimes as a human I just
don't do it correctly
or I'll take off more than I should have
in hindsight I'll look back and say I
wish I left a little bit more on the
trade that part is always going to be
there no matter how good you get at this
you're always going to be wrong even in
your winning trades you're going to wish
you would have had more
held on longer got out sooner
yeah it's it's always like that okay so
this craft that you're involved in now
is a lifestyle it's not you learn how to
make money and that's it you've reached
your destination excellence
is a Pursuit
it's not a
destination it's final it's always
always going to be something that you're
striving to do better and reach for
and mine is my x's and I've been open
about that as well I always want to make
them better because I have lots of ways
to get into things but I'm never fully
satisfied if I'm going to be honest with
you I'm never satisfied ever
with my exits and I have
got out on the highest tick a handful of
times and I got in and out of trades on
the lowest ticket a handful of times
but
you would think with 30 years
I I would have a whole lot more examples
I I don't because I'm either trying to
out think my algorithm or I'm trying to
find something that I haven't
identified yet
and because of those distractions my
mind's going a thousand miles an hour
it's hard for me to focus which is
another reason why I don't like to have
people chatting to me
and even when my son's next to me
they're not allowed to say anything to
me because that small little distraction
would like now like me pointing over to
him like it takes me off my train of
thought
and you have to especially for someone
like me I have to be very dialed in and
I'm very easily distracted I'm like a
dog sees a squirrel like what what like
I can't focus so
maybe you don't have that uh
issue in your trading maybe you're you
can multitask
you know and and do exceedingly well
even as a Trader I don't have that skill
set I can't like I have to be 100 dialed
in because I have so many things that I
can see as an opportunity
see where is you you have one model or
two two things maybe three things that
you learn from me and if one of those
things occur it's easy for you to focus
okay I see this but you you have to
understand like I have 80 plus things
that are jumping off the chart at me
which one do I want to eat off of
I'm like a dog in a meat market turn
loose like do I want to run over there
and bite that do I want to run over here
and bite that like it that's the that's
the closest analogy I can give to you
like I hear so many things I can see as
an opportunity in price
whether it be a a three handle Run a 10
handle run a 15 handle run a run that
goes eight handles reverses for four
runs for 13. like those those things are
jumping off the chart all the time to me
and depend upon what my mind is focused
on at the time or if I'm if I have a
means of sitting down trying to explain
something to an audience or if I'm doing
a lecture or whatever or if I'm teaching
my son
whatever one I go with
okay
that's the one I go with and I'm always
this is the part that you mean I'm
saying I'm always regretful that I
didn't do one or the other because I
have so many of them to choose from you
think that if I sat down and I divulged
all of them to you that it's going to
make you a better Trader it doesn't
it's it's almost like
well if you have more than one child
which one's your your favorite
you can't say which one's your favorite
right but when you're in the market and
you're trading and you're looking at
Price action it is very difficult for me
to say
I love this one more than that one
so whenever I come to the
decision on this is the one I'm going to
go with that's it but the whole time
price is running
I know my mind at certain times that the
other one's going to do certain things
and then price presents this certain
thing that I would expect in that
instance where that particular model to
work for me to take an entry but I'm
already in something
I'm wrestling with that the whole time
the Market's ticking that is such a
distraction so imagine if that's what it
was like for you so please if you're if
you're upset with me because I'm been
honest with you and told you I'm not
going to teach you
everything
and it's not important for you to learn
everything all you need is one thing
just one thing
and the most important thing is where
price is going to go
because literally like there's so many
ways to get into a trade
if you're right in where you where you
think is going to go if you have that
understood
it makes it a lot easier
and it allows you to hold on to your
trade and you don't have the frustration
you see many live streamers and they get
in there and they make whatever they're
making you know glad hand and Cherry you
know not cherry pick but they'll be
their chest and they're amazing this and
that and the market just keeps on
running
and then they in the same live stream
they're crying about how I gotta learn
how to do this I gotta hold on hold on
you got to spend more time understand
where it's going to reach for and not
just focus on these lower time frames
in the lower time frames are wonderful
for entry and in managing risk
but if your trade is entirely
linked to and found it on a lower time
frame draw on liquidity you're missing
the point entirely
you're completely missing the entire
focus of why you should be taking Trace
you need movement folks as a Trader we
need displacement and a change from one
price to another over a duration of time
how much time
you have to you have to come to that
conclusion what it fits for you for some
of you holding overnight it can't happen
you won't let yourself do that others
you can't be in a trade longer than 10
minutes
in 10 minutes is long-term position
trading to you
and I'm not saying that that's a bad
thing because if you decide on what your
main comfort zone is
how long can you hold a trade before you
start getting antsy
if you're really really impatient
and you can't overcome impatience then
you will do very very well in intraday
charts working with one minute time
frames and you can get your setups in
one minute bars get it be done and stop
trading for the day go do something else
and you would probably be very very
profitable doing that
but
will you be comfortable seeing these 30
handle runs that happen over the span of
the entire daily range how about 100
handle moves or a thousand handle plus
moves that I've just outlined in NASDAQ
over the last month or so
are you going to be regretful about that
and let that beat you up that's it's
very important that you understand these
things and when I got into trading I
didn't know those things
we're going to be barriers
they're going to be speed bumps to you
and sometimes roadblocks for others
for you finding your success
I don't know why somebody need to hear
that that's why I said it so
let me drop these on here for reference
and move this fit because it's a little
too much
all right so again this is a 15 second
chart you probably don't have that
on your trading view but you're watching
it online
so what would a high frequency trading
algorithm entry be on a buy model high
frequency trading algorithm
you can see very plainly that I outlined
that we would likely draw up into the
consequent encroachment of this Wick
here on the 15 second chart
and then potentially draw to here now
the draw I'm thinking is up here because
it's it's going to move on the folks
that see this as a high low
break and retest and try to go lower
that's that's what the algorithm is
running on it's already ran to the the
majority of
the position holders here because their
spot would have been right above here
not because you're looking at a 15
second chart because they're looking at
Dom's depth of Market they're reading
all these types of things okay and those
gimmicks are they're not helpful you
believe they are I promise you that you
have a religion
it's faith-based on that stuff being the
Catalyst as the why markets growing up
or down it's not
to the short holders that would use this
as a short
this run into this inefficiency right
there
into this order block that's a trade
it's a hyper entry trading algorithm but
that's for the sell side
I mentioned when we got into our time
frames before we dropped into the second
chart I said that you know I believe
that we're gonna move higher and I gave
you the outline as to why I believe that
based on these second charts
so
Folks at like Goldman Sachs will tell
you that there's noise on these lower
time frames and if anybody tells you
they can find trades in this or find
profitability in it run away from them
they're coming and I assure you I
promise you but how many times have you
sat here with me on Livestream and the
dances to my record so
the opening here it trades down into
that
and then we have a short-term High
it's broken to the upside
so now think for a moment
your mindset is I'm strapped in
I'm in the saddle I'm only running for
buy side so the high frequency trading
algorithm that you would be studying in
this practical in this this type of
price action would be only looking for
Longs or only looking for buys okay and
how could you use that well what have I
taught you
what was what were the what were the
signatures that you've understood so far
about what price uses to go higher
you have to have a shift in Market
structure
here you have a swing High it rallies
through it on this candle right there
it runs higher that's fine but what does
it leave small little inefficiency right
there
and just ran our Target there
that's it but that's it right there that
is all you need folks what you just
watched me outline here
I told you the direction I favored I
told you what it was likely to do
and I'm using a 15 second chart tell me
somebody else out there that's wrote
books made courses with a 15 second
chart and can tell you how it's going to
act and behave like this
it doesn't happen
so a order block
okay is a change in the state of
delivery
okay it is not a Zone
it is not every down closed candle that
is an overblock it is not an up close
candle every single one is an odor block
it is a frame of reference
where a change
in where price will be drawn to or from
that occurs here why am I using this
down closed candle and not this one over
here
this one has the larger body so it's
spent more time and recorded more time
and duration at its extremes
that lowest close that makes this an
order block
this swing high that it's part of when
it trades above it here that's a shift
in Market structure so that means high
frequency trading algorithms will trip
to buy side and they'll all be looking
primarily
for their largest leverage to be on this
side of the marketplace
now the chaos high frequency trading
algorithms that trade up and down all
day long
they'll take this trade too but they'll
also take this shortness very bad Gap
here that trades to it and trade back
down into this
inefficiency and change in the state
delivery which is that opening price
don't believe me look
here's the opening price
he'll never call this stuff live you'll
never see him do it folks
yeah I'll do it with a 15 second chart
just to rub it in your face the opening
price
for everybody Gap how do you qualify a
high probability order block it will
have my FVG
not every down closed candle use an
orange block
not every down closed candle with a fair
value Gap like this is a long
wait that's a contradiction no that's a
refinement
I'm teaching you narrative logic
framework
the fact that we had this idea here what
was the first side of liquidity taken at
CPI
we opened here
at 8 30. it opened rallied up here
stopped short then went down below to
take the buy side I'm sorry to sell side
so what side the marketplace did the
algorithm run to first what do smart
money Players the folks that don't write
books that aren't going to be talking to
you I'm it
I'm the one that stepped out I'm not
supposed to be doing these things not
you're not supposed to know these things
so I had to create a language
so that way if I'm tapped on the
shoulder again I am teaching this I'm
not teaching that
it's Pepsi or Coke they're they're both
colas they're both poison okay but you
have a choice so you have what
a delivery to sell side burst
so smart money the folks that understand
the algorithm the folks that follow it
it's lead
wait for this signature here
because the first
that tells you the direction
because they're going to run for cell
Cipher so this is the reason why I told
you I believe it's going to go up here
how did you know that ICT how did you
know it's going to go higher why did you
why did you pick that why Why didn't it
want to come back down to consequent
encroaching of this week that's what
some of you are probably thinking right
now
holy crow he just read my mind
you're looking around the room right now
for microphones aren't you I bugged your
uh computer right
I'm hacking your system up the ghost
machine
it doesn't need to go down to the
consequent encroaching of this because
the narrative is it ran for sell side
and then quickly repriced away from it
it does not need to come back down here
before it goes up to the buy side and
how it delivers listen folks how it
delivers price after
the second pool of liquidity is engaged
sell side was below here I'll go back up
to the higher time frames in a moment
for now I have to outline all this the
cell side was taken first
that means the move
will be likely prolonged
and much more prominent to the buy side
that means it's going to go higher it
upsets the orders and sentiment by this
drop down here
then it runs for the buy side
it breaks lower comes back up and then
creates a false shorting opportunity
it delivers a short run Traders see that
that we're short they thinking yeah wow
you know I got
four handles five handles or so I'm
getting ready to take out that low down
here it's going to keep going for the
rest of the day lower
wrong
it only reprices to the opening price
here at 8 30.
and also you just can't accept it but
it's all controlled opening price trades
down look at the bodies they tell you
the story
the Wicks did the damage
the body stops right at the opening
price
at 8 30. the algorithm receives that
as information comes back down to it
there it stops on a dime turns around
creates your short-term shift in Market
structure there down close candle
bullish order block
separation here
come back down into it hit the order
block respect it close in the
inefficiency
time distortion
all this movement here as long as we're
not breaking below the midpoint of this
down closed candle everything's still a
go
what I'm looking at is this range from
this high of this candle down to that
low as long as these two candle
reference points here have not been
breached above or below all this stuff
in here I'm ignoring every bit of it
I'm not looking at any FVG
inside of that I'm not looking at any
kind of potential order block because
this range here
that's your dealing range it will not be
anything of any importance or
significance unless it trades outside of
that range and because I'm telling you
and as I told you live here I believe
it's going to go higher and take out the
high the first draw is here and the buy
side above this High here
so all these candles from this green
candle right above my cursor
all the way until we get to this
candle's High right there so this candle
all through
till here
means nothing to me
I'm not looking any of those candles and
having any respect of anything it's
doing because the return from this
Fairway Gap here let me draw it out
This is complicated ICT I just want to
over about oversolding okay I'm not your
man then go go watch somebody else
but you want to understand why the
Market's doing what it's doing
and you can trust and sleep at night
that you know that the stuff that you're
learning isn't going to stop
it's never going to be beaten up or
victimized by anything better is there
anything better this is the market I'm
teaching you the market
the market rallies up into
the inefficiency again
And Trades down only to offer delivery
to the order block close the
inefficiency and then time is spent
marking time that's it it's we're in 15
second candles
so it's just hanging around what is it
doing
what do you think is occurring inside of
all these ranges in here between this
candle is high and this candle is low
that's all one older block
what kind of order block propulsion
block
look at month 4 content on my YouTube
channel
because it all of this price action from
this candle below my cursor all the way
over to here
all these candles are inside this
so my mindset in focus is inside this
range everything is happening inside I
could care less because my mind is
already established what the algorithm
is going to refer back to is this
signature here I've coded
so all of this price action here is
irrelevant it's just marking time where
prices moved in that interval the
highest and the lowest in the beginning
and the ending that's all it's doing but
my mind as a Trader and the analyst is
I'm looking at inside this range here I
want to see this range maintain itself
and then eventually break to the upside
which we get right there
where does it draw to
where I told you here and then what does
it do it stops and then consolidates
what's it doing
what is it doing folks think
the order block it trades down to it
it's spending time down here
for Traders that understand what I'm
teaching you that they're not going to
go out there in public and raise their
hand say you know yeah ICT you know is
right you know this is what we do they
don't want me teaching it to you
trust me they don't want me teaching
this
so I it took a great deal of prayer and
answered prayer to have this shown to me
in charts so that way I can convey what
it is that's happening outside the chart
the algorithm is not
only doing what I'm showing you in
candlesticks there are other things that
I know that I can't teach because
there's no way for me to bridge that gap
between what you can see in a chart
like I can't I can't say okay if it does
this this is what it doesn't work like
that so there's only a limitation of
what it is I'm willing to share with you
and you have to be
content with that
but I promise you if you just take a
step back and look at what is I'm
showing you it's light years
way way way Beyond everything else
you don't need to have this much degree
of understanding but what do you think
is occurring in here the algorithm is
allowing time for Traders that are in
the know that are real smart money
they're not Wyckoff Traders they're not
supplying demand guys they're not
Goldman Sachs guys
okay
they don't know this stuff I promise you
they don't know this
it's allowing them to get their orders
in before the algorithm reprices
then it goes to your first point of
reference which is the consequent
encroachment this Wick here
stops and then spends time
what's it doing
allowing them to build a larger position
what's the model where where's price
being drawn to higher
so allows them to accumulate more Longs
and then as it runs up
they're Distributing it all their
initial entries in here they're selling
it some in here and then new algorithm
entries
are in here
killing more
and as it runs up they sell sell sell
sell sell sell and that provides
liquidity
so there's this dance that's always
occurring
between inefficiencies and liquidity
premium to Discount discounted premium
always that's what's current it has
nothing to do with harmonics has nothing
to do with animal patterns has
nothing to do with Elliott wave has
nothing to do with anything that you see
in a retail book price is not moving on
any of that
that's not what's going on folks in
buying and selling pressure is not it
that is not it
your Market profile your volume bar is
turned vertical okay so you're you're
looking at them over here okay you're
looking at that and you're looking at
level two data and you think that that
makes you smart or that makes you
in the know
that is a gimmick it's a red herring
you're looking at stuff and you're not
seeing the things I'm showing you
I'm showing it to you in a 15 second
chart think about it 15 seconds
prices behaving in a way in which it's
been coded it's behaving
as it's told
it's not being pushed around because
buyers and sellers
that's not what's occurring here folks
sorry if that hurt your feelings I'm
sure some of you worked in an industry
and you feel like you know you're you're
part of the team and all but you know
you have a title
that you have an ignorance you have no
idea what makes these Mars go up and
down
and I'm not I don't care about titles
so one minute
here we have it
opening price we trade down to it here
rally up
consolidate around
what's it working in here on the one
minute chart
main threshold
rally
consolidate
allow smart trade smart money to
accumulate more longs
and displace into the upside now look
what's occurring here we're getting
short-term highs
we run above it short term High run
above it when it starts doing this and
you watch me do this many times and I
just did it again yesterday in my trade
for ES
when it starts creating these short-term
highs every time it runs above that in
your long high frequency trading
algorithms are dumping portions of their
position above that that's why I do it
okay I'm in there doing the same thing
that these entities are told to do when
they work with this algorithm and if
they're doing it
they're doing it because it's a purpose
in mind they're offset distribution
if they had accumulated long positions
in here and in here how do they
how do they exit
short-term highs move away from it above
that high is going to be by side
sell to this buy side
creates a short-term high retraces back
down increasing short-term High when it
runs above it again sell offset
distribute offset
they're long positions and distribute
them to willing buyers
where are the Willing buyers above
market price
every time you create a short-term High
somebody in there some Joker okay some
clown that there believes that Elliott
leaves and animal patterns move the
market around they're in there trying to
trade their little gimmicks and they're
trying to go short
so if they're going short they're going
to try to do what they're going to use
an order that they think is protective a
short position they use a buy stop where
are they going to place that buy stock
above the recent swing High
so using narrative
reading where price is going to go
why it should go there when it will
consolidate and pause
I've taught you that live today
I've taught you I've literally sat down
here with you and told you now did I
tell you
exactly how to do it right before CPI no
because I have to wait and see what it
does what does it leave
it leaves Clues all the time but I have
to wait to see what it will run for
I can't call the high and the low of the
day until midnight
in New York
but if I'm doing analysis and I'm
talking to someone they say hey what do
you think about this and what do you
think about that
if I don't have the reference points
that's required at midnight
I can only talk about what I know based
on the information that's being shown in
the information that we have available
at that time
when we have these high impact or medium
impact drivers that come out in the
marketplace
I have to wait for the potential for
manual intervention manual intervention
is here
we initially opened ran above the fair
value then dropped for sell signs so
think about what I taught you we
outlined real time before the market
delivered where the liquidity would be
and the inefficiency that would be
utilized
it opened ran up just above it let's go
back down to the 15 second chart
oops I gotta change it oh yeah
that
we opened rallied above that fair value
Gap I outlined
then ran for the sell side then it
ripped higher for the buy sign
the fact that it ran to the fair bag Gap
here then to the sell side in itself if
it was not a high impact news driver
like this
that type of run would have happened
over the morning session
and a later run in the afternoon would
have been this move here at the buy side
but because of the removal of liquidity
believe me there are people that want to
trade this but Brokers and liquidity
providers they pull
access away from the marketplace that's
intervention that's manipulation that is
a barrier to you being profitable
whether you like it or not it's gonna
happen and that's what they do around
non-farm payroll too
and they say oh there's a there's a an
absence of liquidity not because it's
organic believe me there's people that
want to trade they think they're going
to have something that is profitable
during this whole move
they created some kind of thing with a
moving average crossover
and they want to trade it they believe
it's going to make them rich
no it's prevented because these types of
moves offer a lot of movement in a very
short span of time and somebody could be
really wrong by by accident make a lot
of movement in terms of profit in the
broker if they're be booking them they
have to take that hit they don't want
that
that's the reality of this business
folks okay they're not going to come out
and say yeah that's right it's true
you're going to hear people come out and
say oh he's full of he's a liar
who's out here showing you what the
Market's going to do in a 15 second
chart
you gotta look man if someone is saying
something and they can't bring it and
show receipts then okay then then don't
trust that person
but if someone's willing to sit out here
live and explain all the mechanics
before it happens
either they know what they're talking
about or they had something to do with
it
and I'd leave that up to you you decide
if I'm full of you'll know if I'm
not you'll know
but after the fact
how we treated what was the first pool
Equity that was written the sell side
now think about if you were long
or any Trader that was long
if this report ran down and hit that
stop loss would you be willing to get
back in to go along
be honest now
chances are no you wouldn't and that's
why they do it
they run for the liquidity on the side
that they don't want to want
oh no let me say it right they run for
the liquidity first on the side that
they want to make sure they scare out of
entering and being
on the right side so it's the first run
on liquidity on medium or high impact
news drivers that tends to be the side
that would be the winning side if they
wait
then you see the buy side taken after
but you have to wait you have to wait
what does it want to do it pulls back
inside the range what range between the
two pools of liquidity that's this line
here and this line here let me thicken
them up
foreign
if you're on Twitter and you follow me
on Twitter if you like what I'm teaching
and this is resonating with you give me
a hell yeah
like the cuss to say heck yeah
okay so these these two reference points
that's their that's your range okay so
after took the cell side out and then by
side it pulled back into the range
now both of those pools of liquidity
Define a very specific range for
liquidity purposes we outlined buy side
was above here and sell side was below
here
the algorithm knows both those points of
reference just like I showed it to you
live before it was being used
where'd it go to
consequent encouragement
right in the middle
range Low Range High liquidity above it
liquidity below it
pulls back to consequent encroachment
the bias I gave you is going higher
would it reach for the first draw here
and then we wait does it want to take
the buy side here
then we went into
high high high
what I tell you offset distribution
algorithm starts selling and offsetting
their long position and every time it
takes out a high they're doing that
distribution they're selling to those
buy stops
what did it do after that
we're off the highs
listen folks
I don't know what you call foresight
versus cherry picking okay I don't know
where you're from what your culture is
and beliefs about things but when
someone says something and it
happens it's it's pretty set in stone
that either it works or it doesn't and
if you can't see this
like really there's nothing else there's
nothing else I can do
that make you understand that these
things are driven
100 controlled
well one minute chart
take this film off here
so in all this business notice that uh
this Wick here
I went inside the range between that
high and that
close
with that 15 second chart
so you might have a measurement of
consequent encroaching on this Wick here
that's fine but in Nest Wick I want to
be in the lower time frame very very
small time frames
and I just showed you Precision with 15
second charts
I told you how to omit
and don't even refer to specific candles
that's
that's one of the arguments that people
will say
they'll say hey uh you know time based
charts or nonsense they're garbage you
know this that that's someone that
doesn't believe number one there's a
nail Rhythm too doesn't believe
that you can use the element of time as
the most influential factor in price
delivery because everything around price
delivery is first controlled
and delivered by a schedule it's time
it's time and price Theory
time and price Theory not price and some
gimmicks
okay I know how to use a time-based
chart because I know time
I know the time when the algorithm is
going to behave I know what it's likely
to follow
and then I also know how to Omit certain
candles don't pay attention to certain
ones
and that's the Folly that I see people
over the years they've taken things in
look at this older blocks don't work
because they'll point to down closed
candles that aren't being respected you
have no idea what an order block is
and the folks that are making YouTube
videos
the simple way of using order blocks the
best order block you don't know what an
order block is take those videos down
it's embarrassing stop okay seriously
stop
all right so I wanna
ask you point blank
if you see
a reason to be accumulating a long
position in here
and in here and the market gives you
all the signatures in here
we understand this this pattern here is
a three drives pattern or as Linda Rask
and Larry Connors wrote in their book
Street smarts which I love and adore
that book not everything in that book I
subscribe to but it was one of the very
influential
manuscripts that taught me how to view
stop hunts
like that that book rung in the first
introduction to
victimizing Traders
where when I got stopped out I just said
well you know that system didn't work or
I did it wrong and I would beat myself
up emotionally and psychologically and
wreck myself you know constantly about
how I did that wrong not knowing that
one of the primary functions of the
market is to go to where liquidity is
and if you're wrong obviously you know
you're the liquidity so when I first
started that's how it was for me and
maybe that's where you're at in your
development right now maybe you're
you're struggling because every time you
participate maybe sooner than you should
even with the demo you're getting
stopped out and you're getting
frustrated and just know that I went
through that for years
I know you see the things that I do and
teach and show and call in them real
time too and there's it can't be a time
when ICT was a noob there was
there really was and I was the poster
boy for it like I blew accounts like
crazy I did it in stunning fashion okay
if you're gonna do it and do it right I
was the that was the best one at doing
it every possible thing that would have
caused me to blow an account I did it
recklessness greed impatience
um system hopping testing stupidity
seeing if certain things that you know I
had a hunch about none of it was helpful
and then because of the pain of losing
money
and the ideas that initially came from
Larry Williams you know his uh
uh confidential trading course for
future millionaires or something that
effect you know I've heard you heard me
talk about it many times
that that gave me a framework to start
looking at the market differently
whereas I was always jumping around
and while I don't use the things that he
teaches or taught then predominantly I
still believe that that would be a
wonderful starting point for someone
like to uh to know
how to look at price in the beginning
but I there's a lot of stuff that he
does that's indicator based now that
you know I just I love him to death and
he is my first real Mentor
um if I was honest it would be Ken
Roberts was there well not not
technically it's really my uncle my
uncle Stan was my first Mentor he's the
one that was talking me into trading
when I was 14 15 years old
and I really wasn't interested showing
me charts and stuff
but uh
the first paid Mentor I had was Ken
Roberts and I bought his
world's most powerful money manual
course and it was about trading
Commodities and uh very very
poor presentation of the marketplace but
it made me think I could quit my job in
Uber it's a span of 20 years I could you
know retire I started fleshing out this
whole idea of getting rich long term
and uh if I could make a thousand
dollars a month that would get me there
that's how I first started now contrast
that with what you see on Instagram and
YouTube and Twitter and discords and
everything else that's out there it's
real fast Lamborghini lifestyle you know
get rich real quick
and at this you know it's unfortunate
because you shouldn't be thinking like
that
but it's going to take you a lot longer
than you want them believe it will just
know that and I was in for the long term
I knew it was going to be hard
but I didn't realize how hard I was
going to make it for myself I knew how
to do most of what I'm doing here
um
the first three and a half years but
then I started to Tinker with improving
it and made more mistakes and just went
back to what I had arrived at
so
with that information
coupled with
chance meetings with people you're not
ever going to meet that combination of
insight you know makes me who I am in a
circle Trader ICT now the guy but uh
I want you to think about
what level of contentment do you require
are you trading to be
the best social media Trader
are you training to be the guy that
makes the biggest pit haul or Point Hall
the guy that tries to get the highest
high and the lowest level what is it
that you're trying to do because I went
through all those stages
as a Trader I went through all of that
the market
and the one you got to settle in on is
the the person that makes the money that
you're comfortable with making
some of you think that you want to make
millions of dollars and I'm gonna be
honest with you it's scary sometimes
when you're making big money
and you're probably not prepared for
that I'm going to be honest you're not
prepared for that nobody is when you
start making big money it's a weird
feeling you think it's going to be like
easy it's not
because it's intoxicating
you think that every Big Win is going to
be available every single time you get
into a new trade and you gotta control
you have to control that impulse
smart money distributed
real time I was explaining it to you and
look where we're drawing downtown to
the high end of that but I saw the
quarterly pool
that's this over here
and the lows are over here
okay
so when I show examples I'm doing you
know entries and stuff
and the guys out there that are trying
to sell their black box they
hate the fact that I'm able to do it
and they want to say it's cherry-picked
and I can't trade and my students don't
make money and do what they do
um I I understand marketing I understand
doing all that stuff but it really looks
bad
when you're constantly out there saying
that my students or I can't do this
stuff and I'm constantly
doing it real time I'm not afraid to be
out here and doing this and calling it
the logic is real
the authorship is genuine
and it repeats it's something that's
transferable
and when I'm outlining what it should do
and how it should behave
I'm leaning on elements that
you aren't able to know
and I'm trying to teach by example with
experience and repetition for the folks
that really want to learn how to do it
you can get it from what I'm teaching
you can get the very thing that you're
looking for but the problem is if you're
constantly moving and evolving into what
your your definition of success is
watch this little area in here
if you're constantly changing that how
do you rate or measure
success like what is it that you're
looking for that meets
the goal like are you trying to trade
to be better than me or better than
somebody else that doesn't like me so
you can Flex on social media because if
you're doing it that's stupid
if you're trying to be
the thought the most followed Trader
I should run into that right there
you're trying to do all those things
they're they're
superficial they don't mean anything
doesn't mean
making money being able to take care of
yourself and your family and build
generational wealth that way you can
transfer this information once you learn
it it's yours it's your skill set
you'll probably be met with the same
thing that my own kids have and because
all of you think out there man ict's
kids they should be so good at trading
and this and that other thing they're
kids
just like I was I wasn't interested when
I was 14 and 15 years old my uncle was
trying to tell me he had made money I
didn't give a I didn't care it
didn't mean anything to me I wanted to
be a kid and that's where my kids are
and I'm trying not to rush them because
believe me I want them to know how to do
this
and they just are kids they're this
their children at heart still and even
my 20 year olds you know they're still
trying to find themselves and my
daughter's completely lost she's
Perpetual student
college kid
because she doesn't want to embrace
adulthood and go out there and fail
and I'm her golden parachute that keeps
protecting her
let's see here
don't close candle
yeah
so far respecting that to see how if we
get up into this area here till we get
above it and treat us support
and let's go to a daily chart
maybe we have a little bit of ways to go
to get up into that
inefficiency there
initially we have worked into this high
so there's buy side here so that's what
we're looking at
also on
how the market was reaching into those
short-term highs and I'll tell you this
um a smart money offset distributes
their position when they're long
so look at this High here okay I'm going
to make this purple because I know I
think we got other colors on the
lower time frame or maybe I delete it on
recall but let's go back down until one
minute chart
yeah deleted it
that purple line here is that Weekly or
daily chart High
we went above it and since we went above
that we're in
kind of like an area of
the word excuse me I can't think of it
I'm trying to
say but we're above that high where
liquidity how far do you see it reach
on the daily chart let's go back up to
it real quick
or weekly router
this High here the next important level
above here is inside of this
inefficiency
right there
okay so we have consequent encouragement
about midpoints let's get the
measurements about it might as well
delivery you're gonna do it do it right
so 44.28 okay so 4428 is consequent
encouragement
and again I'll just throw this in here
because
invariably I know some of you are like
can you show me your FIB settings it's
the first time I watched your video
and that's an extension
okay so there's your ICT FIB settings
rewind the video if you want to see it
again so consequent crunch is midpoint
and that's above this High here so buy
side that would rest above here so buy
stops who have advice up about that
long-term hedge fund Traders big large
funds
rated here 44.28 okay that's the
midpoint of this candle's low and this
candle is high and that inefficiency
here is a FVG what kind of
fair value you got City sell side
imbalance buy side inefficiency meaning
that if the market were to efficiently
reprice to this
it would be doing it with a run higher
we've only had one pass through on the
downside with this candle here between
this candle is low and this candle is
high we have a partial run into it here
but we now have exposure still with
inefficiency
between this candle's low
and this candle is high
so what I'm saying is
if we look at it like this
that's the only real
at this moment
inefficiency that resides
in that old
gap between here and here
but not
a Zone I look at very specific price
levels
the 50 level of this inefficiency here
that is consequent encroachment at 4428
so that's a real level it's not some
range it's a very specific level
now because we have this range between
this high
in this candle's low that's shaded in
blue
I would do the same thing with that so
that we would have
a consequent quotient level of 4441 so I
have
44.41 is a key level to the upside
and 4428
they should be on your charts how you
note them is your business
I have it written in my notes
and so piece of paper that key levels
you know I have you know notations of
what time frame they're anchored to
that's it so me showing you that it
would mean nothing to you but shown you
in the chart like this and teaching it
I'm already always teaching the levels
I'm interested in anyway every time I'm
doing analysis or whatever
but that's how I'm referring to upside
and where it might draw to
but we just poked our head above this
old high and then let's go back down in
that one minute chart
remember I was counseling you to look at
how we were going higher
higher and higher
smart money that went long in here and
down in here
they would be selling their long
positions
above this high
and that's how you get your three drives
High formation
okay which is retail pattern it's
wonderful but how do you know when it
forms
everything I've outlined here this
morning I told you and brought your
attention to it right when it was
forming
is that cherry-picked I'll leave that up
to you just uh
so I would like to see how we behave
at this Gap right here
do we go through it like a hot knife
through butter
and go into this buy side or do we run
above it come back down and act as
support and then run which a little bit
more sustained run could manifest itself
if it did it that way
so we had what was that five minute
yeah so we had our five minute
Gap I told you to watch that there
went higher but inside this range of
this Wick okay let's go through that
four minute
three minute
two minute
one minute
did you notice how the bodies
except for the four minute
look it again here's one minute look
where the bodies were
they going inside the FVG no
just the wickwork
how about the two minute
look where the bodies were
the Wicks went down to offer what
the inefficiency that was in here
what is it inefficient
South Side delivery it's a buy side
imbalance cell side and efficiency busy
it is a FVG by classification
but specifics it's a buy side and
balance outside efficiency meaning that
it will likely need to drop into that
again offering
repricing once we leave that range
becomes what it's a balanced price range
let's go into three minutes
look where the body stopped here
in four minute
see what's happening there the Wicks are
doing damage but it's off offering the
sell side but the wicks
and bodies are not both inside that fair
Vegas
so what's it telling you
it's likely to go higher which is why I
told you I would like to see how it
trades to this and if it goes above it
events that the draw on here is what
we're looking for but if it goes above
it here but falls short of this high
does it act as support
let me see these flaring their own
colors let me see
I'll just do this
I always tell myself that
pour my water into a
a cup that we don't hear my water bottle
crackling but I never remember to do it
such a rebel
there you go
buy side so we didn't get a return back
into offer a support which would have
been a nice little
area to study for entry but we did get
the Fairbank as I mentioned here
let's go up into our climate chart
so now how far can it go ICT
when I have these types of runs what I
like to use the FIB for I'll take the
FIB
anchor it to the low
draw up to this high
and pull up the
extensions
okay this will be first partial assuming
that you would like if you're looking at
Price action
whether you back test it and it's
already happened like when you go to
work and come home later on you're
watching this video or you're at school
or if you're waking up again you're
sleeping while it's being live
you go back through the data like this
and you look at the price swings like
this you measure it one half of one
standard deviation or negative 0.5
that's always going to be a partial
no matter how you trade whether if it's
this time frame or another
if you have an extension that offers you
profitability I don't care if it's not
even five handles you have to learn to
take something there when you're first
brand new at learning how to do this
because it will reward you
and allow you to graduate into
trusting
trusting yourself trusting price action
and measuring when it doesn't reach it
how often does it not reach it versus
how many times it does
and then what you're seeing here was
negative one standard deviation which is
really the measured move of this low up
to this High added to this High
projected up so in other words if you
were to take this movement from here to
here
duplicate it from this high projected up
that's what this negative standard
deviation of one is so it's a perfect
measurement
I like to look at
how we have traded also so let's assume
for the moment and play Devil's Advocate
that we were long
in here
and we rallied up and we took partials
here
and we wanted to trade the daily range
not trade the session
when I'm doing my examples I'm teaching
you how to trade that particular session
so I'm moving my stop up to protect the
open profits for that particular session
which is what you watch me do yesterday
and you see me do in last Thursday's
example
so I showed you both
of those positions
working what the long side
why because my higher time frame
analysis that I've been sharing with you
has been calling es higher
why because it's going to trade in
sympathy to NASDAQ even though NASDAQ I
told you was to be was going to be the
leader
how do you manage the impulsiveness that
comes in with
not being in the strongest one because
either you didn't know it or you did it
by error
I'm teaching you how to not even concern
yourself with that
so if I've already told you that NASDAQ
was the leader on the upside but I'm
going to teach you with the medium of
the es and mini s p
cynics will say oh well you you didn't
trade in in queue so you're not even
following your model no I'm teaching you
and those individuals that will struggle
with the idea that they didn't trade
NASDAQ when it was the strongest one
because they didn't know or was told by
me after November of this year
I won't be telling you these things
so you have to lean on your own
experience and what you know
so
while it can be frustrating
that you're not in the faster running
Market
it doesn't matter because you can still
find you can still find setups
so by having this
outlined ex you know experience where we
know that the Market's likely to draw on
these higher time frame premium arrays
that means it's going to go up
how do I engage with it well how do I
teach you first start looking for one
good setup per week
just find one good setup not an everyday
setup
because if you can find a setup that you
can find once a week that same model
that same approach that you use for that
one setup that you've been waiting for
for one period of trading inside of an
entire week
you're going to forge discipline
self-control
you will get your ends met by that
and because you're getting experience
with it you can take that and reduce it
to a smaller time frame and you can find
more of that same model in formation
across the entire spectrum of the week
silver bullets exist in many runs but I
just gave you a very specific
time when they form every day
but unless you know where the Market's
going to go
it's highly unlikely that you're going
to be consistent with it because
you're just going to be guessing
and you're gonna look at every little
separation between three candles and
think it's a fair value got that it's an
entry on and it's not
you still have to know where the
Market's likely to go to
now Devil's Advocates say we were long
and it wasn't a CPI day it was just a
normal every run-of-the-mill day and we
went long and everything behaved as we
see here
we were taking partials here we were
taking majority of our trade off
in here the stop would have remained
below
the opening price
at 8 30 when the market started making
its run let's go back into
a limited chart
here's your E30 opening price
you would still have your stop or it
would be below this opening price
initially
let's get this scrubbed up here a little
bit
this Wick consequences would be in here
your stop would have to be below that
but ICT earlier you said it doesn't need
to go down it doesn't need to go down
there but it can revisit the consequent
encouragement it can
8 30 is when the news embargo lifts that
means there's going to be volatility
it's going to get up and down not to
this magnitude because CPI is a little
bit more aggressive
think of it like non-farm payroll it can
be a little bit more wild or more
animated
so or if you want to be very
conservative
your stop loss again you're trading for
the daily range so that means you're not
trying to do your 30 contracts your 40
contracts Max position okay you're
trying to trade the daily range or
you're trying to maximize the
availability of the full Daily range
your stock could be placed below here
minimum constant encroachment so let's
give you
the specifics on that
so stop loss would have to be below 43
88 and a quarter which is so close in
proximity to 43.87 and a quarter which
is the low end where I told you the sell
side look what being resided which is
relative equal lows here
and no no not that I'm sorry
here
and again I mentioned the buy side here
so
we've already worked that sell side
so how do you place your stop loss and
feel confident that it's not going to
hit it and knock you out if you're
trying to day trade
day trading is position trading for the
daily range
intraday scalping
is session trading that means you're
trading the morning session before lunch
in New York and in the PM session
there's a distinction there
when I say day trading what I'm saying
is you're trying to capitalize on the
majority of the daily full run from open
to close you're trying to get the
alliance portion of that move that's not
scalping that's day trading
scalping or intraday scalping or session
trading is where you're getting in and
out typically many times within the same
hour or so or two hours
how do you trade that ICT versus when
you're teaching us recently in the last
year or so when I'm doing my examples
I'm teaching you how to operate inside
of the session whether it be the morning
session or an afternoon session whatever
one I'm trading in at the time
I'm capitalizing the move that I foresee
that would be just the lines portion of
that specific session of the day whether
it be London session New York session or
New York PM session whatever it is I'm
trading it's relative to that specific
session
if you want to capture larger runs on
price
then you're going to leave
your stop loss which
I know some of you don't like that it
makes it
terribly fearful that leaving a stop
loss while the Market's running all up
here
and up here your stop loss would still
be below the opening because
you won't learn how to play stops and
move stops effectively in the beginning
by trying to move them tight or try to
see what I do like when you see me do
that it always comes with a price
invariably if you Trail your stop loss
it will be hit eventually it will
absolutely be hit my stops get hit when
they're trailed up eventually boom it
gets out but I have taken the majority
of my trade-off in profit before that
even happens
so when I do those examples I'm teaching
you
how to graduate into that now I know if
I want to be in a day trade if I think
the daily range is going to expand and
close near the high of the day and I'm
bullish
then I'm not going to need a rush to
move my
stop loss it's going to stay where I
initially place it and I'm not worried
about reducing its exposure because
throughout the day what am I doing I'm
taking partials to pay me which is in by
default it reduces the exposure that you
would have with a stop loss at or below
the low end of that range which would be
known here there's no need for it to
come back down here it's already done
the damage
and Traders are not going to be wanting
to go in here go long because they've
seen this big wick down here and it
whipped here now they're scared
and they don't understand what you're
being taught that the first run on
liquidity is the tip that's the that's
the signature that you're looking for if
you want to be long
the best time to go along is after sell
stops have been taken
I've said this in old videos on YouTube
some of the videos aren't even on my
YouTube channel anymore where are those
videos you're hiding stuff that's it's
just their old the production quality
sucked but the things I talked about
even when I was on baby Pips many of you
let it go in one ear out the other
but it's still it's still true
so if you're looking for
uh bias you want to learn how to do
daily bias it starts with understanding
where that Weekly chart is likely to go
to
that's that's the first
thing you have to decide is it going to
more likely go up on the weekly candle
or down why would it be wanting to go
higher or lower that's what I've been
showing you
that's what I've been putting your
attention to on that Weekly chart
and every time it starts to go low
intraday charts on one minute three
minute and five minute candles you see
people out there trying to chase it like
it's going to go lower
and it's only going down to present new
buying opportunities that's all it's
doing it's going into discounts
so as a day trader you know you could be
still long your stop loss will be below
the the low end of that dealing range
where sell side was already tagged
lines portion of the move will be off
here and you would have taken partials
Above This High here as well
you would not as a day trader put your
stop loss below that low
why
what do I teach you about the lunch hour
lunch hour macro runs on liquidity what
liquidity the stops that would favor the
folks that have been profitable all
morning long going into the New York
lunch they have trailed their stop loss
because they don't want to lose open
profit when really they're guaranteeing
no potential further open profit because
the market will in fact many times go
down and take out the low of the day
that was formed prior to 11 or noon near
political time
they'll take those stops when does it
occur between 12 o'clock
New York local time and 1 30 New York
local time
don't believe me go into your charts and
see if it's what's going on I don't want
you to believe anything I'm saying I
want you to go into the charts and back
test and look at that stuff because you
will see it you won't need to hear me
say it all the time
it will be in your notes and you'll
it'll be part of your repertoire
so I taught a lot of stuff today and for
someone brand new or this is the first
live stream you want us to buy me it
probably feels disjointed it feels like
it's
not really you know organized well it
didn't really teach you anything that
you can go out and do tomorrow
um actually I taught you a lot that you
can go into your charts right now when
I'm closing this live stream you can go
into your old price moves and start
studying it with these things and
reference points that I gave you
um I outlined it live for you I told you
where the Lakota on both sides would be
I told you the framework with the fair
value got I mentioned that we would
watch this one here we're bullish okay I
didn't say we're topping just means that
we're looking for the 9 30 opening
okay what is it going to run for and I
told you I want to see how it behaves at
this very value Gap and we're down here
and we would want to see it run for the
buy side which it did the longer term
draw
the 4428 I think the first one was
okay so that's Costco encroachment of
the old weekly
City
okay so have that on your chart so 4428
and uh
treat that going forward into the rest
of the week
and study how we deliver if at all it
may not get to get up there this week it
doesn't have to do it this week
but I'm looking for it to graduate
towards
those levels have outlined on the weekly
chart nothing says that we are making a
high
score that we've topped okay
I think that's going to be sufficient
for today
hopefully you learned something
hopefully I'll give you some homework to
go into your charts and start analyzing
and see where things are manifesting
and build up that experience with your
journal the more experience that you
gain in studying old moves the better
you're going to be because your brain is
going to retain that as framework and
when you start watching price real time
tape reading where you're not pressing a
demo entry you're not trading with a
live account
you're just watching price and observing
what it's doing that is a critical part
of learning how to do this whether you
learn how to trade through me or anyone
else I promise you if you put more time
into that
you will be more equipped better
equipped
to trade and try to get these funded
account challenges if you want to do
funded accounts or trade with your live
funds
and you'll know you won't need me I
never tell anybody it's time for you to
start trading with real money
you'll know because you'll be bored by
the results you'll see yourself doing
all the time you won't be emotional
about it and when you get to that point
and you're learning
that is my opinion for you to decide
whether or not you want to get in and
start risking real money
because you're not influenced by the
money or swayed by the periodic times
where you do it wrong you're doing it
right more times than you're doing it
wrong so therefore the results show that
there is a probability of sustained
profitability
if you stick to that same approach going
forward
so if we found this one insightful today
folks and I'll talk to you next time be
safe