welcome back folks
it's been a while since i've posted
another video to the youtube channel
so i appreciate your patience and as
always your continued interest
in my content all right so we're going
to talk about
liquidity i'm going to try to make this
as brief as i possibly can
i tend to go overboard sometimes with
insights and
commentary but i'm going to try to do it
as short and concise as i possibly can
which invariably will always
inspire questions concerns it will
create
gaps in your understanding and that's
normal okay just know that it's meant
for you to investigate on your own study
because i'm going to frame it in that
capacity so that way you know
while it's not just perfectly
form-fitted for this example
students of mine for a long period of
time will
hear certain things that i've talked
about in passing
in other commentaries and other youtube
series
videos that you can find on this channel
i'm not a pattern trader
in the sense that i'm looking for as
it's commonly referred to as
a trading pattern like a harmonic
pattern okay like a bat
or gartly or
a fibonacci sequence we're not looking
for those
things so while i may reach for
fibonacci to
show a level of projection and maybe
show
and highlight an area that is
visually representing a valuation that
would be
undervalued or overvalued or in the
sense that it's overbought oversold
without using an oscillator okay we're
looking at specific
ranges so i'm going to touch a little
bit on my l7 ranges
specifically in this lesson it's going
to be a seven range example
and again it's not trying to teach you
everything because there's no
way i could do this but it's also one
more
illustration of my i haven't ran out of
yeast
okay this baker has a lot of yeast and i
can
continue to teach for decades in the
future and still not run out of content
because i understand the algorithm now
what i'm going to show you today
would be normally reserved for students
that are in my mentorship but i want you
to appreciate the level of
systematic delivery of price
why it does what it does and try to just
simply suspend your belief system
on any other model
or school of thought like if you're a
supply and demand
you know follower or if you're an elite
wave trader or harmonic trader
if you trade uh market profile
all those things just for a moment try
to put that
to the side and try not to lean on
any of your logic just for a moment okay
during
the time of this recording just suspend
all belief in that
i'm not saying believe this
wholeheartedly but i want you to just
listen to it
and then go into your charts and you'll
find it okay
so all right so we're looking at the
dollar cad and this is a pair
admittedly i don't trade a lot but if i
don't get a set
up in euro dollar or pound dollar i will
sometimes
resort to trading this pair or the
aussie dollar
okay so so i just want to toss that
you know the little disclaimer out there
i'm not actively trading dollar cat a
lot
but i want you to think about some
general themes here
again i mentioned the l7 range theory
and it's basically trading inside the
range
i'm going to frame a range for you so
that we can see a little bit of the
context that's
required but most of the things i'm
going to show you here are pretty
simple and straightforward and it's not
hard it's not about moving parts
but there are very specific rule-based
ideas that need to be considered when
you
look and study at old data and you'll
see that this
occurs when we're looking at
liquidity okay the easiest way to
determine that
is anything that would reside above
a short-term high
or an intermediate term high now you
might look at this area here and say
which one is the high
well this candle is slightly higher than
all of them but whenever i see
multiple candles or multiple levels that
look very close to one another in height
or in depth in terms of the the lows if
we're looking at
if we're considering the opposite in
terms of looking for
sales liquidity buy side liquidity rests
above old highs
now it can come in the form of these
areas like this where it's
relative equal highs okay that's one of
the concepts that
i use to frame the idea and
understanding of liquidity
now liquidity can be formed on the basis
of a single
point of reference like this high or
this high or this high
or it could be a collection of
relatively equal highs or relatively
equal
lows like this there this would be
considered
relative equal lows in my school of
thought
this is relative equal highs in my
school of thought this is a single
by side liquidity pool old high this is
a single
bicep equity pool short term high
these things okay are not required
for a label sense it's just i'm showing
you
the contrast between the two
but generally anything above an
old high would be buy side liquidity
that means there's buy orders up there
now as a new trader that sounds a little
alien it doesn't make sense
who would be wanting to buy up there
because your books are telling you buy
low sell high
there's always traders that are going
short or traders that want to buy on a
breakout that goes above that so that's
the
context of why that's buy side liquidity
and i teach it
from a institutional perspective i'm not
looking at it in terms of saying
you know this is a resistance level i'm
teaching that this
is an area where there are willing
buyers up there
and that perception of price action
once you start adopting that and looking
at price with that
view your
opinions your bias your
analysis will slowly start to migrate
away from
away from the retail logic that all of
us are
indoctrinated with when we first come
into trading that's a normal thing
but statistically proven if you look at
all of the
retail logic that's available to us why
is it that
90 of the traders lose money it's
because the logic is flawed
okay so if it's flawed what is the
common denominator as to why retail
logic
fails more times than it wins i'm not
saying it can't win i'm not
now i'm not saying that retail traders
always lose and i'm not saying that a
retail trader can't be
profitable even using retail logic but
they have to make a departure from
all things retail at some point they
have to inject their own experience
into the analysis and that experience is
going to be a byproduct of looking at
things
experientially and seeing okay i've
learned this pattern in the books i've
seen this author
i've seen this you know educator or
trader
guru mention this
idea but i've seen in this instance when
that pattern's there
it fails because of other things that i
didn't learn in other books
and you're going to have these
epiphanies that's experience that you
can't just get from a book
i can't transpose all of my experience i
can talk about things that i learn
experientially
like what i'm going to show you here but
it's important for you to understand
that
the main common denominator is the
markets
are manipulated and they're manipulated not on a random basis but they're manipulated with a rule-based
structure so i'm going to give you a
little bit of the details
and how you can start looking for these
types of signatures in price
so if you look at this dollar cad we
have an old low here and price has
rallied up now
retail logic states that we have this
low
as a support level why because price
moved away from there
we don't go into describing why it would
have turned there
from a retail trader they just
deem it as well that's support because
why if
price hits it and repels then it's a
support level okay that might be simple
enough for you to subscribe to i don't
look at like
that i look at it as okay there is now
engineered liquidity
now what does that mean that means that
the market has turned on a dime here and
rallied higher
i see this as a liquidity pool
of sell side orders okay sell side
liquidity
anyone that would have an order below
that would be a seller
they want to sell why would they want to
sell below that because anyone that's
long here
or even chasing price they're going to
look back to this level and feel
confident that well it bounced there
before so
even if it starts to come down which may
be very uncomfortable for them
they have belief and faith
and confidence that their books have
indoctrinated them
into believing that this is a level that
should prevent
price from going lower and i used to
think like that until i lost
thousands of dollars and then it quickly
dawned on me that i'm probably not
following the right things
so i want you to think about that low
with
the target or bullseye of
the price wanting to go down to that
level to attack
the liquidity that rests below that low
now it may take
months before it gets to this low but if
it gets to this low
this is what i want you to start looking
at and it doesn't only work on daily
charts this works on
hourly charts it works on four hour
charts it works on weekly charts
okay so it's important that you know
that this liquidity
idea i'm teaching you here is just part
of the framework
but we can see eventually on the 9th of
november
price trades down and goes below that
low this
is an important event when this day runs
below this low
it's a crucial event algorithmically
because what it's doing is it's going
into a pool of liquidity
now we don't know with any
absolute assurity that what i'm going to
outline here
is going to unfold but i'm going to give
you the things you'd look for
to build confidence that it is likely to
and you'll see by going through your own
charts how fast you can see these
scenarios developing we're going to go
down to an hourly chart and study
this fractal where it goes below this
low here i'm going to release
information to you that would otherwise
not be shown on my youtube channel so
let's go over to the hourly chart now
all right see here is the hourly dollar
cad chart now right away it probably
doesn't look like much to you okay but
i'm gonna add annotations in a moment
but i want you to take a look at some of
the things without having any scribbles
any kind of
annotations or markings or labels on the
chart
just let me flesh it out for you a
little bit and then we'll throw the
lipstick on the chart
you should be able to see this high in
this low
as a important price range now what
makes it important
it's the most dominant price range in
this portion of price
action so whenever i'm looking at price
i look for clear discernible price
ranges
when the range is clearly defined as you
can see here
what i do is i want to look for
reference points
based on measurements that are very
generic okay so in other words i want to
know what this high is here
on this candle and i want to know what
the low of this candle is
now we're looking at this with the
expectation that
we're anticipating a run below that but
we don't know if it's going to continue
we wait for something to occur which
i'll outline here
and then once it happens it gives us
framework for short-term bias
and where the draw and liquidity is
going to be in an opposing order
in other words we see a an attack on
southside equity with this day here
if something occurs as i outline that
will be your
green light to anticipate opposing buy
side liquidity
to be taken okay so the concept i'm
showing you here
is purge and revert okay purge and
revert
all right so when we look at liquidity
you want to be able to look at it on the
basis of daily highs and lows
now when you look at daily highs and
lows you can add period separators to
your chart like tradingview.com allows
you to do
i'm not sure why it takes so long to
load up like that but there it is
but if you put the period separators on
trading view
this is the levels that you're going to
get now
i'm not going to argue that what i'm
going to show you use
better or that you can't use this either
i'm just teaching you the way i look at
it okay so if you're here on my channel
that more or less indicates that you're
interested
to see how i think about it may not
subscribe to everything i say
in fact i would count you not to do that
there's things i'm going to say in this
video and maybe in other videos
that will be offensive to you because
you are holding fast to your
your your logic your system your your
method and if it's profitable
don't allow me to change your mind about
something that may be working for you
but if you can take something from the
things i'm going to show you here and
glean
insight that may improve upon what
you're already doing
that's really my only intention here
okay but it
will be better if you could suspend all
of the previous
ideas that you have about price okay and
looking for things
i don't do it like this okay so what i
do is i look at the
midnight to midnight time frame and i
delineate my
session breaks like that so it'll look
like this
okay so all my vertical lines here are
midnight to midnight new york time
once this low which is highlighted
with this line here that's that old
daily low
and we see that run below that old daily
low here that is a
purging of liquidity now once this purge
occurs
we want to see the day of that purge we
want to start looking
backwards okay and other video series
and other videos and other commentaries
i've done
with forex and trading technical
analysis concepts and such
you'll hear this repeat
three days okay i use a three day range
of look back okay if you look for the
last three days
you'll have all the liquidity pools you
need to make money
you'll have all the liquidity pools to
target
for your trades you'll have all the
liquidity pools that you could use
for trade entries and you don't need
anything other than that
you don't need to have a ipta 20 day lit
look back period you don't need to have
a 60 day you don't need to have a
40 day you don't need to look back on
your weekly charts and see how many
times something hit a level
14 different times to have any faith in
it
the market does not look back 20 years
ago
the market does not look back five years
okay it looks at predetermined price
levels
and that's the reason why the algorithms
operate the way they do
and what i mean by that for some of you
that are not technically inclined or
familiar with computer programming for
those that are this will make a lot of
sense to you but those that aren't
uh just bear with me for the folks that
are technically inclined
i'm not trying to talk down to those
individuals that aren't i'm just trying
to be
as inclusive as possible and
comprehensive so that way you understand
what i'm saying here
so it doesn't go right over your head
because i can clearly see
there's going to be a lot of people that
are going to be confused by this lesson
but if you just take it for what i'm
going to show you here and then go into
your own charts you'll see what i'm
referring to
and then it'll click so the day of the
purging
in other words the day it runs below
that old daily low
when that happens we count that as day
one okay that's day one of that event
of purging we wait
to see if it goes higher and reverts
not reverses okay i'm not saying
reversal
i'm saying revert what is it reverting
to it's reverting to
buy side so it draws to cell side
liquidity
and that's counted as day one that is
day one
day two day three that's our look back
on the day of liquidity purge
so the day it occurs you look back
three days now inside the range
prior to the liquidity purge you got to
look back and see where is that range
now you could have looked at this say if
you're looking at a 15-minute chart
maybe you would have seen it as
this high to this low and that's fine
there's nothing wrong with that you
would be just using five-minute charts
to get the same premise i'm showing you
here on an hourly chart
it's all scalable folks the things that
i teach
are very friendly to making it your own
i don't mean that by saying take my
content rename it and put a youtube
video up
okay that's not that's not what i'm
saying here what i'm saying is
it allows you the freedom and
flexibility because if the method
and concepts are legitimate it will
allow
anyone any number of people to come in
and form their own model and which
doesn't seem logical to a new trader or
someone that's a neophyte
someone coming to this for the first
time like it was for me
there only is one way of doing it
successfully and i've learned
it took me about six years to get there
but when i first started in 1992
it took me six years before i realized
that there isn't
one way to be profitable there is a
myriad of ways but there
are certain things that you need to
understand that puts the odds
more in your favor then if you didn't
know it
and the adversities that you have and
suffer through
are really avoidable okay you have to at
some point you have to admit that these
markets are
100 controlled they are you know we have
uh breakers in the marketplace that says
once it trades this much trading halts
for a little while
okay isn't that a measure of control
sure it is
and it's not limited to that they know
where these markets are going to go
they're
driven there okay and this is an example
of
engineered liquidity engineered
liquidity is where they run
down take those sellers out of the
marketplace for what purpose
it allows individuals that are on the
smart money side of things
informed traders okay large
institutional traders bank traders
and they will use that liquidity to be a
counterparty to their buying
so it is a way of looking at price and
saying okay
i don't need to have an overbought
oversold indicator i don't need to have
a divergence in an oscillator i don't
need to have harmonic
on my side i'm just looking at where
liquidity is
and if we see an old daily low taken
that is a significant pool of liquidity
there's lots of orders below an old low
like i indicated on the daily chart
before transitioning to the hourly but
this event where it goes below that low
it's being paired with smart money that
wants to buy now
right away some of you are looking at
well this is all hindsight i'm teaching
it through hindsight
but i promise if you go through your
charts the things i'm showing you here
they repeat over and over again which is
a basis for a model
this could be your unique trading model
and it's not really shown anywhere in
any of my content
i don't even teach this even in
mentorship what i'm showing you here
is fresh but it's using concepts that
i've touched on even in this free
youtube channel
and in my mentorship so i'm blending
both of
the worlds that are inside my mentorship
and outside i'm bringing them together
with something for free
right here so that way you can gain a
greater understanding of what the
markets are doing and why they're doing
it
if this is true if my assumption and my
argument that i pose to everyone that
comes to me
if these markets are not 100 manipulated
by an algorithm
then the things i'm going to show you
here won't hold up
if price runs below an old low that
sells liquidity has been purged
only if we start to move away from it
now it might be a sweep on stops
and then it continues higher but if it
runs below it and then
goes back above a specific level what
level would that be
but we want to look at the day that it
occurs and it runs the liquidity out
so this day here i've annotated the
daily high
if that high is traded to and through
that is a market structure break
only on the basis of a liquidity purge
now it does not mean it's 100 successful
it just means that
from an algorithmic standpoint if we're
looking at logical steps of
of processes we look for this if this
occurs then we look for this
if that occurs then we look for this and
if that occurs we look for that so it's
a matter of looking at
a recipe for a model
that would be unfolding dynamically so
if this
stays high when it takes the liquidity
it's broken
on the outside here i don't need it to
close above it
that's not i don't need that because the
narrative is
it ran below an old low for liquidity if
it's going to go higher
the algorithm will start its macro and
macro is a short order of
processes that begin and
go step by step and it's like a small
little
algorithm in a sense and the large
algorithm that creates and controls
price action
it's just a bunch of smaller little
algorithms that
tie together and it's very complex
obviously
but just know that you can reduce it to
something as simple as what i'm showing
you here it may not seem simple
right now because i'm a little wordy but
i need you to understand there's certain
things that are at play here that
cause these things okay that occur so
the run below the liquidity
if that day's high is broken we see it
here
then we can start looking for buy side
liquidity
for the algorithm to revert to here's
the previous day's high
that's all these little blind segments
are i'm looking at the daily high
that is between 12 and 12 midnight each
day
so this day's liquidity is tape
taken out but it's a break in market
structure
on the basis and narrative that we've
taken cell side liquidity out
so now once it does this where do we
anticipate price going to
well you first have to revert back to
this high
in this low so we're looking at how much
we're going to
retrace from this low into this high it
may not ever get back to that high and
here's the thing you don't need to have
it go there but you need to know where
the midpoint is
and that's what this level is here so
that's basically equilibrium
between the high and the low of that
obvious range
now the algorithm knows this range high
and it knows the low it forms here
the midpoint is equilibrium so what
we're doing is we want to look at
three days back as far as in terms of
time
the liquidity above the daily highs as
far back as day three
and the filter is the midpoint or
equilibrium of the range that it's
traded in prior to
the liquidity being purged now i already
know some of you
you know some of your ears are smoking
right now you're thinking man this is
too much
i need a trend line right now somebody
tossed me a moving average i say t is
killing me here
trust me okay when you watch this video
a few times
and go into your charts you'll see it
it's there but the range
needs to be filtered okay once we get to
the 50 point or 50
level of the high and the low that's all
i really use a fibonacci for folks
you know i'm just looking for
equilibrium and anything
at or above it in my mind is expensive
in other words it's a premium market so
it's going to require a whole lot more
for me to be a buyer
and many times it will negate me being a
buyer
but it will not disqualify
a long entry that i've maybe entered and
i did not so
we are clear now i didn't take a trade
on this i'm just showing you
conceptually
how you can study and see these things
going forward
but you can use these ideas
to frame the logic on holding
long positions or partials to get to
this level and then
day three in this case here so what i
mean by that we have the high
the low the logic behind the run on
stops on the sell side liquidity rate
okay so this is purged if we get a run
above the day of
the purging and then we start looking at
the previous day's highs
and above that is going to be liquidity
until we get to the 50
level of the range once it does that
we are in an iffy like it might not
continue going higher it could but it
might not
but if we have day three still in close
contention with this level in other
words it's not that far above it
and it's not a lot of range in terms of
where
the equilibrium is and where the
previous day or day three's
high would be that bicep equity would be
potentially attacked
so we can see each day on the
10th of november
we had the break above the old high here
market structure is broken so now we're
thinking buy side liquidity is going to
be the next draw
that means your bias on a short term is
look for this high to be tapped
and maybe this one we don't need to go
all the way back up here
okay we don't need to go all the way
back up to the last up closed candle
which is a bearish order block
okay you're looking at high probability
high probability
this is what this is high probability
short term trading
so if we see that they're all on bicep
liquidity is
the context that the algorithm is going
to be operating under
they've already done the damage guy
going down traders are going to be
looking for a continuation they're going
to be looking for
bear flags they're going to be looking
for bearish garlies they're going to be
looking for bearish
you know anything to get them short
and supply and demand traders are gonna
be looking for
supply zones to go short at
traders that use simple support
resistance levels are gonna be looking
at okay well we bounced here let's draw
that out in time
and it might sell off here and when it
starts to go down like that they get
really excited
you thinking like this are thinking well
we have a break in market structure
your eye goes here where their eyes
looking for this
level to be touched again because it's
support level
you see the paradigm shift that's taking
place already in a short little video
now this feels long for some of you
but it's a very short window of time
that i'm framing
a mode of logic that repeats all the
time
on all time frames but if we're going to
use it in this context using a look back
of three days
then it's framed on a daily chart and it
can be
reversed obviously if we're looking for
runs above old daily highs
but look back is three days equilibrium
is the
high the low split in the middle so all
i did was to get that level you put a
fibonacci on this high
to this low and whatever the 50 level is
you annotate that on your chart
so each day after this day you are
looking for
this pool of liquidity to be traded to
and this pool of liquidity to be traded
to once it does that
high probability goes away
it changes okay so the algorithm goes
into a
different mode of delivery it can become
a deeper retracement or it could
accelerate
into that high that's not what i'm going
to teach here i'm not teaching that that
and i know some of you are already say
say you're holding back
no it just requires a whole lot more to
teach and
i don't have the time for it and you
wouldn't want to sit through it anyway
so each day this high
you know being broken of this creates
the market structure shift
bisect liquidity here if we draw that
out in time
and we're going to draw this one out in
time
okay and
this one here because it's above the
three
and it's the last one so if we continue
with that bias you know we'll see if
there's any
continuation of that logic reaching for
both side liquidity
all right so now we have bicello cody
here bicello cody here
and by sell equity here and we're going
to look at
the 11th of november and we're going to
look at that on a
15 minute chart so let's drop down to
the 15 minute time frame and look at
this
here and how it attacks these blue
levels
all right so here is the 15 minute time
frame of that dollar cad
and we can see the short little lines
are always going to be
individual daily highs
the elongated blue lines are going to be
those old liquidity pools
that we're looking for price to trade up
into so
on the 11th we have price trading in
here
and again all i'm annotating here is
this candle's high
which makes that high we don't use the
the midnight high
when we're looking at all this data here
if this midnight candle
makes a higher high we don't call the
11th daily high that one
because it's really technically the 12th
so we're
using only the data that makes
the individual day prior to midnight in
new york time
so the highest high and the lowest low
that's what we're looking for
but as soon as we get to midnight
everything starts
new that's a new range for the day
so we have equilibrium here so we know
the price could jump to that
or at least this level here and this
level is the initial one because it's
below
equilibrium and it's the old liquidity
pool on day
two look at how price trades back down
in
to this run here isn't this an optimal
trade entry
watch here's your swing low
all right so here is the fibonacci laid
on that
price swing i'm using the bodies of the
candles again not using the wicks and
the tails because the bulk of the volume
is in the bodies
so it's going to give you a pure read on
where the buy signal is going to be
all right it doesn't mean that you can't
use the wicks and the tails it just
means when i'm looking for optimal trade
entry
i prefer to use the bodies of the
candles because it will give you a pure
read on the entry if i'm looking at
ranges
okay like when i outlined on the hourly
chart
and showed you where the high was and
the low was and then did the 50
when i'm looking at finding equilibrium
i will use
the wicks and the tails okay i get a lot
of questions you know by way of email
and people get confused
you know why does ict um use the wicks
and sometimes the bodies
he's not consistent it confuses me i
just answered that for you
okay the bodies are going to give me the
pure entry point
the wicks and the tails are used just
for measurement of ranges
okay so if i'm going to look for a
pattern of entry i'm using the bodies
if i'm looking for equilibrium
measurements
then it's always going to be wicks and
tails okay
when it comes to order blocks that's a
different theory which i won't touch on
here
but again take for what you get
so we have the optimal trade entry in
here trades down to that and we have a
standard deviation of
negative one-half and it overlaps
basically with that old liquidity pool
and then we have it trading up to
equilibrium here at negative one
we have negative two just above
the old liquidity pool and we have
negative 2.5
which is with this new liquidity pool on
thursday before friday's trading
and the market trades there on friday
and again we have price trading
down initially creating a judas swing
what's the context we're looking for
price to revert back to
buy side liquidity because it's already
done its job
over here running that old daily low so
each day we're looking for
clues if it's going to go to the buy
side equity each day it's going to be
reaching for a specific
level of liquidity it's not guess work
it's very easily
discerned what is the previous highs
where above that high can price reach to
then price will start they're stepping
towards that
it's not respecting trend lines it's not
respecting
patterns it's respecting where the
liquidity is
okay the market's going to go where
there are orders it has no regard or
respect for
anybody's trading pattern okay the
market's gonna go
where there is counterparty period and
if there isn't enough counterparty there
the market will create it it'll engineer
it
it'll run up blow out equal highs it'll
blow out
equal lows and it'll change sentiment on
the basis of that event
here we have the market trading above
the equilibrium trading to an old
liquidity pool and trades back down
now we still have time in the week
and it can still continue but isn't this
an optimal trade entry as well
and a breaker we have a
low a high a lower low use the highest
up close candle
i'm just adding this in here just for
bonus no extra charge
we have the body right there so when the
market trades down into that
that's your bullish breaker and your
order block
down close candle before this
displacement optimal trade entry
we'll add that again watch what i'm
doing i'm putting it on the bodies
we get above thursday's liquidity pool
here not by much
but we have a standard deviation of
negative one that with these
equal highs here or relative equal highs
we could potentially see it
try to get up and snag that i'm not
saying it will
because we're above equilibrium but that
is how i would look at it now if this
was say
say this was tuesday wednesday and we
were still in an active trading week
that i would still be hunting longs and
i would look for a standard deviation
of negative one or negative one and a
half
because it would be expanding above the
relative equal highs
and i would look for it for like 10 20
30 pips and i would look for that type
of thing to occur and try to attack that
132 big figure
that is not an analysis i'm just saying
that that's how i would use it if it
were
you know still in an active trading week
now what am i showcasing here
am i just talking about hindsight and
just trying to dazzle you with something
that's obvious in the charts
some of you might come away from this
video with that opinion and you're free
to have that
but those individuals that go into the
charts and start looking at what i'm
showing here
is simplest short overview of what i
just did here
you look for areas in the marketplace
with old highs and old lows and if the
market trades down below it
wait to see if it wants to break the day
it trades below it in other words
this is the event day if it trades above
that then we potentially have a market
structure shift
so we start looking for previous day's
highs and the liquidity that will be
resting above it
previous days high with liquidity
resting above it you are not
looking back three days every time a new
day comes back and then finding that we
are looking at
three days back counting day one of the
purge on liquidity
that is how the algorithm reads it how
does it select which day michael if
there's an algorithm how to do it
i'm telling you this is one of the ways
that it does it it
looks back three days now why three days
you're probably asking why is it three
days ict
well there is classically there is a
and i have to show it to you like this
if you're looking at a chart
and
we're looking at an old low
i teach this and this is really this is
a fundamental
truth that if you look at most turning
points in the marketplace
you see some kind of
depiction of turning point like this in
price this would be like
a swing low now if you're using things
like with mt4 they have a
a fractal indicator i don't i'm not i've
never been a fan of that and even if you
look back at the stuff i did when i
stepped out on the stage
just to teach on forex in 2010
i went against that whole mt4 fractal
indicator because
it requires five candles and five
candles
good grief the move is already done
we're anticipating
the lowest candle to go into something
like this generally
that's how i take as i teach it there's
something down there we're anticipating
the next candle if it has a higher low
right away that's the turning point for
me
so we look back three days because
this event like it does here when it
runs below that old daily low that's
indicated by this line here
when that occurs it might not just be a
one day event it might be
a two day event where it goes even
deeper so
when it creates that we count that as
day one
two and three and we identify that
liquidity
on those days if it
goes lower i'm still going to refer
back to the original day three it just
gives us one more day of potential
liquidity it may reach for
but it's three day on the basis that it
creates turning points and just like
everything else i teach if you just
reverse it and put this here
the swing highs form generally like
this we have a high a higher high and a
candle that has a lower high
now this candle's high might be lower
than this candle's high or it could be
higher the real point is that there's a
candle that has a lower high to the left
a lower high to the right and that's
usually a classic swing high
swing low again has a higher low to the
left a higher low to the right
and this could be a higher low than this
candle or it could be
lower it doesn't that's not what we're
really
pressing here there is logic behind what
i'm showing you here you can
use other things for that which is a
completely different lesson but for just
a classification of a swing high swing
low for turning point basis
this is what it graphically looks like
most times it doesn't always you know
appear like that
but on most cases it does look like that
and that's the reason why the logic is
three days because the turning points
generally form
with that type of structure all right so
your job your homework going forward
using this
information is to see how the market
reaches for liquidity i get a lot of
questions all the time how do you know
what
side of the market to trade on because
if i could do that ict if you could just
teach me how
to learn to be a buyer or seller is it
going to be an update or a down day
i will be profitable and i'm going to
tell you you're not correct in thinking
that
because there's other things that's
going to get in the way when you think
you've scratched that itch then you'll
have 20 more that says well ict talks
about the candles and the wicks and then
you'll argue about that
when what i just gave you here did i
bring in commitment traders reports
no did i bring in the traders trinity
which i don't even look at anymore
no did i talk about pivot points no
mitigation blocks nope did i teach
catapult whiplash nope
there's lots of different patterns and
there's lots of different ways that you
can take small little samplings of the
things i teach
with the proper context and narrative
and it becomes a complete model
you need to look at all of these days
here with the times of day that i teach
which is the london open kill zone the
new york open kill zone close kill zone
and look how these patterns form there's
optimal trade entries in these
days based on the logic that it's going
to reach for the liquidity above here
and here period
it's structured it's not contrived
it's not form-fitted because if you go
back and look at every other event and
here's the other thing reverse it and
look at how the market does when it
trades
above old highs but here's the thing
you're going to if you are going into
this to find
times where it fails okay if that's what
you're trying to do right away
you're going to miss the lessons that
it's going to show you
by doing it with the investigative
approach in other words
does it show this logic because in
future lessons i'll touch on this again
and it'll be on my youtube channel but
you need to first see
this okay anything i mean i can look at
my order block theory
and go in and find 50 examples where it
would be viewed as
failing if you just look at it from the
perspective that youtube people
put up videos and they think they
understand my order block theory no
it's not complete my mentorship has not
exhausted that
you you can always torture the data and
if you manipulate
you know hard and fast and long long
enough it will
confess to anything but there has to be
a logic
in play so let's go back in closing take
everything off and go to a daily chart
the market has consolidated for a long
period of time in here
and we have this old low when the market
drives down below that
i don't care if it's going to go up a
little bit and then
continue going lower because that's not
a
model i'm trying to frame here i'm not
teaching you long-term trading i'm
teaching you a short-term way of
determining
where the next draw on liquidity is
going to be is it going to be
aiming for the buy side or the sell side
now there are
other ways to discern whether
buy sides going to be attacked or sell
side liquidity it's going to be attacked
and that might be your model but they
all going to lean
on general principles that are generic
and that means when we have a period
like this in consolidation
this old low if it runs below that even
if it will go lower
and i'm not saying it will or won't here
i'm just saying if it does or if it will
or if it's more inclined to do so
all we're doing is looking at short-term
liquidity
to frame short-term intraday trades
that's all i'm
i'm posing that as a study on liquidity
here
so i framed it on the basis
higher time frame liquidity pools which
is sell side here
short-term trading logic algorithmic
principles understanding the open float
where the market's gonna attack a
specific side of the marketplace
until it gets to a specific threshold
and then it becomes low probability
now obviously if it trades higher and
goes more
higher than i've outlined on that lower
time frame
then that's a model outside the scope of
what i'm showing you here
it does not reduce its effectiveness
here it does not mean that this is any
less
of a model and that longer term or enemy
term trading is better
it just means which would resonate more
with you as the individual because i'm
talking in a way that it allows the
flexibility of the reader and viewer of
my videos to see
if it resonates with them if it doesn't
i'm not offended
no mentor should be offended because the
mentor should know that
everything isn't always going to fall in
the expectations and alignment
with everybody's psychological makeup
you aren't always going to agree with
everything i say
and the weak-minded individuals that
come here
and they are met with something that is
against
the grain of what they believe in they
just quickly dismiss the entire channel
and they
really dismiss the likelihood of
potentially picking up on some really
amazing things
for free that may make them a stronger
trader
the ones that come here and they say
okay that doesn't really resonate with
me but
they go into their journal and say all
right ict mentioned this this this and
here's my concerns about that
and why i don't feel any gravitation
towards that at the moment
so it's not killing the idea it just
means that you have
observed something you've recorded your
observation
and you kept an open mind about it
because something else in the future
that you may come in
contact with with this video or maybe
you're joining a mentorship maybe you're
not i don't care
but you'll come in contact with another
lesson that it will say
oh that makes sense because i remember
him talking about this
other concept or this principle and how
the markets deliver price
and then it becomes a complete
understanding about something that you
immediately dismissed initially so
always have an open mind don't be
you closed-minded to the idea of
learning something that may be
uncomfortable at first
or it may feel too dry like this lesson
could be viewed as this is really boring
you know you could have said this in in
five minutes yeah i could have said
if the liquidity is taken below the old
low look back three days and see if it
goes to the bicep liquidity but that
does not frame all the necessary logic
that i gave you in this video
okay try to try to reduce it down to
what you think it should be said
and then also lean on the things that
i've also outlined here that were
important in terms of thresholds what
logic needs to take place
and understand also that you may have
been
able to watch other videos and you're
more versed in the things that i've
talked about in old
videos and that's usually what happens
people come they watch the videos and
they are highly opinionated because they
want to get to the next new stuff
but there are always new people coming
in and if i talk about something
i get waves of emails if they're new so
i always like to try to
sprinkle this within my videos that say
look you know you're not going to learn
this in one video and i can't
encapsulate everything in one video
because there's a lot of other
subject matter that these things lean on
but i tried to reduce it to something
that is
scalable you can see it understand it
the logic the things that the only
moving parts is what i showed you here
like i said i didn't require all the
other things that i know
and that you all have learned from me
you don't need all those things
and if you have a price action model you
the
the best price action models are the
ones that can be reduced to the
back of a business card okay i actually
did this on
baby pips when i was active on their
forum
i did an article and it was uh here's my
business card
and i basically said you know you may
have a lot of understanding about price
and i believe i do and i believe my
students do but
those that are profitable can reduce the
idea
that they would use to frame a setup
from beginning to end
with money management and everything it
could be reduced and written out on the
back of a business card now my question
to you is
do you have it in your mind that
learning here
is going to require you more information
that you cannot fit on the back of a
business card
because if that's what your expectation
is if that's what you're afraid of
by delving into this youtube channel or
even my mentorship
don't let that be a thing that is a
problem
it's not it's that's a normal fear and
concern
because there's a lot of information but
think of it like this
if you're going to be a doctor you have
to learn a lot about things
in the body that may not be your
specialty
when you start practicing medicine you
may be a foot doctor or a hand doctor
but you had to learn about the skeletal
system
on this on the cranium you know the
clavicle
you had to understand you know the
patella the kneecap all these things
they're not specific to the foot
in the sense that anatomically
that's the area that you're studying but
something that is occurring in the knee
may be a real reason or root cause of
the problem you're having in your foot
so when i teach i teach
an all-encompassing approach because i
don't want any weaknesses
at all so i don't want anyone to think
that
coming here with all the information
that's available to you that you're
going to drown in the information and
come out
with nothing because
you we could sit down here every single
week and put
one principal you know
on the back of a business card and say
here is a trading model and this is all
you need to do
don't do anything outside of this you
won't get a trade every day
and that's also a problem you're going
to have people that want to have a trade
every single day
and if that's the case then you're a
scalper at heart you want to be a
scalper
okay then focus on trading time of day
with the logic i showed you here
principles like this
where you need to know how the market is
going to draw on
buy side or sell side and that gives
your internal
intraday bias should you be buying and
selling
you don't care how the week is going to
close you don't care what the trend is
going to be over the next four days or
the next three days
what's the daily range going to expand
in direction higher or lower
that's all scalper cares about and you
can make money doing that
you don't you can make money doing that
that would be opposed to the long term
downtrend or uptrend on a daily chart
and weekly chart monthly chart
because it's scalping so when you have
these questions or concerns or if you
read other people's opinions
or watch their review videos and such
they are entitled to their opinion they
all have their own
view on me and other people and that's
fine they're welcome to it but it
doesn't change or
reduce the effectiveness of the things
that i teach or that you learn here
okay so you have to be balanced about it
and go into it with a proper mindset and
i've given you a structure here to go in
and start studying and you'll see
that these things repeat and as far as
intraday scalping
intraday short-term trading this is one
of those little dandies that repeat
a lot but you have to have the context
of where the market runs at liquidity on
a higher time frame chart
until thanks language good luck and good
trading