good afternoon folks
happy Saturday to you
so we're gonna do a little bit of a
review today
keep you too long
so here's the dollar Index is our weekly
chart
there is a fair value Gap in here
that has been left in place from
last week's trading which is this weekly
candle
I want to see if we can
keep this level
into in the form of
resistance in other words it can go up
here hit it and how we trade after we go
into it
it's going to be vital for me going
forward now if we were to go above it
come back down in I would expect it to
act as
support and maybe reach up into the
rejection block which is this highest up
close
price here and then eventually
the high and the consequent
encouragement of that Wick
I want to wait and see what
we get on Sunday's opening and I'm going
to allow Monday's Trading
because there's a lot of things
happening
around the world and if you're not
paying
attention
and these things might surprise you
so just check the news headlines and
you'll see what I'm talking about but
moving on into a daily chart
so there is our weekly Fairbank app
viewed
with a daily Candlestick chart so it
doesn't look like there's any imbalance
there at all
but on the weekly chart
there is
okay so we did have some support off of
this fair value Gap here
I mentioned when we were dropping go
back and look at the other commentaries
that would reach into here at a volume
and balance instead of a couple of that
then this is the area to watch
we traded down into that on Thursday
rallied up into
consequent encouragement of this Wick
right there
so it's a wait and see so somebody's
trading Monday's trading we keep my
cards close to my vest I'm not certain
what we'll see but it could be pretty
volatile next week
you're a dollar daily chart
okay we have a weekly imbalance
here
and you can look at that on your own
charts and try not to put too many
things in front of you to look at but
also leave you somewhere to go in and do
your own investigation
so we have a weekly fair value Gap year
again look at your weekly chart and
you'll see this same thing here easiest
way to identify it with study is put a
rectangle on
the daily chart from this low
to this candle's High
and then go to your weekly chart and
you'll see right away what that Weekly
fair value Gap is so the fair value Gap
is formed now because of this
leak close
we've worked off of this everybody Gap
and I want to see
does this find out find its way above
the weekly fair value Gap in active
support
there's been some
issues with the crops
from agricultural standpoint for folks
that follow the commodity Market
the grain markets because there's a
drought right now corn wheat and
soybeans
are expected to have a difficult year so
that would be
bullish for those grain prices
and if that's the case that would
probably be seen with a dollar index
that is consolidating
or lower
but we have the added
uncertainty of
War you paying attention
so
there's a lot of things to to weigh out
so what do you do with this information
when I see it like this I stay to
the day trading side of Market not doing
longer term analysis sticking to
intraday
trading the sessions only morning
session afternoon Session One in session
that type of thing
hourly chart here you can see
we ran above by side
shift in Market structure here
right there and then we rally back up
this is model 2022.
here's your entry and then drawing down
into and then balance
that would be your perfect 2022 model
Market trades all the ACT down into this
low here if you look real close you'll
see there as they pass on a balance
outside and efficiency with an order
block
that's why you see this nice little rip
higher uh there is some
unfilled
south side of bounds by side and
efficiency
so for the balls you would need to get
back above the weekly fair value Gap
find some support and rally
um
otherwise you know we could see
consolidation on the dollar
and make a run for Euro sell side
liquidity here and dig in a little bit
deeper on that Weekly fair value Gap
that has just formed
it's in a time frame
okay just a little bit more detail
nice city
after a shift to Market structure there
after buy side's taken
and balance sell off
optimal trade entry here
and sells up again
frequently go
what is a breakaway cup Breakaway Gap is
we have a city or busy
in an area close to a swing high or low
in this case it's moving lower so in
this swing high if this is a optimal
strategy that you would look to try to
get into obviously you would expect it
to do what drop so if it drops
aggressively that's a very good
signature something that supports the
idea that you're on side and you don't
want to see that Gap filled
so you would treat it as a breakaway cap
and
run down into the 108 45s or so
e-mini s p weekly chart
so we had our inefficiency here and I
tell you
this old High
and buy sell recorded even mentioned all
these things should all be out repriced
to the entirety
of this city and there is a volume and
balance right there that should be
resume going higher
coming into the next week or
later on that would be the next draw
comparatively speaking as I mentioned
also I won't be talking about NASDAQ
tonight but uh Niantic has in fact
reached up into the equivalent of this
volume and balance on
es here
the NASDAQ for that same time period in
that respective date
it did it already trade up into that
area for its volume balance but the s p
has only traded up into this city
with Bonsai being taken here and we
trade it right back down into the low
[Music]
of this city right there
one hour chart on ES
and the chart is shown in regular
trading hours
here's that buy side we've worked all up
to the upside for a move just outside of
that old
city which is the Shaded area here
then we broke lower
heavy volume and balance in here cheated
up just enough to get into the actual
Gap this is a liquidity void a real one
where there's no trading at all
and then
another opening range Gap that's what
you're seeing here these are openly
range gaps opening range gap opening
range Gap
so where we settle at on the New York
session when you're watching CNBC and
they ring the bell and they clap your
hands
uh that's the equivalent
and then where we open up
the following day at 9 30. that's what's
being represented here that's the
opening range Gap
so whenever you hear me talking about
that's the concept I'm employing here
and in reference to time
so there's an opening Gap here
trade up into it
treat it once more as resistance and
sells off
opening range gap for Thursdays
Trading and then Friday morning 9 30
opening
that
separation in there will be
seen as a opening range Gap
all right so you can see
nice little
opening range Gap trades up into here on
the 21st
you break lower we have an opening range
Gap
here
that's not shaded but extend that in
time you can see that we're returning
back into that
now opening range gaps
I don't like to take them
Beyond five days
so I in my opinion they expire in five
days now that doesn't mean that you
won't find examples of where the market
has respected them
that were utilized beyond the
limitations of the filter I'm saying I
use for my analysis so five days after
that
you know six days from this day
basically I'm no longer interested in
needing using that as a you know return
back into it as supported resistance
so I'm not cheating it you know like I
a new week opening
so new week opening gaps
I can hold on to them and use them for
months
opening range gaps and new day opening
gaps
their short term imbalances with an
expiration date and it's five days okay
so oh you know
and we had uh
the market open
Bounce Around trade up into half of the
Gap from the opening range
and we have
a five minute chart here
as you can see where we settled
where we opened
that range here and then 50 of that
opening range Gap is being noted here
so we traded above the short term High
in the morning session
trade back down to the low of the
opening range gap which is the opening
price
9 30 New York local time
regular trading hours you'll see the
separation
check down to that opening price at 9 30
and then rallies what is it going to try
to do it's going to reach for the buy
side here and then try to work inside
and reprice into what all this opening
range got
but we have a lot of order flow here
and here so it's not necessary
to do a complete closure and I mentioned
that I was interested in that daily fair
value got on ES
I sent a tweet out on Friday morning
and I'll show you that when we get into
later but
right away you can see how we went
from noon
to 1 30 we ran by side
and then the Target or bias that I
mentioned I liked for Friday which was
the
Discount Video on yes
we actually traded into it by one tick
[Music]
so here's the 12 P.M to 1 30 p.m New
York lunch
and I taught recently how to use this
information if you have a bias
you think it's going to be drawing to a
specific higher time frame key level I
shared that with you on Twitter Friday
morning I'll send it I favored the lower
fair value Gap and you can see that on
the es chart
that's what we're looking at here so
we ran up throughout lunch to take the
buy side half of
right here half of the opening range gap
between where we settled along the
previous day when we opened at 9 30 on
Friday
measure that with a fib 50 is here
it trades to it here
consolidates and one more time runs into
it and then we change into mean
threshold
of this full shorter block so notice how
it was used here as support rallied up
once we traded below that low everyone
on ipd arrays has an inversion
application everything acts like you
learned about in terms of support and
resistance which high and low do you use
with classic support resistance see I've
already deciphered all that I'm not
looking at just the low seeing classic
support and resistance levels
they'll look at that low draw a line on
that time and price stop there but it
doesn't
and consolidates and rips through it
so my ability to go into order foil Old
Market structure
and refer to very specific levels things
I'm looking for that are very finite
they're not ambiguous that's not a range
that you have to guess about so a lot of
these things have you know required
rules to adhere to
and you're learning them as we go
through this year
so the market rolls back on anyone that
was short in this big gap down with
electronic trading hour you would see
there's a lot of movement from here to
here
buy side here
by side of above some other highs you
can hear that we don't even need to look
at but to eliminate all the guesswork
just get a range on that opening range
Gap it's Friday it's likely to draw down
into its daily fair value gap which I'll
show you
so it's only pulled back to give a
short-term premium then the market
breaks lower
and then you get the typical run back
down into the opening range Gap low here
and then trades into the low
Target which is the daily fair value
and again I'll show you what that is
but you also probably notice that you
see some discoloration here for those
that have been with me for
this year you already know what that is
that's the framework for the Silver
Bullet AM and PM session
so here's a one minute chart
and you can see how that 50 percent
of the uh
border block and convergence of the
opening range the dashed line
is 50 of the opening range Gap and this
is 50 of
the order block or mean threshold
so that's what you're you're seeing here
I'm just annotating that I would have
did a better job of not working it that
way so you're looking at it now I wish I
said it differently but we're going to
stick with what we got here
so at 10 o'clock in the morning until 11
o'clock in the morning we're looking for
a Silver Bullet I mentioned it I favored
the lower end so bias in my opinion was
bearish and I know some of you that are
highly critical or just maybe you're
brand new you're looking at this move
here to here why is it bearish when I
did this run or how's the bearish one
did this run to here or from here to
here
what was the largest move of the day it
was moving from here
down to here and it went one tick below
where I've already told you to look at
on Twitter with the daily favor you got
so bias is what
my bias is bearish
so I wanted to go short I showed
examples of executing
working at the 9 30 opening
and was like 75 or so handles taken out
and you can look at that on Twitter by
the way but the uh
if you want to find out what my Twitter
account is you can go to my YouTube
channel and you'll see the actual
official Twitter link
upper right hand corner but we have a
gap here
we trade up into it right there
and at 11 o'clock
a few minutes after it still went a
little bit higher but that's fine you
can see on the one minute chart there's
a little bit longer
sibi which is a fair value Gap
so it offers it there that you would
have been filled here
and you'd have to have a little bit of
drawdown
is that the rules for Super Bowl this
year you have to enter between 10
o'clock and 11 o'clock
and if you're very uncomfortable with
that idea and it didn't don't trade that
model
and it trades down to the low end of the
opening range Gap so that's almost about
10 handles but we don't need that we
just need five handles for a silver
bullet that would have offered it there
then we have the retracement going into
lunch running on buy side and then we
see at 1 30 we get one more little trap
move that takes us above the relative
equal
Horizon here buy side is tripped and
displacement is shown short-term lows
survey got trades up into it wait for
displacement we're at fifty percent of
the opening range
and we're at the old
swing low which is a down closed candle
bull shoulder block
and
mean threshold level okay so that's what
this is
the market starts to work lower again
time between two o'clock and three
o'clock
we're looking for an imbalance that we
can use to enter on to get in sync with
the directional bias I've shared mine on
Twitter
so here's a city trade up into it
between two o'clock and three o'clock
there's your PM session Silver Bullet
what do you hold for
open range Gap low and then the daily
fair value Gap so we had a nice run
lower here and then we dig below
these relative equal lows and one tick
into that daily fair value Gap and then
retracing back up into the range
[Music]
here is that fair value Gap I mentioned
in the daily chart for ES here
I had this one highlighted but I very
specifically stated that I favor the
lower
as demise on the day and it drove down
in one tick below that low right there
that was was the delivery
so 4381.75
81.50 was the printed level today
[Music]
there's your difference right there
hope you found this insightful I'll try
to be as
directing to the points of possibly good
enjoy your weekend and I'll touch base
with you next week which I'll talk to
you next time be safe