welcome back books this is going to be a
lesson on
time elements in algorithm price
delivery and an introduction to ICT
macros all right so here is a NASDAQ
daily chart here I'm going to try to
give you some context as to how I used
the macro here on Friday that's a fast
uh not from here on Friday for July 2023
so without this
context really it doesn't help
to know the specific times of the day
that are called a macro
so again this is why a council many of
you not to try to teach something
that you don't know yet
and as you can see this is going to be
one of those things where it's an
introduction
it's not going to satisfy everything
initially but everything
leans on other Concepts and aspects to
my methodology so
it's just one more piece of the puzzle
that comes together slowly over time and
experiences the greatest teacher
so take a look at this next chart
and I want you to take a look at this
down close candle here we dug into that
one Thursday
so we have a wick right there
or tail I guess you would call it
and whenever I look at a tail or a wick
my eye goes immediately to the midpoint
okay that's consequent encouragement the
algorithm treats this
has a gap
on Friday we opened
traded higher real close to the midpoint
of that but what my eye was in addition
to that Wick my eye was also
drawn into the high of this candle
and the open of that candle
okay so this is a bull shorter block
what makes it a bull Shore block
we are inside of
this candle in terms of the high and the
opening price
and I'm using those specific price
points and not
the middle or mean threshold of the body
or the mean threshold of the entire
high to low
I'm using this because this is the last
down close candle prior to this run up
after digging into this one so what
specific kind of order block is this one
here
if you looked at my month for content
mentorship my premium mentorship content
that's on my YouTube channel again it's
month four and you'll see that there is
a lecture called propulsion block
propulsion block is something that works
off of it
earlier order block so we have an order
block here
and then this one digs into that one but
you don't ever want to see price go down
below half of this candle's body and we
don't get that we get real close to it
but we don't get it so that to me tells
me that the next day it's still
advantageous to anticipate higher prices
I mentioned on
Twitter ahead of non-profit payroll
release at 8 30 in the morning near
political time that I favored
the specific buy side South Side
liquidities and I showed you that I was
looking for the higher side
to be ran for first and I'll cancel you
to look at the Twitter you'll see that
so all these things lending well to
bullish order block Thursday we
respected the propulsion block
and
or not from payroll I was expecting an
initial rally higher and maybe even
challenge
the high up here but we don't know how
far they're going to rip it or
trust it really ahead of non-profit
payroll so it's a guessing game in the
beginning
how you use the information after
the 8 30 News hits the marketplace that
manual intervention that's utilized many
times to take both sides of the
marketplace and that means buy side and
then sell side or sell side then buy
side and then the real move takes place
so it's generally a whipsop type event
so these two levels here
they are respective
and associated with to
these two specific levels on the down
closed candle there
so you can see here on an hourly chart
we have a high to low after taking buy
side here
inefficiency
and when do Breakers
not provide the cleanest
points of rejection or where we can use
them for entries and whatnot
not for payroll
CPI
and FMC okay those those events
whereas I would usually see
high low higher high
in other circumstances I would treat
this
right here I would treat this as a
bearish breaker and I would not
anticipate this area to be traded to I
would look at this area here as a
balanced price range
which it is in a sense but I would look
for this breaker to be utilized so I'm
taking it through not only the aspects
of time but I'm also telling you
narrative which is absolutely crucial
to understanding what a macro will do
okay so it's not a magic pill where all
of a sudden now you know how to trade
because of there's a specific time of
day
you still have to have some elements of
understanding what price should likely
do and that is complicated it's not easy
you're not going to figure it out you
know watching this video and going into
your charts right away you just want to
go through the process the rest of this
year as I'm teaching more about them
I'll have more lectures obviously you
know and notes for macros in the books
I'm putting out but
it's good enough for you to start with
in studying
so we work up inside this city which is
a premium inefficiency the market wants
to do what rally higher at non-property
roll reaches into this inefficiency it
doesn't need to go up here right away
because we've had the run on by side
with this here
so all this is the inefficiency the
price wants to run up to so price only
rallies to go up to inefficiencies like
here
buy side about here
or it consolidates
or it consolidates and goes below the
marketplace
for sell side or inefficiency
Okay so
note this
outside efficiency it's a fair value Gap
in this inefficiency here which is a
city
both are a fair value Gap
in a 15 minute time frame there's levels
here shown respectively inside of the
daily
bullish propulsion block
highlight
proportion blocks
Wick and this is the opening of that
daily propulsion block where I spent a
couple minutes explaining what that is
that's these two levels here
we also have that hourly
fair value Gap
which doesn't look like a fair value got
now once we go into a 15 minute time
frame which is why you want to do a
top down
from pdra discount and premium and go
through what's available in terms of
price action your first task is to again
identify what is above the marketplace
inefficiency and liquidity by side
and what's below the marketplace
inefficiency and sell side
obviously you can get crazy and look Way
Beyond the scope of where the market
will likely reach for
but we want to look at previous days
highs and lows session highs and lows
the highs and lows in the last three
days and previous week high and low so
all those are very quick easy
go to general rules of thumb they'll
serve you extremely well for knowing
where price will likely gravitate for
inefficiencies or liquidity
so we have non-farm here we're releasing
at 8 30.
and we're in a five minute chart now
here is where I was watching on the
NASDAQ if I was interested in trading
this one not so much on the es and the
reason why I chose NASDAQ not because
it's the better one to trade not because
my tool said to choose this one I was
actually traded in NASDAQ because I had
students asking me okay can you do more
work on NASDAQ because I've been
primarily teaching with the medium of
the even the s p
so I don't want you to think that what
I'm showing here today was a selection
based on anything except for
you my students asking me to perform
something in NASDAQ versus trading it in
the es which is what you've been
predominantly watching me do majority of
this year
so that bullish propulsion block the
wick High
the opening of that
and then that hourly Fair bag Gap that
blue shaded area
in the middle
of the propulsion block High
in propulsion block opening price that's
these two specific levels here the high
the wick the opening of the propulsion
block on the daily chart half of that
range is the
daily bullish order block which is again
propulsion block
premium WIC constant encrosion that
means from the high the propulsion
blocks
Wick
to the opening of it half of that
remember we treat Wicks and Tails on
candlesticks as gaps and the midpoint is
consequent encouragement that's this
measurement right here
you can see how sensitive is
so the market drops after running up
initially here
comes back down below the lows in here
but digs into
all this order flow but specifically
right into consequent encouragement of
the bullish daily propulsion block which
is a order block
then the market starts too
move higher
notice what it's doing first it's taking
buy side and trading up into an
efficiency and then
reverses and goes down to sell side so
one of the things for your notes for
not from payroll
whatever side of the marketplace it goes
for First Rate as a thirty
news hits
usually not always usually that will be
the false run so in other words I'll
give you an example here it rallies for
the buy side first it takes Traders into
the marketplace traps them long
they want to see it keep going higher
and then the market trades lower and
takes out the sell stops one anyone that
is long here
and Below recent lows so they are not
permitted to be allowed
to ride this up so trap along stop out
any shorts
drop lower
induce new shorts
crush the lungs
trap them short
accumulate the sell side and then run
for the buy side here and the other
higher time frame drawn liquidity so
this Candlestick right here
that is your bowl of shoulder block
again same premise I used with the daily
chart here the high the wick to the
opening okay so we're highlighting that
you can see a small little Gap right in
here so I'm not highlighting the the Gap
that's the block
of price action between
this high
and that low that's your fair value Gap
but I'm highlighting this older block
that has that fear that you got that is
suggesting that we could go higher after
stops have been taken that is a high
probability bullish order block
so we're looking for this shaded area
here the key off of and use to get in
alignment with
price action going higher
three minute chart I'm adding that in
here so you can see inside that border
block the Gap actually gets refined even
better
here
you can see the bodies of the candles
just about respecting that
and then sending higher
you have an inefficiency here which is
what an inversion fair value Gap so I'm
going to spare you all that you can add
this to your own charts and for notation
purposes
over here
normally you would see this and people
that look at myself they think this is a
short
they want to go there no order flow is
bullish stops have been taken
draws here
so all this in balance it goes up into
it and then treats it as support so
they're accumulating more Longs in here
and you'll see that I'm actually doing
that same thing and with my live Trading
it rallies up
taste out the buy side here
so we're dropping down into a one minute
chart
and then we're gonna get to the Brass
tax of the discussion here
when we look at time
or when I'm teaching you time invariably
you know folks that are trading
exclusively with Forex or now have
segwayed from Forex or just started
trading or monitoring and tape reading
the index features which is where I'm
trying to teach right now I want you to
think about how
the characteristics of time
are very unique
to price delivery but across all asset
classes
so what I'm showing you here is how I
internalize price action whether I'm
looking at a 4X pair whether I'm looking
at a commodity or whether I'm looking at
index futures
okay so in my mind when I'm watching
price action I'm aware and conscious of
the seven o'clock to nine o'clock in the
morning New York open Killzone you know
that from my lecture notes and teachings
from Forex
then you have the am session New York am
session from index trading which is
beginning of 8 30 in the morning
to noon
then you have what I've taught this year
the 10 o'clock to 11 o'clock AM Silver
Bullet I've recently introduced this
year
macros now macros are very specific
segments of price action
and they're usually 20 minute intervals
not all of them but most of them are 20
minute intervals I'm going to teach you
a few of them this year I'm not going to
teach you all of them I'm not in a
position where I can do that but there
are several of them but these are
specific Windows of opportunity but not
to teach you the introduction to how I
use them
when we look at Price like this
I want you to see that there is price
running up during non-farm payroll into
that inefficiency
it drops aggressively takes out south
side below these relative equal lows and
then returns into that hourly fair value
gap which is that blue shaded area right
in here
it rounds again it comes back down
touches the tie end of the hourly fair
value Gap
then it rise up into the inefficiency
and takes by side once more what does it
leave and it's weak relative equal lows
and what specific measurement do we have
here
the daily bullish propulsion block which
is only blocked
the consequent encrosion of the high and
the opening price again that level is
this here to here okay those two
respective levels half of that is here
now I already know okay I already know
the majority of you this is going right
over your head because you want
something where it's an overall oversold
moving average crossover you know
something really simple but I want you
to understand something
these markets are driven by high
frequency algorithm
they are not meant to be easily
understood
the biggest complaint you're going to
get if it's not me talking about things
longer than they feel I should it's the
fact that I don't make it easy
you cannot make this topic easy
okay I promise you there's going to be a
lot of folks out there that's going to
start talking about this topic in
YouTube videos they're probably bringing
into their mentorships
guaranteed they have no idea to do it
okay they don't and if they did they
would go out there and show you examples
after examples daily every single week
and using the information
you're not going to see that okay so
with that disclaimer
okay and
monologue out of the way I want you to
think about how saying the non-front
payroll event typically performs we have
an initial run by side
sell side
and then time becomes a factor this is
how I teach folks that and I mentioned
this on Twitter space recently a few
days ago
Twitter space is something that it's
just me audibly talking it's usually a
psychological lecture
and
coaching basically without a chart
encouragement that type of thing and
sometimes it's a Woodshed moment where
I'm scolding you for doing things you
shouldn't do which is something I wish I
would have had done for me when I was
coming up
the sell side again is taken here
when it is traded below these relative
equals and into the bullish propulsion
block
consequent encouragement from the daily
chart that's this
level here the blue line and that blue
line right here
okay
so you can see right away that's this is
the reason why I have things written out
in
text format okay numerical levels and
then I'm describing what they are on a
notepad
I don't want all these things on my
chart because it gets on my nerves okay
it's too distracting for me but to teach
you conceptually what it is that I'm
referring to and how to visually see it
I'm showing it like this with lipstick
on the chart I do not have these things
on my chart
I completely empty my chart of all
things unless I'm recording something
and I'm showing you what I'm observing
or thinking and focusing on at the time
so that way anybody that can come
afterwards and watch the video they
can't say oh well you know you're just
making it up as you go now there's a
very Sound Logic being applied to
everything that I ever do
and the excuses
that my trolls and detractors will say I
always have something to explain the
marketplace well that's because I know
the marketplace
and I've engineered a lot of things that
you're learning that the marketplace
will use so
go into
the 10 o'clock hour
here
right before 10 o'clock
you have a 10 minute interval 950 that's
here
950 to 10 10. now I already know that
some of you are going to be first-time
viewers of my content and this is going
to be the video you see first
the things I'm explaining here are going
to seem completely cherry-picked in all
hindsight
but go back and look at the videos that
I share on my Twitter feed where you
actually watch me execute during these
times of the day I'm doing several
examples recently I've done a few with
the 10 50 to 11 10. and I've done a few
on the 950 to 1010 macro
this 20 minute period specializes in
when the market is approaching the first
30 minutes of trading after 9 30 in the
equities Market
that's that last threshold for even when
the Forex markets trading around
okay so if you're a Forex Trader it's
still important to know this if you are
not a Forex Trader and you're using
Futures it's applicable it's all joined
together it's a tapestry of how all the
markets work together harmoniously and
when they aren't harmonious
there's a crack in correlation that in
itself gives you warning signs that
something's about to change
and maybe the chains may be abrupt okay
so that's out that's outside the scope
of this discussion today but I want you
to think about how we were running up
into this inefficiency in this buy side
during
the 950 the 1010 macro what was it doing
it was delivering price to buy side and
inefficiency
this one single candle passed down so
it's doing two primary functions here
it's running to
an area that will be deemed a premium
relative to the high
and the low here
we rally up to liquidity
rebalance
this inefficiency how do we know that's
balanced because we worked back and
forth in it then we left it
going back in all the bodies are staying
inside of it is respecting that that's
that's narrative that's how you read
candlesticks it's not what Steve
Nielsen's stuff okay
this right here
sees us drop lower what's occurring at
the 9 50 to 10 10.
it's already worked in this liquidity
what is it going to deliver next well
what's the profile for not far payroll
we ran by side we left relative equal
lows
we've been bullish on s p we've been
bullish on NASDAQ so it's going to drop
down and take the other side of the
marketplace out
because they've engineered liquidity
here using this hourly
fair value Gap
And Trades down into the midpoint or
consequent encroachment of that daily
propulsion block
I can imagine how this would feel
bewildering for a new Trader or new
student okay
you do not need to know how to do this
to learn how to trade properly with my
stuff I'm only producing this to show
you the level of detail
that the algorithm refers back to when
it's timing its movements for liquidity
when is it timing its movement for
inefficiencies and how it utilizes time
look at it like this we have the New
York open Kill Zone okay the majority of
it is quiet and then at 8 30 we have the
release of the non-prompt payroll you go
something inefficiency
at that moment we have an overlap of the
9 30 am
and the New York open Killzone right in
here there's a lot of overlap where
there's going to be a lot what
volatility we quickly drop down one more
time in efficiency but least majority of
it open then we're rips lower
trades into the hourly fair value Gap
then we chop around a little bit trade
back up into the inefficiency at 950 to
10 10 and then it will do what it will
start its protraction lower
to go into this liquidity here
this drop here all this movement notice
how all this price run is during the am
Silver Bullet 10 o'clock to 11 o'clock
in the morning and the New York am
session between 8 30 and noon New York
local time
so we can see and anticipate many times
where you'll see me doing executions
I'll say I'm looking for Speed now I
want to see big candles I want to see
movement that's a sharp drop or a a
strong Rally from here
I'm utilizing this type of information
here
the macro in itself is just a Time
window where the 950 to 1010 what this
is actually specializing in is it's the
first
20 to 30 and then 40 minutes of the
trading hour
starting at 9 30. so an equities Market
opens at 9 30 the stock market Bell
starts ringing
the first 30 minutes is the opening
range
but that opening range doesn't have to
or
is required to be 30 minutes before the
actual range is useful
it can
form in 20 minutes and then whatever
liquidity is utilized there outside that
parameter high and low
it'll help you determine where the
market will likely go to next
I'll have more teachings on the living
range but at 9 50 to 10 10 what is
actually happening is is the run that
starts at 9 30.
here
it goes into the liquidity here so now
we start a macro between 950 and 10 10.
a macro is a short list of directives
that the algorithm will run it's like a
a small little
list of orders that it has to do to then
seek where liquidity and or if
inefficiencies are we've already went
into a premium relative to the high and
low we're into inefficiency and we've
already bumped by side so two functions
of delivery of price has been met both
of them for the purposes of seeking
liquidity and inefficiency it has
balance this out here
and then it starts its Run for the
opposing side of liquidity
why is it not going to keep going higher
why is this not a bull flag because the
parameters of the buy side here and the
sell side
we have to incorporate the profile of
non-farm payroll which is what
first rally
then go down take out the stops and then
resume going higher
or drop down take out sell side then run
higher take out the buy side and then
drop down
or just be a choppy you know mess that
non-forward payroll can many times be
we drop down during the peak of Silver
Bullet 10 to 11 time window
there is a silver bullet entry in here
they're on am session Silver Bullet time
window
trades down to consequent encroachment
of the bullish propulsion block on the
daily chart and it's also
consequent encroachment of the hourly
Fairbank got the Shaded in blue notice
that
then we rally a little bit
short-term High We Pierce that we have
an older block again
that was shaded from the higher time
frame
you drop down touch another order block
on the hourly chart so you can see the
hierarchy from higher time frame down
the lower time frame the market touches
it beautifully stops perfectly at this
opening price the down closed candle
inside that shaded area which is a
larger time frame or higher time frame
order block from high to opening price
as a dead green shaded area was
and then we rally what does it form
right here during the 1050 to 11 10.
what is the significance with 1150 to 11
10.
you're ending the 10 o'clock till 11
o'clock hour which is the first 90
minutes of trading and then we're going
to enter
the time of day where we enter a New
York lunch and New York launch has its
own macro or it usually runs for
liquidity
we have a low high lower low making this
these up close candles of two of them
that makes this a bullish breaker
and we can utilize that and anticipate
higher prices
running for the buy side here
the buy side here and the high of
the inefficiency that shaded here on
fire timeframe charts I want you to
think about how the macro time
is utilized for the market to begin its
run for liquidity
the run for inefficiency
What specifically is 1050 well it's 10
minutes before 11 o'clock
that's essentially the height of London
clothes for Forex
then we have
the last
hour before we get to New York lunch now
there's a lot of people that argue
because there's no open outcry anymore
like it used to be and you know the
markets are electronic nobody goes to
lunch doesn't matter the markets will
enter some measure of consolidation
going into lunch
it'll run for liquidity or it can
reverse okay so there's three primary
functions that the launch Arrow will do
you have to be able to fit that into the
market profile for that particular day
and we have a non-farm payroll event so
we've seen the initial run here by side
engineered sell side then it drops it
down for sell side now it's free to go
higher because no one's long they got
stopped out anyone that was buying long
on the breakout was raked across the
coals anyone that went short breaking
out below these relative equal lows here
are trapped short then the market can go
higher
so I want you to see
that these time Windows these macros
they're just
a Time aspect to when I anticipate the
market to start reaching start doing
some showing animation okay it's not
enough to Simply know these times a day
inside those respective times there are
specific times in Windows of opportunity
for me and you know you as my students
to anticipate a specific phenomenon in
price where it will start behaving like
we would expect it to
it will start running for liquidity it
will start running for inefficiency
if the macros do not provide
that timing aspect and the market just
simply doesn't budge that is many times
a beautiful illustration for you to stop
looking and closure charts
because the Market's ran algorithmically
whether you want to believe it or not
that's the facts
and if these elements are not producing
movement
driving price to either inefficiencies
or liquidity if it's not showing any
movement that you would expect it fits
your analysis where you think the next
strong liquidity is going to be if
that's not occurring you have to close
your charts and trade the next session
there's macros in the afternoon there's
macros during the launch hour okay
there's macros in the London session I'm
showing you these two here because I
just recently used them proving that
they exist
okay all emacro is is the beginning of a
spooling event spooling is where price
starts to reach for it it reaches for
um
think about like a fishing rod you ever
been fishing before
and you have your hook and your weight
on the end of it and your baits on the
hook and you cast the
fishing line out into the water what's
occurring with the fishing line it's
spooling it's it's running off this this
reel
a fishing line and it's delivering that
hook that weight and that bait
far away from where you're standing
that's what that's what these macros are
doing it's like casting price away
higher or lower
and I'm watching these specific times a
day to do those very things it is not
going to give you a Direction
okay so when you see these people out
there trying to talk about how yeah the
macro here and this is how you know it's
going to be a bias how you know it's
gonna be yourself no you need to require
your understanding about all the other
things I'm teaching you you still have
to know how to tape read you still need
to know how to determine a bias you
still need to know where liquidity is
and how you use that liquidity and work
within a higher time frame
analysis
otherwise this is not going to help you
it's not going to help you okay so if
you don't
know everything else that I'm teaching
this is going to be a point of
frustration for something for a majority
of you I'm going to read complaints
people are going to complain about me in
other people's videos I don't care I
know how to use it it's not imperative
that you learn how to use it but I
wanted to show you again proof that
these markets are algorithmic and they
operate on the basis of time first
time is the first crucial Factor before
price will move
unless a bomb drops unless there's some
kind of geopolitical upheaval something
crazy unexpected Swan event occurs the
markets are not moving randomly
they're not just popping off it whenever
you know a lot of buyers or sellers
coming up they're not going to be moving
because a whole bunch of people on
Reddit are going to try to take down the
hedge funds and go against them all that
stuff is nonsense
and all of these markets whether you
choose to believe it or not every asset
class are driven by artificial
intelligence that artificial
intelligence is an algorithm and it
follows instructions that were coded for
it
and it runs things based on time
period
so let's take a look at this in
relationship to where I executed and how
I traded it you can see how I use this
information
go and I'll take them on and off you can
see they're being
populated
as an subtracted from the chart
and there's executions
and over the course of the entire day
[Music]
you can see the executions
as well
[Music]
so that's a marketer cell model
all right folks hopefully you got
something out of this one
I understand it's probably very Advanced
and it's probably left you with more
questions and that's wonderful that
means you have opportunity to grow in
your understanding if you don't have any
questions you know
it's a problem you probably didn't watch
it close enough but the a macro is
simply a time of day where price will
begin to spool that's all it is it's
reaching for liquidity or it's reaching
for inefficiency if the market is not
showing signs of respecting that measure
of time
then it's probably indicative of a
bailout and don't do anything with that
session or maybe even that trading day
and it'll probably spare you some
drawdown and or losing trades
and so I'll talk to you next time
be safe