welcome back folks
so we're going to be talking about
a concept that's near and dear to me
it is the TGIF setup or thank God it's
Friday
now this is a day-based algorithmic ICT
trading model and you can use it on all
assets
right so as you
may have already noticed that this is a
day specific model that means the model
will appear
one day per week it's on the Friday
hence the name thank God it's Friday
and it's a pun on the expression we say here in the states uh TGIF thank God it's Friday
meaning that you survived the work week now you can party and rest on the weekend
but the pattern and the characteristic
of this pattern is a retracement into
the current weekly range
and I want to talk a little bit about
the weekly power 3 and the distribution
phase of that
so let's take a look at the NASDAQ
Futures Contract this is a one month
chart
now obviously you we want to do a
top-down approach when we're doing our
analysis and the TGIF trade is going to
be
extremely precise if you are anchoring
it against some higher time frame
premium rate or discount array now
I'm describing a premium distribution
meaning that the assumption is the
market has been going up
and we're going to be looking for some
measure of exhaustion for the weekly
range and then it will pull back into
said weekly range
as you can see here the monthly chart
for Nasdaq and for those that are just
watching this video in the future I'll
count you to go through and look at the
dated analysis and commentary
videos I placed on my YouTube channel
that we're focusing on how NASDAQ and
all the stock index features were called
higher so you can see here on a monthly
chart
right here
we can see a small little imbalance in
the form of a fair value Gap cell sign
of balance bison and efficiency that's
defined by these ranges
extremes which is this month low this
month high this only portion on the
downside or sell side delivery it would
be requiring buy side delivery so you
can see buy side being offered here in
the month of June 2023 so this is a
premium fair value gap on a monthly
chart so with these levels in mind let's
drop down
okay you can see how on the weekly chart
now you can see the weekly
and those respective levels here
from the monthly chart you can see we
did in fact reach up into a monthly
premium fair value Gap
a high that fair value Gap is here
and the law of the Fair makeup is there
okay and it's linked
directly on the monthly chart but then
dropping down to a weekly chart
it's going to look like this so it
doesn't look like there's a Fair makeup
at all
on the weekly but it is on the monthly
so we have to do our top down analysis
in the hierarchy of my premium and
discount arrays will work from higher
time frame down to a lower time frame
so you can see it is Monday
so the last
week of trading
this is represented by that week here so
we've started a brand new week so we're
going to ask
all of you in the audience to disregard
this little candle just ignore it while
it's being
shown in the charts because I have no
way of taking that out okay so you can
see we did reach up into a premium if
everybody got now when it does that it's
very likely to see some measure of
pullback and you can see as we hit up in
the upper end of this premium Fury gap
on the monthly chart but now we're
showing it on weekly
we went up to it and then came back down
towards the low end of that range okay
and that range being again
that Fairway gap on the monthly chart
so let's take a
closer look here and drop down into
that little section of price action and
take a closer look again you can see
zoomed in on the weekly chart
doesn't appear like there's a fair Vega
the market trades just shy
of that hello
which would be again the monthly premium
fair value up high or the highest part
that makes up everybody got that was
referencing
the monthly time frame
there's a small little tiny little
imbalance in here I'm going to reserve
commentary on that
so just focus on this area right in here
okay and notice how we've had multiple
weeks of NASDAQ going higher I've been
counseling you to anticipate NASDAQ
being the upside leader
across the three averages thou
s p and NASDAQ NASDAQ being the leader
issue on the upside and it has performed
stunning fashion to the upside
outperforming the es and outperforming
the Dao
but I want you to take a look at how
each one of these weekly candles are
created
true they're all up close candles
but notice where the close is ?
it's above midpoint of the candles entire range
the close is near each candle's High
this candle here closed near the high
it closed really close to the high
close to the high
and close to the high
so I want to talk a little bit about
my power three concept now
I'm not going to go into great detail
here but I do have lectures on this
YouTube channel
that cover this and it's mentioned in
laced throughout a lot of the teachings
so I'm a firm believer of repetition
makes Mastery you have to see things
over and over again to condition your
mind and your eye to see it you can't
just watch a video and you can't watch a
five minute trainer or condensed version
of what I'm teaching because while you
may feel like you watch the shorter
version of my content by someone else
that is not teaching you anything except
for the same thing you get with Cliff
Notes okay
it doesn't
compare to the the full detail
so power three
is not linked to any one particular time
frame but when I first introduced it it
was appropriate at the time
to teach it on a daily chart okay so
let's look at this with the reference of
a weekly range the low of the week
where we started trading here to open in
other words this is open high low close
bar most of
analysis is done on candlesticks today
okay I know I have moved away from this
type of chart which is how I used
my commodity charts and s p charts and
bond charts back in the mid 90s when I
first started Trading and then over the
years my eyes have
you know unfortunately taking the toll
what looking screens for a long time
it's a lot easier to to read the data
with a Candlestick now
but from a power three stance
1.the open
2.the decline with the below the opening price
3.the rally higher making the high of the day
4.and then the close near the high today
5.this is po3
6.where we anticipate the market moving higher on the basis of a weekly analysis higher time frame analysis
we think that it's
drawing to a premium array something to
make it want to go up here or Draw to it
and so on Sunday when the Market's open
we anticipate if we're bullish that
opening price or this opening price at
midnight New York local time
you can open drop down we would not see
that as bearish we would anticipate that
so it's the accumulation phase
below the opening price
the manipulation
is the open and then decline but we're
utilizing that function
to accumulate long positions
or for the purpose of studying we would
anticipate it opening trading down into
some discount array what would that be a
fair value running short-term sell stops
on a lower time frame trading down to an
old High
something that would promote some
discount or quote unquote a support
level
then the market would displace higher
above the opening price returned it into
some kind of
imbalance that would be seen with a
bullish fair value Gap or a bullish
breaker
and rally up
so this is the expansion portion of
power three
and creating the extreme high of the
week
and then trading off that high to close
and this would be the distribution phase
of power three so it's open high low
close
accumulation of Longs at that opening
price and down when it drops below it
this is manipulation this is where
retail Traders would chase that move
lower
and then they get raked across the coals
as the market goes higher reaching
towards some higher time frame premium
array some kind of Target okay think of
it like I've outlined here the market
has been drawing each week up into this
area here
well that's each one of these open high
low and close would be represented about
each individual Candlestick here so even
though these are candlesticks
this candle here would be represented by
the open then it traded down then it
rallied up made the high and it came off
the high and close near the high
same
function
but I'm teaching power three with this
open high low close
bar and obviously everything I do is
reversible just whatever I've said in
previous for when it's bullish you would
just use it when it's bearish it would
open
the accumulation of short positions when
you think the weekly Candlestick is
going to go lower reaching for some kind
of discount array some kind of sell side
decoded something to that effect you
would see the opening price and then
rally up we would see this open as
accumulation of shorts and then
manipulation higher
tricking retail Traders and thinking
it's going to break out to the outside
smart money would accumulate short
positions here and then write it down
throughout the week reaching to some
discount array and then before the end
of the week it comes off the low closes
on Fridays close near but off the low
so I want you to understand that premise
now this theory of mine is not limited
to a weekly it's not limited to a daily
chart it's on every time frame
every single time frame so as long as
you know where the next draw on
liquidity is regardless of what time
frame you're trading what style trading
you're utilizing this idea of
understanding accumulation manipulation
and distribution will serve you well in
terms of finding setups sticking to
institutional order flow in order to
trusting that price is going to continue
moving in your direction if you're on
side if you're offside it means you're
incorrect about what you think is going
to happen in the marketplace then you're
obviously going to get stopped out and
that goes without saying but assuming
all things equal
if you're right
you know this is how we interpret price
action
so I want to take your focus into that
very range right there that is
encapsulated by a down and up Arrow so
this
weekly range here okay we're gonna look
at that we're gonna zoom in
with this range in mind I want you to
think about how without those levels I
have drawn on the monthly
you can see how if you don't have those
reference points it's kind of hard to
determine what it would be reaching for
that's why you want to spend majority of
your time on a higher time frame charts
because the Market's going to gravitate
towards these higher time frame premium
arrays or discount arrays if it's
drawing towards a premium array that
means that the bias is going to be
primarily bullish each day of that week
or the week to come you would be
anticipating
any decline is to accumulate long
positions
and then distribute those long positions
to a premium array
so that week right there let's zoom in
all right and I'm using the continuous
contract here so that way you can see
the distinctions and
or the similarities right now it is
mid-june
and this is the NASDAQ weekly
candlestick
so the low of the range isn't marked
here it is not the opening price so the
low of this candle is not the open the
open is just slightly above the the low
you can see a small little separation
there and then we have the Run higher
makes the high of the week and then we
close here on the week
TGIF or thank God it's Friday
is a setup that I've codified for end of
week range Concepts I don't want to say
reversal pattern sometimes I have
mistakenly referred to it as a reversal
pattern it is a reversal pattern in the
sense that
in the last portion of
Friday's trading you can if it hasn't
occurred yet you can anticipate some
measure of retracement into the weekly
range and when I say that what do I mean
the lowest low of the week all the way
up to the highest high of the week
that's your weekly range okay now let's
assume for a moment that is two o'clock
in the afternoon New York local time and
you're trading or studying the index
features and it just so happens to be
we're looking at the NASDAQ
I taught that there is a PM session okay
between two o'clock and three o'clock
there is a formation that I dubbed the
ICT Silver Bullet okay I codified that
as well I've already shared an
introductory lesson on my YouTube
channel I will be teaching more about
that as we go along and there'll also be
some more tips and tricks with it in my
books to come but you'll you won't need
the books I know that sounds like a plug
go by my books when they come out
um the first book will be released when
I get to 1 million subscribers on the
YouTube channel I get a lot of questions
as to when it's going to be released
that's the timeline
and then six months after that the
second then
going in perpetuity until we get to uh
the final fourth book
so the uh the range for that entire
range of the weekly low and the high
when we assume that there is a high form
for the week okay and we can assume that
is the case when we get to about 130
or so on the Friday
and then we can anticipate some measure
of retracement into the weekly range if
now again this is a major
point that needs to be required in the
analysis if the market has reached some
premium array if it has not reached a
higher time frame premium array
then it could continue into the close
and close right on the high so that's
how you distinguish whether or not it's
going to form or it's going to keep on
going and closure on the high but
because we traded up into that monthly
fair value Gap
and because we have been trading up for
a long series of weeks
each week being bullish
we've maintained a bullish delivery and
we have been maintaining a bullish
analysis on stock index Futures over the
last few weeks so none of this has taken
us by surprise
but I want you to think about when you
anticipate a high of the week is
probably in and I'll talk about that
when we get into lower time frames for
the sake of conversation let's assume
for a moment that you had the ability to
determine
that there was a high already formed and
now anything going into the clothes on
Friday of this week
inside this weekly range okay try to
ignore this one here
so I had to take the screenshot of this
chart and it obviously shows the new
week we're working off of them so this
range here we're not even concerned with
this we're only looking at the high this
candle and the lower that candle in the
respective levels that's being
identified here so the high of the week
range and the low of the weekly range if
you measure with a Fibonacci
from the lowest low all the way up to
the high
now you will be doing this intraday
as you approach the afternoon session
doesn't mean that you can't see this
TGIF pattern form in the morning session
it's more likely to form in the
afternoon especially if we had
continuation on the upside in the
morning session then it's more likely to
create
in the afternoon session
but the Range High in the range low if
you put a 0.20 and a 0.3
level on your Fibonacci that's basically
giving you the 20 and 30 D marker for
the entire weekly range and that's the
only thing that's being shown here I'm
denoting where 20 of the range from the
high down to the low 20 percent of that
range is here which will be 15 326.75
and then 30 of that range would be 15
252 and a half
so those two levels here that is your
sweet spot okay that's where TGIF will
likely draw into
there are times when it can draw into
forty percent or more that's
more of a conversation for reversals
or Market tops or bottoms but we're
gonna Reserve that for another time
because it's outside this code with this
discussion
meaning that if we can watch price
delivery on Friday whether it be in the
morning session or the afternoon session
if we get to some level of
a premium Target being reached or as we
saw on the monthly chart we traded up
into that fair Vega the day of the week
is Friday it's been going up every day
so it's
within the realm of reasonable to
anticipate the market drawing back okay
so
the fact that it's dropping down I I
learned I'm sure you've probably heard
this also in books and such and other
Educators it's profit taking and I have
been guilty of using those terms early
on in my career where the market would
be dropping lower and I would assume
that that is profit taking and I don't
believe that is the case and I'm not
going to try to sell that to you it's my
argument and
case that I make that these markets are
algorithmic and everything happens
because it's designed and engineered to
do such so if there was an algorithm and
I'm going to assume for a moment some of
you don't believe there is one that's
running the marketplace
then it wouldn't do
some of these types of things but if
there is an algorithm then it should do
these types of things right that's my
argument I'm not trying to be dogmatic
about it here but I just proposed the
idea so that way you can go into price
action with that in mind when you're
studying it
so if there was a reasonable means of
measuring or a macro
a short little list of directives that
the algorithm would follow to reprice
from the highest high the week down to
some predetermined
price
what would that be
well we're going to walk through that
here but the bullseye if you have a
little sweet spot that the market can
retrace down into
in other words we don't anticipate it
closing right on the high so if it's
going to come off the high before
Friday's close and ending the week of
trading it's going to stop somewhere
between the 20 and 30 percent range
now right away this is going to sound
like oh here we go we have a Cherry
Picked example but I promise you I have
very very long-term students that have
learned this from me years ago and they
see me do this with the daily ranges
they see me do this with the weekly
ranges and they're able to do it as well
so I'm teaching you the concept and the
building blocks to understanding it but
there's a lot of other things you can do
with this information but this is just
an introductory to the TGIF
set up
so here is that same idea now being
applied to the
and on trading view if you're following
along that that's the teaching medium I
use and pull it off on a Wiki chart you
would see that this range again
disregard this this is the new week
Candlestick so we're not worrying about
that we're talking about last week and
how we could have used this information
on Friday I promise you buttons were
pushed on Friday you're going to see the
execution but I'm teaching you
conceptually what was in my mind how my
students also know about this pattern as
well and how we look for it
so here's 20 and 30 percent of that
Weekly range from the high
and those levels being shown here 15 3
26 and three quarters and 15 252 and a
half
all right here's the NASDAQ
sets our contract daily chart
all right we can see that this
Candlestick here
makes the high of the week
and the high comes in at fifteen
thousand four seventy five and a half
and then we trade down into
the range between 20 and 30 of the
entire weekly range the weekly range
being the high here
and the low here
20 percent
of this entire range here
subtracted from this high
would give us this level right there and
then 20
and 30 respectively would be that TGIF
draw on liquidity okay so think about
like that the market will likely draw
down to 20 or 30 percent of the weekly
range so that's how we can anticipate
Friday's trading in terms of a intraday
reversal or a weekly retracement I'll
leave it up to you how you want to
classify it okay either one of them
would be considered correct in terms of
describing what it is you're Trading
Monday's trading here
Tuesday's trading Wednesday Thursday and
then Friday opening making the high of
the week and then trading down and
closing inside
that 20 and 30 percent of the total
weekly range that is a successful
TGIF trade
now let's go into the details with this
a little bit more
right here is an hourly chart okay you
can see how again we have a short-term
High
we rallied up
don't look at this as support because we
don't know what the high is yet so I'm
just showing you these are the levels
that once the high is in place and we
can anticipate forming in the lunch hour
or just before lunch
around 1 30 going into two o'clock
the assumption is that we're likely to
draw down into 20 or 30 percent of the
weekly range if we've been bullish and
we've been bullish for a while and we
hit our higher time frame premium arrays
and targets so it's reasonable for it to
draw back if it's going to draw back
it's going to do so in a controlled
manner because the market is
algorithmically delivered so price is
controlled it's filing a script so
therefore where can we anticipate the
market to draw down to if a retracement
is in fact what's going to come in
before Friday's close
we have to Define where the weekly high
is the low is obviously here it formed
on Sunday so Sunday at 6 PM we're seeing
that Candlestick here represent that
Weekly range low
and then we can see Friday
all that range in here the highest high
we anticipate that high for me Friday
morning to Friday's lunch or
certainly between 1 30 and 2 o'clock why
because it's likely to retrace into the
close
now in terms of keeping things easier
for some of you that are
I guess familiar with trading in some of
the terms that are used unfortunately
incorrectly they'll say profit taking is
coming in and the market will retrace
lower
and it's not an absence of buyers and
it's not the sellers overtaking buyers
it's absolutely controlled
the market will just simply gravitate
towards 20 25 30 and sometimes if it
goes behind Beyond 30 percent that could
indicate an all-out reversal on a
long-term basis I don't suggest that's
the case here today because today is a
holiday and we've only had a short span
of time trading where on a holiday we
only have like until one o'clock in the
afternoon or so the Futures are trading
so
I don't suspect that we've created the
high yet that could obviously
you know be different when we open up
later on this evening to start a full
normal session to start our normal week
so that's our weekly range viewed over
the scope of a hourly chart
okay so we're going to get into this and
get a little more detailed
dropping down inside that range and
zooming in towards the high end of it
this is the 15 minute Candlestick chart
so 15 minutes
we can see that the high forms in here
around the nine o'clock in the morning
hour
on Friday it rallies up
creating what
a Juda swing
so all this initial run here sucks
Traders into thinking it's going to go
higher it's been going higher don't
fight the trend don't fight the FED
don't try to do this don't try to do
that everybody has an opinion about what
they should or shouldn't do
but if they don't have the Rules of
Engagement that the algorithm is
employing
all of the ideas or the the Dogma that
every Trader has and subscribes to as a
religion whether you want to believe it
or not your trading system is a religion
you have faith in it you're investing in
it you're paying tithes to it so the
bottom line is all this
deciding of taking on risk
it's going to have to be rooted on
something that makes sense
and I don't believe that buying and
selling pressure is the sense behind why
prices going up and down it's 100
controlled
so if we can see that initial surge at
the open on Friday as we see here
the market runs up creates this tendency
to want to
expect to keep going higher
an old highest broken here
but I teach that is by side liquidity so
the market goes higher they're running
out these relative equal highs because
those pending orders that would be used
for Traders that trade on a breakout
they want to buy strength
smart money employs that as their
counterparty to going short
and they're going to trade with this in
mind 20 to 30 percent of the weekly
range
TGIF Thank God It's Friday there is a
systematic approach to trading these
types of days on a Friday where it
trades back to 20 to 30 percent of the
range what does it look like well
everything I've already taught you
but the premise is is why and when it
will reach for
that 20 to 30 range of the weekly
highest high in the lowest low of the
week
look what we see here 50 minute
last up close candle prior to this move
lower this displacement here the change
in the state delivery is the opening
price that is my ICT order block okay it
has nothing to do
with an Fu candle okay you see all these
people trying to add things to it or
change the name of it there is no Fu
candle okay it's not an engulfing candle
it has nothing to do with any of that
the fact that the market is likely to
create the high here see I already know
I already know that this is going to
form because of that fair value gap on
the multi-chart we traded up into it
and now I'm talking very uh assertively
aren't I
I brought receipts today I promise
the up close candle is what we're
measuring whether you want to have the
wherewithal that goes short up in here
or not you don't need to you want to
wait for it to displace
one big candle up
and then it runs right over top of it
that opening price is where the change
in the state of delivery is made when it
goes back through it which is right here
then we have a short-term low taken
with this candle
and it closes and creates in the candle
here and then as soon as this candle
starts trading we have what
that's your 2022 model
so no matter how you slice it okay
I have so many people that will come to
my Channel or they'll talk about they'll
commentate around my content they'll
either be supportive of it or they'll
try to take shots at it and say I don't
like them because he has this he talks
too much he doesn't really have this or
that I have a lot of things
and it's imperative you go through all
of it because you're going to see how
all that fits together
the TGIF is a strategy that you
anticipate price delivering to in other
words it's a draw on liquidity that's
all it is and it happens on a Friday
and it reverses whatever has happened on
the weekly range it's going to go back
into 20 to 30 of whatever that Weekly
range has done is that complicated folks
does that sound complicated because it's
not it's really easy but how do you
trade it how do you go in and implement
it take it and go out there and study it
you go through the process of everything
I've already taught you you could trade
the Turtle suit which is the run here
above the buy stock so when the buy
side's taken you can sell short right
there that's a very very difficult thing
to do for New Traders
you have to really trust you know what
you're doing
you don't need to be able to do that
wait for it to give you your 2022 model
here's your favorite you got with the
short term shift in Market structure
here or if you want to use that one
either one it validates it then it
trades up into what
the 2022 entry model so it's trading
in this little area and because we have
to Traverse over lunch that's why we
have multiple passes
during the lunch hour
nothing has changed
treat this candle in this candle and the
highest one that trades into it which is
this one here
until we take out the low
here as long as you don't take out this
High all of these candles in between are
all time distortion
the range is already defined
2022 model
I teach more about time Distortion in my
books by the way I'm not going to teach
it on the YouTube channel I'm not going
to teach you on Twitter because
some of the things that I teach
you know
there's people out there already taking
my content and trying to write books and
get ahead of me and they're writing them
incompletely they don't they don't know
the details that my books are going to
have so this is a money grab for them
I don't want anybody looking at me as a
cash cow because of my ability to teach
this well and other people that learn
from me are making lots of money now
I want you to learn it properly but
you aren't going to learn it just by one
covering of it okay whether it be on me
or someone else no one's going to teach
it better than me because you know I
authored it I codified these Concepts
you're only being introduced to them
and don't fall victim thinking you're
going to hear somebody tell you in an
abbreviated format this is how you do
this is how you do that
but I want you to see how all the things
that I teach you can find them
throughout larger fractals and price
action that means
there's more than one way to skin a cat
with my Concepts just like there's other
ways that people can trade and they can
find theirselves and it's fun it's
wonderful but with my Concepts you don't
have to be a one-trick pony
there is not one PD array not one model
that is superior to the next
it's whatever one that you feel
comfortable with the one that makes the
most sense to you okay so
obviously we see how we moved from this
area here
this fair value Gap in the form of
Mississippi it's outside and bounce bios
efficiency so this move down here
separated by this candle's low and this
candle is high
all the sell side needs to be what
it needs to be delivered with buy side
we see that here
but look how many times it's doing it
why is it doing it that many times
because it has to Traverse through the
lunch hour
the lunch hour there's a macro that runs
within lunch hour and it usually runs
what the stops so where would the stops
be
right about this High we see it run
there and we return back to here but
there's no necessity to get above it it
says respecting with these little
Mohawks these little tiny little
deviations outside of the range that
creates my fair value Gap this low so it
goes above it here a little bit a little
bit here we expect that we anticipate
that type of thing it does not undermine
the the overall scenario
then you watch price melt into the 20 to
30 of the range before Fridays close
that would be the shade area here
zooming in here again you can see this
is the 15 minute order block
and we're trading up into that shaded
area that was found and defined on the
hourly chart you can see we have that
run on the stops here
then we drop down take out sell side and
then one more time rallies back up to
the 15 minute bear shorter block so this
is a reclaimed bearish order block
sell sides below here
the market drops
here's the model 2022 again
short term low
drop everybody you got rally up if you
don't get that entry
okay because before two o'clock and you
have a rigid rule set now that you're
going to be algorithmic behind every
trading idea that you employ whether it
be paper trading studying or live
Trading
you're going to stay Within These sweet
spots in terms of time I've already
talked between two o'clock and four
o'clock uh the afternoon PM session you
can finally trade a price run that will
seek liquidity
it's Friday the market has shown a
willingness to do what give a Judas
swing in the morning we're seeing that
here this is a Judah swing then it
overlaps all that so it's a change in
the state of delivery here that's your
bare shorter block we have a model 22
one hour Fairway Gap in the form of a
city that's the Shaded box here and then
we hit the bearish 15 minute order block
again
it drops creates a fair value you got
it's also a breaker high low higher high
how many models have I shown you already
which one would you have taken
that's the part that makes this
complicated I don't make it complicated
I don't complicate it am I detailed yes
but notice that if one of these patterns
and whatever it is premium array that
you're gonna identify as yours
you already see that the one that you
like you would be utilizing that
and the other ones aren't
so important to you
so you're able to see what I'm talking
about and find what it is that meets
your model
I'm not trying to press you into a mold
where you only do this entry technique
you don't only do whatever I point to
you find your own model using my
Concepts and there's no better way than
another don't look at okay well if I
sold up here it would be more money than
entering on the fear of a gap here
or trading into the breaker here you may
not have recognized this as a fair Vegas
but you can see this high low higher
high the down closed candle here extend
it through and it's trading onto it here
and here
that's a bearish breaker
now other students here would see okay I
see the run-on stops
it breaks lower here's a breaker it
trades up I would trade that as a
breaker
another student may see there's a
breaker there there's a fair value Gap
here I'm going to split that up into
four gradients and I want to take my
entry in the lower portion of that and
lower half of it and we have a fair
value Gap here so I can trade into that
and 25 of this range from the high and
the low that one hour Fairway Gap or
sibi
that's what this area is here you'd be
trading off that gradient again how many
models have I shown you here just in
this
it's not a one hit wonder
the premise is that there's a high
forming when it's been bullish all week
long
and we're going to trade off that high
down into 20 to 30 percent of the range
that's all TGIF is TGIF is not finding
the right PD array in the move I'm
giving you that freedom to pick which
one you're going to use
now watch what happens if you've seen
all this stuff in hindsight while the
Market's trading right around here and
you missed it it's already traded
outside of
the fair Vegas
you missed it what can you do well has
it traded to the 20 yet after leaving
the fair value Gap up here I mean it
hits it here yes
but we still have time it's still a
little bit after 11 o'clock in the
morning on Friday we still have the
whole afternoon and lunch session is
still go through
so what does lunch usually do it runs
stops
so we're expecting and anticipating a
rally up to clear the board of any
trailed buy stops
does it sweep that high no it doesn't
need to
but it will run rejection blocks now in
your notes rejection blocks are the same
function as running out liquidity
what's the highest up close
this one here prior to this High here is
it here
no
there
extend that through in time you can see
we sweep that it does not require it to
go above this High we're trading inside
this Wick which is what a gap
so because we've seen it create a little
Mohawk outside the
one hour
very bad you got
it's also defined on that one hour bare
shorter block the opening price
so we anticipate that little movement
outside of that it's reasonable we don't
want to see it but if it happens we're
not freaking out
so since we created this little
deviation outside that guy
returning back to it is permissible
notice where the bodies are inside of
that one hour fair value Gap
the Wicks do the damage so how do you
cut through all this stuff if we already
anticipated a run in permitting a mohawk
a little tiny little coloring Outside
the Lines if you will
we have to look in here where is the
rejection block think about your pdra
Matrix I've taught you in core content
month four
on this YouTube channel
there's your highest up close that's
your rejection block extend it to the
right and as you see what we're doing
we're wiping that out it does not need
to take out the wiki rejection blocks
are a very instrumental part for me
utilizing time Distortion and I promise
you I'll give you more details but it
requires a lot of other things for you
to take anything away from it don't
listen to anybody out there doing time
Distortion lectures because they
absolutely have no idea what they're
talking about I promise you
so getting back into this Fairbank app
here if you want to utilize the TGIF and
you anticipate it drawing down into 20
to 30 of the range of the weekly
expansion that you've been witness of
whatever that week would be any future
week you can utilize this information
okay
you missed the ideal entry inside the
Fairway gun
it moves outside of it
can you participate
sure you can
we're dropping down into a one minute
chart here is that fair value Gap that
was on the five minute chart
until we hit it here at the low end of
the one hour Fairway you got that's the
Shaded area here
and now we ring into two o'clock
time period which is this bullish candle
right there that's two o'clock on Friday
and then we drop down
so what did I teach you about two
o'clock to three o'clock in the
afternoon on index features
my ICT Silver Bullet well here is the
ICT Silver Bullet we have a high low
higher high reacting off of an hourly
bearish
Fairway Gap in the form of a city
we have a fairway Gap here so is order
flow bearish it sure is it's respecting
every premium array small little Fairway
Gap here goes into it rebalance
and the bottom end
of the hourly fair value Gap
we would anticipate
displacement lowered boom does it happen
yes it does
breaker fair value got trade up into it
get short
reach into
30 to 20 how far can it go well you have
to wait on time
TGIF you submit the time so I'll show
you this is the the two o'clock P.M
ending so it's three o'clock so two to
three that one hour interval right there
there's your fair bag Gap that forms the
ICT Silver Bullet how many models have I
shown you just in this lecture how many
opportunities to get in
multiple
another one right here
it's still inside the Silver Bullet time
frame so if you missed this one you
could have done this one
put it but it hits the 20 Michael
wouldn't that be the end of it no
there's still time time ends with this
shaded area here at the close
okay four o'clock when that Bell Rings
you see it on CNBC ding ding ding
everybody claps their hands like they
did something special
all this time you're gonna submit to it
and as we get into the last hour trading
three o'clock to four yes I understand
that trades till five o'clock but the
bulk of trading ends at four o'clock
unless earnings season comes in and does
something after the bill but the point
is the majority of the trading is done
before four o'clock
in New York local time
so the entries must be taken between two
o'clock and three o'clock for a silver
bullet okay so I'm adding all that extra
value into this lesson
here is a one minute chart zoomed in
here's that favorite you got
inside of the hourly Fairway Gap City
and where it bumped the bottom of it and
it reacted during the two o'clock hour
created the fair value got with the
breaker high low higher high reaction
we're seeing this is a signature saying
that yes order flow is bearish yes the
algorithm is driving price down towards
the 20 25 and 30 percent of the weekly
range that's where we'd anticipate it it
gives you a fair value Gap I'm getting
short here 15 contracts at 15 357 even I
want to be ahead of that candles High I
want to make sure I'm getting filled
that was my entry
I'm holding to see if we get into the
last hour of trading how we trade we
trade into three o'clock
we trade half of
the 30 and 20 so 25 of the weekly range
has been traded to here
small little retracement and then I'm
anticipating another Drive Lower
I'm not trying to buy it
I want to see does it take out that load
it's formed in the last hour trading
here is sell side my limit order was
placed right there
as it went down into it boom
I missed all this movement here that's
fine 20 handlers or so
then off the low of the day enclosed
way away from where my cover was so
15 357 even short on 15 covering at 15
280 even
full pool no partials
that's what it looks like folks
TGIF thank God it's Friday
the pattern or setup is simply using 20
to 30 of the weekly range as the draw on
liquidity on a Friday okay on a Friday
if there was no Judah swing at 9 30 when
the market opened up on Friday and
rallied higher if it wouldn't have
formed that in other words if it would
have just kept climbing higher and
didn't reverse then I would anticipate a
lunch time or going into 1 30 to 2
o'clock
then create the high of the week so for
some of you are thinking well how did
you know how did you know or how would
you know
one of those two scenarios are going to
happen you're going to create the Judah
swing at the open on Friday at 9 30. if
you're bearish you're anticipating it to
pull down into 20 30 of the weekly range
because the weekly range has been going
up right
well for this week it has or last week
rather and then we would expect it to
create a false run at the open lore
Traders into trying to buy it
and then get trapped near the high and
they drag it lower into 20 to 30 of the
weekly range
look how close we got to 30 of the
weekly range right there isn't that
crazy
now
you can have static rules where you can
take this 20 to 30 percent of the range
of the weekly range and you can do
gradients on that again you can take it
this is the low the lower 25 percent
half of it the upper 25 or 700 in the
range that makes up the 20 to 30 range
you can take a partial as it touches 20.
take another partial at the upper
portion or upper gradient level before
50 if it gets to 50 take most of your
trade off
then roll your stock to the most recent
swing High
and see if it can reach to your next
gradient level and it would have done so
here I just elected to wait to see what
this load was that formed in the last
hour this one here had already moved
here so I want to in this retracement I
was comfortable with anticipating it
ripping lower to take that one out and
it did and I did not require to trade to
30 percent
so what I was using using is just simply
the load it Formed here
allowing traders to think that the low
was formed and they go in they think
they have the
you know the 345 350 algorithm that's
not an algorithm there's a macro that
runs and when you don't know what it is
you won't see what this is doing here
all this was doing was pulling up
against
short-term buy stock buy sides relative
equal highs here so I knew it was likely
to go up there but stay inside what
range 20 to 30. so relative equal highs
I was comfortable holding that that's
reasonable for it to go up there and hit
that then it broke lower attacking the
sell side so all the people that try to
buy long
in here thinking you're going to catch a
little bit of a move going into the four
o'clock hour
they have no idea what they're doing and
you can see that there's a distinct
difference between what you think you
see
in other YouTube lessons from other
people versus what I'm showing you here
I promise you if you study this go back
through every single weekly candle on
any Market
you will see this
you'll see a multitude of potential
entry patterns using what I've taught
also on this channel
you only need one you need one entry
model if you want to get really nuts
about it you can have every single one
of them understood but none of you know
how to do that yet okay I promise you if
they did if anybody's out there on
YouTube saying they can do it they know
like the back of their hand now they
know everything I've taught they would
be out here executing like I'm doing
I'm showing you evidence and proof that
these things are the reasons why I'm
getting in
where I'm holding what I'm entering and
what the logic was
if they say they know my stuff they
don't they're just familiar with it okay
I have a lot more teachings for us this
year hopefully you found this one in
cycle and I really do appreciate you
hanging out with me until talk to you
next time
be safe