welcome back folks this is April 2017's
content for the ICT mentorship
this month we're going to be teaching my
day trading model
this is lesson one
and we're going to be covering
Essentials to ICT day trading
all right folks  ICT day trading model
and the essentials to the ICT day
trading
okay for the opportunities inside the
DailyRange
now the aim is to capitalize on the
movement existing in a single day now
this makes this type of trading the
hardest and it's why most analysts and
Technical  gurus if you will that like
to talk on CNBC or in the higher time
frame World they'll they'll scoff at day
trading they'll say that it's not likely
that anyone could be profitable trading
this time frame but as you'll learn in
this month it's very very precise and
our aim is to capitalize on the movement
that exists in a 24-hour trading period
it's important just because the name
again I've said this many times is day
trading it does not mean or equate to
Everyday trading so not all dates are
going to be ideal for day trading
generally there are two setups per
trading day on average and we're going
to go over both of those setups but
we're gonna be talking about other
scenarios that can take place in a
24-hour trading period for this month
that will also help you when we get into
scalping in the May content
the DailyRange is the goal for us as
the day trader in other words our
expectation is to capitalize on at least
65 to 70 percent of the DailyRange that
means we're going to leave a little bit
on the table possibly near the high or
the LOD but we're trying to
get the lines portion of the move that
comprises the DailyRange or daily
candle
now typically the DailyRange will be
close to the last five days average
DailyRange and I'll go into detail
about that and how we can arrive at that
figure but generally what we're looking
for is a range that is equivalent to the
last five days averaged across in other
words what's the most Pips it's moved in
the last five days averaged and then
that's going to be our expected daily
range now there's going to be times
where I'm going to teach you where
average DailyRange can be actually
doubled or even expected to be more than
doubled in a single day
DirectionalBias frames a large portion
of all day trade setups
that means we're gonna be looking for
directional plays primarily so we're
going to have a preconceived idea going
into the week looking for specific
criterias to link ourselves with
institutional order flow
now the ideal scenario is to day trade
in the direction of the weekly time
frame I'm going to give you insights in
this specific teaching here how we can
do that
now the more HTF ideas
that you can find to support the day
trade this is going to increase the odds
and therefore make it better for you
a day trades permit the trader to limit
the stop loss on all trades now while
we're dealing specifically with day
trading in this entire month's content
the advantage is even if you do not want
to be a day trader or you don't have the
ability to sit in front of the charts
all day long and babysit there's going
to be a way of doing this type of
trading without sitting in front of the
charts all day I'll give you that but
also I want you to think about how using
day trade entries
and using the very small stop losses
that this time frame permits in this
discipline of trading you can lower your
initial risk when we're trading these
long-term position trades or swing
trades and or your one shot one kill
so these setups while they are really
limited to you by your own imagination
you can't
just look at this as a well it's a day
trading model or discipline so therefore
you know it doesn't fit me it doesn't
fit my criteria or my personal makeup as
a Trader it doesn't jive with my psyche
as an individual so therefore I mean
just just discount this and maybe you're
looking for something that's going to be
taught later in the mentorship and
you're not really going to pay too much
attention to this one  you'd be really
doing yourself at the same as a service
because it helps you reduce the amount
of risk lower the amount of Pips and
it's also going to have a framework
where you can incorporate with the last
lesson number eight of this month we can
incorporate the entry techniques that
we're using for day trading and then
overlap that with HTF
setups which can give you many many
times over the Standard three to five to
one
setups in other words we're looking for
setups that pay out five to one or three
to one ideally but
when you're using day trade entries and
you're high trading off a higher time
frame setup wow the multiples can be
ridiculous they could be in the double
digits very easily
it's important not to take many day
trades in a single 24-hour day and as I
mentioned earlier there's two primary
setups in a day and we're going to go
over that in the next teaching but for
now just understand that just because
you're day trading and we're not talking
about scalping here but we're looking
for specific setups that allow us to try
to capitalize on the majority of the
DailyRange now it's not important that
we get all the DailyRange believe me if
you get a portion of the DailyRange and
you go on the profit that's way better
than 99 of all the other Traders out
there because most people are losing
money so if you're capitalizing on a
DailyRange and you're getting some
portion of every single day that may
equate to maybe 30 Pips and maybe the
average DailyRange is 120 Pips and the
DailyRange for that particular day you
traded was 100 Pips but you only got 30
or maybe 40. that's not a loss that's
not a missed opportunity that's actually
very successful so you're doing well and
if you can continuously do that you'll
grow in your understanding and bring
yourself to holding for larger portions
of the move and getting in better
entries and you'll get larger portions
of that DailyRange but don't think that
you can day trade a lot and therefore
get a lot of Trades okay that's not the
answer to what you're looking for in
terms of profitability or Pips
now the if the data ranges combined with
PD arrays are the foundation to all of
my day trades
FOMC days and non-farm payroll days keep
us on the sidelines and they are
basically a no setup day so while we can
play in the sand and use our demo
accounts to keep close to price and stay
dialed in in terms of what they may be
reaching for as we just did just this
past Friday
week of this recording just because we
may be able to forecast or see
analytically where IPDA may take price
it's many times better just to sit on
the sidelines and just let that one day
go by without you participation in those
types of days really does not increase
your odds even in day trading
all right so what frames the daily
setups
obviously we have to concern ourselves
with HTF institutional
order flow and that's going to be a ride
that looking at monthly weekly and daily
PD arrays in the last 20 40 and 60
trading days
I'm going to assume that you have a firm
understanding about what a PD array is
and looking back the last 20 40 and 60
trading days you have to look for those
HTF and we're going to
focus primarily on The Daily  for day
trades you don't need to see anything in
terms of a weekly or a monthly primarily
because you'll generally see something
on the daily that'll line up for a
discount or a premium PD array
now IPDA will be seeking new levels in
price for liquidity that's the role of
the interbank price delivery algorithm
it seeks to move price to an area of new
liquidity
the weekly chart or current candles
direction is what we're primarily
working within so what we're doing is
we're blending our expectation of what
IPDA may be seeking in terms of new
liquidity above or below us in terms of
market price
and we're forecasting the weekly candle
direction that we're presently trading
in so in other words if we're getting
ready to go into a new week we're going
to be forecasting what IPDA will be
reaching for higher or lower prices
relative terms to the PDA rays and in
the if the data ranges in order how far
back are we looking for the most
obvious logical premium or discount
array and what's the direction that's
most likely favoring higher or lower
prices and then we incorporate that idea
in forecasting the present or next
weekly candle and we look for that
expansion higher or lower in relative
terms to what we expect in terms of the
at the data range and institutional
order flow
the day of the week is Paramount and
understanding about day trading because
there's certain days that have high
probability and there's other days that
can be a little bit of a hat trick in
other words you may expect something to
happen this particular day but it may do
something entirely different and then
there's other days that are predisposed
to really just be a quiet day we'll talk
about that
and the most important is time of day
time of day for day trading is
absolutely Paramount just because we are
day trading doesn't mean that you can
just sit down any old time and say okay
I'm going to buy the Euro here and
therefore I'm going to be profitable or
I'm going to sell short the Euro Yen
because you know I got off work and I
can sit in front of charge now it does
not equate to that they are specific
times of the day that IPDA will move
price and gyrate price around and then
the market makers will facilitate trade
but at those particular times and there
are no set brokerage operating hours but
there are time windows that we have to
work within so while I don't trade in
zones in price I do trade in zones and
time so you have to be flexible with
time and demand specifics in price that
means we're demanding specific things
that occur in a window of time so the
flexibility resides in time not price
price must hit our level must go to our
level and we look for price to reach for
that contrarian PD array for our profit
we do not wait
for price to get exactly to that level
because we're always going to look exit
early but we're always looking for these
x's and entries to overlap with specific
times of the day
and what we're primarily focusing on are
volatility expansions or large daily
ranges
okay time of day what time of day are we
referring to obviously if you've gone
through all my pre-dutorials in these
times that they aren't going to be new
to you but for completeness sake I do
have to incorporate them
primarily we're going to be looking for
day trades at the London session open
and that is basically the ICT killZone
for London and we're going to be talking
in terms of NewYork Times so when I
refer to a time here
it's going to be relative to what time
it is in NewYork
so typically London the hot spot for the
higher low the form for the day is
usually between two o'clock in the
morning and four o'clock in the morning
NewYork time now it can deviate and
transition a little bit earlier a little
bit later relative to the economic
calendar and or daylight savings time it
has a little bit of overlap where there
may be some transition time before the
market observes any movement from a
daylight savings time or not
in daylight savings time  the way I
overcome that is I look at my London
open killZone beginning at 1am NewYork
time and ending at 5 AM NewYork time
so it gives me that window of four hours
where it allows literally nothing to
escape me I'm looking already at that
time window and I'm looking at the
acting out calendar relative to the pair
I'm trading so there should be some kind
of a manipulation just before or at the
time of the news release that either is
medium impact or high impact and then
therefore the trade setup is seen the
next time window we look at is the New
York session open now this is primarily
the easiest one to work with
you're gonna you're gonna see that
with the insights that you're gonna
learn in this particular teaching you'll
know why that the NewYork session
really really is so much easier and
that's why I worked primarily the
majority of our mentorship thus far in
the NewYork session because I want you
to get really friendly with that time
frame  you know London can be a little
bit of a beast so you have to know a
little bit more understanding about IPDA
how the DailyRange is formed within the
weekly range and in the weekly range
forms within a monthly range so all of
these fractal ideas they have to be
utilized in modular fashion and over a
period of time you'll get a better
understanding about how the sessions
unfold and when London is to be avoided
which we'll talk about this month but
NewYork primarily is really really good
now the only time that you would avoid
NewYork is if the London session puts
in 80 percent of the average DailyRange
and there's going to be very few times
that it does that but generally unless
they DailyRange is almost entirely
completed in the last five days average
DailyRange is what I'm referring to
that measurement if it's met or exceeded
in London that is when you want to move
to the sidelines and don't even consider
trading NewYork because it's probably
either going to bounce around go
sideways or it may catch you in a
reversal to you weren't expecting and
it's just better just to just sit on the
sidelines and don't worry about it wait
for another trading day
London close now I've taught London
close day trading strategy in the past I
used to do it I lost interest in it
because it just doesn't give me enough
of a payment if you will I'll touch
briefly on it this month but obviously I
have my own teaching on it where you can
watch that in my free tutorials but
nonetheless London close is the time of
day where we look to really Bank our
positions and
there are times when if the market is in
a reversal  intraday but it goes down
into a logical level of support or
trades up into electrical level
resistance that may be the very moment
in time that a reversal occurs London
close is not always just simply close
existing trades and move to the
sidelines many times London close can be
incorporated as a entry point for longer
term One-Shot one kill or
swing or position trades
foreign
close is basically just a Time window
what we're looking for is  the two
o'clock hour now
I'm not going to  argue that everyone
else around the world is going to say
NewYork is you know later in the day
than that  I'll leave everyone else to
believe whatever they want to believe
but what we're looking at is the two
o'clock hour and specifically the three
o'clock which is the close of the bond
market that to me is the close of the
NewYork session so what we look for is
in days to have FOMC interest rate stuff
that comes out at two o'clock hour in
NewYork time that usually will run
until around three o'clock in the
afternoon NewYork time and then when
the bond market closes at 3 PM that's
it whatever's happened by then that's
the DailyRange and there's nothing else
to expect
very very rarely are we even concerned
about that because generally by noon
you're you're done you're not really
looking at anything past noon
Asian session open  this is primarily
8 PM  my time in NewYork  we're
looking for very small little setups
that takes place in  this time of day
but many times  during the Aussie
overlap into Asia you can actually get
the daily lower high formed  in the
Asian session open for like the Yen
pairs  Aussie and kiwi those types of
pairs can generally
surprise the traitor by forming a
special or important if you will high or
low at that time of day when you would
normally expect it in the London session
those pairs generally can have a
surprise and form their particular daily
low and respective low at that session
time
and London lunch this is generally
between 5 AM to 7
00 AM that time window is when the
market goes pretty much quiet and It
prepares for the next leg either in the
direction that London creates or a
reversal and on days that don't promote
anymore follow through it can just be a
continuation rate from London and goes
right on through the NewYork session in
consolidation so London after 5 P AM
NewYork time you generally want to just
anticipate a mode of transition
retracement or consolidation so if we're
for instance if we're looking for lower
prices and we've gone short in London
it's pretty good idea to take something
at or just before 5 AM just in case we
get a reversal because there can be
London lunch reversals
and because there's usually an economic
report that comes out late like 4 30 in
the morning my time or it could be a 5
AM release economically but nonetheless
you want to take something
during the London session in terms of
profit because the London lunch hour can
cause a reversal or a deeper retracement
that may squeeze on your profits and
depend upon how far that retracement
goes and some of them in London can be
brutal  you don't want to get
the opportunity to pass you by where a
good position except would have been
favorable for at least a portion of your
trade so be mindful that between 5 AM
and 7 AM that is considered another
lunch and we look for either retracement
or consolidation on that particular time
of day
okay day of week I'm gonna give you some
characteristic specifics about  each
day and Sunday generally we opt out
because the DailyRange is simply too
too small it's only a couple hours but
there are some things that we need to
know about Sunday for those data
providers that use daily  Sunday
candles some provider some Brokers don't
use Sunday at all but if it if your
broker doesn't use Sunday
don't worry about it just use
everything that we teach and I'll refer
to later on and we get to that
discussion about what we do with Sunday
you just incorporate that with
Monday's data it's not that big of a
deal
okay Monday and generally this can
create a small range typically
um if it's a really large range
and it comes right out the gate  you
know Direction wise and you understand
where you're at in terms of the the PD
arrays if we're trading up into a
premium right from the jump of the new
week and Monday becomes a high range or
large range day and it trades into a
premium PD array that can many times be
the high of the week that's the
characteristics that we look for so
that's kind of like a tip that we can
add to back  the one shot one kill
content if Monday is a big range day
and we trade up into a premium relative
to the Daily
then we can really anticipate that being
the high of the week
now generally Mondays are going to be a
small range day unless that type of
scenario unfolds or the opposite would
be if Monday has a big range day and
trading down and it goes into a PD array
that's a discount on the daily chart
then we can anticipate Monday becoming
the lowest low of the week
Tuesday usually is a good day to trade
in terms of specifics of one shot one
kill usually on bullish weeks Tuesday
has a 77 likelihood of creating the low
of the week in London and therefore it
creates a high probability  scenario
to be a day trader on Tuesdays and
reverse is said for when the markets are
bearish if you have a 70 likelihood that
Tuesday's limit open will create the
high of the week so generally Tuesdays
are really good days to trade for day
trades
Wednesday are really ideal scenarios
because what you'll see is you have
Sunday if you use those candles in your
platform
Monday and Tuesday or if you don't have
Sunday you have Monday and Tuesday
behind you and it gives you some insight
as we're going to share in this teaching
to help frame confidence around trading
Wednesday with a particular mindset
going into London and NewYork so
generally ideal day trading is seen on
Wednesday because you have some data
midweek
Thursday again is generally ideal
scenario but you gotta be careful
Thursdays can reverse
um usually the weekly range is again
capped by Thursday's NewYork session so
be mindful that if we do get a good day
trade in in Thursday's London open
it may fizzle out and actually reverse
the week
during the Thursday NewYork or London
close scenario
Friday is typically a small range as we
close a week but if there are objectives
that haven't been met by Thursday in
terms of the PD arrays you could see a
surprise expansion on Friday running
into that PD array so it's kind of like
a toss-up it depends on what we've seen
in the weekly range if Thursday has met
the daily PD array whether it be premium
or discount that we've traded for in
terms of a Target
for the weekly range as a whole if
that's been met by Thursday chances are
Friday's going to be a really quiet day
if it has not been met Friday can
generally sometimes surprise us and have
a big large range day
the weekly range framework
okay what we look for is on Sunday we
determine the new trading week's opening
price now this will Aid Us in intra week
with day trade directional buys to work
with now I already know some of you are
thinking and panicking oh no you know I
don't use Sunday candles my broker
doesn't use Sunday data no problem just
use your opening on Monday it's not that
big of a deal it's still going to come
to the same consensus anyway to just
relax it's not going to be that much of
a disparity
but we're going to note this Sunday
opening and we're going to note it and
draw it out in time all the way through
our 60 Minute or one hour chart all the
way up to Thursday
now the weekly range framework what we
do with this is we take that opening
range price
from Sunday and we draw it out on our
hourly chart and we draw it all the way
until Thursday now why is it Thursday
well because your profile say on
Thursday you could see a reversal unfold
for the week
so while we do have some rules that
we're going to be sharing with you here
Thursday May change that entirely and
it'll also frame a high
probability reversal confirmation if you
will if price gets back above and when
it's bearish like for instance look at
this chart here if price were to trade
back above the opening price on Sunday
during Thursday's Trading
we've probably turned the corner we've
had a major intro week reversal and that
many times indicates a longer term
One-Shot one kill bullish so we could
get in sync with that if not the next
day and Friday we can certainly be in
sync with it the next trading week so
think about that in terms of intra-week
reversals
if we see it trade back above
well in this case since it was bearish
for the week if we trade above Sunday's
opening on Thursday we've had an
intra-week reversal and obviously that
goes without saying it's pretty obvious
and some of you that are very cynical
would say well good grief that's the
obvious Michael but think about what
it's telling you you've had a
intermediate term reversal
so now therefore Friday May not give you
a setup to trade long but next week you
can you can trade long on Monday right
out the gate looking for a low in New
York and London
they get along and take those positions
throughout the rest of the next week if
this scenario was reversed and we had
Sunday's opening
forecast all the way and drawn
through our hourly chart all the way to
Thursday
and it started bullish for the week and
then traded down Thursday
through that Sunday's opening price that
registers a potential weekly reversal so
therefore we can get in sync the very
next day on Friday selling short or the
next week our scenario would go into
that new week going short rate from jump
on Monday Tuesday and Wednesday looking
for the high of the week to form and
then therefore going short every day in
the following week based on the insight
but the suddenly opening price filter we
look for price to trade Above This level
generally early in the week during
bearish weekly DirectionalBias in other
words we're expecting price to trade
down away from a PD array that's a
premium okay we've seen price move up
into a premium it's already traded it
has already fulfilled a premium level so
therefore we're expecting expansion on
the downside and we see the opening
price and then price starts to trade up
Sunday and going into Monday trades
above it so therefore we're seeing a
little bit of a Judas swing that's the
criteria we're looking for and then
throughout the rest of the week as long
as price is lower than this Sunday
opening price each day of the week we
look to sell short in all of our day
trades
caveat is
until a HTF PD array
that's contrary to how our trade is
unfolding is traded to in other words if
we're looking for bearish ideas
okay directional lies we're expecting
the weekly candle to be closing lower
than it opened on Sunday
no it's the weekly candle closing Friday
will close lower than it opened on
Sundays opening or if your data provider
opens on Monday
if we're expecting that down candle on a
weekly basis
as long as we are trading below the
Sunday's opening price
we're looking to sell short every single
day in London and continuation in New
York but this is only true in this case
while we're looking for Sell days every
day of the week while we're below the
Sunday opening price
that's true only until we trade to a
HTF discount PD array that
has us on caution and we may see an
intro week reversal if that happens
otherwise we continuously take day
trades short in London and continuations
in NewYork
can't continue with the weekly range
framework
the opposite said here for Sunday's
opening price filter
we look for price to trade below this
level early in the week during bullish
weekly DirectionalBias in other words
if price is trading at a higher time
frame discount PD array whether it be a
monthly weekly and daily there's
suggestions that you know the prices
really oversold institutionally speaking
not because of indicators but in
relative terms if we expect something to
to be bullish on a daily chart that's
really the only thing we really need if
the daily is at a discount and we're
trading at a discount PD array price is
suggesting higher prices institutional
order flow suggesting higher prices
we've gone to forecast the weekly candle
to close higher than it opens on Sunday
as long as price is higher than this
Sunday opening price each day of the
week we look to buy long in all of our
day trades that means we're looking for
the low the form in London and a
continuation by in NewYork and we
continuously hold this idea throughout
the week until a HTF PD
array in the form of a premium is traded
to
then we would expect a potential
intra-week reversal
so I know it's just probably you know
going way past your heads and it's going
a lot of information because many of you
probably shortchange yourself studying
the previous lessons I'm going to give
you a few examples we're going to look
back at the cable over the last three
weeks and give you some scenarios and
what this did and how it helps
okay so we're looking at a British pound
USD weekly chart so every range here
represents a weekly amount of data in
other words it's the Open high low and
close of an entire week
I want you to focus primarily at this
chart and think about Power3 I've
gone through my free tutorials you
understand what Power3 is but I
want you to look at these candles and
remind yourself that the weekly range
candles that are large have the opening
price and closing price at opposing ends
of the Candlestick range
now this is important because it's
teaching you to focus and anticipate
range expansion range expansion on a
weekly chart is a gold mine as long as
you know what the most likely probable
Direction is on the weekly candle that
we're forming right now
you can find setups you don't have to
worry about missing anything because
last time I checked there's every new
week There's a new candle forming on a
weekly basis so there's new setups to
form now some weeks are better than
others you're going to be small weeks
there's going to be Wick real high Wick
real low candles and then creating a
small little body those leaks can be
challenging sometimes but there's other
times when the when the candle itself is
rather small and
you're not going to make money every
single week every single day every
single month that is not going to happen
even with my content because you're
going to do something to break the rules
or the markets is simply not going to do
what you hoped it was going to do but on
a large scale probability Spectrum you
have more odds of finding opportunities
using this criteria than in any other
fashion no other discipline out there
gives you this Focus point to work
within
so now looking at this weekly chart
we're going to look at a bullish candle
okay and what we're focusing on
primarily is that the open is usually
near the low of the week
and the close is near the high of the
week now let's think about this in
relative terms it's a weekly candle so
therefore the open is Sunday's opening
or if your data is only providing Monday
not Sunday candles it's going to be the
Monday opening okay so what we're
looking for is that a little bit of
movement below the opening price when
we're primarily bullish and then we're
going to be looking for expansion
throughout the rest of the week until
Friday's close
all the way between the open and close
that's your range that you're working
within now I know what you're thinking
how do I know how far away the close is
going to be there's calculations and
things I'm going to give you to
determine what the weekly range may be
and there's going to be things you have
to overlap with that in terms of if the
data ranges and PD arrays but between
this lesson and what you learn in later
lessons just for now focus on the
fundamentals of knowing that there's a
large range based on the weekly candle
that ranges between the opening on
Sunday or your data provider only
opening on Monday that opening price to
Friday's close that's your time window
we're looking for day trades throughout
the week Monday through Friday we have
five opportunities and if we're going to
be fair about it we generally have
basically  nine setups that are pretty
much solid we generally don't rush a
London setup on Monday but if you're
absolutely aggressive you can be looking
for setups on Monday especially if you
have a big range starting right out of
the gate on Sunday going into Monday
Frankfurt so if that happens then that's
pretty much a a sure deal that you
should be paying attention to London on
Monday so you still have to be paying
attention to it so regardless of where
you live in the world around midnight in
NewYork time on Monday you need to be
looking at the charts and see how big
the range was for Asia on Monday's
trading so from Sunday's opening all
into Frankfurt set up you know what that
looks like by looking at midnight and
Monday morning NewYork time and if it's
a big range then you primarily want to
look for the weekly high or low to form
on Monday because it's in a rush to get
somewhere in a hurry if you look at the
daily chart many times it's going to
line up with a premium or a discount
array and you can pretty much know what
they're going to probably do the rest of
the week
and the same thing in Reverse terms
looking at a down candle for the week
we're looking primarily from the open at
the beginning we get Sunday or again if
you don't have so many candles in your
platform we're looking at the opening
price on your Monday feed
to Friday's close that's the range
you're operating in so you're looking
for shorts in this scenario every day
looking for shorts as long as we're
below that opening price formed at
Sunday or Monday that filter gives you
focus to look for now again we don't
just simply go and look at just because
for instance Tuesdays long and open may
be lower okay it may be lower than
Sunday's opening price in Tuesday's
London open so that does not mean simply
go in there and start going short
because I just said something in general
terms like that no we're going to show
you in three examples of what can happen
and why that isn't always that simple
you have to look at again the PD arrays
and The pdra Matrix
okay our first and three examples here
we're looking at the daily chart of the
pound
and this is illustrating a
premium PD array on the daily chart in
the form of a daily rejection block
okay and an old low discount PD array so
we have two reference points framed here
and we're going to look at the week of
this recording
okay you can see all of the days for
this particular week are noted and our
opening prices forecasted throughout the
week until Thursday Thursday has a
delineation so you can see the
separation amongst all the other days
Monday Tuesday Wednesday and then Friday
you can see that we had that daily
rejection block premium PD array
traded to and above the opening price on
Sunday
and price started trading softer right
away on Monday trading lower now on
Tuesday okay we had Pro sell off right
after the transition from Monday into
Tuesday it sold off then went in
consolidation
in a consolidation continued all the way
into
the London open for Wednesday and then
price rallied again now think about
what's happened here on Wednesday
Tuesday and Wednesday price had traded
down into a fair value Gap so we had Gap
support and you can see that Gap really
being noted here on the previous week
but we'll look at that week after this
one but
price traded down and found support and
couldn't find its way below 124.30
Tuesday and Wednesday finally it rallied
up
creating another consolidation and then
Thursday it trades up intraday
creating a high that's higher than the
consolidation that was formed in
Wednesday then it was rejected and then
we sold off
on non-farm payroll on Friday
the general consensus is that we were
looking for cells below that opening
price on Sunday because it had traded
into the daily rejection block PD array
in a premium basis
this is the reason why I gave you
short objectives of 12420
123.75 and then 123.10
12310 didn't get traded to but 123.75
did and we had a low of the week of
123.65
and that's 10 Pips below the low that
formed for this old low discount PD
array
okay our second scenario or example for
case study
we have a daily rejection block premium
PD array and we have a bullish order
block low discount PD array
okay on the previous week prior to the
week of this recording
okay you can see the opening price on
Sunday and right away price shoots out
the gate on Monday trades up
aggressively trades higher
and then sells off again in
London on Tuesday
and then trades down through that
opening price now watch what happens on
Wednesday
the the Mantra would be okay we're below
the selling point of Sunday's opening
price so therefore I should be looking
to sell short because we're below
Sunday's opening price no the reason why
is because we traded down into a fair
value Gap relative to the daily chart
and we have that daily discount bullish
order block see how it stopped it dead
in its tracks so while we're still below
the opening price
and we hit a PD array in a discount
contrarian scale in order we're looking
at something that would be opposing our
expectations on Lower pricing
if we're at a discount on The Daily
if it hits that we have to look at what
that PD array is is it premium or or
discount in this case it's discount so
therefore it's going to offer support we
cannot be a seller in this
particular setup we anticipate what
unfolding it's a reversal
so we have Wednesday's profile Wednesday
reversal or low of the week form and
then we can change gears and forget the
Sunday's opening price and we're going
to focus primarily on the weekly profile
and we transition from that now we're
going to incorporate the weekly profile
of Wednesday low of the week so you can
see the low forming at that PDA rate
discount on a daily basis with the order
Block in London on Wednesday it trades
down and then on Thursday it trades down
into that fair value a gap
also a discount PD array and then
expands up above the opening price
that's seen on Sunday
and then on Friday it opens and trades
down again into
a bullish order block that was seen on
Thursdays trading and then it expands up
against once more closing in the
liquidity void
formed on Tuesday's Trading
so you can see how it's just simply not
watch a video from ICT and there it is
it's as simple as that you have to blend
some things and look at what would be
barriers what are what are the barriers
or speed bumps to you getting to what
you think price is going to do because
we understand if the data ranges looking
back 20 40 and 60 days we understand the
PD array Matrix what makes a premium
array what makes a discount array and
where we're at in that scheme of the
Matrix are we above or below equilibrium
in this case when price traded down
Wednesday into that daily discount
bullish order block you can't just
simply say I'm going to go sell them
short because it rallied up in London
it's sold off a little bit but traded
down to that bullish order block inside
the fair value Gap these are all daily
PD arrays in the discount manner so if
it's discounted it's trading at a daily
chart it's going to resist going lower
but it will paint all kinds of scenarios
that would look like Sell setups in the
retail Spectrum and then all of a sudden
you see the market trading higher and it
goes up into its respective contrary
discount PD array in this case it's the
Tuesday liquidity void being closed in a
fair value Gap up at the 125 50 level
okay our last example here
we have the bullish order block low
discount PD array and we have an old
high or equal highs premium PD array
okay and we have the opening price on
this particular week's Sunday's opening
and price trades right from the opening
it goes up a little bit on Monday and
trades down right away into the bullish
order block low discount PD array and
then rallies away from that and then we
have one more attempt to go lower on
Tuesday trades down into it
Tuesday and then expands up so now
Tuesday we've traded above Sunday's
opening we are at a discount on The
Daily so therefore we have our scenario
expecting the weekly range or candle to
close higher than it opened on Sunday so
therefore our Mantra is every day we're
looking for an open decline low of the
day buy it in London
in NewYork we're looking for
retracement into the range that was
created from London's low to the high
formed prior to 8 20 8 30 AM in that in
that realm  we're looking for that CME
opening which is 8 20 AM NewYork time
when that occurs generally that's going
to be the setup in NewYork and so
usually a continuation therefore and
we're going to be looking for an
expansion continuing on the up move so
we have the criteria met with a discount
PD array on The Daily being met will
Monday's Trading if we trade above
Sunday's opening price on Tuesday so
therefore Wednesday Thursday we're
looking for openings in London to trade
down by at a logical discount PD array
in its lower time frame hourly chart
and
look what happens on Friday the criteria
says that Friday can be a quiet day and
the weekly range can be capped by
Thursday's trading in NewYork and you
see that happens here
notice also because we did not hit the
old high or equal High
premium PD array that particular week on
the 24th of
march on Sunday we opened up
rallying right away and it makes a run
for what the daily PD array equal highs
once it hit those equal highs then on
Tuesday we see the week that we just
talked about it creates that failure
swing around that
125-90 level creating the high of the
week on Tuesday so there's that overlap
of PD arrays that caused the previous
examples weekly High the form on Monday
and Tuesday
so you have to blend some things but
incorporating the Sunday's opening price
and blending it with PD arrays from a
discount and premium basis on a daily
chart you can frame out what the weekly
range will be this assists you also with
one shot one kill
but more importantly it helps us frame
whether we're going to be a buyer or
seller each day as a day trader and if
that condition is really there if we
don't get the open and decline
in London that we're looking for to be a
buyer and say this rallies we don't do
anything with it or if it trades down
later in the day in NewYork we can be a
buyer in NewYork and then look for that
expansion on the upside one more bullish
so hopefully this has been in cycle T
we're going to build a lot more on this
information throughout this month and
give you a lot more details and and
processes that you go through but this
is a strong Foundation it helps fill in
a lot of gaps from my day trading and
intraday stuff and Power3 and
especially with the one shot one kill
setups that you learned  about in the
previous month in March
but
it's important that it's simply you
don't look at the opening price on
Sunday and therefore it's above or below
so I'm going to just do that no you have
to incorporate the PD arrays and again
this is the reason why it's not just
simply watch a video and do it you have
to study you have to have these things
on your chart know what they are
identify them label them on your chart
and when it's traded to you anticipate
specific things to unfold IPDA will move
from one PD array to the next from a
discount to a premium from a premium to
a discount and knowing what they are on
a daily chart will help you build and
framework for your weekly candle
forecasting it and if you're trading in
the right direction you only need really
one good day of the week think about it
if you get 30 to 50 Pips in one trading
day that is all you need but I already
know you're going to want to do more
than that but use the rules that's been
shown to you thus far this month in this
first teaching and we're going to build
on it and
our understanding about how we can
incorporate all these rules and more
rules leading to your complete day
trading system
until next lesson wish you good luck and
good Trading