foreign
folks
long time no see how's everybody doing
I'm checking Twitter
I prompted uh those that follow me on
Twitter give me a five by five if the
chart and my audio is good and the
volume is good for you let me know
as soon as I get a
5x5
from any of you I'll know I'm good to go
thank you folks thank you thank you
all right so
I may require
the
I gotta be careful it looks like the
volume is a little too loud goes into
the red so I'll have to talk like
I normally do
it should be fine anyway
now we have
a few things that we're going to cover
this morning
and if it is your first time here
watching a live stream from me uh
usually when I do a live stream I'll go
in I'll look at live PA and
depend upon how I
deliver how long ago this morning I
don't think I have a whole lot of time
for the for the teaching part of it in
the review uh it'll just depend on you
know what we do at the opening and we'll
see if we can look at some live price
action no promises but uh we'll see what
we see
it's important for you to keep up with
the ICT mentorship 2023 playlist so
anything that I've put up whether it be
a live stream like this
or another lecture I add it to the 2023
mentorship playlist on my YouTube
channel
if you're new okay and don't get this
out of the way here some short
housekeeping if you're brand new to my
channel and you want to know where to go
in and start
my advice is to go into the 2022
2022 ICT mentorship playlist it's 41
videos the the first video you really
don't really need to watch that one but
for completeness sake you know to say
you watched it the first one kind of
like sets the tone for what you're
trying to
or should be expecting
if you have never seen anything from my
content if you really don't know how to
read PA and you really just
want to get down to the Brass tax
because I am long-winded because I want
to give you value and if I'm going to
teach something I want to get
the highest form of understanding
communicated to those individuals that
want to learn if your short attention
span or if you are not really interested
in knowing everything about why you
would be incurring risk or taking on
risk
if anything less than that then you're
really setting yourself up for failure
so if a teacher or an educator is making
themselves available it's important that
their passion is behind that education
because your results
are a direct reflection on my ability to
communicate the logic and I want to
convey as much detail as possible
instead of just saying you know this is
what a Buy Signal looks like this is
what a sell system looks like and then
give you a static screenshot of this is
what it looks like all the time it
doesn't look like that all the time it's
slow there's like subtle little
variances in the way PA is
delivered and it's important for you
especially for someone that's new okay
or if you only
referred to PA through a
retail perspective and when I say that
when I say we don't trade retail or we
don't follow retail logic we're not
looking at the things that permeates
this industry which is collective in all
the books courses and regurgitated
so that's what makes my content
sometimes a little overwhelming or over
complicated because you're trying to
form fit the things that you think you
know into words I'm teaching and my
challenge has always been
don't believe what I said or say about
it go into your charts and see if what
it is I'm saying is there or not I'm
confident if you do the due diligence to
do that you will find it
okay so if you're new and you want to
like a study program I tweeted this the
other day on my Twitter account
but the best shortest cut
right to the point
pardon me
is the 2022 playlist that is a model
that I designed for my daughter
my heart went into it I wanted to make
it streamlined I wanted to present
something that was time based that way
it removes a lot of the when does it
form when would I look for a setup and I
don't know what session to trade I don't
know you know should I trade London
should I trade New York that pattern of
looking for that run on liquidity a
shift in Market structure and then going
into a FVG that can be traded
in Forex it can be traded in Futures
contracts index futures
currency Futures I have students I don't
trade crypto but I have students that
swear by their results being in crypto I
don't trade synthetic
things okay so I know I get a lot of
questions from the folks in Africa I
don't trade the volatility index okay so
I don't do anything crypto
but that model is something that you can
go right into the marketplace and start
studying and seeing it and watching
other students when they share their
examples and or results with me on
Twitter
many times you're seeing that very model
form and that model is in my opinion and
I may be incorrect in this but I'm
assuming a great deal here and give me
the Liberty to do this because I'm going
by what I'm seeing in this feedback a
lot of the funded companies
are coming forward and you know
basically stating that
majority of their profitable payouts are
coming from my student base
so that's a testimony in itself what are
they using what was the thing that
bridged that gap between not really
knowing what they're doing and going in
and finding money finding profitability
finding consistency
I believe in the ones I've interviewed
and once it's reached out to me it's the
2022 model and I have charter members
that have paid me
to learn one-on-one not in the sense
that they're sitting right next to me
but this is what I did with them every
day I would sit down I'd go through the
charts and I'd explain them what they
would expect to see in the PA
and I'm in the high 90 of accuracy and
it's been like that for years in the
witness of thousands of people now
there's hundreds of thousands of people
that are publicly
watching this stuff happen and
that model can be used on intraday
charts it could be used on higher time
frame charts and I've been beat up
lately with a lot of requests for coming
off of the lower intraday charts a lot
of you don't want to trade or can't
trade those one and five minute charts I
understand that but I also include and
as I'm including it right here
that same approach to using this shorter
time frame charts
the only reason why I'm doing that
is because it affords me lots of
examples that we can see there's there's
consistency and using the logic you can
find continuity in your analysis and
therefore results could be expected to
pretty much be you know routine or
business like you know if you go to your
job you're not changing what you're
doing every single day you're doing the
same monotonous tasks all the time and
as a Trader that's what you're trying to
do you want it to be boring and
monotonous and
the the best way I can communicate it
was that 2022 model
I couldn't make another model simpler
than that and it's working it's working
in the hands of other people and even
for people that just started following
me last year they got funded and they're
getting payouts and they're doing well
some of them are trading their actual
live money in my personal opinion when
this is my personal opinion this is not
to discourage any of you I don't think
you should be trading in your first year
there's a lot of things you'll learn
about yourself and there's a lot of
things about PA that you have
to learn as well but that can't be
appreciated
if you just go and watch a couple videos
in this thing let me see if it works
with my account and then risk real money
or risk you
not being successful with a combine or a
challenge from a funded you know prop
firm or whatever
so just go slow I promise you
the folks that are doing very well
they put a lot of work into this before
they did it and I'm talking about the
the six figure earners you know the guy
just did 300 000 in three months another
guy you know
um jade
he uh he's killing half a million
dollars okay folks this isn't Mickey
Mouse money okay that's that's real
money
it's not demo you know these guys are
killing it Paladin killing it I have
lots of other people that are getting
ready to come forward as well that are
just smashing it in their own accounts
not doing prop funded accounts
take your time
Nothing's Gonna Change okay the
algorithm is going to change they're not
going to turn around because ICT has
told too many people about it
the markets have always booked like this
and the only thing that's going to
change in the future is it's going to be
much more efficient
so it'll be less of the the choppy
consolidation because there'll be a lot
more people involved therefore the
liquidity increases
so it's not a disadvantage to you
or a reason for you to be concerned
about more people growing in our
community
using my content it's literally going to
make more liquidity for efficiency we're
not going to be the buy stock read then
reversal that's we capitalize on that
retail mindset
my approach to trading and teaching you
is that we Harvest liquidity
we hunt it it's prey retail logic things
like moving average Crossovers and
things like that there's a place for
that it does make money you can make
money flipping a quarter but
predominantly there is
a large degree of
well
neophytes that enter the marketplace and
when I first started and I promised this
at the end we're getting into the
teaching but it's important for you to
know where we're we're going where you
should be in your expectations and
learning
but retail-minded Traders think that
every single time a overbought or sold
oscillator goes oversold therefore the
market should go up and that's not true
and I I learned that lesson hard in my
first year and well first year and a
half I was insisting upon buying
oversold conditions all the time
and I didn't understand bear markets so
it can stay oversold for a long time and
you could be buying falling daggers and
it's very painful trying to catch that
and
what I have done in my career is try to
communicate things that you wouldn't
really learn from anyone else
and make it into a language that way
it's communicated
through charts when the things that make
these price moves run are not actually
in charts
and that sounds like imp like it's an
impossible thing
there are things that are occurring
outside of the kill zones I talk about
there are traits that occur
but I could never
bridge the gap between what I know about
what's going on therefore finding a
chart that is repeating all the time or
enough times to make a a setup you know
for it so the things I teach you like
specific PD arrays a multiplier when I
say when you're looking for a setup
you're looking for what is your
multiplier your multiplier is the thing
that you use to get in that's not a
model
okay it's the the multiplier that puts
you in a trade whether it be my order
block whether it be a fair value guy
inversion or standard if it's a
institutional Oracle entry drill an
optimal trade entry okay a propulsion
block
all these things are specific
multipliers the things that you're
looking for in PA I teach you
know I think it's in month four of the
core content and forgive me if I'm not
being accurate but I think I think it's
where it is month four where I go
through the pdre Matrix
those are in my opinion they're the ones
that is the easiest for me to
communicate using a time-based chart
now that I have other PD arrays that are
not requiring a chart like I don't need
a chart but that's so complicated and
some of you complain about what I've
already taught as being complicated I'm
not even going to touch that like I
don't need to have a chart I could be
driving around my Corvette know that at
this time between these three minutes I
know it's going to do this and then I
know it's going to go this and I know
that that's algorithmic
but you you're here to learn how to do
something that repeats over and over
again you can visually see that you can
trust
and that 2022 model I promise you if you
study that and spend time with it in
between your practice sessions and back
testing that means going back and
looking at chart moves that have
happened
um
it builds this experience space that you
that you require to lean on
I have had a lot of requests
for longer term swing trades so I teach
in the core content quarterly shifts
that means like every two to three
months there is a major intermediate
term
price swing that takes place on the
daily and weekly charts
that is a like a macro perspective so
when you sit down
like right now I'm sitting down for the
first time
being away from the charts for a few
days I did some day trading on Friday I
might share some of that with you when
we get into es but the
I teach
in the Twitter spaces that I do
and also in all the things that I'm
rambling about usually in these videos
or presentations
if you feel like I am not getting to the
point the point is is I'm teaching you
how you're going to have to navigate
these things
and one of the things I talk about in
the realm of psychology is if you're
under a lot of stress
not feeling well I had a loss of in your
family or whatever it's important not to
trade it's important to stay away from
the charts because you're going to be
hurting
in that pain that discomfort that
boredom can even you know spurt on
you're going to do something impulsively
so
yeah I've been going through something
emotionally with you know a pet
so I can't focus so that's why I've
spent some time away she's improving
thank you but uh
I I can't focus when it's like that and
some of you communicate that same type
of thing in other facets of your life in
Twitter you know you're going through a
breakup and you've been sick you just
got fired and then you're wondering why
you're not seeing success or consistency
in your trading because you're
emotionally charged
so even though my Concepts I believe are
superior
you as the operator me as the Opera I'm
the author of this stuff and if I am
sitting in front of the charts and I'm
in a state of mind that is unstable
I'm hurting I'm emotionally charged you
know I'm sick
or I'm fatigued if I haven't slept in
two days you know it's usually when I
need a nap and sometimes that happens a
lot so whatever those things are is
going to be for you that as a as a
barrier or a distraction
or if you feel an overwhelming desire to
want to trade because you feel like you
need something to make you feel good or
get high off of it don't don't consider
my Concepts as the Silver Bullet quote
unquote to fix that for you
because you can fail even with these
high-end High Precision elements that
I'm teaching you you as the operator
will fail yourself just like I would
have failed myself if I would have
pushed last week and did things that I
knew I wasn't going to be focusing on
it doesn't mean that the logic is flawed
it doesn't mean that your ability to
trade is expired it just means that you
are not firing on all cylinders that
means you're not focused
and you're going to be impulsive you're
going to be reactive okay we don't react
to price we anticipate it but if you go
into the charts with a need to be right
a need to feel better to feel like you
are not worthless because maybe someone
broke up with you
those things will channel into and
you'll actually see a setup
because you want it to be there versus
it being there so just be mindful that
when I'm teaching you that you have a
great deal of responsibility you have
that responsibility and your success is
solely yours but your failures you have
to own them too I don't co-sign for
either one of them
so with all that Preamble and monologue
out of the way let's get into it
I mentioned uh the last few times we
were doing market reviews and Analysis I
talked about how
the
let me go over my chart I'm talking to
you with the
YouTube Studio it's not gonna help me
there we are
so this is the dollar Index and it's
shown on a weekly chart
so
I mentioned that we would likely reach
up into and we wanted to see get up into
the halfway point of this last up close
candle prior to this rotation lower
so this upkin over here
the initial draw was that order blocks
open price
that's what's being denoted here we saw
it expand up from that it tells you that
this Gap here I wanted to see that
treated as an inversion Gap
okay or inversion fair value cap that's
what's the ifbg stands for
now this is the problem that will arise
if you're watching someone that is
trying to teach my Concepts when they're
not even fully taught yet
they would see this Gap here
and it runs up and they'll think okay
that's a short because look at these
relative equal lows down here
no
there's a logic that has to be applied
to it and a narrative
the fact that we have unfinished
business
in this order block
there is
uncertainty
there's a lot of you know
there was concern about the U.S debt
ceiling potential default
um
the the war scenario on the other side
of the world okay all these things
are causing concern and that concern is
a
Catalyst for flight to Quality
or a safe haven and at the time at the
present the dollar is still considered
that but I think it's waning nonetheless
that sense
typically the the dollar higher in
foreign currency is lower and we're
going to talk about 4x7 to work today
and not just es but uh I started with
the dollar Index because the dollar
gives me that risk on risk off scenario
now
if I believe that the dollar
is likely to go higher I need to know
where it's going to likely draw to I
just can't just indiscriminately go out
there and think well
it's going to go up let's just see where
it goes let's just find out okay that
that to me is myopic
you know you need to have a specific
level not a Zone
okay and not a not a supplier demand
Zone there's specific levels that I'm
teaching
this last up close candle
right here
has the low
the opening price and the mean threshold
which is the halfway point from high to
low
that's what those levels are the last
time we talked I said we would like to
see it get up into and I said we'll see
if it wants to get up to mean threshold
of that order block right there
nothing said we're going short on dollar
I didn't say we're shorting anything in
dollar
we were looking for lower prices on euro
dollar and we'll cover your dollar when
we get a dollar
so in fact we saw a price run up into it
last week and now here we are on the
present week
this is this present current
weekly Candlestick for the dollar Index
did this Gap over here act as support
yes
intra week it did it on this week but
then last week it did it as well traded
down into it and now we're trading here
so
when we when we get a LTF
daily chart this will be more impactful
too but uh whenever I give analysis out
whether it be through a tweet or in
video
invariably there's this sect of my
followers that will say Okay now what's
going to happen
when you should be thinking about what
you just watched and have you broke it
down yourself have you
spent any time in the LTFs
individual sessions individual days over
the scope of each individual weekly
candle and see where the setups form
with the 2022 model
because that's what you're supposed to
be doing
if you're just waiting for me to put up
a new video or talk about something on
Twitter you're really doing yourself a
disservice because
a lot of the work 90 of the work for you
succeeding is done by you it isn't just
by listening to me because if it was
that easy everybody that watches my
videos would be funded making money and
quitting their job and be rich and
where's all the odds right
they don't do the work and that's why
it's offensive sometimes when I tell
people you're not putting in the work
because what you think the work is
is many times insignificant it's not
enough
and you have to put real time into it
and what you're doing in that time is
spending it in Old moves
using the logic and the experience I've
shared I told you that I was wanting the
dollar to go higher that was go back and
listen to the commentaries it's there
it's not ambiguous
but because I State my opinion there's a
lot more of you publicly that are
following me you sometimes are weighted
on baited breath just to hear me say
something and you take that and you go
out there and you bet real money with it
and that's why I said don't bet the
farmer I'm constantly reminding you
there's risk if you don't know what
you're doing don't be deceived in
thinking you think you know what you're
doing simply because you watched a few
of my videos
it takes time to learn this and you have
to give yourself the time and patience
that's needed to do it
so we did in fact see the inversion fair
value Gap form here and we're rotated up
into
daily bearish order block this right
here will be much more
easier to see and understand now let me
go into a daily chart
[Music]
okay so here's that daily candle so it
looks just like that Weekly candle we've
got this big old runoff here like that
it does not folks listen okay
it does not need to be an engulfing
candle that does not make an order block
okay so many people out there typing
that stuff up in pseudo mentorships
things and like that's not that's not my
order block okay
the idea of
the market rotating after hitting a key
level
you take it right to the last candle
that candle does not need to be
engulfing anything
that narrative that's the thing that's
missing from these 20 year olds that run
around thinking they know how to do this
stuff and I'm talking to you because I
know you're listening okay I'm telling
you these things so that way you can
improve and not hurt the people that
you're trying to fleece
and being more responsible with your
students than you are so here's the
bearish order block the opening price
now why am I using the opening price
versus the low Whenever there is a
short little stubby tail or Wick okay
whenever it's like that I generally as a
rule of thumb but not always but
generally most of the time I'm going to
go right to the opening price and the
reason why I'm doing that okay and this
is where you write things down folks
this small little
tail on the candle
I know that there's probably something
in that LTF that I'll be
able to use even if it wants to go
outside the realm of the opening price
so I may be able to look at something
that may or may not be supportive for a
trade
in that range but
for a anchoring on a HTF
basis
I'm anchoring it to the opening price
now let's assume for a moment that it
was a longer
tail in other words this little segment
down here on the candle say that was
longer and the opening was actually
something or somewhere up here
then I would use the low
and I would use the consequent
encouragement of that tail or halfway
point of that little Wick
so those are the two key levels I'll use
for a Candlestick that has a longer Wick
okay so there's a little bit more
insight about water blocks
and I'm telling you why I'm using the
opening price versus the lower high so
I had that in your notes and go through
your studies and you'll see that that's
a very good general rule to help you
okay there will be instances where it
does other things okay but I'm not done
teaching but just grow and what I'm
tearing what I'm sharing to him giving
it to you
so we have the weekly order block we
traded out in through it hit the daily
bearish order block we traded up into
that now look at the bodies of these
candles
weekly order block
daily order block look at all that
encapsulation and PA the
volume
of all that Trading
the majority of it's being shown in the
Candlestick bodies yes it expanded as we
would like to see anyway we're expecting
a new higher it went above these levels
we don't expect it to stop dead in its
tracks when we're bullish we really want
to see it go to it and through it
because the narrative the expectation we
had was that dollar should go higher
and notice that all of the
sustained price runs was on the buy side
delivery that means candlesticks that
are going up
infrequent were the down closed candles
these are daily candlesticks by the way
but look how it opened here
traded away from it
opened right up here and then traded
down
we expanded through and fell short of
the mean threshold of the weekly order
block and it's important that you
annotate your levels
now I'm showing you how I do this here
and some of you ask all the time how am
I doing that
[Music]
on trading view this is what I have set
up as middle
Center for it to appear here and when
I'm doing the new week opening gaps
it would just show on the right so it
shows over here
and you'll see the new week opening Gap
when we get into ES
so we're seeing it dig into these levels
expanding up reaching reaching reaching
and then finally once it pierced the
mean threshold the weekly order block at
104.540
then we had a rotation lower
where'd it go back to
that Weekly inversion Gap the fair rate
Gap that we anticipated seeing act as
what support folks that's narrative
that's not picking both sides of the
marketplace if I'm telling you a
specific PD array
that level
on that PD array if it's a range
like a fair value got it's the high
consequent encroaching which is the
midpoint
and then the low of it that's not a Zone
where you am it's ambiguous like where
do you trade a supply and demand Zone
okay that's why I'm not supplying demand
and I also cut through candles supply
and demand would not use this level over
here
based on anything like that because they
say don't we don't cut through candles
they need a fresh Zone everything from
ICT is fresh baby everything there's
nothing stale here we always have fresh
bread and my students are always making
fresh bread they do it on their own they
don't ever run out of yeast just like
this meant they're talking to you I
don't ever run out of yeast you're never
going to run out of opportunities it's
never going to happen there's no reason
for you to rush it because once you get
it nobody can take it from you nobody
can say you can't do it because they
don't like you they don't like your
personality whatever you can find these
setups once you have the understanding
you can go into any Market any time
frame and murder it
literally murder it
but you're trying to be too quick to
assume that everything that you already
know
will complement what I'm teaching you no
no no no no no no no
what I'm teaching you will make the
stuff you tried to be profitable with
profitable if you Inc if you include the
things I'm teaching how to reprice the
DOL that's the first
lesson the first lesson I start to drive
home in a student's mind is where's the
price trying to gravitate to where is it
trying to get to well initially I
started with the order block weekly then
the daily and the mean threshold of that
Weekly order block does your chart show
this because you're looking at a live
chart right now with me in the live
stream
did it pan out like I showed absolutely
it did
the same direction I was looking for
everything I was looking for in terms of
the specific levels I gave you the logic
I talked about it beforehand it's here
now
so it wasn't done with a one minute
chart it wasn't traded or worked with in
a second chart sub one minute time frame
it wasn't even an hourly chart I used
weekly charts
it works folks you can make this work
for you where you are at in your life
School business job your relationship
causes constraints that you can't do the
intraday charts I get it but don't think
that it's a one-trick pony that only
works on a one-minute chart there's a
lot of one minute setups that allow me
to teach you that there's no short
supply of setups
you will always find setups
but there's going to be times when the
market will be
well look at all this mess in here I
don't like these types of periods I
don't like that and that's why you see
me do what I took time away I did road
trips
now looking at the PA in
hindsight that makes perfect sense to
you while I was doing what I was doing
right but at the time you're thinking oh
they changed the algorithm ict's On The
Run
no I'm relaxing because I know that all
I need to do is see a shift in Market
structure what was that
see this high
it breaks it what does it leave Fair
there you go
see that
now
we're going to talk about gaps today my
personal private students and the public
students all of you could probably
majority of you here
um
are constantly asking this question you
can you talk about the Breakaway gaps
can you talk about when FVGs
should not fill I'm going to teach you
about that today okay so
if we're looking for
a DOL
and we are in this vicinity right here
the first thing we want to draw our
attention to was this imbalance here
that shaded area now what I'm showing to
you on the daily chart and that's the
time frame this is being shown in right
now for the dollar Index I promise you
all of this works in
es it works in Forex because I'm
starting the whole presentation this is
going to be 4X in the beginning and then
I'll end the discussion and in today's
live stream on the index features
but everything I'm teaching you here is
applicable to Forex and Futures and
commodities and gold
and bonds we're going to talk about
bonds today too okay but all of this
HTF gives you in my
opinion you're welcome to disagree
you're never going to convince me
otherwise but the HTFs is
where the majority of your time should
be spent
because it's so easy to get lost on
these LTF charts especially
if you're new because you'll think you
see all kinds of stuff you know the
Three Stooges pattern you know there
isn't one that I'm just making a joke
about how everything can be applied to
any time frame if you wanted to be there
you'll see it it's like a mirage
you're thirsty you want to get that uh
that new drink of uh success
and just like sometimes in a desert
you'll think you see something out there
it looks like water and you get up on it
it's just more sand
and you don't want to fill your well
with sand by chasing setups that are not
there they're Phantoms
HTF removes most of that
not all of it removes most of it so
let's let's talk about and again I'm
gonna before I get into any discussion I
want to take you back to the weekly
chart and show you what this is again
this shaded area
right here
real quickly
I like to be complete folks I don't like
to leave
anything up for
debate
that little section between this candle
here that low
and this candles hi and the reason why
I'm drawing attention to that is let me
take this away just for a second
can you see how this candle dropped
stopped the next candle here opened
traded down all the way here and came
back and stopped the next week it opened
traded up a little bit but didn't come
back all the way to that candle's load
see that
so there's this distinct Gap separation
between those two key levels there and
then we expand lower
we open trade up leaving this little
portion of PA between these
candles low and this candle is high
remained open
okay so it's only dropped down so that's
sell side delivery what is it
inefficient
by side so it's a city sell side
inefficiency buy side
oh I said that wrong sell side imbalance
beside and efficiency City
that little distinct Gap there
stands out if we're standing over here
on the the right of all this price
action look how fortified all these back
and forth movements are here
all these candles moving back between
over and over again inside of this range
here
you see how that is back and forth back
and forth back and forth back and forth
that is not inefficient at all
that's a lot of back and forth delivery
in other words think of the analogy how
many times you use like a paint being
applied with a roller on a wall
in this area paint has been distributed
back and forth in in paint and this
analogy would be price so the range of
offering liquidity up and down in that
shaded area
there's no inefficiency whatsoever on
this time frame so where does the
inefficiency exist
thank you
right there
it only has one roll down
never up until we get over here
Okay so
that FVG there was the draw
up and the context was I want to see it
trade up through it and come down and
act as support
and that would make it an inversion for
your value guy
if I didn't hold that expectation
it would be treated as a standard fair
value Gap in a premium relative to the
high
in the low here
that would be a premium Fair Vega and
the way you know that is you take the
FIB
anchored on high
down to the low here's equilibrium and
the FVG exists right there at
equilibrium or above is premium at
equilibrium or below is discount
but I did not say we're looking for
lower prices when it got to this fair
value Gap I said we want to see it go to
it throw it and come back down and treat
it as support that's an inversion fair
value
don't take my word for it here go back
and look at the other reviews that I've
showed here go and look at the tweets
listen to the Twitter spaces sometimes I
cuss there just be mindful that you know
it's live here I try to
I tend to do the better job because I'm
looking at candlesticks but if I don't
have a Candlestick chart in front of me
on Twitter spaces I generally use blue
collar language and my imbalance is
inside me just make me not the best
Mentor for that
but that little Gap here is this segment
when we go down to LTF
daily chart
now you know what you're looking at
all right there see it doesn't look like
a gap here because look what it's done
it passes back and forth back and forth
okay do not assume this is really
important do not assume
that a inefficiency whether it be a fair
value Gap
that's
a bicycle sound efficiency or a sell
signing balance biasound efficiency
either or
don't assume if it's on the daily chart
that if you see on
or a weekly chart rather don't think
that we see these back and forth moves
on a daily chart that now makes this a
balanced price range it doesn't
because on the weekly time frame it's
inefficient still
the HTFs have to have
bodies hit the floor
that means it's got to cover that Gap
even though these individual daily
candles have worked inside that range
that's not you're seeing the formation
of that Weekly FVG with all
of this in here
on the daily chart it's
it's something you have to study on your
own
working a HTF down to
LTF the HTFs
are apparent
the LTFs are subordinate
they're only going to behave in a manner
that allows
certain price delivery within the
context and constructs of a higher time
frame imbalance or liquidity pool that's
it that's the the
Continuum what you're looking for Market
has to go up to a premium
for what
only two reasons it's going up to take
the buy stops
or it's going up to some inefficiency
some Gap
markets only go down
to go to an inefficiency a fair value
Gap below current market price or it's
going down for sell stops I do not care
this is no disrespect to anybody else
out there that teaches and made money I
don't give a flip
the markets don't go up and down because
your indicator said so the market
doesn't go up and down because there's
momentum of buying and selling pressure
that's not what that is not what is
going on here okay it's never been that
way but we have been LED down the
Primrose Lane with books authors
teachers whatever
saying that it's buying and selling
pressure
it's not
these markets are absolutely controlled
period
if we can see
the likelihood of PA wanting
to at least get up to this level here
why did I use that fair value yet
remember I'm painting why I said this
was something important why did I pick
that Weekly fair value you got and why
did I want to see it trade through it
and become support because it's at a
level that on a simple run of the daily
chart using this dealing range this low
to that high remember I had to fit back
to it
folks this is real learning this is the
point okay the point is you want to know
what you're doing if you want to go out
there and gamble your money go watch
somebody else okay you're you're welcome
to do that but if you want to learn and
you want to learn correctly and you're
at the right place
that FIB at 50 is halfway or equilibrium
relative to this high
in this low
so if I'm waiting to see price to try to
gravitate to here
I want to see does it perform what I
would really rather see happen I don't
want to see it go up there and then
sharply break lower because if it does
that then I got to drop down to a lower
time frame and look for a FVG
or something else on a short-term
premium to sell short pieces that would
likely run into these relative equal
lows but my experience in 30 years told
me
it told me that all the factors that's
going on right now in the world
geopolitically
you know all the turmoil all the things
that's going on the economy all that
stuff is it calls for uncertainty
and because of that I want to see yes my
PD array is going to be a draw on
liquidity it's going to draw up to that
Weekly fair value guy but I already
already announced to you that I'm going
to see this do something other than just
go up into it and treat it as an area to
sell sore from I want to see it go
through it does it do so yeah look where
it closed
above it I did this stuff real time in
live streams where I taught you how to
discard or disqualify a fair value guy
so that way it looks like cherry picking
because I'm showing you examples and a
lot of people that hate me are trolls
and people can't keep up with me
they'll insist that it's cherry-picked
but they have they don't know the logic
and if they would just simply like
listen to me now I'm telling you what
I'm doing
so that way you can go back and look at
the things I've shared say oh oh yeah
there is there it is right I'm not
pulling things out of thin air I'm
pulling it from 30 years of experience I author these things
so I'm sharing that language so that way you can learn how to do it so this FVG was the initial DOL
when we shifted Above This High here
that candle right there that runs above
that short-term High
that's a shift in Market structure now
Market is in a buy program
a buy program is
is now when you start looking for premium arrays
where do you look for those premium arrays?
well what is the dealing range
that is this high to that low
we're only interested in premium
so we don't look at this short term High as a turtle soup run above and go dollar
we don't look at this High here as I run above that internal suit and go short lower
no we're looking for the first first equilibrium or higher PD array
we started on a HTF
you want to you want to do a top-down analysis
because large institutions, big funds are going to be using HTF charts
so we're going to cannibalize
their long-term models their long-term
model
through here was bearish
so we're looking inside the scope of
this High to that low right there
midpoint is here
that shaded area in Orange I'm assuming
it's a hue of orange but that shaded
area that's the weekly inversion fair
value that's the first level of my
interest
okay
so this specific weekly point of
Interest I gave you the context as to
what I want to see with it it wants to
go higher great
I need to see something specific I want
to see it trade to it and through it
we've seen it close right there
if a market closes above a FVG that you think should be bearish
that's not a good shorting opportunity
many times it's communicating to you that it will become an inversion FVG
oh there you go the penny just dropped I
just gave you something again but if
you're not listening
okay if you're not you're trying to
filter out the buy and sell signals then
you you think I'm teaching you in Morse
code
I'm teaching you specifics in detail I'm
this is the point you want to be trading
with Precision you want to read the
charts without me and nobody else
helping you it'd be independently
wealthy all these things have to have a
lot of understanding and logic so that
way you know you can trust it it's not
changing and morphing all the time the
rules aren't changing the goal post is
not being moved you know that these
logic or this logic
is sound you've seen it many times
before and you can trust it so that way
when you go forward and you're in
forward testing and then before
a combine challenge or if you're trading
with your own account
you'll trust it
you won't be nervous it's the same type
of thing like when you go to work you
know the different routes that you can
take to get to work
is the map changing sometimes there's a
detour that's required there's
construction well guess what sometimes
the market will do a little hiccup and
and you didn't see a specific time frame
do something and it might stop you out
okay recalibrate like a GPS
yeah what's that what does it do it
reroutes you as long as this objective
of the weekly order block which was the
draw in liquidity
this was the
multiplier
the inversion pair value got
so I wanted to see does it get to and
through it yes does it treat it as
support in the LTFs it does
and then trades out to that Weekly order
block daily order block and the last
level you heard about was we want to see
if it wants to get up to that 104.54
which is the weekly
bearish order block mean threshold
now that's a lot of stuff
there's no way I could say that in less
time and teach you what I just talked
about what was going through my mind why
did I talk about that level right there
that's the shortest absolute shortest
way around getting between point a and
point B to the point that was the logic
that I used
think about how you could have said it
with less words
and make it make sense you can't so stop
okay stop expecting something to be
condensed when this is condensed
but it's specific so that way you
understand the match behind it so let's
go into
grading a price swing
so we have these levels here the first
one I drew your attention to was that
Weekly worldwide now
I could have very easily laid all these
out here
in advance and said watch all three of
these get hit
but you're learning
your understanding is a graduated
experience and
charter members could go right into this
and see it right away you know people
have been with me for a very very long
time
if you're new or relatively new
if I lay this level here
and what I'm about to say is not to be
construed as talking down to individuals
okay I'm just reminding you where you're
making the mistakes you are I'm not
making the mistakes I'm telling you to
be careful
but if I say I like this level here
and you foolishly go out there and you
try to trade with your money or risk
your funded account on it or try to do a
combine challenge
and insist because ICT said it's going
to go up here between this point here
and this point down here
there's lots of room for air
if you don't have a lot of experience or
don't know what you don't or you're
impulsive
and you chase price even if you do use a
stop loss you'll get caught up in these
retracements that you won't expect or
anticipate
and you'll walk away thinking this stuff
doesn't work
and then now here we are it goes right
to the levels that I've talked about so
between these two price points with this
shift in Market structure here
running up into that Weekly bearish
order block mean threshold again this
level here
right there let me take the FIB off
because there's more lines on there that
I want to show you
that level here is not anything in this
fractal of any importance it's the
weekly chart
it's this one here
the mean threshold this is the halfway
point of this candle and that's done by
like this you take the FIB
drop it on the low to the high bam right
there 104.540
that's why that level's there it's half
of that
now let's drop back down into the daily
so we had a market structure shift here
and right away we have this fair value
guy
now watch folks this is not quarters
Theory okay because you're going to hear
somebody come out and say oh he's
teaching Quarters here I was doing this
stuff before quarter stories we'll even
talk about
this this is what grading a price swing
allows you you have to know what where's
the DOL
where is the terminus the end of the
line where do you think price is going
to go it doesn't mean that's where it
stops ultimately in reverses where do
you see your setup form where's the
framework where is the dealing range
that you're going to work within that
dealing range is
always in the past high to low we frame
the equilibrium price point here and
we're aiming for a premium why do we
want to see that because we want to see
it trade into this FVG and
above it which would nullify it would
remove any need to anticipate lower
prices on dollar
it's signaling to you algorithmically
that it is not going to go lower it in
fact wants to go higher
so if we can do that
and we see it does it closes here
that really increases the opportunity
for this FVG to be inversion
for Vega that means it's going to act as
a
resistance broken turn support to use
retail minded logic but this would never
be construed as that because it doesn't
fit any of the type of thing that you
would expect with retail support
resistance
nor does it meet the criteria for
supplying demand
before
you go out there and you wreck yourself
in your live trading or whatever it's
important to know these types of rules
because if you are slow in making money
and fast in trying to preserve or keep
it those two
modes of thought or
conducting you know a daily routine move
very very slow when you're trying to
make money because there's lots of
opportunities to do that every single
day there is
every single week every single day every
single session there's something that
you can capitalize on
every single day
and in fact
specific hours of the day
you can trade one hour candles
and treat it just like this whole idea
that I've shown here on the basis of
that Weekly Candlestick all this stuff
is applicable inside of a 60 Minute
candle
it all exists there
it's a it's a tiny little you Universe
within that one time frame
you can break these things down smaller
and smaller and smaller
but you don't have the experience yet
and you have to give yourself the time
to acquire that experience and once you
have it then it gives you confidence and
you got to be very very careful once you
get that confidence if you know what
you're doing it doesn't evolve into
egomaniac
attention okay I was always that
when I was in 20. in my 20s I this kind
of stuff made me feel Superior to
everybody and I communicated that always
and I don't even know my stuff is
superior I don't view myself in a manner
where I have to go out there and stay
and prove it I don't have to do that
anymore
I have students now that are doing it
this price range
okay
that I'm looking forward to if we get
this shift in Market Circle I'm sorry
shift in Market structure here on this
candle here
that that moment we have entered a buy
program
so we have to go back into this range
and anchor it to
where we anticipate price going
that DOL the initial one
was here
this one I I don't believe I mentioned
it
but I'm gonna say I didn't but you can
see clearly it's anchored on the daily
chart but I did tell you this one here
this is where we want to see if it wants
to get up into that
so all of this run here
we could be sitting still anticipating
not reacting anticipating a run above
that short-term High here why am I
talking about this high man he finally
talked about it he's finally saying it
I've been screaming at this monitor
Michael why are you wanting this High
why don't you use this High why don't
you use that high why not that high
low lower low lower low
okay
we consolidate all through April and May
I'm Audi see ya I want the market to
show me something
so when I was down in Florida when I was
cruising around in my RV and I don't
live in an RV
Cooper
I want to see it move out of this range
okay
let's just for a moment let's ring in
the bond market okay if you are on
Twitter I believe it was Twitter
if it wasn't Twitter
either I did a video short little video
commentary on Twitter or it was
mentioned somewhere in my commentary on
the YouTube channel but I know I talked
about it
and you'll see the chart right away and
remember those that have watched it
but during this consolidation in here I
want to see it
perform a specific way I want to see it
show me something all through here I
wanted to see the dollar go lower I
expected it to take out that low
but because it was showing unwillingness
to perform or show any willingness to go
lower
how did I how do I get to the point
where I didn't trust it
talk about how when we don't want to
take a trade when there's something in
the PA that says don't do
anything okay let's do that right now
here we have this love right there
see that little Pierce below it right
there a little tiny little short move
below that low
right there
it can and it could have very easily
traded back up to this level and then
resumed
if it would have done that then a dollar
really would have embarrassed longer
term
but because it consolidated
I want to see does it
have confirmation through the bond
market
all this consolidation is going to be
shown in the bond market I want to go to
the daily chart for
zbm2023 which is a symbol that's used
for bonds
uh it's not the month that you should be
trading or tracking it now uh its volume
has rotated into the September contract
but I'll I'll show you what I mean in a
second
to understand how the dollar is likely
to perform
I use the bond market
okay and right away some of you that
just want to have one market you want it
to be real simple and short and sweet
this is where most of you drop off
because you know you're like oh this is
complicated that's how you feel folks
don't watch my videos okay I promise you
you'll do something
either be successful at what you're
doing or you'll hurt yourself and you'll
come back here and you'll learn how the
markets really work but this
consolidation in here
I want to see does it perform
in a mirror image of what the bond
market is doing the bond market
zbm2023 was in a Range okay and I want
to see it go down into a discount if the
buy Market goes down on a discount that
would result in the dollar Index moving
into a premium
here's that range
okay we were in this range and until
this range was given up until it left
this range dollar wasn't doing anything
equities we're going to range mount
that's why I stayed out taking RV road
trips
I don't care about the PA when
it's in here like this can I trade that
absolutely can you trade it absolutely
but to meet a expectation in the
community that's been craving higher
time frame charts swing trading ideas
can you do something off the women in
charts I don't know why he's always
talking about the one minute charts the
answer the reason why is because it
gives me lots of teaching examples where
I can call it before it happens and it
pans out precisely and that is where you
should study
whether you trade them or not you should
study those LTFs because
you're getting so much experience by
using LTF charts because
it's not noise like the Goldman Sachs
boys will tell you
there's absolutely a rhyming reason why
prices listen
is it a different price
okay is it a different price if you're
looking at the bond market Bitcoin
um
gold whatever it is whatever asset
you're looking at is price booking at a
market price differently
if you're looking at it on a daily chart
or a one minute chart
if you were looking at right now if
you're looking at the bond market right
here
this is this is live
it's not delayed data
right now the price is showing at 127
and 12 30 seconds
that's what it's showing right now if I
drop down into a one minute chart
look at that
holy crow it's the same price
so don't listen to these goobers that'll
tell you you know there's noise on the
LTFs you're looking at the
same price
price is doing the same thing
in all time frames but the narrative as
to what it's going to do next hello
is going to be derived from what time
frame you're using right now
in layman's terms I'll say it like this
it's going to behave in a manner that
the HTF outlines this is
right now this is PA
on the June contract for bonds as you
can see it's real spotty okay if you use
ZB I'll come back to the daily chart in
a second I just want to make a point
okay that's the symbol that's being
shown right here
zbm2023 the m is the Futures Contract
month
code for June all the volume
is rotated into now the September
contract so that is going to be the U
symbol watch how all these little dots
become much more
smoother see that that tells you
that all the volume and open interest is
now rotated early
in the bond market s p
the June contract is still favored but
it will be changing here shortly
now let's go back out to a daily chart
for bonds and I'll tell you what I was
doing and what I was thinking
and I gotta go to the June contract
because that's what was being traded in
April and May
okay so here is the business on the
bonds we're in this range I wanted to
see this break that range
oh he's a breakout artist I knew it ICT
is a breakout artist he's a break and
retest guy no not
no I'm not I want to see it leave this
this is Market profile notice there is
no volume bars to the right of my chart
okay I I don't use that stuff that to me
is Mickey Mouse stuff if you make money
with it God bless you okay God bless you
run with that idea that's not what makes
markets go up and down though
market profiles to me is a schematic
it's a a behavior a graph now if you go
into my core content on my YouTube
channel which was premium content people
had paid money for that
those lessons are the language that my
students had to understand when I was
doing you know live educations and
Analysis every day every single day I
was doing analysis and I was on the spot
every single day
calling every single day what it should
perform where was this bad this mad rush
of people coming out and saying ICT is a
fraud he can't do this stuff I'm paying
him he didn't call that right it never
happened
if anybody's gonna expose me it would
have been those individuals that paid me
you're seeing the testimony again it's
happening in front of you I'm teaching
you the logic
you're getting it right from the source
I needed this range here to leave
I didn't care if it was going to go
higher or lower because I didn't know at
the time which one to trust because
remember on The Daily dollar Index I
wanted to see that low taken out that's
what I wanted but I had to submit myself
to what price was showing me it was not
willing to go there yet so I had to take
a step back and wait
wait a minute man you're supposed to be
I have 30 years experience right that 30
years experience gave me the insights to
say sit still bro
sit down this dance ain't for you sit
down wait
let the elephant enter that swimming
pool think about a children's swimming
pool okay A little tiny little swimming
pool if they swimming pool the size of a
child use
if you filled it up with water and an
elephant came over and sat down in it
what would happen to the water
it would be displaced right it would it
would leave the pool
being replaced with the the mass of that
elephant smart money
is like that
in this range here
right here when we saw it close right
there outside that range
that sets the stage for
up move in dollar
but I have to wait I have to wait for
something this is Wednesday May 17th
let's go back over to the dollar Index
I know I should have I should have
charged you money for this
all right so here is May 17 3 there
okay
lo and behold that's the day that the
dollar Index is trading inside of its
FVG right there after post
the shift in Market structure so this
High broke to the upside how can we
qualify that as a shift in Market
structure for the dollar to keep going
higher I just taught you are we seeing a
mirror image that would constitute a
expectation for the bond market to enter
a sell program it means bonds going down
dollar going up
we're in a consolidation we're in
uncertainty here so I have to wait when
this happened okay all focus goes to the
sphere Vega
but now I don't want to see it go up
here to go short why
all this stuff that's happening in
the other side of the world I'm trying
not to use words that'll flag my channel
because I've had friends that are not
even
you know technical traders or dealing
with the markets and they talked about
these topics and they they lose their
channel so I'm not going there
but just think geopolitical
w-a-r all those things all that
uncertainty the debt ceiling the
potential default all that stuff was a
catalyst
from a macro perspective
which is why I didn't believe that that
FVG would be a short now if
it would have went up there and started
to sell off like I said I would use a
LTF four hour one hour
chart
short of you know a premium like that
and get in sync and then run for these
lows here but the context that I went
into and I shared with you was I wanted
to see that Weekly FVG trade
above it and come down and treat it as
support look this is the daily chart for
the dollar Index look where the bodies
on the lower end of that Gap look where
the bodies were
was that not respecting that Weekly Gap
that's not supplying demand that's not
support resistance this is algorithmic
It's referring back to a level I drew
your attention to beforehand
now how can I do that I'm not a time
traveler
there's logic there that means there's
something going on in price delivery
that is well beyond buy and selling
pressure it's rigged
and there shouldn't be any reason for
you to be upset about that it shouldn't
scare you you should be thankful
you should be thankful that they rigged
these markets because that presents the
opportunity that as long as you're in
sync with what it's likely to do next
well guess what
there's a 90 likelihood that new Traders
will lose their money in the first 90
days or less
that's a statistic but on the other side
of their trades there are people
with lots of experience that know what
they're doing they're the winner of
those losing trades that the losing
crowd loses to
there's a buyer and seller for every
trade it's a net sum zero game but the
game is rigged
there's no reason for you to be mad
about it start punching the air that's
the reason why that broker did it to me
the broker didn't do anything to you
unless you're trading Forex because they
they have individual liquidity pools
when you're trading futures
you're all getting the same price
that's the that's the it's a gentleman's
Market okay if you want to be a Savage
you trade Forex and when it's wild it
moves around that's why I left Futures
because you know in the 2000s it was why
we have really big wide price ranges and
300 range days on the on the regular
well that dried up
and the market started getting real
Consolidated so I went back to what I
started with which is index futures
I don't care if the s p trades with a
five handle day
and I said that correctly I don't care
if the s p traded a five handle day
folks that's exactly what we were
looking at in the 90s
that that type of stuff in the in the
early 80s and such those days that was
like the normal
you didn't have this wild crazy
volatility it's great don't get me wrong
but if things got so slow and down to a
snails crawl in Pace
that's okay
you can still do all those things and
there's very small little ranges it'll
just look like
what the charts look like now but the
amount of movement will be much much
more
condensed
and a lot of you aren't even prepared to
trade in a market like that because
you're so used and you're baptized in
all this High volatility
when Forex shrank up
and all the pairs had smaller ranges
social media it was constant bellyaching
oh man when's the big days coming
Wednesday but it's moving folks if you
can get 10 handles or 10 Pips from a
price swing that's good
what's wrong with that what's wrong with
if if you just got five Pips
who cares that the range is really small
but you have to have your expectation
calibrated to what the market profile is
right now that means we're in
consolidation I need to see what I need
to see bonds leave because bonds will
qualify whatever the dollar is going to
do I'm gonna do a mirror image of it
so bonds broke lower
that means this is qualified as a break
in Market structure and it shifted
higher
fair value guy right there let's play
Devil's Advocate and say for a moment
because this is a daily chart and this
is the dollar Index by the way so if
you're a Forex Trader this is the gold
mine that you want to be in okay this is
where you want to be mining these things
from ICT the things that you think is
boring other people say it's
this is the stuff that makes you wealthy
this is the stuff that finds constant
consistency and continuity in trading
longevity you want to be around for a
little while longer than a couple months
hopefully
it's this Insight this is the stuff that
gets you there
let's say that you saw this happen after
the fact you were working you were
sleeping you have a business you're
running
just couldn't be in front of the charts
and you saw afterwards the day closes
like this
the very next day folks
the very next day what do you think the
bias should be for your analysis
bullish
reaching for what that fair value guy so
between
the 17th
of May
until we got to the first objective
which is that Weekly order block here on
this debt here so from the 17th of May
to the 24th of May
that run
here
to here
that right there is a sell program in
Euro that means selling short that means
every day you're going in with a bias to
go long in Euro it's also a bias to go
long in pound dollar it's also a long or
buy program for Aussie dollar it's also
a long for New Zealand versus the US
dollar it is a short
oh
I just said that wrong you like that I
made a mistake there this is where I
wish I could go I can edit it
the Dollar's going higher so it's a
short in euro dollar short in pound
dollar short and Aussie dollar short in
New Zealand dollar because the dollar
going higher okay it would be a long in
dollar yen
it would be a long in dollar Swiss okay
because we're looking at this is the
dollar Index so if it's going higher
that range between here
by this date it's after the fair buy you
got right here let me put it in the
chart
yes my obsessive compulsive is flaring
right now
I'm sorry it just shows you I'm not AI
I'm a mistake all right let's see extend
right take that off
okay so there's your favorite Gap so
after that forms the next day here until
it gets to your premium array where's
the DOL
weekly order block what's the multiplier
if you're a swing Trader
it needs to find support here so that
sets the stage for your swing trade but
as a day trader you don't need that
you're in there before that which is why
I don't do swing trades I'm using the
information I'm showing you here between
this here the very next day and I
apologize if you hear my stomach because
I'm fasting right now the idea of
expecting higher prices on dollar Index
every day until it gets this objective
first here that sets the tone for a bias
that gives you your bias because that
bias is derived from the narrative
that's being shown with HTF weekly and daily charts
also inter-market relationships the bond market versus the dollar Index
and Market profiling
so we are in a consolidation we have a shift in Market
structure how do we qualify that
the range that I told you the bonds were
in I said why is the market
consolidating go back and look at
Twitter
I tweeted it
it's there the bonds are in a Range
until the bonds leave that range all
markets will be in consolidation
because interest rates what makes the
world go round
and then after that that narrative is
set
then we can have a bias
so the bias is bullish here for dollars
bullish here it's even bullish on this
day but not in the scheme that we would
expect it to open and then buy it and go
up we're in that range now that fair
value Gap so what we would expect is to
consolidate or retrace and does it
support the low end of that range and
look at the body showing you that that's
a signature that's algorithmic so
as a swing Trader
you could use this day here as an entry
and then pyramid in here
for a run into that
using that implied dealing range an
implied dealing range
is not a dealing range like this whereas
we have a real
High and a real low those are actual
we're looking for a price run from this
low up to this order block on the weekly
chart
until it does that that's an implied
dealing range we don't know if it's
going there anything can happen a bomb
could drop somewhere you know oh you
know some kind of a hack that hits the
markets I expect that's going to be used
in the future by the way but that run
here that is a implied dealing range it
has not really manifest yet but we're
seeing
with anticipation that that's where the
draw in liquidity is the initial one was
here so now let's go and add our fib
to this low I know this stuff is amazing
and I could talk about this stuff all
day long
all right so
right there
from this low
to that high
which is the weekly order block what I'm
showing you there is the range okay it's
an implied dealing range
if we have that
look at the levels I have here
50 which is equilibrium and 25 and then
here's the high the high of the run
which is Terminus at the end of the run
if you're going to use this as you're
dealing not not the only range if you're
implied dealing range it's where you
think it's going to go so before the
candlesticks even form
before they even form folks you could
have this in your chart like this
it would look like this right here
okay say it's Meandering around like
this in consolidation and you you start
doing your analysis you think okay what
happens if we were to break lower in the
pound I'm sorry if we were to break
lower in the bond market
then that would give rise to the dollar
Index
hi
low is your dealing range
weekly FVG okay that sets the
stage for if we're going to go higher
I'd like to see us remove this bearish
you know stance that I hold on dollar
during this time period if it goes to
here and goes above it and three says
support I'm not bearish on dollar
go back and listen to my reviews it's
there I didn't it wasn't word salad it
was very specific
but because we have this range here
we can take the low up to that Weekly
order block
let me take the FIB off and show you
what you're doing this is what you could
do here
I know some of you are brand new or much
it's the first time you've seen this oh
this is hindsight
go back and look at the reviews folks I
was talking about all this stuff before
it happened I didn't give you this much
of a breakdown but I'm teaching you how
to create a price swing how to
anticipate where the next setups are
going to form before they ever come into
the chart
forget supply and demand supply and
demand requires the candlesticks or
ranges to be in the chart I'm going to
teach you where they will form before
they will form where do setups form show
me how to buy and sell Michael where are
these PD arrays that work how does it
look in the chart before it gets there
what should I anticipate how do I how
can I trust this though
okay let's do some time travel
low to high that's terminus we have 25
percent
50 and 75 of the range we require bonds
to do one or the other go up or go down
and leave that range I showed you on its
daily chart
it broke lower not yet
but now we have a
let go of that Michael good grief we
have a shift in Market structure right
there well in the bond market we
qualified it with it going lower it left
its range going lower
that's going to give
momentum to the upside on longs
not that that's driving price but that's
setting your mindset in motion for it
we're in a buy program for dollar
so
right away we can anticipate somewhere
in here in this area there's going to be
some kind of accumulation
we consolidate here and then we run
what does that make that right there
that's a fair bag out right
yeah it's a fair value guy
more specifically it's a breakaway Gap
what is it breaking away from it's
breaking away from this consolidation
it has a shift in Market structure so
this is your Gap to trade this is the
gap that you use to qualify as a
breakaway Gap and then trust it's likely
going to draw here which is why I
communicated to you I said we want to
see this traded to but I'm more
interested in trading it up above it and
coming back down and finding it as
support which makes it an inversion Fair
Vega
now
I know if you're new this sounds like a
whole lot of stuff please just give me
an overbought oversold indicator and a
moving average to follow that's okay
you're not ready for me
that that's all that it means it doesn't
mean that you can't learn this it just
means that you're not ready yet go watch
somebody else there's lots of other
people that'll Entertain You and tickle
your ears you want to learn how to read
the markets and really know what to do
come back here
50 equilibrium look where that fair
value got forms
equilibrium
what do you think's significant about
that 50 level
and why didn't that Gap fully close
it's a measuring Gap
that Fairway Gap is a measuring Gap this
low this candle did not come to that
candle's High
uh oh
we're seeing some context and narrative
that just ain't in your books baby
that means we can anticipate this price
run here to here to be duplicated to the
upside
meaning
let's say we have
this low is lower than that low and that
low and relatively equal to that one we
don't need this low here we want to see
the energetic price run that's this one
here so where's that root that root
price run begin that low right there
so if we take that and measured up to
the high of that fair bet you got
why that because that's the highest
range so you want to use that as your
base Point extend it from there
and you're putting it right on that same
I'll show you like what I'm doing this I
can give you one second
I'm taking that high of the fair bag out
here's the low of the fair value I'm
I've duplicated that so we now are
seeing a range that's projected to go
above this Gap
which is why I was saying I want to see
it go through it and then treat this Gap
as support
this was the draw
now it does go through it
here's the upper 25 of it okay it comes
back down
immediate rebalance
one day delay
remember when I talked about immediate
rebalance it's that next day or the very
next day after that then you'll see the
price run there it is
goes into the weekly order block
trades up into the daily order block and
the weekly mean threshold order block
trades all up into those levels each one
of these targets
okay you're looking for price to
continuously reach for them
you don't want to think that okay this
is my first objective and once it trades
there go try to find some other set up
in another Market no you want to stick
with it does it continuously keep
digging into that the next level it does
okay the last review I did I said okay
this is the level we're looking at next
we want to see if it wants to reach up
in that 104.54
it did
every time it was digging higher I
literally watched people on social media
about their long positions in Euro
failing
this is the reason why it kept going
higher if the dollar is going to go
higher euro is going to fall it's going
to go lower
and then it drops from there down to
some random level
which is let me get this off here
down close candle
inside the weekly order block I'm sorry
weekly fair value got which is now an
inversion Fairway Gap this is the
treatment of it on the daily chart it
comes down hits it
look at the reaction there do you think
he could have took shorts in euro dollar
on that right there and the last one to
three days well let's go over to euro
dollar
finally get the hell off of the dollar
Index get to something that makes sense
we don't trade a dollar around here
right
so here is the euro dollar
and this is the daily chart this is the
immediate rebalance right here
one Euro and this was the Fair bet you
got I mentioned that we would draw down
into up here we drew down into it and
then we rallied one more time
into this up close candle right here
that's a bare shorter block oh here we
go with the hindsight folks listen
your surgeon that cut on you and did
your surgery before he got his license
he was cutting on cadavers that means
dead people that can't sue you so that's
hindsight too he's looking at something
that is a safe he doesn't want to do an
exploratory surgery on you while you're
living
and try to do new things they have to do
those things
clinically in cadavers you bodies that
have been offered to science for
research
you need to go through these exercises
yourself look at PA study not
just recently go back through all of
this stuff here
and that's what back testing is it's not
going into a Forex tester and testing
the thing that that's a mock-up forward
test without live data that's a stage
you can include yeah but when I say back
testing you're going through old moves
and studying and breaking them down
that you're really going in there in
detail looking at what it's done what
what it didn't do where you would have
been stopped out and being honest about
that how much risk would have been
incurred not using the best entry use
the worst potential entry then does it
pay it out still okay so
here's a fair bag app I told you we
would gravitate down two and let's go
back over the last few days here here's
your order block here on your daily
chart
let's drop into a 60 Minute chart
in this high
down to that low here
do you see anything that stands out I'll
give you a minute while I'll get a drink
but what did I just teach you about
dealing ranges
you break the the dealing range down
if we were seeing the Dollar Tree down
into that inversion Fairway you got
on the daily chart
the inversion pair backup is based on
this weekly chart
that is a discount for dollar we could
likely see it rally dollar rallied that
means that we're likely to see euro
dollar sell off how can we anticipate
that and where would it form
here's your high
down to that low right there
where's equilibrium 50 right here in
close proximity what do you see
as a PD array that would be at that
level or higher for a premium remember
if we want to be short the highest
probability shorts are occurring in
premium markets above equilibrium
continuation pattern or continuation
premium
for selling short in a
bear Market it's been a bear market for
a while you can sell right at the 50
level
but specifically
in a premium we want to see it get into
this range
here
to here
is premium
in that range
between this low
and that high where is the PD array that
the first one exists
at a premium and that range from this
high down to that low
when we re when we retraced higher went
into this area right here it went to
this
area which is a city south side
imbalanced by side and efficiency
so if this is what you saw
congratulations you did it right
and it trades up into it here
dollar goes higher because it's on its
inversion for your bank account
you're a dollar sells off
this area right in here also is running
what
buy stops
retail Traders see this run here
in all this consolidation they see that
as a bull flag
so they're thinking something like this
euro dollar has been going down for a
long time it must have made it low
and they see this right here as a flag
pattern you see how it's like a big
flagpole consolidation and they think if
it can break Above This High here it
will duplicate
it'll duplicate that same run
oops
once we break the high
they want to see it trade back up in
here or something that effect I'm doing
it very Loosely because
bull flags and bear flags are trash but
the
the logic here is opposed to what a
retail minded Trader would see and it's
taking liquidity into account that means
the market went lower we traded here and
we started to move a little bit here
nobody in their right mind keyword
would have trailed their stop loss on
shorts to that that level right there
but on this move lower I promise you
every time they can hear you out there
that's trading Forex because they're
Ultra scared they don't want to get
stopped out they don't they don't want
to have their profits erode in the
trailer stop loss too tight and you know
what I'm talking about you're not in
your head thinking stop talking about me
there's liquidity above old highs and
lows that's 101 in terms of
understanding where markets are going to
reach for liquidity
but if you can see that liquidity and
pair it with some retail minded idea
that would be opposed to what I'm
teaching you
remember I'm teaching you how smart
money sees price and engages it I'm
teaching what the algorithm does so the
algorithm will deliver price Above This
High to take into account for buy stocks
being brought to the marketplace those
Market orders are now buying at the
market
which is what smart money will offer
shorts
to the marketplace at that same time
where and what price range in this fair
value guy
where would be the opposing draw on
price once it went into here right about
this High here is the buy stop so it
trades there which is the opposite of
what we saw a dollar doing at this
moment right here
dollar Index
let's see here right at uh 2 A.M on
third Tuesday June 6th okay 2 A.M
the dollar Index
was making that low here on the fair
value guy
see that so it's a mirror image so
you're qualifying setups not just on the
basis of you see it on your chart you're
trading you have to use some
inter-market relationships that would
say the opposite for instance if we're
trying to go short on Euro you want to
see something that would constitute a
long in dollar if you can't really see
it in dollar that's opposed to your
cable trade which is pound dollar or
Fiber which is zero USD whatever you're
trying to do in your Forex pair it needs
to be in a setup that would be opposing
in the dollar
if it's a Forex pair that has a currency
other than the dollar in the first of
its name
if we see this setup here that's
potentially long for dollar which is
we're trading in that fair value
if we're expecting prices to go high for
a dollar we would look for pairs that
begin with US dollar in their name like
dollar Yen dollar swissy
those pairs would mirror what dollar
Index is doing which is go higher
but because the dollar is likely to go
higher here and euro dollar
being inversely related to it
it's going to go lower but it's not
randomly just going to some level and
starting some you know
mystery as to why it was going to go
lower it's what I'm teaching you this
range the algorithm refers back to it so
it only needs to go up to equilibrium
slightly higher so we measure that with
the 50 level that's the only thing I'm
using the Fibonacci for
I'm not using Fibonacci for entries I'm
using Fibonacci for premium and discount
range
delineating a specific range to know
where a setup should likely form but in
that range what range specifically it's
this
there somewhere in that portion of this
price like lower I'm going to look for a
premium array well which ones exist
we have the FVG here
[Music]
man I should have charged money good
grief this this I could have made easily
a hundred thousand dollars on this
just folks relax
so that's that's the first one that's
your first premium array using month
Force lessons on The pdra Matrix
so what's the next one
are all down closed candles back and
forth PA so all of this right
here
this is balanced we've had lots of up
and down movement in here
and then we go back to the little high
so we have an order block
which is the last up close candle with
the highest close so it would be the
opening price that would be Dylan needed
there why would it need to go there
it doesn't because it's shielded by all
of this up and down movement there's no
inefficiency
none zero
so what PD array do you use that one
which did the market use that one
what time of day did it occur London
Kill Zone
two o'clock in the morning
that's what I teach you
what's the opposing DOL
okay so you've got this much right how
do I know
where price is going to go to next
Michael because that's what you're all
wondering whenever I tell you
something's going to happen I said hey
here it is folks you know it it panned
out invariably
folks will come out and say all right
what's next
they're wanting me to get it wrong
they want me to get it wrong so they can
say ha ha
you had 9 000 times in the recent that
you got it right but look what you just
did you missed on this one buddy haha
you're a fraud scammer
you can't win with some people but
if you're looking at that as liquidity
here okay and we're at equilibrium or
higher that means we are truly over
bought
there's no indicator required to see
that you don't need to put a Williams
percent R up you don't need to put a
stochastic up you don't need a CCI you
don't need a macd you don't need ads
though this chart is only showing you
ranges being measured which is what the
FIB is
and then
looking for
inefficiencies or liquidity and I draw
that out on the chart so that way you
can see it it gives you like a visual
eye candy that your
attention is focused at a specific area
on a chart and then I go and I talk
about what that is so that way you can
see it and understand how to use it
going forward
so at this moment right here
if in fact the market does go higher to
take the buy stops here and just trade
into a short-term premium which is
relative to this the only Range High and
that low
do you can hopefully you guys can see
this run from this high down to that low
probably that's retracement this is a
significant price swing like I'm not
looking at like this little thing here
to here that I'm not concerned about
that I want to focus on intermediate
term price runs
regardless of whatever time frame I'm
looking at my eye goes to specifics
in PA I'm not just taking
every little micro price swing I'm
looking at
from here to here
maybe from here to here but from here to
here absolutely
and whenever I see these ranges on the
weekend or in the morning I'll go
through my charts
before the kill zones or before the
sessions begin and I'm doing this with
all the ranges that are
Salient which is you daily
four hour an hourly and 15 minutes so
I'm looking at all the potential dealing
ranges that the market May refer back to
and then I weigh out whether or not like
I just did with this price run here from
high to low how many PD arrays are there
so you think because I've taught you
the
the propulsion block
FVG
institutional order flow entry drill
bearish order block
ing block
all those things
you're thinking okay which one do I use
here's a perfect example which occurred
in that price run
just the fair value got
that's all
and it only needed to go up to this
level here at the same time it went down
to its FVG on the dollar
dollar went down to a discount it's
bullish
Euro went up to a premium bearish
time of day two o'clock what's the
candle here what's the time
it's always local time New York you're
you're trading view chart should always
be set to New York
that's the time that the algorithm runs
on I don't care what anybody else says
okay this is the way it's coded
so it reports
on time on duty at two o'clock in the
morning after
hitting this then prices allowed to run
higher higher higher higher then in two
o'clock off the races boom what's it
going to reach for
how do I how do I Target a run like that
where does it go to next
well if it went off the buy side
here
and it went into uh inefficiency
here it's in a premium above 50 percent
and the dollar is looking to go higher
it's in a short-term discount it's in a
FVG
nothing says the dollar topped I don't
try to pick tops I'm trading in the meat
middle
you don't need the Precision highs and
the Precision lows you don't need that
you should you try to avoid that when
you're using HTF charts
try to avoid picking tops and bottles on
hard time frame charts you absolutely
can pick tops and bottoms in the lower
time frame charts because they're going
to behave
subordinate to the HTF
what I mean by that
if we're bullish on weekly and daily
charts for dollar
it's real easy to nail down right to the
PIP
short-term lows
at
key times or kill zones for
dollar Index intraday
it's just using these types of tools
here
but if you're going short here
and you're looking for
the opposing DOL
that's this low right there what what's
the reason behind that
what would be at that low of any
importance and why would it want to
revisit that low because it was a sharp
rally here this induces traders that go
along the pattern that they formed here
is a pseudo bull flag I teach that in
the core content where do fake bull
Flags occur
in this situation like this and what I
teach in a core content
it only goes up enough to validate the
buyers on breakout on a bull flag
but it only really goes up to where I
teach you the algorithm sees this area
right there
it runs above that short-term High here
and then because it took buy stops in to
the marketplace smartmailing smart
Milling smart money goes short here
so they're selling short here at the buy
stops so
two things are being accomplished here
Fair Vega premium it trades up into it
and takes the buy stops or buy side
liquidity right there this high
so your chart would look like this for
annotation purposes and for your journal
entry
I know man this is awesome
you're all thinking I wish I would have
known this stuff two years ago six
months ago I know so those buy stops
that buy sell liquidity has been purged
so if smart money is selling
to those buyers
what are they trying to get out at
discount
your eye goes right to where retail
would be trying to be fortifying
or protecting their position
we'll be resting below that low
sell sign
doing a clinic today
give me a thumbs up if you want me to do
one of these every day this week
except for Friday I got I got plans on
Friday
if you want to see me do this
every day this week
Live on YouTube
and teach you stuff that will knock your
socks off
thumbs up this video or this live stream
I like that it's pretty fair
request
so the market drops precipitously
and goes right to where the sell side
liquidity is
see that
now
what you want to study is because we
have that Gap this old Gap here that's a
daily let's go back to the Daily road
trip real quick
that's this FVG right there
okay
because we're inside that range
and
we're here
we have a gap that's outside of it you
see that here
we have that right there and we have
this up close candle right there so
that's a this is a bearish order block
and it's also right in the middle of
that shaded area which is the daily fair
that you got so this is consequent
encroachment essentially right there
so in my mind if we want to take
this low here out where another level of
sell side would reside
how I'm doing that in case you're
wondering I highlight it by clicking it
when they have the little balls on each
end
you go anywhere where the ball isn't
and you hold down control and drag it
away from it and you can create a
duplicate
and then drag this over hold down shift
and it'll make your line straight I
learned that from my students so I'm
very appreciative of that oh every time
I do a live stream
or do a video and people watch me do
things on trading view I always get
emails messages or whatever same here's
a tip for trading View and I love that
thank you so much
so you'd be watching this
there's your order block
foreign
I would want to see it stay below this
candle
more specifically using that level here
but if it trades Above This
candle here I would be sitting still one
euro
I'm not saying it's a short
but for me if it wants to go lower it
would need this see that Candlestick
keep it at Bay and not trade back to the
high end of the Fair makeup on the daily
chart it doesn't need to do that
because if it does it means something
all together something else and it's not
a trading environment for me to do if I
was to look at it that way
and it's already fulfilled a role here
it took buy stops and then sell stops so
in my mind it can consolidate but if it
wants to go lower it would need to stay
in the lower half of this shaded area
right in here okay all right so that is
the business on that
um I talked about
Breakaway gaps I talked about uh
pdra Matrix and how you shouldn't be
worrying about
which PD array
um you trade the one that the market
gives you
not all of my PD arrays are going to
exist in every price run
I mean that that's that's an epiphany
right there for some of you because you
think that every single one of those PD
arrays exist in every fractal of price
action
it doesn't
so when I'm looking at price and the
people that don't like me or they sell
something they view me as a competitor
they try to derail your studies and put
nonsense about me out there and make up
lies and new whatever Photoshop stuff
they can't erase the fact that I'm
calling it before it happens
and they can't erase the fact that my
students are now making fortunes with it
with real money
in leading the pack and profitability
so we are the cult of profitability you
want to be a cult member to sign up
every day and study okay it's free you
don't have to give me a Paypal payment
you don't have to give me your credit
card number you don't have to do any of
that stuff I don't run Discord channels
I am not teaching you crypto if anybody
says anything
that I'm touching crypto they're a fraud
they're a scammer I am not doing any of
that I'm not running some private little
area drawing people in you're never
going to hear me say you want to join my
private mentorship for money if they're
telling you that I am
offering that that's not me
drop it don't do it I'm not charging you
I'm doing I'm gladly doing this
I'm enjoying this
and it doesn't cost you anything but
your attention
and then you have to study it after we
spend time together
so I've covered what I want to cover
here on
Forex but let me just uh
drop into cable real quick I haven't
looked at her for a while
yeah I would have preferred uh
Euro over Cable cable doesn't have all
that much clean run in here it's this is
too muddy muddy meeting it's got like a
smaller Gap here another Gap here and I
don't like that
it's not as clean and obvious enough
take a look at this chart in this area
here
okay look at this area here on cable
which is pound the versus US dollar
pound dollar
look at that and compare it to Euro I'll
toggle back and forth for a second
you see how obvious that is that that
Gap really stands out and it's singular
one
one of them versus same area look you're
looking there uh cable chart
got Gap
what's cleaner PA Euro so if I
were trading last night in London
session which one would I have traded I
would have traded the euro
I would have not taken any trade in
cable even though cable did in fact run
lower it didn't go down to take out its
sell side because it only needed to go
down into this imbalance here
and that's where we saw a trade to so I
wouldn't touch cable here the euro
dollar last night was really nice
and let's take us into
the weekly chart
and let's look at ES
and then bring this discussion today to
a close
I know I know can't you make it one of
those four hour sessions nah not really
because if I want to do this every day I
want to kind of preserve my
release
so here is the business on the weekly
chart for e-mini s p so for all you die
hard Forex folks that don't think you're
ever going to learn anything from me by
teaching Forex Concepts in es trading
because it's not limited to just Forex
in my stuff that I teach in
yes unless specifically stated
its price delivery
so smart money Concepts
SMC
that's my work
these are my Creations this is my stuff
if you want to learn how to do this I'm
showing you it
doesn't have barriers by asset
it's not limited
so because my focus has been primarily
on index features
all of the all the teachings obviously
are being seen in this medium or asset
it doesn't mean that it can't work in
Forex or that it stopped in Forex it
just means that my attention is in this
market here
all right so now think about what we
were talking about in relationship to
the bond market okay now we're going to
take a little bit of a step back
and think
if the bond market is signaling that it
wanted to go lower recently out of that
range then I'll I'll take you back to
that chart in a second when we get to
the daily chart with e-mini s p
but that bond market moving lower
sets the tone for
a market
that will see movement because we left a
range in bonds so therefore all other
asset classes are free to move
they're free to move
and they leave the consolidation
so once we are in that profile
the profile being we're in a trending
environment not consolidation
or in trending that means that price
swings can now evolve and allow daily
charts to start booking
sustained runs not just intraday
volatility only and that's your that's
your you know Cuisine you have to eat
from it's a little bit more of a
sustained price run when the bond
markets are trending if the bond market
is consolidating
that is a true testimony to anticipate
consolidation in your in your specific
Market whether it be bonds or whether it
be index Futures whether it be
Forex
it is a precursor to tell you what type
of environment we are in from a macro
stance
it does not mean that you can't make
money within that or outside of it only
it just means that from a market
profiling stance that I call profile
it's not the volume
profile where you see all these little
horizontal volume you know communicators
and such none of that is necessary V WAP
is not necessary level two data not
necessary in all those PA uh
junkies that use the ladders you know on
the right side of the truck it looks
cooled on it seeing all that stuff
flashing around that's distracting you
don't need that
everything you need is in the chart a
time-based chart will give you
everything you'll be able to forecast
where and when they're going to form and
now guys those folks are waiting for
something
they needed to go to those levels and
sometimes they don't work
when I'm teaching you how to anticipate
where and when these things will form
and by doing it over time you
desensitize yourself
to the uncertainty where it's paralyzing
fear right now and you're like I don't
know what I'm doing this is so
complicated
go slow
there's nobody I'm not telling you you
should be trading with real money in
your first year so why are you insisting
that you should
just because everybody else out there is
doing it you don't know how long they've
been studying you know how long they've
worked very hard
and
nobody comes out here you know Johnny on
the spot first time never failed and as
a superstar nobody nobody has ever done
that okay they've always had some
measure of learning that's required and
some are faster than others and give
yourself permission to grow at your own
pace I'm not grading you onion speed at
which you find continuity and
consistency so don't you do it either
now
we are I'm sure I'm looking at the chart
from right weekly chart on ES e-mini s p
uh when we were down here in this Gap
year I said we're gonna look to trade up
into this volume and balance which is
the Shaded area in white
the volume of balance is the opening on
this candle here and the closing on that
candle here there's no body
by any
candlestick
ever since that formation there until
this candle in this candle which was
last week and the week prior
notice that
so this was the DOL and
then I said inside of you want to see
the real sweet spot would be that little
separation right there this separation
there with the blue lines that my
friends
is a real liquidity void
that's an absence of any trading new
book price no delivery no trades were
engaged no stocks were taken no entries
were given
there's no trading between those two
price points so while this was enough
for the draw which is the volume and
balance
because we only had this little Wick
between this closing price and this
opening price my eye jumps to that and
you can see the other one that I'm
looking for if we continue on the upside
it's here
that's where I see it right here that
same thing this right here look like
that here when we were down here I said
watch this FVG in this order
block the opening price extended down
don't take my word for it I have it in
recording go look at it it's on the
YouTube channel I do not delete tweets I
do not change anything on my videos once
they're up there you can't edit them
they're there
so we did in fact draw higher now here
is one of those things that's making
a lot more sense for the Die Hard
students here that really want to know
what it is that makes price behave a
specific way
bonds move lower
out of the consolidation freeing up the
markets to behave in a manner that's
trending
causing dollar to go higher
dollar going higher is what risk on or
risk off
meaning foreign currencies go lower
meaning that the rallies in equities
while they still can manifest and
materialize they're going to be held at
Bay they won't be
explosive types of runs they're usually
going to be like that keep on creeping
higher small little retracements
creeping higher so that's profiling
that's Market profiling understanding
the behavior of how price will deliver
now let me make a distinction in
contrast it with something like this
let's say for instance that
we did not need
to come back up to here
say all this didn't exist as a volume
and bounce and we didn't have this Gap
here okay
then
e-mini s p NASDAQ Dao could
accelerate
lower in shorts
but because it is being manipulated
heavily the stock market should not be
where it's at folks I'm gonna be real
honest with you this thing should not be
here
but I have to follow the the breadcrumbs
that the algorithm is laying out there
this is what the smart money entity the
people out there that's not making video
courses and not on YouTube or not on
Twitter they're not on TV Talking Heads
they're not out there telling you what
to do with your money because they're
out there actively fleecing large funds
they're trading against them they're
their counterparty they're the people
that are inside the measurement of net
net Trader position chart when you see
the large Traders
when they're trading they're
opposed to them they're providing the
liquidity
that's smart money
and they're constantly in a dance with
large funds constantly you learn how to
place your stop loss
with the same logic that they do
and that's why you fall victim to it so
while smart money is not out there
looking for your one micro lot on Forex
or your mini contract in s p they don't
see you they don't see your one contract
that you're trading okay they don't see
your micro contract your you know your
little tiny insignificant anything
they're not looking at you
they're looking at the large pools of
liquidity that large funds bring to the
marketplace and just like a
a large fishing boat that drags a net
okay they're out there trying to catch
fish but sometimes these innocent
dolphins and sea turtles get caught up
in that net you're that dolphin and or
sea turtle you just are a casualty of an
event that's going to happen whether
your stop was there or not
so they're not out there to get you
they're out there to get
the large fish
and if you're in the wake or in close
proximity to where they are you're
getting scooped up in that net too
so it's imperative you understand how
they go after that crowd of large
liquidity
and you have to learn how to navigate
certain markets are going to behave in a
behavior
that is explosive sometimes
and other times it's just something you
you just can't you shouldn't be fighting
it
we've been calling es higher we've been
looking for these very specific levels
and it delivered like gangbusters
I told you that NQ or NASDAQ was the
stronger to the upside
why didn't you do all your trading in a
NASDAQ because I'm teaching that if you
use one medium one market
you can use even the stronger Market to
trade this slower Market in sympathy
it'll move with it meaning look at
NASDAQ
nqm2023 on the weekly chart which one
was more explosive
clearly NASDAQ you were told that NASDAQ
was the stronger one to the upside so
the sixth sister is what
yes
so es will move slower
it'll still go higher
but this imbalance over here
strongly and quickly
reached to for NQ back to ES
we have not even made its way up to that
respective in Balance this volume
balance
see that
still
es has moved higher but it does what
performs lethargically as I told you it
would because NQ was stronger I'm
teaching you visibility I'm teaching you
how even if you were only following es
and you never wanted to touch the NASDAQ
because NASDAQ is a little bit Wilder
it's thinner
and because it's thinner it moves faster
it runs for liquidity faster because
there's less contracts in close
proximity to market price so it will
quickly run farther away it will run 100
handles faster than es will
it doesn't need much to do 100 Handles
in NASDAQ which is why you shouldn't be
doing a lot of contracts in ignorance
not knowing what you're doing
that thing will roast you rip your face
off and cremate you right there and
restand
but
I can teach you how to find when it's
going to be an outperformer sometimes
NASDAQ will be lethargic and it'll be
reversed es will outperform it
somebody that's new or recently started
trading they would think there's no way
that's like that listen I've been around
here for 30 years I've seen it
but to know what it's going to do
beforehand that's visibility that's
experience you're learning that you
experience that real time with me over
the last few weeks
the benefit is now knowing what it did
you can see that we have tools I have
Concepts I have logic that can be
transferred to you and your
understanding and you can take that
going forward
and also to relieve the people that are
new
and when they hear me say just follow ES
they're not upset because es didn't
perform
now if you're looking at saying you told
me to follow yes I'm studying yes and
even though you did say NASDAQ was going
to be the upside leader and stronger I'm
studying es and I'm regretful because I
could have took live trades before you
should have
and made money in NASDAQ you're a jerk
you're a terrible mentor
well that's a student that's not really
trying to learn that's somebody that you
know is going to look for Fault In
anything external apart from them
the reason why they didn't make them
make money or more money is because of
somebody else
the reason why they lost money is
because somebody else calls that they're
never going to be responsible and you
have to be responsible you are in a
driver's seat nothing I tell you should
be a reason for you to press a button to
get in Risk real money nothing not one
thing
which is why sometimes I'll say like I
mentioned when the senators were all
given Sally phones ahead of the more
Memorial weekend I said anything can
happen folks don't bet the farm on it be
careful because I know there's a small
group of you probably larger than I
realize that are taking what I'm saying
and going out there and trading with it
with real money so I want to remind you
there are real risks here
I'm never painting this and you're going
to get rich I'm never doing that but I'm
teaching you and promising you that
you're going to read PA better
than any book course or Educators ever
going to take you to they're never going
to get this they're never going to get
like this there's so many facets to this
stuff that helps you become a freak
a Precision freak
and when you are understanding the
markets to this degree in this depth
there's no reason you you never are
scared you're never fearful you respect
the risk that the markets provide
and offer many times
but you're not paralyzed by uncertainty
you know exactly what you're looking for
you know what you're going to wait for
and when it forms you take the trade you
take the entry you know where your
Stop's going to be you know where your
first partial you know you're second
partial and where your Target's going to
be
you're not worrying about it
because you understand yourself and you
understand what the Market's likely to
do because you've been studying it with
great detail not just let me watch a
couple videos of ICT I got this lick
let's go no that's not how this works
so
yes
we had a real Gap here and that was
where I took your attention to very
specifically look here that's going to
be the draw
imbalance whatever you got rallied right
in there so in between here
and here
let's do the same thing we just did
there's our low
that's where our price point started
up to here
in that run right there
you can go into LTFs for
your own homework I'm not going to do it
here this is for your study
from here
to here
on your FIB let me help you also because
I know some of you are probably saying
can you open up your settings he read my
mind here's what my Fibonacci settings
are
okay
so I'll leave that up here for a second
so you can get it
and these levels down here
the 0.25 and the 0.75 with 0.50
that is going to give you your
gradient levels for grading a price
swing which we're going to go into next
okay but on the LTFs like
one minute and five minute charts look
at that range around the 25 I'm sorry
for around the 75 the 50 and the 25
respectively and see if you don't see my
PDA race manifesting there
we have this run down here
same thing you're going to do this is
for homework
from this low up to the high of that Gap
right there that's the draw
so if you were a swing Trader or a
short-term Trader or a day trader
working within this profile
trying to find Longs where do they form
price wise it's around this gradient
the 50 percent
and the 25 percent
go into your LTFs I could
make this a five hour long video which I
don't want to do but I promise if you go
into your LTFs you're going
to see these levels there's PD arrays
and setups that form there
study that okay this will help you see
algorithmic price delivery and that you
can anticipate them where
everybody else out there is waiting for
something let me ask you a question okay
for the folks that trade market uh
profile and trade with v-wop
where's B walk gonna be on Thursday at
10 A.M
right
I can tell you where price is going to
be and then I have elements in time that
I use where I know they're both going to
meet
see you're a victim
you're a casualty to uncertainty and you
have to wait around for something to
react to
just like an overbought or sold you
can't do anything until that overbought
or oversold indicator tells you you
can't do anything directionally until
your macd says it's sloping down or it's
sloping up I don't have that my students
don't have that and when I talk to you
this way I'm not trying to be arrogant
I'm not trying to be condescending I'm
telling you what I'm doing is light
years ahead of everything that you're
doing right now
that's why when my results are being
shown to you it looks like it's
cherry-picked but what do you do when
when I'm doing it with weekly charts now
in Daily charts and it's delivering
how many things did I say in addition to
this that didn't happen that it was only
this
and I say these types of things so I
want people that are on the fence that
listen to these goobers that just don't
like the fact that I'm doing this for
free and I'm that good
they want to take your attention away
from it
and I'm trying to be respectful to them
because I could literally go ahead and
smash all of them
but I don't want to do that that's not
why I'm here I want to leave in November
you know on a high note a good note
where I'm not adversarial to anybody and
I want even the people that don't like
me and are selling other courses I want
them whether they openly say they did it
or not they can secretly add all the
stuff I'm teaching if it makes their
product better that makes them better
and that makes their patrons better
that's all I care about I don't want to
hurt anybody I don't want to make
anybody you know lose their business
okay I want to help that's all I'm doing
this for I Love It I enjoy it and I'm
passionate about it and it's not limited
this is the people that like me
I have a lot of people that are
long-term followers and that were haters
of me in the beginning
so let's go into a LTF
discussion on ES let's go down into a
well let's let's just drop down to four
hour
thank you
so here's that daily discount fair value
in the market rallied
Consolidated worked inside of this
imbalance and into
this breaker
we have a low high lower low less up
close candle extend that in the future
hits it here hits it here
my eyes don't
I gotta look at it see
I'm not sure if that one hit it too
you did so it hits it here multiple
times okay now this breaker is not a
supply and demand Zone
okay uh Sam seiden and those who follow
him
if they were to say that as a demand
Zone okay
now it's no longer fresh it's definitely
stale bread now it's a it's a crouton
they would never use that logic okay
my PD arrays as long as the narrative
stays intact looking for higher prices
these PD arrays can be
reused okay their their sponsorship
doesn't expire simply because it's
traded to it before
we're in a large consolidation here buy
side here the market rallies up creates
another area of
equal highs it drops back down where is
it dropping down into inefficiencies
here
and look real close you see that right
there
what is that
what is this little thing right there
I'll give you a second to think about it
okay
what did I tell you es was gonna do
go higher right up into that Gap that's
what this two blue lines are up here
okay that real liquidity boy which is
the highest portion of that volume
imbalance on the weekly chart
so if the Market's going to gravitate up
to there
we're not looking for shorts folks so we
wouldn't look at this as a rally up
until it to go short
we don't want to see that so if we can
see it go above it and close above it it
does it on this candle here but we're on
a four hour chart so it's definitely
going to do
a close on an hourly chart or a
15-minute chart but we're going to just
do a top down
this fair value guy
would be treated the same way I told you
I wouldn't want to see the dollar Index
FVG to be an inversion
failure fair value yeah
that means that we don't see it go above
it
and then treat it as support
look at the bodies of the candles that's
the narrative that's the the real story
is in the the bodies the Wicks do the
damage yes we Wicked through it but look
where it closed
we traded down look at the body's closed
right there that's consequent
encroachment that's the midpoint of that
Gap right there
here I mean
make it nice and obvious
so 41.82 and a quarter
the open on this is 41.82 and a quarter
oh look at that
now you're gonna tell me you're gonna
argue with me
okay uh dollar menu mentor gonna tell me
that that's buying and selling pressure
that this happened to make that lineup
exactly right there really
really
I'm sorry I'm sorry that nobody told you
in books before me I'm sorry that you
can't find it on your own I'm sorry
but you have it now so stop wrestling
with me you guys you make arguments
against me
when I'm telling you something it works
phenomenally and how these markets
really Book price
inversion for your bag
if you ever have an inversion fair value
Gap and here's for your notes folks
I was gonna say this for the book but
I'll give it here today if you have an
inversion Fairbank yet like that
and you have a FVG
that's just below that level inside of
your dealing range meaning you have this
low
to that high
this inversion fair value got we would
want to see it trade through that
because we're bullish buy side
this later on we don't know that's going
to form yet because we're here
it rallies through it
we expect
ICT tell me how to know when the fair
Bay gaps shouldn't close in here's one
of those signatures
inversion Fair bag you got
all this area should stay open
for a portion of it should stay open
okay so in other words it would look
like this this is what you would
anticipate
as a fair value guy
some of you would see this entry in this
shaded area here
some of my students would see this as
their multiplier meaning that they would
go long when price dropped into it right
there
other students would see this and say
okay I want to see it show me proof with
the bodies respecting either consequent
encroachment or the high of the fair
value got
is there anybody closing at the high no
we do have a body close right here on
this candle at the consequent
encroachment as soon as it does that we
now can trust that this area here
should not be traded down into
technical science baby take notes take
notes Goldman Sachs okay because this is
the real so this rum here goes for
what it takes out the by side liquidity
now folks that just simply watch one of
my videos and they see the relative
equal highs and relatively close that we
like to Target we don't look at this as
we can trust this as a short typical
retail idea we want to see something
that's going to be at a later time
uses a long to go right back there and
Target those individuals
so this area here would be a
buy side liquidity pool
[Music]
okay so that will be a first partial if
a student would use this entry on this
if everybody got they could they could
use this as what specifically what kind
of Entry would that be
right in here what entry would that be
institutional order flow entry drill
meaning
that you're only needing it to go to
that level or just below it of this fair
value Gap trusting because we have an
inversion FVG here that's
going to support price if we get a
signature showing that either one of
these conditions occur a body closes at
the High
or closes at the constant encroachment
as soon as that happens as soon as that
happens the algorithm will immediately
spool and go the other direction and aim
for delivery to the upside going after
buy side or inefficiency above old highs
buy sides here
did it look like it wanted to go in a
hurry higher
I mean my chart looks like this does
yours look like that
it draws to this area here
right in here and then what do we get
open immediate rebalance bang hits it if
you get an immediate rebalance you know
where it's going to go I told you weeks
ago that was going to go up here
it's on YouTube it's in Twitter it's all
over the place
we were going long we were focusing on
Longs Longs bullish buying long
where to right here
right up here
immediate rebalance even though we took
out by side here
guys out there trying to teach Fu
Candles there are no Fu candles okay
that's not my stuff you want to pretend
there's a mythological creature out
there called a Fu candle it's your
business but they'll say okay look at
this it's running up here now they took
the stops now it's gonna sell off
no
how do you know when it's going to take
out relative equal highs in Reverse or
when it's going to keep continuing when
you have a HTF PD array
that has yet to be traded to so I'm not
going to look at these equal highs being
traded to and then reject and go lower
that's just a partial and I'm holding on
looking for higher prices
and running into you know higher prices
still
now what happens if it's trading like
this on going into a Friday or Thursday
and we're getting into this area here
but doesn't quite get to the high it
could wait until the next week's Monday
or if it's a holiday into Tuesday okay
wherever we open up at
all these things have to be weighed out
when you're reading and are trading it's
not to Simply get in there and just hold
it over the weekend because over over
the weekend there is enormous
Gap risk
Gap risk is the likelihood of a
opening that is unfavorable to your
position
for instance say you're long and you're
up 80 Handles in a position you're
holding for ES
it could open up where you're now only
up 40 handles
or in better scenarios it can open up
and now you're up 120 handles right from
the opening
and if you get something like that you
should just take your profits there
because it's likely to come in and close
in that Gap and you don't know because
you're probably just now learning you
don't know if it's going to fill that
Gap and continue higher or close that
Gap
sputter higher a little bit and then
Korean lower even still
so
there's lots of things that you have to
know and by the long drawn out boring
stuff I'm teaching you I'm giving you
all that experience in my dialogue
that you haven't encountered the reason
for requiring that or leaning on the
necessity of having that information in
the beginning
most of you have no idea
so and that's why that that effect if
you watch my videos multiple times it
feels like you're watching a brand new
video when you're paying attention it
sounds like I didn't hear him say that
the first time when the video is the
same one but now it's more meaningful to
you because you're not trading or you're
doing back testing you have more
experience and you're like oh that's why
he said that now I understand it you
can't just watch my videos one time and
I promise you that that is not a reason
for you to run my ad Revenue up okay I
don't care if you watch my videos I
really don't I only put them up there
and I'm not taking them down when I stop
in November they're there to keep people
from wanting to buy it from Jokers out
there trying to sell it because they're
still trying to they're on my YouTube
channel stop trying to fish around for
the videos the videos that you need are
those and I'm teaching you even more my
charter members the people that pay me
they're in the audience right now
learning just like you are and the
things I'm talking about right here
they've never learned that
they've never learned this
this is all fresh right from the oven to
buy CT and it's not in your books
so let's go into uh
let's go into a 15 minute time frame
foreign
but you'll have plenty of things to
study when I'm going
so we have
here's today Tuesday Monday okay so
Monday
Monday was the day we traded up into the
high end of that gap on the weekly chart
okay the Gap is defined by this level is
the high and this level is the low okay
and
all through here
see how we ran up in here
this is all non-farm payroll garbage
this is trashy you know delivery then we
rally
see how we fell short of that gap on the
weekly
chart it didn't get to the low of it
here and then careened all the way back
down into this down closed candle
and then back and forth
back and forth
open down one more time this low right
there
is constical encroachment or just below
it of this Wick
then it wrong uh rally strongly up into
the low that Weekly got And Trades up to
consequent encroachment or midpoint of
that
range high and low of the weekly Gap so
think about it like this you ever played
uh the game Who horseshoes
in the U.S we have a game that we take
two steel posts little metal poles and
we beat them down under the ground
and we have real horseshoes
and you stand over there and you got
typically two horseshoes a player and
you try to toss the Horseshoe and try to
get it to ring around that that little
metal post
think about your trades and where you're
trying to see price go to okay whether
or not
you get that horseshoe on that post or
not
is irrelevant you're aiming for it to go
to that post so you're tossing
horseshoes in that vicinity with the
expectation that it's going to get a
ringer okay
a ringer in this case on that Gap would
be getting to the high which is what we
see it trade to on Friday
but is it a losing trade if you got long
and you got out in here
and left it thinking that okay it might
not trade
you know Friday's afternoon session
into that high it might leave it till
the next week
I don't think it would be a losing trade
I don't think it would be illusion trade
at all
and if you stick with that narrative
that as long as you're tossing trades in
with the expectation that the the
direction you're aiming your horseshoes
or your trades or you're trying to take
partials you're trying to reach for
these levels to get paid at you don't
need a ringer
to be profitable
that's this is the right
expression in
your equation for
successor uh failure you think success
is only if it goes to the Target you
called for
that's not true
success is making money
success
is being profitable how profitable you
got more money in your pocket than you
had last week you got more money in your
account than you had yesterday
that's success it's modular
long-term consistency or longevity in
trading is long-term profitability that
will absolutely have periods of drawdown
where you're losing trades and that's
okay you
limit your risk cut your business size
in half each time you take a loss and
you try to get 50 of the previous loss
you got and once you get that they can
go back to a little bit higher risk a
little bit higher risk
going slow in the beginning is important
but keep in the proper perspective and
what you're looking for in PA
where is it going how should you expect
price to deliver I've covered all that
today
I covered how how a price should deliver
I showed you where it was going to go I
told you specifically where I was going
to go weeks ago
and we got it here Friday
now is it
okay I'm on a 15. is it
[Music]
today let's go into
Thursday Friday
okay so here's
current new week opening Gap very very
small little tiny little opening Gap
did it gravitate back to it
yes
new week opening gaps are like that
little Post in the game of horseshoes
you don't need it to be a ringer
but it's your everybody in smart money
is aiming for that
okay we're consolidating consolidating
consolidating and then we broke lower
trapping Traders going short why because
they think it's gone up too long it has
to be going lower so sell side has been
taken the Trap Traders short rallies
small little Gap trades down into it
here but we gravitate back to that new
week opening Gap
go back over here
you see this little section of price
action here
if this stays open
and we take out that low then we're
going lower until that I'm staying
bullish on ES
simple as that
very simple right it's not complicated
it's not you know making something
bloated with uh
assuming moving parts
and we don't need this level and you're
probably saying what is that level
to be honest I don't remember off the
top and hit what it is I don't have my
notes next to me so
the uh
below the Gap and the high of the Gap
here
and new week opening Gap
all right so here's the third uh was it
Thursday
Friday Friday
post
non-farm payroll
we have a gap in here
if we're bullish
okay if we're bullish
are we looking for premium fair value
gaps to sell short from
hopefully you've been watching this
live stream close to nothing though that
that's not what we want
so how do I know when to anticipate a
FVG to perform as an
inversion Fair Vega you have to have
narrative
where are you
are you looking for bullish or bearish
is the market has the market traded to
your HTF DOL
that's this here that's that gap on the
weekly chart
so if we see a gap like this here
right here
[Music]
everybody else would see that as a
return into that let's go short and go
lower
now
if we see things like this
that already should tell you no
because this drop down here was this get
sell stops taken
and either put Traders short
or take them out of their lungs
then we have a market structure shift
here
we have a gap here and I love seeing
gaps that would look like some kind of
uh let me change the color here it's
sponky
all right so
everything we have this Gap in here
that Gap when it trades up into it there
if you are just a casual viewer Netflix
and chill type of uh ICT student you're
going to get tripped up and you're gonna
be like the Joker I just blocked on my
YouTube channel that was posting stuff
saying this stuff doesn't work it only
works sometimes this is nonsense folks
listen okay if you can't make it work
that's where it stops where you can't
make it work you haven't done enough
study to learn it yet but it's always
there the Silver Bullet is every day
in the times I've told you and the
things I'm teaching with Market
structure shifts and draws on liquidity
which is the most Paramount lesson
that's the thing you need to know up in
here
halfway point
consequent approach between the high and
the low of that Weekly Gap
think about that analogy I just gave you
with the game of horseshoes okay
midpoint is a real good Target
real good Target
best a perfect ringer would be at the
high end
but we're consolidating in here
and we closed on Friday right around
here so we're consolidating at 4 30.
what's the likelihood of it getting up
into that high
to close that Gap in
very very low
very very low because we're going into
the close and we're going into the
Friday close
so they're going to leave that portion
open and trade it in Monday indoor
Tuesday
so you would stay bullish until it hits
this level then once it happens
you go neutral
you sit still
not what do we do next what do we trade
next you trade sidelines
that wins all the time you can't lose
money on the sidelines that is a
position not trading is a position not
being long not being short neutral on
the sidelines no risk incurred that is a
position and it always always is
profitable it means you have the same
amount of money in your account on the
day ends that you had when you started
I don't know why it's such a hard thing
for people to sit still they always have
to be doing something because day
trading is everyday trading to them and
it's not to a professional it's not it's
absolutely not
thank you
so when you see things like this and you
anticipate that a FVG would
become a inversion Fairbank
weaning we would not we would want to
see price
trade above come back down in and then
rally we want to see that
and if we don't see that
we do nothing
because the bullish narrative that we're
holding see in your mind
or in my mind
we fell short of that low of the gap on
the weekly chart which is this level
here and this is where I'm thinking
price is going to gravitate towards it's
going to go up there so all smart
money's doing is keeps throwing
horseshoes until it gets up in this area
here every retracement every discount is
an opportunity for a high frequency
trading algorithm to go long
what did I just say yes
every single short term discount
PD array is utilized by high frequency
trading algorithms to go long and then
throw their orders into this Abyss
up in here in this area up here because
that inefficiency that the average bear
the average Trader I shouldn't say bear
because I'm not saying difference to
bears but the average person
the average Trader doesn't think like
I'm teaching you they're not even aware
of that volume and balance they weren't
even looking at that they're arguing
with me why are you looking at gaps when
the trade when trading during that time
that wasn't the front month contract
blah blah blah that's exactly the reason
why it works
wake up
what are you doing arm wrestling me when
I'm telling you what works and it
happens
like I don't agree with this so
therefore let me argue about it instead
of saying wow this works let me
just keep doing what he's showing
that's what I'm trying to convey
but it's like there's a number of you
that don't want to learn you want to
argue you want to debate I'm not here to
debate I'm here to show you how
to make money and get the out of
Dodge in November I'm getting back to
enjoying my life
but you're wasting time all this
nonsense of arguing and saying this
doesn't work that doesn't work because
you did five examples casually you got
to put your yourself in from these
charts and really dig into it
you have to really make an effort to
learn this and give yourself permission
and notice it's going to take you longer
than you probably thought
but there are people out there that are
absolutely murdering it
murdering it they've never made this
kind of money in their life before ever
and they had the same thoughts you're
holding right now what if I can't do it
what if I can't make this work for me
I've done all this study what happens if
I fail what happens if you just keep
going
because that's what happened for them
they did the work they stayed at it they
didn't talk themselves out of it they
didn't let other people on the internet
talk them out of it
you roll your sleeves up say you know
what this stuff works it only feels
complicated right now because I'm brand
new
and now I'm going to sit down and be
disciplined I'm gonna put myself in
there and show myself that I can do this
okay
uh the rage right now is the the funded
accounts of 50 what was it 150 000
funded accounts okay
um
Trading
let's just say for instance let's play
devil's advocate for a moment okay
let's say for instance that you've done
the work you spend the full calendar
year doing everything I tell you to do
I mean think about it some of you are in
college or you went to college you
submitted to four years of
ninety percent of the things you learned
in college you don't even use in your
career that's just the truth okay I
don't care where you are
the fact that you were willing to put
that much time into something and
probably paid for it and probably still
paying the loan payments that you can't
even file bankruptcy for if you go broke
you you are having to pay that whether
you're doing that job or not
all that effort and time that you were
willing to put yourself through for four
years with no certainty that you're even
gonna love what you're going to school
for
if you don't love the opportunity that
these markets present
don't touch them
don't trade don't learn the trade don't
do it if you are not 100 convinced that
this is for you
do not touch these these markets period
don't let anybody entice you into
thinking that you can learn their easy
Black Box this that no thing if you're
not absolutely convinced that this is
for you do not go any further stop you
will save so much pain misery probably
money
if you're not 100 convinced that this is
what you see yourself doing
don't touch it
because you can't be lukewarm half-ass
go in here and think I'm going to try to
dabble with it dabbling always gets your
fingers burned
you're gonna lose money
you're gonna make money if you stay with
it long enough but it's always going to
be a give and take
you're never going to be perfect you
don't have to be perfect you just need
to be profitable and I teach with a demo
account to desensitize yourself about
being right or wrong
no other Mentor out there stands out
there championing the fact that it's
demo but everybody else has to sell
they have a problem with me because they
think that that reduces the efficacy the
what does I do and teach and my students
are making money with it
what would you do if you made three
hundred thousand dollars in the last
three months do you think that you would
believe anything anybody else has to say
about what you're doing that would be
contrary to it hell no you ain't gonna
give a you ain't gonna care what
anybody says nobody in your family
nobody at your job nobody that you know
nobody on the Internet is ever going to
be able to talk you out of what you have
now masked for yourself and that's a
skill set that you carry with you as
long as the days are long and you can
breathe
and your mental faculties are there you
have that skill set nobody can take it
from you nobody
and you're gonna let some Tom Dick or
Harry on the internet tell you don't do
that it's a scam when you're seeing
people being interviewed by funded
companies I don't own these
companies I have no affiliation with
none of them and they're all saying that
the number one group of traders that are
making money at their places are my
students that should be your testimony
right there if you've ever been sitting
on the fence and thinking should I do
this should I put the effort in these
people are convinced they did the right
thing
these funded companies
love my students they love them
who's next who's next
you sit down you learn a skill set okay
you learn this skill set
you get comfortable in yourself you're
not recklessly trying to go out and take
a trade
one of the questions that came up that
let me cover it how do I know when I can
go for a funded account challenge when
should I transition into live fund
trading
minimum expectation
and threshold is for you to be
completely devoid of any kind of bubbly
feeling when you're when you do it right
and you made money in your demo or
whatever
if you don't feel any kind of emotion
like it's just I mean I've been doing
this for months it's the same stuff I
don't feel any attachment to the outcome
I don't care that it was right I don't
care that it would exactly like I
expected to
if you're not in a rush to do something
every single day look at the live
streamers on YouTube
they're out there pressing all the time
they have to perform
like dancing bears they got to do
something for Their audience
if you can sit still and say I don't
need a trade right now and you let the
market pan around and it moves a lot and
you feel no regret
all the things I just said
and you're consistent in a demo minimum
six months
minimum six months
better traders that have been doing for
a longer time if they're consistent like
for instance say you're a profitable
Trader and you learn from me and now you
you supercharge your Trading
practice in a demo for three months but
if you are not profitable trading in
general before coming to me
you have to do at least six months in
demo but at the end of that six months
you need to be completely desensitized
to the outcome you don't care
you don't care you don't feel no there's
no rush that you got to get in there
you're not salivating on Saturday you
can't wait till Monday
that means you're an action Hound you're
you're you're all hopped up on goofballs
because you're gambling
you're not trading you're gambling and
you just want to have that outcome to
make you feel significant again
you don't want to have that if you're
thinking like that or feeling like that
do not do a combine challenge don't try
to do a funded account because you're
emotionally charged you will fail it
and it will set you back that's mental
scar tissue and it builds into a callus
and eventually you won't want to do this
because it's too painful
when all of it is available to you every
single one of you that are listening to
me right now whether it's recorded and
you've watched it later on down the road
or right here live
you can do this
you absolutely can do it
I'm telling you you can do this if I
didn't believe it I wouldn't tell you
and you're now seeing other people
around the world doing extremely well
and I'm so proud I'm proud to be a small
conduit to the bridge where they were
and their Newfound success and I'm
excited to see where they're going to go
I'm excited to see where you're going to
go
but if you're not passionate about this
if you don't absolutely I mean listen
I'm not selling you a timeshare folks
okay there's no upsell later on you're
never going to send me any money
and I have more faith than you
succeeding than you probably do in
yourself
don't sell yourself short
it's going to take work it's going to
take effort but let's assume for a
moment let's just save her argument's
sake that you did everything I told you
to do
and we're at that six month threshold
and you've spent time trading and you
don't feel like you have to be in front
of the charts every single day you just
know what you're looking for you know
your model you know what you're trying
to trade on and it just happens to be
there and you take those trades
you're at the funded portion okay you
don't need any money like big big
account size money and you went the
route that the shoestring budget you can
afford the funded account stuff
and you got a 150 000 account
okay 150 000 account you're funded
you're doing the things that I'm
teaching you to do and you're using the
logic I'm showing you here
this is Friday okay inversion fair value
got
trading and tossing the orders up into
this Gap that Weekly Gap and then every
discount
every short term discount what does that
mean
what's this level right here
this took 25 level of this range from
high to low these two levels again are
that Weekly Gap
so we can
throw gradient levels in there
75. look at the beautiful reaction there
look out hovered around equilibrium see
that and then closing on the week
two positions
scaling
long another longs partials
partial and then stop down
all of this
idea of I'm trying to make a lot of
money in a short period of time
that needs to go away too
I want to get a better payout than the
last guy I saw on the leaderboard of
ftml
or my funded Trader or TOP Step or
whatever I don't know all the companies
I guess I have no affiliation with none
of them but
foreign
you're doing this to make money you're
following the logic you're doing all the
things that you're expected to do based
on the things I'm teaching you
if
you do those types of things and you
stick within the narrative that I share
with my experience when I sit down with
you either on Twitter or in these videos
where I do analysis or I show you where
I think it's going to go next right now
we're at a point where I'm neutral
I'm neutral my targets have been met
so I sit still and I let let the market
then dictate to me what I want to do
next because it's already done it's
quarterly moved for me
it might continue higher or it might
reverse at this point I don't have an
opinion that's Hardline enough for me to
say I'm going to take a trade in this
direction I don't have a Target next
and I want you to grow comfortable in
those periods
because these periods here where
everybody blows their account
the folks that go out and say all right
now what next what what next
they are the ones that will absolutely
fail they're blowing their
demo accounts they will never pass a
funded account challenge
they won't hold a funded account
challenge in profit you know wherever
the stage is where you whatever you do
in the future you can do a profit split
if they get to that point they will blow
it they're they're constantly trying to
do something else they are not
comfortable in between trades they're
not and if that's how you feel
you have to work that out and these are
the periods where I sit still I'm
content
I'm content I murdered it on a higher
time frame weekly and daily chart for
you and for the folks that want to see
swing trade ideas where it's going to go
in the HTFs well there you
go over a thousand handles
in NASDAQ
and however many Hunter handles or so
and uh
e-mini s p
what did you do with the information
how did you use it what are you going to
do with it now at the end of this live
stream in five minutes
and like oh I watched this and he could
have said some things in five minutes
and not wasted my time you're never
going to be a profitable Trader if
you're thinking like that
because I'm telling you I would have
paid money to sit in something like this
today when I first started
I would have gladly spent money for this
because it wasn't ever in any of the
books and courses I bought it was not
there none of this stuff was out there
none of these things
you're hearing it from The Source these
These are these are Concepts that were
never meant to be in your hands they
were never meant to be understood by the
public
that's why they work so good because
it's the market it's the market
if you had a hundred 150 000 or 100 000
account so you did the threshold of a
hundred thousand whatever that is okay
and you did the work
of following the logic
doing what is necessary and you traded
when the setups were there not during
non-farm payroll okay and I'm answering
this too because people say ICT says
don't trade on non-farm payroll Fridays
and I made this much money and I made
that much money and blah blah
no
I say that new students new Traders new
developing Minds in these markets should
absolutely not trade on non-farm payroll
nobody should be trading during the hour
of non-farm payroll period
you can and I've done this before I've
shown you executions and recorded did a
whole thing
I did live sessions I've done sessions
with my private group everybody knows I
can trade on non-farm payroll okay I
don't need to be out here dancing for
the people that want me to dance for
them I don't owe you anything
what I'm giving you is the Insight on
how to do it so if you want to trade on
non-farm payroll Friday say you want to
you do the things I just talked about
here you wait
you wait until it
gets all the initial volatility in the
marketplace and as long as the objective
that you're looking for on a higher time
frame chart the daily
whether it be buy side liquidity or sell
side liquidity or a premium fair value
or a discount for everybody you got
they're the only four outcomes
and you're saying that's a complication
really
what do you use to get into a trade
right now that's made you lose money
consistently but you're still holding on
to it thinking it's going to turn around
to turn into some
Golden Goose for you that lays golden
eggs because I did all that stuff when I
was younger
I did all that same stuff folks
and I learned by losing lots of money
losing lots of accounts I've blown
dozens of accounts
I've done that okay and it took lots of
them for me to realize that I was not
going to Beat It by being tenacious
I had to stop doing all these retail
things that I kept buying books and
courses with
when I took myself away from all that
stuff and said okay
somebody's winning
every time I'm losing somebody is
winning what would they be seeing in
price and that was the start of what I
was setting myself up for to be who I am
today and a circle Trader
when you have an understanding of that
statistical probabilities state that the
average Trader you know is probably in
ill-informed they have no idea what
they're doing and I apologize my dogs
are going crazy
they probably see something outside of
like a deer or something
you sort of Saw Bailey this morning she
was freaking out we opened her pool up
yesterday because it's been really cool
in Maryland
unseasonably cool but there's two toads
swimming around and I had to fish them
out I can't run it to the bottom and she
doesn't like getting baths but she was
really looking like she wanted to jump
in there so
anyway Bella's doing better thank you
for your concern
but here's an example
of if you know what you're doing you
know what you're looking for
and you just want to have one trading
opportunity where you work your magic
one day and stop
do nothing else but you're staying with
the ideas that I'm teaching you from a
HTF basis
using the idea of liquidity and
inefficiencies sticking with a higher
time frame bias
only trading in that model looking for
inefficiencies on HTF
charts where large pools of buying and
selling will occur from the aspect of
smart money which isn't in books you
know the logic that they use to buy and
sell I'm not talking about Goldman Sachs
okay Goldman Sachs doesn't know this
okay they don't they don't know it
the things that you're learning
every high frequency trading algorithm
they Implement these ideas
what constitutes a high frequency
trading algorithm buy or sell
isn't on the basis of a pattern
it's not on harmonics
has nothing to do with anything
supplying a man has nothing to do with
that
there is a draw that price will stay
within a buy program it'll Buy
as long as this criteria is in in play
or in existence
and there will be a sell model
that they'll only shorten when these
specific things are met and there are a
there are many chaos high frequency
trading algorithms where they trade both
directions
all day long all day long up and down up
and down
that's the part I can't teach you
I can't I can't create a language
where
I just can't there you go I'm just going
to leave it that I can't so therefore
what I can teach I have
and any one of the things I've already
taught and I have more things I want to
teach between now November
but any one of these one
things these PD arrays okay if you apply
it with where the Market's going to go
where is it likely to go
and you stay with that in that model and
you trade around specific times of the
day
you can find profitability and it's not
hard
just Silver Bullet there's another model
I just gave out and I told you you can
use it in every one of the kill zones
London
New York am New York P.M
every single day you have three solid
opportunities
really good opportunities I taught you
how to trade the lunch hour
I mean think about it folks you have so
many ways to choose from but which one
makes the most sense to you which one
can you use
here's an example right here of using
the logic your baby brand new spanking
new right off the showroom floor you got
your 100 000 account you're funded now
okay
using the logic there you go nineteen
thousand dollars one day
would that be enough
would that be enough if half of that was
done by you
would that be enough
if one tenth
of this was done
would that be enough for you I don't
know what's going to be enough for you
but many of you look at this is this
isn't good enough
because you watch somebody else do
something folks literally I could sit
down here every single day enroll these
accounts up hundreds of thousands of
dollars in days
it's no effort for me to do it okay but
that doesn't communicate a realistic
objective for students
because if I show you these things all
the time
you're going to think when you make five
thousand dollars over a month that's not
enough and you're gonna press harder and
you're gonna wreck yourself
hi reward trading or really big results
that's for people that are trading with
the expectation of trying to fleece you
to sell you something I don't need to
sell anything to you
I don't want you to buy my books how's
that how's that work for you I saw a guy
tweet to me ICT is thinking about all
the money you want to make from the book
sales I'm trying to put so much into
this YouTube channel that you don't feel
inspired about
how's that work for you I don't care if
it sells a lot I don't care I only want
it in print because everybody out there
that has pretended they found this stuff
on their own there's no way none
of you Jokers would have ever learned
this stuff by looking at charts or
studying it you never would have learned
it because I'm telling you I was
influenced by people you'll never meet
sorry
and you hear these guys out there yeah
you know I figured this out you didn't
figure out you figured out where my
YouTube channel was and you found out
where the telegram channels had my
leaked mentorship videos that's what you
figured out
that's the only thing you did
the books will only be there for the
purposes of concreting it in history
that it came from me and that's it
that's all that's the only reason why
I'm doing it
but I'm putting so much into these
YouTube videos in the content that you
really won't need to buy it
you won't need to so stop listening to
the from other people out there
saying oh he's trying to get your money
I don't want you to buy the books period
don't buy them let them be
barely profitable for Amazon if you do
this I don't care
it's just the record of this is what
this is what it is this is what it came
from and this is how you use it and then
when people want to take that book and
rewrite it in their own language and
create courses I don't give a
I don't care because it's going to go on
forever it's always going to go on like
that okay I don't care I'm not losing
any sleep I'm not getting poor because
of it okay I'm not gonna diminish
because other people have taken my
and rebranded I don't care I'm confident
that they will now start putting things
in people's hands even if they do that
it's not classy
it doesn't have any any uh ethics behind
it
but people are still going to do it but
I know the end result will be the people
that buy it from them won't get hurt
because they'll know the real even
they call it something different I don't
care but none of this stuff I'm teaching
you existed in anything else and it's a
million dollar Bounty folks one million
dollars of my my cash in your
hands I'll drive it to your house give
you a cashier's check if you can prove
that all the stuff I'm teaching existed
anywhere in print prior to 1996. folks
it just doesn't exist
and this is the bottom line because
believe me a million dollars is a lot of
people out there could use a million
dollars and I'm telling you they all say
it oh it's replanted where the it
come from
where did it come from where did I
Rebrand nothing
you guys talked and talked to talk
instead of rebranded Chris Laurie I had
Chris Laurie come out there on Twitter
and say nope that's not my
now you're saying Al Brooks I'm waiting
for Al Brooks because he didn't talk
about her fair value guy
he didn't teach no invarian inversion
fair that he got he didn't teach as an
entry none of that none of that
even holds water I blow holes
through all that there's nothing
out there like this and when you
understand it you're gonna appreciate
that because you're holding something
that
99.9 of the people out there have no
idea even exists
and I've been hiding in plain sight
behind a demo account the whole time out
there hiding in plain sight
because it's a demo oh don't listen to
that guy
my kid my students are killing it
they're beating the out of
everybody else's students
they're murdering it I got people that
are doing so well they don't give a
about being on social media
what are you gonna do when you get the
skill set are you gonna go out there and
flex on social media I'm gonna go out
there and show the trolls are you gonna
live your life
and do what you want to do live how you
want to live
there's going to be people doubting you
all the time
who gives a
who cares none of that stuff means
anything
if they got the time and interest to do
that kind of stuff that means they're
miserable leave them there
leave them in that you can't fix them I
tried many years I tried to do that kind
of stuff for people
and I'm at that point man this is the 50
year old kicking in I just don't get it
either you subscribe to the ideas
because you've seen the effort the
efficacies of it and you've seen the
background of the logic I'm sharing and
how it's in the charts every day it
repeats over and over and over again
but is it for you
because I'm gonna be honest it's not for
everybody
it's not
for some of you you need a moving
average crossover you need to break out
strategy and as long as you have good
sound money management folks that can
make you money I'm not saying you can't
do that I'm not saying people that trade
with v-wop can't be profitable I watch
people on YouTube do it
they do it live
that's no problem I don't care
but that's
that's grade school level
to what's really going on in price
you're not going to get any closer than
perfect
I'm sorry
but that's just the way it is
and when I talk like this it sounds
arrogant it sounds like I'm I'm a
conceited prick I promise you I know I
was one in my 20s
but I'm just talking to you like a
friend
I'm trying to intervene because you're
holding yourself back
you're holding yourself back you are the
one holding yourself back it's not me
I've already taught you how to trade
I've already taught you how to read
price I taught you models I told you
entry strategies and and how to take
partials and where to move a stock I've
taught you now again why certain
imbalances will stay open
how do I know that go back and look at
the examples when I'm doing it it's
there
but I'm not obligated now and I wasn't
obligated in the past to prove anything
to you
I started out this whole thing on baby
Pips as a social experiment to see if I
created the same laboratory conditions
that I went through would I get an ICT
it never happened
I put all the things I taught in the
order to put I put them in all the
lectures all the video series all them
before I even did paid memberships
all those things that was the way I came
up in that order from my journals these
are the things that I did where I was
spending my attention and not one person
out of this entire community
came out looking like me
and that was the reason why I did it it
was a selfish reason I wanted to see
could I as a laboratory scientist mad
scientist try to create the same
scenario and with another ICT pop out
and they didn't
and because I got the feedback from
people that they were enjoying the
things I was putting out
the understanding they were gaining the
confidence they were getting
I fell in love with the idea of helping
more people
because originally
it was just a self-centered just
experiment to see if I could create it
and because I wasn't able to do it
I was pissed off
in my obsessive compulsive kicked in as
I get well then I'm going to put the
work in to try to create one
and then when more people started giving
me feedback
it became like a like a rocket fuel and
I was like wow this I really like this I
I love it I only would sell my
one-on-one mentorship
in the 90s you wouldn't even like you
would never I would have never gone on
the internet and shared this stuff then
never I would have never done it
I was selfish
and at the time I then believed if I
talked to everybody it would fail
everybody would do it and as I learned
more and more and more and learned how
the markets really book
yeah I don't give a I could
literally put commercials on the
internet and on the TV that had no sales
pitch and say come to this YouTube
channel and learn how to do this I
promise you you want to spend any money
but you'll be better than you ever
thought you could as a Trader stop
buying people's courses
it's done
in the channel will grow like crazy
I make all kinds of AD Revenue
I don't need it
I'm walking away in November November
I'm closing the chapter on Inner Circle
Trader I want to be Michael Joe
Huddleston I want to be that I'm going
to I want to be the husband I want to
meet the Dad hopefully you know my kids
give me grandkids and I can do whatever
I do spoil them and that's what I want
to do
everyone wants to know what I'm going to
do next
that's what I want to do I want to be
humdrum but me again
and that's all I want
but in my absence I want to be able to
look in on all of you
and see what you're doing and hear from
you
send me an email I'm going to keep
innercircle Trader gmail.com always
and if you have a testimony you want to
share with me you know that's great you
know do that let me know what you're
doing
I'm always interested in that I have a
lot of emails I'll always get to you you
know in a real timely manner
that's not the uh
mode of contact it is optimal but um
Twitter is while I'm on it but in
November I will no longer tweet but my
Twitter's
space in my Twitter account will be
active
and my YouTube videos will stay up
I just won't be doing any more of them
okay I'm confident when I'm done with
you all
come November you will have had the best
learning experience from me as a mentor
the best I can do
and I don't claim to be the best Mentor
I'm not
um
I know invariably
some of you will do very very well with
this information
and you'll probably write books and
you'll probably make courses and you'll
probably do whatever and actually teach
it better once I'm done divulging what
it is of not you know made available to
people
my only request is is you credit me
I don't I don't give a what you do
with it after that because if I cared I
wouldn't put it out here
but I want you to give me the
opportunity to give God the glory for it
that's what I don't want you to rob me
from I don't care if you make because
I've made millions of dollars for people
in the Middle East I've made millions of
dollars for people in Africa that
they've sold my okay these people
have made lots of money selling my
videos okay one of my biggest trolls
have been selling my videos but pretends
he hates me his whole channel is about
me okay but he sold my and I know
and I don't give a I don't care
he's got kids let him feed him the point
is this I don't care
I don't care
eat from my table for free I have plenty
you're not going to starve me I can do
this stuff on my own
and I want to see what you all do with
it
and I don't mean I bought a Lamborghini
that's not what I'm looking for I want
to see what you do with this in terms of
helping other people how are you
impacting other people
and I don't mean by teaching people
I'm talking about how you impacted their
lives
what did you do for them did you buy him
a house did you pay off their student
debt for them did you help them out when
they needed a car and they just can't
afford to get one
do you support families financially that
are destitute
and you're not trying to get a reward
for it I promise I will never ever ever
share that publicly I will never say
this person told me this this because
that's your reward then
but I'm asking you I I know I've put
people on the rich end with my content
and they rebranded and made mentorships
and that's how they made their money
that's not what I wanted to do that's
not my target my target is to transform
the lives and the minds and the thought
processes of all of you as students to
not just simply listen to me as a mentor
about markets but how to live your life
better because I did not do the right
things
and I want you to know that I did not do
the right things I was not there for my
wife as much as I should have been I've
failed as a dad I should have been at
their games I should have done all these
things that's why I give you those
lectures
so that way you don't make those same
mistakes in the process of finding your
success and living in your success
because you you can succeed into failure
I did
lots of money
the ability to live however you want to
live and buy stuff
and you have a deficit in the emotional
category for fatherhood and husbandry
it's not all about the money folks right
now it does feel like that
but there has to be a purpose for all of
it and how you live your life and what
you do with it
that's impactful not only to yourself
but the people that you're helping
and as a 20 year old when I had this
information it was all about me
and I've wanted it to be about me
I don't want to be the center of
attention I don't want to be at it all
and
I hope that you understand that when I
do depart in November
I have all of your best interests in
mind and I'm all rooting for you I I'm
always rooting for you I'm
constantly in prayer that you all
receive
what it is I'm trying to convey and
sometimes when I've listened to
recordings or whatnot
I wish I could go back in time and add
something else
okay
um
it would have been much more
helpful if I would have said this or
that so like I said I'm not the best
mentor and
if I don't do it for you come November
don't give up
keep working towards it
because if you see just a little bit of
evidence that you can do it once in a
while that's okay
because long term consistently
profitable has a period of hit and miss
Break Even if you can get to that point
where your break even where you make a
little bit but then you lose it but you
don't blow out that's progress
that's progress and you'd be surprised
how many people come to me in that stage
they've done all this stuff they make a
little bit of money then they lose it
and they can't they don't blow their
account but they just can't find
profitability you are the best student
in my hands
you are the best one
so don't think that that's a reason for
you to feel like you know I'm feeling as
I'm doing this because I can't be
profitable I'm not going to waste any
more time with this stuff
come into these lectures
and do the things I'm telling you to do
and just sit back and watch the
transformation
it'll happen
it will happen
the ones that don't do well under me are
the brand new never learned how to trade
don't know anything and they have no
reason
to have that velcro effect
that I can I can't cling to them or they
can't cling to me long enough to let
them have this logic seep into their
understanding and then they see it for
themselves it's too easy for them to
walk away
it's too easy
because they don't have anything to to
lean on as experience or Reason to see
well let me stick with this
if I did signals if I said you know I'm
buying here I'm selling here the only
thing that's going to do is grow a
dependency in me
and I don't want any of my students to
be dependent on me I want to be
independently minded so they go out and
they do their own thing and they're
confident they they say ICT it's been
great I learned from you but I don't
need you anymore babe I'm gone
Watch Me Fly and I want to watch you fly
I want to see that
but you have to put some work in and you
got to let the information
be presented in the manner that I'm
presenting because I don't know how to
do it any better
I don't know how to do it better than
I'm doing
but I know it's working for a lot of
people
and all you have to do is keep showing
up keep studying and fall in love with
this part of it because this is what
you're going to do the rest of your life
so you might as well love it
you might as well fall in love with it
it's just like your second spouse
okay I mean you're gonna have to love
doing this
if you're miserable if you hate Trading
this ain't for you
it ain't for you but if you know that
you're going to lose once in a while
but it's okay nothing changes anything
this means that you gotta fix that to go
to a new Equity high it's fine that's
the right mindset and you're not in a
hurry to get there
regardless of how old or young you are
just relax let it happen it took me six
years to find myself
many of you probably already have what
is you're going to be trading with but
you're wrestling because every time I
bring out something new you want that to
be the thing oh wow that's new let me
try that
if you already got something you're
seeing results with stay with that
stay with that find some consistency
with that and then once you've done it
for a few months if you want to
supplement your understanding Del Ventus
you know supplementary studies with
other things that you are interested in
but you only need one thing
one thing
and you can make all the money you'd
ever want
so
hopefully hopefully you guys have
learned something today I had a lot of
fun spending some time with you
um if
you know like I said if you like this
stuff and you want to see me do it again
on uh tomorrow
and a Thursday I guess it would be so
Wednesday and Thursday I'm heading out
with my wife on Friday for the weekend
and I'll be home on Tuesday so I won't
be doing anything on Monday so
I think that'll be it for this one
until I'll talk to you next time
be safe