alright folks welcome back
this is a new year and some
new discussions we're going to talk
about major moves with seasonal
tendencies now i'm going to talk about
specifically
commodities in this lecture now it's
important to know that
if some of you are hardline crypto
traders or
forex traders there are seasonal
tendencies
in forex there are seasonal tendencies
in
the dollar index there's seasonal
tendencies in stocks
so try not to read so much
into this lesson and think of it as only
applying to the markets i'm going to
refer to
in its delivery okay so
understand a seasonal tendency is a road
map it's a
generalization of what has happened in
the past
and if there is some measure of
repeating phenomenon okay in other words
if
we think that the market is going to go
up at a particular time of the year
to a specific time of the year and we
measure it over
the last five years over the last 10
years the last 15 years the last 20 and
25 years
there are services out there and i'll
turn you on to one
in this teaching that i have a lot of
faith in myself personally
but it's important to note that and i'm
not
saying this is going to be the case
every single time you look at the
marketplace
there are some certain caveats that have
to be considered
and i'll briefly discuss those as we go
along but i'm going to try to keep this
video short
because i know some of you have very
short attention spans when it comes to
my lectures because
i think i'm talking too much but i'm
just trying to give you an extra value
and insights that you would otherwise
have to pay for elsewhere
so let's take a look at a
dollar index chart to begin with
all right so we're looking at the dollar
index and i'm using tradingview.com
all right so you can find this
information yourself you can go pull up
your own version
of this chart and take a look at the
things i'm referring to here
and it should be on par with what i'm
showing
in my charts now i'm going to refrain
from showing any kind of real
annotations until we get to the very
specific market
i want to talk about but i'm going to
talk about a few of them
and review some of the
potential opportunities that make their
sales
available each year in these markets
so i've always begin my
analysis with the dollar index okay and
the reason why i do that
is because i want to know if we are on a
risk on or risk off environment now risk
on
would be where the market has the dollar
index going lower
as we see here around july of 2020 to
present
and that would allow or permit the
likelihood of markets to rally or go
higher and that being like
foreign currency against the dollar and
also
commodities because if the dollar is
going lower that is more or less
inflationary
for commodity prices so they're going to
see a an appreciation in
the cost of producing and or purchasing
commodities so if we can just simply
understand that going forward everything
in this teaching
will be very easy to follow along if
you're someone that's new to my channel
or new to commodities or trading in
general
you're probably going to want to watch
other video series on this
youtube channel and it'll help fill in
some of the gaps i'm certain that you
have watching this if
the dollar index is going higher that's
going to be deflationary for
commodity prices and also for foreign
currencies
they're going to go lower in
relationship to the higher prices in
dollar
now if we have that risk on risk off
scenario
in mind when dollar is going lower
that's risk on
when dollars going higher that's risk
off
if we have this period of time
when the market is clearly indicating
that the dollar wants to go lower
that means we are on the watch for
big moves on the upside okay really big
moves
one such big move this year was the
soybean
market and i've been very vocal about
that my students know about that
and i've also tipped the community off
in my youtube channel and if you look at
that over here
i have a bunch of things that i've
shared publicly here now when i look at
this
i can see that it doesn't really give me
a specific date and i'm actually
learning something as i do this video
with you right now
i'm going to include the actual date
that i posted okay so i wish it would
have given me a specific date but
nonetheless it is what it is
the uh the thumbs up that's highlighted
here
just so you guys know i like to post the
comment
and then i wait for the first thumbs up
and i'm usually the second thumbs up
because it's my way of checking to make
sure that it's
viewable on your end because i've had
members in the past say i can't see my
post or you know the posts i make to the
community tab they don't
they're saying they didn't see it or
they did say they couldn't see it so i
usually wait for someone to do a thumbs
up
that means it's visible on urine as the
audience and then i'm typically the
second thumbs up
so it's not me being conceited or loving
myself it's just
a way for me to know that okay that post
has been seen
it's public now and i can leave youtube
and go about my
business somewhere else but
if you look at about a month ago i
mentioned
that if you take a look at the grain
reports soybeans as i stated since june
of 2020
was poised to continue to rally into
2021 and i state here
corn will be next now notice there's no
edit here like you see here there's an
edit
it means i want to not change a typo or
something like that
here i'm telling you specifically a
month ago that corn
is going to be the next big rally okay
it's going to go up
why well if you look at here i'm telling
you that china's buying everything it
can
and i give you the reasons i'm not going
to read it you can see it here
but i also talked about bitcoin and i
called 20 000
before christmas and when i was on
twitter which i'm not now i also posted
in july of
2020 i stated that i felt that
we would see bitcoin 30 000
by the end of the year going into 2021 i
was off by one day
so sorry the
next level i called for bitcoin and i'll
let you scroll so you can find this on
your own
i called forty thousand and went to like
forty two thousand something
and then it has recently uh had some
difficulties
so i'm making calls here
publicly because i've had people in the
past
make some derogatory comments about how
i don't really put my neck out on the
line say this is what i think is going
to happen
and i used to do that a lot on twitter
but i don't have twitter anymore so this
has replaced my twitter
and you can follow along and see what
i'm
suggesting in my expectation i don't do
everything
but i toss out once in a while something
for you guys to
study and we're going to take a look at
the corn market
here in relationship to the soybean
market
and we're going to use that dollar
bearishness from july as a
context to anticipating higher prices on
every market i'm going to cover in this
teaching so let's move on over to
soybeans first all right so here's the
soybean market and
in june of this past year
i was warming all my students up to the
idea that we were going to
eventually make a run above these highs
here and that we would have a
pretty big bull market going into the
commodity market because of the dollar
index being bearish
now some of you that are in my
mentorship are getting really nervous
right now because you're thinking i'm
teaching mentorship
when all i'm doing is talking about what
you've experienced before it happened
so please don't send me emails okay i
know some of you are highly protective
and i love you all for that
but i want to kind of teach something
broad brush
and i'm really not doing harm
to what you are participating in so just
give me the liberty here to be able to
be a teacher
outside of mentorship too because it's
why this channel exists
the there is no mentorship joining now
by the way
so we have closed the doors do not send
me emails
and it is what it is this is not a sales
pitch it's not meant for you hey come in
and join learn how to do this
everyone that's already emailed me if
you've emailed me and we haven't got to
yet
that's fine we'll get to you and we'll
consider you but anyone new
we're not taking anybody else in so it's
too many people it is what it is
and we're done but
if you look at what has transpired since
june of last year we've had this
extremely
handsome price run on soybeans
so if you were to use the
we'll say eight dollars and 80 cents a
bushel
okay right in here you're not getting
the best entry here not getting the best
entry here
but from 880 up to 1080 that's 10 000
per contract okay that's twenty thousand
dollars if it goes to twelve eighty
and if it goes to fourteen eighty
that's another ten thousand dollars
how many bitcoin moves
have you seen in your lifetime as a
crypto trader
the one we just recently seen and the
big run up in 2017 right
i called 2017 and i called the top then
i mentioned many times that you know new
traders that
got exposed to crypto feels like that's
the only market
that uh traders could have gotten
wealthy on
and i kind of taught this back in 2017
and in 2018 and 2019 every time i get a
new student that the first question
comes to mind is
you know do you regret missing bitcoin
because i've been very public and state
that i don't
trade crypto i didn't trade bitcoin but
whenever i make my calls public you know
obviously it comes with
a great deal of kickback if
if it opposes the view of a certain
group of my
audience members i don't do this to
upset anyone purposely
but you know i get more requests for me
sharing what i think is going to happen
than people coming back and saying i
really wish you wouldn't have said that
so i try to be as open as i possibly can
and tell you what i think is going to
happen where i think it's going to go
and
for the most part why i think it's going
to go there
and every call that i've made publicly
you're welcome to look at and weigh in
the balances
but these are big moves that take place
in the commodity market and you don't
need a bitcoin move
to define wealth because
what you see here can be the same thing
if not more than what you saw in bitcoin
this past what seven months
or yeah six or seven months so the same
amount of money that one could have made
in that bitcoin run
you could do in this right here and i
stated this very market
when i was making the case and argument
with the crypto traders that were saying
i should be uh regretting not being a
part of the largest
bull market in history well there's
always a big bull market
there's always a big mega trade okay
every year the markets create them
and i tried to state this before that
i have tools that help me fare those out
and one of the things that i look for is
a seasonal tendency
if a seasonal tendency indicates that
the market's likely to go
up by itself doesn't mean anything
but if we can find a time when the
market is bullish
and a seasonal tenancy is suggesting
that
historically it usually goes up
then we have something to work with and
then it's a matter of just waiting for
market structure to get in sync with
those two
underlying premise if the market is
bullish
and the market is showing a bullish
seasonal tendency
we wait for the market to give us a
bullish market structure
so we have multiple things in here and
i've talked about soybeans before
so i'm not going to try to redo that
here and waste time
but we we see markets making runs like
this a lot in hindsight but it's all
together something different when you're
able to see it
outline it before it happens and call it
with
you know a large degree of appreciation
on the upside
so we're seeing a huge amount of
potential
price run that would otherwise
be either ignored
or not expected
there's a lot of people on youtube that
are claiming they got the signals at
work
they got the the calls that make the
money they got this and they got that
and they're pointing to these tiny
little itty bitty fluctuations in the
marketplace
tiny little fluctuations and i outline
for free give it to you on a silver
platter
30 000 points in bitcoin
publicly given to you if
you look at the soybean market i showed
you that one as well
and a month ago i tipped you off with
corn
so let's take a look at corn
all right i'm gonna go to corn and
we'll use the nearby contract which is
march 2021.
okay so here you go a month ago
right there okay
corn gonna go higher
it's gonna be the next big move that's
in the community tab on my youtube
channel
unedited okay i got
a lot of flack from people saying that
i've used
rented servers that i've done fraud
that i cheat people i lie to people
i give them a false impression that i
can trade and
nobody's ever seen me call markets
before it happens and it's just
that still finds its way in discussions
in certain corners on the internet
and i have been giving you million
dollar maker
moves okay i'm giving you the big moves
because i can and i'm sharing them
publicly i'm not selling them i'm not
making you
come into my mentorship to get them
i'm giving you for free because i can
afford to do that
i don't need to have people pay me for
signals
i'm interested in teaching you how to
find these things
and honestly everything on this youtube
channel
shows you how to find these moves but
you don't want to listen
to the discussions and the lecture
points that are boring
and it's one thing to see people
go out and take my content and just give
me some
latitude here i gotta make this point
there's a lot of people out here taking
my stuff and making youtube videos about
it because
times are tough right now and they want
to try to get a group
get over a thousand subscribers since
they start making some ad revenue
because they need a hustle because
either they lost their job or they're
paranoid because everything is going on
this year or in past year rather
and they need to make money i understand
that okay
but when you are trying to teach
something that you don't know
you're doing more harm to the audience
and
if you think you know what i can do and
what i teach
then you should be able to pull out
these market moves before they happen to
not talk about them in hindsight that's
the difference between me
everybody says oh ict's a scalper he's
an intraday trader
he's mr 10 pips 20 pips no but i can do
more with that type of trading than
anybody else
that's trading these larger big position
trade swings
because i can parlay that up and have
velocity behind the equity
but you don't need to trade a lot if you
listen to what i teach
you can sit back and be very passive in
investment
and capture these big moves we're going
to assume that you were in here
around that 4.20 cents a bushel
and went above today 5.20
a bushel that is a five thousand dollar
price move per contract
now it took a month to get it
but if you would have had say i don't
know
ten call options you wouldn't had the
full
exposure required for margin
to do the trade you could have done some
call options
and whatever you paid for the option
that would be the amount of risk
total plus commission that you would
have looked at
as incurred risk
five grand for a month some of you
probably don't make that in a month
i know when i was working as a younger
man
i wasn't making that much money you know
we're talking about
back in the 80s but uh
1980s it's it sounds funny to say it
like that
and i'm laughing because i think about
how my son was
asking me earlier before i made this
video he asked me to take his dad
um what cool cars were there back in the
1900s
and he did to hear him say it that way
made it sound like i'm even older than i
really am
but the the idea of
looking for these types of price moves
and seeing how much is available
on one position okay if you can find
trades like this
and it can present moves like this or
like what i showed in the soybean market
those types of moves if you can find
them and fair them out
over time they can make
you wealthy now the problem is this
like it was for me when i first started
in 1992
i read a book ken roberts
his commodity course and you all
probably heard us enough i'm not gonna
you know beat it up you know even more
but
i felt that i was going to be one of
those success stories
and i was going to make a fortune in my
first year
and i was going to do everything in the
book that said and in my first trade i
lost 50
of the account i've made no bones about
it it is what it is
and even my students that first come to
my youtube channel
or they traded other markets and they've
tasted pain and loss because they don't
really know what they're doing
then they see what i do in these videos
and
it opens their eyes to what they did not
know and they can go into
old data and say wow i can really see
this is making perfect sense
that's the difference between
understanding what the markets really do
versus what the markets did and let's
write a book about it
you know it doesn't work it doesn't help
okay
if all these books were able to help
people make money
then they wouldn't need to make more
books the the people that made books 100
years ago
would have been enough there would be no
reason to make another book
so it's this trap that you all follow
and i did it too
trust me i did it i wasted a fortune on
buying books and courses when i first
started
and honestly none of that crap worked
none of it it caused me to lose more and
feel even more insecure about myself
and it it was like an endless circle of
always learning but never coming to the
truth
when i got exposed to how the markets
really
book it changed everything
and i went back in and turned everything
else upside down
and it started working
these ideas here i'm just going to make
it very easy for you
if you go to amazon
and you buy the book how many million
dollar trading commodities last year by
larry williams
okay let's go over to amazon and i'll
show you what that
looks like all right so here's the book
i'm talking about and you've heard me
mention this before
so this is where you can go and get it
notice that i'm not giving you a link
i'm not doing an affiliate program i'm
not trying to get paid for you making a
purchase
i'm just freely giving you the
information if you don't want to buy the
book
then don't buy the book but this book
was one of the first
books that i bought that made sense
and made me money so
the things i like about this book and
let's see if it can pull it up
here table contents this chapter here
chapter four
where he says my million dollar
fundamental system
and going into
this area here he basically covers
all of the most important things
that make commodity markets move on a
large scale
okay so all of these things here chapter
four
that to me is
the real shining chapter in it
doesn't mean that there's other parts in
this book that isn't interesting or
noteworthy but there are things like he
talks about the
phases of the moon and the influence of
buying and selling on that i don't
subscribe to any of that
but i'm not here to beat him up because
he was my first mentor
so i'm not trying to say that ken
roberts wasn't a mentor because he was a
mentor because
you know that was the very first book i
read but it lost money
everything i did with it was completely
i abandoned everything i learned from
him
and the next mentor i had was larry
williams
and this book was highly influential now
if you go through this book
you will see the effects and the
impression that larry
had on me and you can also see
i amped up especially if you're in uh
the mentorship level stuff um
and again i hate to say it that way
because it sounds like i'm dang i don't
want anyone
asking to join because i'm not taking
anyone new i have to keep putting that
in there i'm sorry
but if the students that
like who we were all in a big room okay
we were all like at a
a live seminar and i said okay who's
here that's in mentorship
raise your hand and you'd see whatever
you know number of people would be there
to raise their hand
and i'd say okay who has gone through
this book i'm talking about here
and they would raise their hand and then
i'd say okay now raise your hand
if you've seen me amplify and fill in a
lot of the things for precision
based rules with this information
because this was the foundation i
started with
i started with this and i built on it
and i built on it and built on it and
it just further solidifies the
importance of having a solid foundation
if you're going into this with like
elliott wave
okay or harmonic patterns
you that is a
niche it's a gimmick
it's a stylized
perception it's not objective it's not
it's subjective this chapter four
that is objective okay and then
if you read it you'll you'll know
exactly what i'm referring to what makes
it objective
it's rooted in real
market truths that are either present in
the marketplace or they're not
it's binary whereas if we had a
collection of people that traded
harmonic
patterns or if we had a collection of
people that traded elliot wave
they would have a difference of opinion
i'm certain of it
if we were giving them the same market
and
that is what highlights the
in my mind the lunacy in following that
kind of stuff
and don't get me wrong i wasted years
doing both of those things
okay i know about both of them it isn't
like i read a book and
you know i never dabbled in it i did all
that stuff i've done point-and-figure
charts
i've done everything i've done
everything out there
for as far as trading goes and honestly
all of it is flawed because it doesn't
start on the basis of having
real logic behind it it's based on a
pattern
by itself they go in looking for
patterns or wave counts
versus understanding what it is that
sets the market up for a move higher or
lower
and where it should draw to now
larry doesn't do that but larry gives
you
the three primary rules and tools that
he looks for that sets up these big
million dollar maker
well i shouldn't say a million dollar
maker but uh fortune makers
okay um what's a fortune to me you know
if it makes
fifty thousand dollars yeah that's a
small fortune you know i don't look at
for fifty thousand dollars
the same way i did when i was in 1992
but
you know if i lost fifty thousand
dollars i'd you know i'd want it back
you know it's it's a meaningful amount
of money to me
and to most of you listening that's
probably a significant amount of money
as well
especially if you're a new student and
or never traded
profitably you would love to have that
type of windfall
victory in trading if you're looking for
a book
to give you a real solid foundation to
understand
why a market should go up or go down
this chapter right here in this very
book
i think that you should subscribe
to what's being shown in that chapter
i don't get anything for this i don't
get a kickback
larry doesn't know i'm even doing it and
i mean it i've said this book many times
over the last
10 years or 11 years now talking about
things from
you know books that were influential or
books that were
worth your time reading this is a 1970s
book
1970s i was a child at the time when
this was
published and put in print
and it's still effective today why
because
it's rooted on things that work
and the man made money with it not a
little bit of money he made a million
dollars
and then he did it again in 1987 for
people that doubted him didn't believe
he
really made money with it and he won the
world's cup robbins contest
for futures trading in 1987 and still
holds 11 000
as the highest percentage gain in that
contest history so
if you take this information and go back
into
a market like this you'll see
a lot of those things that he's teaching
exist in this market here
okay and before we had this big
extrapolated price move here
i told you in my community tab on my
youtube channel
right here a month ago corn will be next
and i'll give you the fundamental
reasons why okay
so uh when it comes to fundamental data
i do consider it when it comes to
livestock like feeder cattle live cattle
lean hogs they're all commodity markets
i look at it
in regards to the grain reports apart
from that
i do not consider fundamental data at
all
but if i'm trading agricultural markets
which are commodity markets as i just
mentioned
then i'm going to consider it and other
markets like the food groups like
coffee cocoa and sugar if we go into
if we look at coffee this is kind of
like the the heart of the teaching here
today
if you look at this price fractal it is
something that i have taught many times
with the medium of 4x
and i'll give you a minute pause the
video before i put the annotations up
but try to look at what you think you
see in this price action
and then when you're ready unpause the
video and you'll see my annotations in
the discussion going forward
okay we're going to add annotations now
all right so we are looking at coffee
okay and there is a seasonal tendency
for coffee to rally about the second
week or third week of july
i want you to consider the likelihood of
mid-july being a seasonal tendency for
coffee to go higher
now think about what i showed you on the
dollar index
in july it was going lower it created an
important high and
just fell out of bed went lower
that again sets the stage for markets to
go higher
in the commodity market just like it
does in
forex so from having a macro perspective
and looking at things seasonally
blending those things together
it gives us framework to find really big
moves
you don't have to be an intraday trader
you don't have to worry about the power
on a daily candle if you don't have time
to do that
if you don't have the life framework
that promotes that type of trading
you don't need to do it don't feel like
you have to be
an intraday trader don't feel that you
have to be a short-term trader
if you look at these types of price
moves and you think well you know i
could be a participant in something like
that that makes sense
i don't want to have to be relying on
making a decision
each day buying and selling buying and
selling because that takes a certain
type of personality that isn't really
everyone's cup of tea now
i started with this type of trading
swing trade position trading
i started that way and it was like
pulling teeth
i just couldn't endure it i didn't want
to deal with it it was too slow
doesn't mean i can't do it technically
it just means i can't
submit to it from a personality
standpoint
but the analysis concepts that i use
this helps me frame every type of trade
that i'm comfortable with which is
day trading intraday and short term
that's my
forte that's where i excel and i can
find lots of those types of day trades
short term trades or swing trades
intraday in the
overall price model that's being shown
here now what am i actually showing here
well if you look at the relative equal
highs over here
you know this is a buy side liquidity
pool and the market will likely want to
go back to that point we also have a
consolidation
that leaves the consolidation comes back
up to the consolidation in here
and drops lower and another level of
decline
hits a important level 100 and in
rallies
it breaks a short term high here so we
have a shift in market structure
so when the market comes back down into
a bullish order block which is this down
close candle right there
we have an optimal trade entry so we're
using the lowest low to the highest high
projecting that up that gives us two and
a half
standard deviations and above the buy
side liquidity pool
so that means about one dollar and 34
cents per pound
for coffee as an upside objective back
here
in july mid july when the seasonal
tendency for
coffee is bullish the market rallies up
it touches these relative equal highs
sells off a little bit goes back into a
bullish order block
here and we have another optimal trade
entry that sends it up again
to a target above the buy side liquidity
pull resting at relative equal highs
so if you look at the total range i'm
going to take this off here
if you look at the total range from this
run here to here you can't say that you
would be a buyer here but you can assume
that you're
close to this area here not at this very
low at 101
which is the best case area for a low
and the best case area
for an extra high is the 135.65
so inside this range the best case which
is impossible
would be 34.65
handles okay or 375 dollars
times 34.6 because the point value for
coffee is 3.75 cents per point and every
handle
and what's a handle from like for
instance 134
to 135 that's one full handle that would
be represented by
375 that's
100 points or one handle price move
in this case the price moved twelve
thousand nine hundred ninety three
dollars and seventy five cents per
contract
from here to here
all of this is a market maker buy model
with a seasonal tenancy mid july with
the dollar index selling off in july
which we were looking for ourselves as
my group was
following along and this type of price
move here
is what i teach i teach these types of
moves
i don't say buy here sell there but i
guide you in every year i take my
students back in and say okay
this is the seasonal tendency this is
what we were looking for this is what we
called in dollar index that sets the
tone for all these other markets
i point to the markets to have these
potential extrapolated price moves
and we've looked at corn there's five
thousand dollars
we looked at soybeans twenty thirty
thousand dollars there
we have bitcoin thirty 000
points i'm not sure what that would
equate to you in terms of dollars
but these are moves
that are not small they're very
significant
they're major moves and if your tools
can help you fared out these types of
price action moves
every single year this is where
the majority of your focus should be but
you will not
find them if you're just lazily going
through the charts looking for
any old pattern for the pattern's sake
you have to have the logic behind it
so notice what i've combined here i've
combined a market maker by model
which is what i teach even on this
youtube channel for free
big round number one dollar per pound
for coffee and i'll let you go out to
the higher time frame charts you can do
that on your own
and see what one dollar mark looks like
in hindsight
and so you can see a big support level
around there
and also if you use the
kc well let's just do it
kc and then use the front
current month use this on kc number one
exclamation you click on that and you'll
see that we have
this down closed candle prior to this
run up
there's your order block all it's done
was worked off of that
went right into it here and created your
optimal trade entry
and then rallied now you have to use
the trading month's contract
when you're looking at commodities
whereas this is just a
a cumulative chart of
all of the nearby current front month
contracts right now the front contract
month for
coffee is march 2021 prior to march 21
it was december 2020 and prior to that
it was september 2020
so these contracts expire in the
commodity market forex you don't have
that issue
okay but in futures or if you're trading
commodity markets
you have to be aware of that so if
you're looking at over here we don't
have those
pretty easy to see relative equal highs
like we see
in the march contract
here see that so
you have to look at what's available in
the price action
but you all know the market make or buy
model
you understand the optimal trade entry
because that's the flagship pattern here
in this channel and you understand order
blocks because i've introduced them
publicly here
and we know that a run on relative equal
highs is the draw on liquidity that's a
standard procedure that i've taught very
publicly here
on this channel and it's caught fire and
everybody's talking about it now
that's wonderful i just wish that the
folks that were doing that
would just make a reference and say hey
look you know i picked this up from
ict and you'll get more respect for me
by doing that
it doesn't mean go and take everything i
have and teach it all over again but i
know that this was going to be popular
when i gave it out
and it's just unfortunate a lot of
people trying to
glory hound and take credit for
something they didn't earn
or work for so these are pretty big
moves
and every single year we have these
types of moves
so you don't need one of these types of
moves okay
i mean people waited around for years
for this to occur
in here i called six thousand to twenty
and then changed gears before twenty
and said no it's not going to go so at
nineteen seven i said it's gonna go to
six thousand and then from when we got
to six thousand i said it's going to go
to 3 000
and i failed to be accurate there it
went to like 3 400
or 32 i can't remember recall exactly
where it was but
the point is is it eventually dropped
down to um
something in here i'm not sure exactly
what the low was
yeah 32 something or 31
and 31 22 in there
and then we had this little run here in
and everybody thought that was going to
run above here and i was like no i don't
think it's going to happen
and we tanked here during the pandemic
and then that extreme set the stage for
the low and then from that point all the
way up to where we went to 42 something
where is it at 40.
42 000 and that was it
and then we fell out of bed so it
dropped 10
000 points in short order
in here does it want to go lower
i don't know to me it doesn't have a
seasonal tendency yet
so it doesn't fit this discussion but
i'm trying to draw a contrast and please
don't take this as me kicking
sand in the face of crypto traders okay
i'm not doing that i've done it in the
past
okay i'm not i'm not trying to say it i
didn't do that in the past because i did
but all i'm trying to remind you is that
big market moves weren't invented by
crypto
okay there are fortune making moves
occurring
every single year for those individuals
that know how to find them
and that's why people like myself
used to have a lot of fun reading
people saying that you know everybody
else that isn't trading crypto
can't catch big huge windfall price
moves like
it created in 2017 2019 and now
obviously what was seen in 2020 going
into
2021 there's a way to find these big
moves
and i gave you the foundation that i
started with
now that's not all that i do i've put a
lot of structure on top of that
foundation
that's unique to me
it's not white cough okay it's not
supply and demand it's not all those
things that people like to say it is
because they want to use those those
name tags when they're teaching my
content
and you hear them say order block you
hear them say breaker those are terms
i invented i invented those terms
they're they're coined by me
so when i hear them and if my students
hear them
right away you know you just know that
this is a derivative of
what i have been teaching and it's just
it's offensive
to see people do that and not give
credit where it's due
because you didn't endure all the
hardships
all the pain the loss monetarily family
friends everything insanity in many
instances to get this so
hopefully you can now think about
how seasonal tendencies and i gave you
one in this
lesson here coffee is one
that if you go back and look at your
data now here's what's going to happen
i'm already going to predict this okay
you're going to hear in certain circles
if you are part of
one that has the
conversation of ict coming up once in a
while
they're going to go into the charts and
they're going to look for times where in
july mid july
coffee didn't go up it's going to go
down well you got to look at what the
market's been doing
ahead of july if it's bullish going into
july that's your
indication that this is a good strong
seasonal tendency for coffee
and there are times where
if you look at coffee
and some of you're like i ain't never
trading coffee why is this guy keep
talking about this
this market if you look at coffee on a
i'll do a weekly chart okay
and you can see we've had some spikes
and such
okay but you want to study go back as
far as the data will permit it
but looking at all this right here is
this market bullish or bearish
it's obviously bearish so are you going
to be
likely to anticipate a mid-july
run higher in coffee in this instance
here's the thing
it can happen but it's most likely not
going to happen
okay is that very clear for you if the
market's bullish
like it's been here then in july
there you go there's july right there
it's going to run higher
boom now if you look at something that's
bearish
let's find july and there you go mid
july
now we get we have a little bit of a run
but look how fast it gives up the ghost
and goes lower
you see that there's a difference
between knowing what you're talking
about and just trying to look for
something to say it doesn't work
that's what trolls do that's what
critics do
here's another area bearish um
july right here mid-july
there okay ahead of that is it bullish
or bearish
it's been going lower so is the seasonal
tension likely to send
coffee higher on that year no and look
what happened it fell out of bed even
more
so if we look at a time when
we had a break in market structure here
we have
mid july right there right
there it dropped a little bit and then
dropped again
so it was a break in market structure
but has it really made a bullish move
not yet it's still in transition in here
same thing we're going to go to a july
and that's last year and there you go
so i'll counsel you to go back and look
at all the times when
coffee was bullish
and when it was bearish
okay here's a nice area where it's been
bullish right
july mid july right there
bam higher
now we had reached a level up in here
and i'll let you look at the
higher time frame charts and study it
but here's july
that year and it rallies
doesn't take up the high but that's a
nice rally but then it falls out of bed
because we hit an important level here
and i'll let you go back and look at
what that is historically using a
monthly chart
and i'm really doing you a disservice by
trying to go through
some of them i'm just giving you the
argument that some of my critics
you know the thumbs down crew they like
to thumbs down my video
the which i love i love that because it
makes me smile
who can look at videos like this where
i'm literally giving you
lottery ticket winning numbers that work
over and over and over again okay for
free
i'm doing this for free there's no sales
pitch
you can't join my mentorship now i just
love doing this
and if you like these kind of lessons
and you find it useful to you
or inspiring you just give it a thumbs
up it doesn't cost you anything
just click the thumbs up and there it is
it's done why do i want that to happen
because i want this channel to be bigger
than it is
because there's a lot of people out here
on youtube
that are misinforming people with things
that don't work
and the trading community could really
use a breath of fresh air
and everybody that's came into my
mentorship that's it there's no more
sales pitch
there's no more 20 22 20 nothing like
i'm done i'm trying to get all the
mentorship teaching done
i'm getting all the payment stuff done
and then i'm going back
to being who i was before 2016
in august when i started this mentorship
doesn't mean i'm not going to continue
with my mentorship group and give them
private teachings
because i don't want to be focusing on i
just want to go back to doing it relax
and have time to do like i'm doing here
if you couldn't afford
the mentorship just know that i'm still
going to present
lessons here i'm not going to teach the
same level
obviously for those that join my
mentorship that would be unfair
and be unreasonable but
there is a plethora of wisdom
in these videos and if you've only
watched them one time
you didn't get it all you have to go
through it a few times
and take notes and then study some
charts and then you'll find out that
you've
seen something that if you go back and
listen to the videos again
it'll mean more to you and it'll feel
just like a new video was given to you
and it's the same video i gave you from
the beginning it's just they're very
dense
there's a lot of like this video there's
a lot of things and nuggets in it
that if you learn a little bit more with
practice
you'll appreciate the things i've said
that would otherwise have
been glossed over by you by your
attention just not being dialed in
because you don't know the importance of
the things i'm saying
but for those individuals that have been
a commodity trader
maybe some of you are futures traders
and you've traded
commodity markets and maybe you traded
coffee before and you never were aware
of something like this
this is something that you can
plan and predict months in advance
so when we get to july if the market's
been bullish
you can anticipate something like this
unfolding now obviously it doesn't give
you an entry pattern
it doesn't give you an exit pattern it
doesn't give you the stop loss
but i'm teaching you a foundational idea
which is important you have to have an
understanding of why a market should
even be doing anything at all
just because you think you see something
harmonic or you think you see something
that's an
elliott wave based idea or even a supply
and demand
idea doesn't mean anything by itself
just like an order block by itself means
absolutely nothing
you have to have some context and you
can't get any better as a context
than having a seasonal impact
behind a market move that has happened
historically over and over and over
again
and you can see it you can visually see
it
and coupling that when it's bullish and
there's lots of seasonal tendencies
there's other seasonal tendencies for
coffee for it to go down
specific times of the year and it's
other times when it's predisposed to go
up
to and the same premise you go into it
looking for what the market was bullish
or bearish going into that specific
seasonal tenancy and by blending that
with market structure
and are we in a risk on a risk off
environment that goes back to the dollar
index
if you're if you're expecting a buy
signal in commodities
but you don't see a weaker dollar you're
probably
looking at a market that isn't going to
pan out for you
doesn't mean it's always like that it
just means that the probability has
shifted to a very low probability
in your favor versus
if you were expecting a move higher in a
commodity market
and the dollar index was bearish and you
can see it going lower
then you have a risk on scenario because
dollars going lower
and that other market that would be in
a normal perspective it would be an
inverse
expectation so dollar lower commodities
higher
so there's this relationship of macro
and i talked a little bit about that and
i'll
take you to the post on my community tab
now this is the post i did
today and again today is
january 12 2021 and
i did a post like this earlier this
morning
and i talked about the importance of
using
seasonal tendencies and it's the the
main thing
i think everyone should try to focus on
because there are specific times of the
year
that you should be focusing on one side
of the marketplace
and not the other it doesn't mean that
you abandon the other side of the
marketplace
because what's really interesting and
i'm going to finalize this video at this
point
if there is a time when the market is
seasonally
bullish you can look at the seasonal
tenancy as a way of
timing the other direction because the
markets
find a way to punish those individuals
that look for these types of patterns
and they don't
exist and i'll say it like this
if you're bullish on the market and the
seasonal tendency is bullish
and the market structure is bullish then
you have a high probability buy
with the dollar being bearish okay
if you are bearish on
a market and the market structure is
bearish
and the dollar index is bullish
then you have high probability in your
favor
if you see a bullish seasonal tendency
and we'll use coffee as a
example here if we have this seasonal
tendency mid july
and the market's been bearish going into
that mid-july time period
we don't look for a buy we would look
for
a short-term rally to sell short into
and then probably see a better
price delivery on the downside as a
result because the seasonal tendency
would not be there and that gives us
many times what i mentioned here
it departs from the norm in price action
it tends to
incite excitement and price action and
important opportunities
so it's far more important for you to
know
this than an entry pattern because it
gives you
the foundation to why a market should
have a big move
because if you're in trading or trying
to get into trading just to get
10 pips 20 pips as a forex trader okay
or
try to make 25 pips as a weekly
objective which is what i kind of like
teach people
to aim for in the beginning i think
that's a reasonable
objective it's not high and lofty it's
something that i think that could be
easily obtained
and you could still make a career off of
that as crazy as it may sound
but i don't want you thinking that
that's all you
can do with what i give you here on this
youtube channel
you could literally turn this into
whatever you want it to be you want to
be a big swing trader catching mega
trades
well this is one way of going into it
now notice i didn't even talk about
commitment of traders you notice that
did you also notice that i didn't talk
about breakers
or mitigation blocks you see what i'm
referring to there
i have a lot of moving parts but you're
able to take
what makes sense to you that resonates
with you
and say okay i'm going to use these
things that make up my model
but if it doesn't have things that are
rooted in
market truths you're not going to see
those things pan
out for you it doesn't make a difference
the buzzwords the cool little names
the things that you see me show you in
your charts
doesn't make a difference unless it's
rooted and founded
in rooted in a market truth and what is
the market truth
the markets will move
based on a higher time frame premise
and when we're referring to agricultural
markets like
foods and grains they are fundamentally
driven by supply and demand factors
those markets have
real supply and demand every other
market out there
is manipulated commodities are a real
market that has supply and demand
factors that govern them
they are the world's grocery store
so they have a real value like
corn is always going to be worth
something but your share of tesla
could be worth zero two years from now
as crazy as that might say i'm not
saying
that's what's going to happen but tesla
stocks you know the shares
there's no real reason to think that
there's value behind that
or that it would be in perpetuity worth
something
it doesn't mean that but it's viewed
that it has that value right now but
corn will never go to worthlessness
it's a food it'll always have value and
in times of turmoil and what i
anticipate going forward
there's going to be a shortage of food
and that shortage of food is going to
put so much supply and demand pressure
on these grains and that's why you're
seeing these big extrapolated price
moves
why because it's fundamentally driven
so if you're looking for supply and
demand and you want to trade supply and
demand
you can't find a better way of doing it
than trading commodities
period that's real that's real supply
and demand
there's no real supply and demand with a
currency
it's all manipulated and in the cryptos
manipulated too
bottom line is this don't think that you
have
to worry about making money in these
tiny little intraday fluctuations
the same tools and premise that i teach
with these
intraday can be applied to the
larger daily charts and if i would have
just told you that
this chart here for corn
if i told you that was a an hourly chart
or a 15-minute chart and didn't tell you
what
market it was you wouldn't have known
any different
because price is price but
knowing where these big moves come from
and putting your neck out on the line
i do that and if i don't know what i'm
talking about
i would fall on my face miserably
and you keep seeing me pointing to the
next big moves pointing to the next big
moves
because i have almost 30 years of
experience doing this
i don't want to steer you wrong i don't
want to see you fail
i'm inspired by your excitement and your
enthusiasm
it motivates me it keeps me going
because it allows me to relive moments
just like you are having right now
i went through that when you want to
quit i went through that dozens of times
when you feel like you hit a home run
because you got
more understanding and you can't sleep
and you're excited
i've been there i know what that feels
like and it's amazing
but nobody around you is going to
understand that excitement
because they think what you're doing or
trying to learn is nonsense it's a pipe
dream to them
but i know i went through that i had all
the adversity
and everyone around me saying the same
things it's a waste of time
don't believe any of that don't listen
to that stuff
stop talking about what you're planning
on doing and just do it don't share your
dreams with other people
because they're going to tell you don't
bother
who wants to hear that so
dig into your charts dig into the videos
that you find on this youtube channel
start studying make 2021 the year
that you've framed out a model that
makes sense to you
doesn't have to have all the moving
parts that's available but something
that makes sense to you
that's rooted in why a market should go
up or down and where it should reach for
logically i teach that here on this
youtube channel
and if you put the time into studying it
i promise
you will find something that you can't
find elsewhere
and at least for free since i'll talk to
you next time be safe
and good luck and good trading