okay folks welcome back
all right so we are looking at another
discussion and lecture on institutional
order flow
and before I get into it I borrowed this
from a
another YouTuber
it's not important who it is and I'm not
saying that there's anything inherently
bad about the other YouTuber I'm not
trying to so Discord or anything like
that but
I do see a growing number of you in the
comments section and folks that email me
and or reach out to me through
tradingview
the
idea of order flow
using a Dom which is a depth of Market
which is over here
on the left hand side and you have the
footprint which is in the middle of the
screen here
see all these little look real technical
right that's institutional and all this
down here wow that really makes your
chart look amazing when I was younger I
would have loved to have added all that
on top of every other indicator I had on
my chart okay because it would have made
me feel like I was
smarter and more informed
and I want you to think about
what it is you're learning from me okay
if you're new or if you've been with me
for a little bit of time
um
it can seem a little daunting
a little complicated if you will and
it's because you're trying to rush
through the process and if I were to ask
you to look at this here look at this
information
what should you do with all this now I
know how to use this information I know
how other people use it and I have
friends and I also have students that
use things like this in concert with
what it is that I do and they are
profitable
so I'm not trying to discourage you
from using these tools because if you
feel like it helps you
if it's advantageous for you it helps
you
Trust
your model
everything I'm saying here today
if you feel uneasy watching the video
just turn it off
okay I'm trusting that you're all adults
here you can see through what it is I'm
trying to convey I'm answering the
question of do I see the necessity for
these types of things in trading and in
the short answer that way for folks that
want to know right away and not waste
any more time
um I don't believe that it's necessary
to know these things in fact I'm going
to talk about why these are no different
than any other indicator out there
because it's a faith-based premise that
has to be applied to everything whether
it's my content my Concepts somebody
else's stuff or even this
um
you know
institutions
that may subscribe to these types of
things here
um it doesn't make prices go up and down
the only thing really you're doing is
with the left hand side over here you
know the Dom depth of Market
when you see orders
coming forward on that display
they can be spoofed okay spoofing is
where in order to be placed above or
below the marketplace
and pulled away before the market prints
it and it will look like it'll make it
look like there's more buying or selling
interest in a particular market so how
would that be any more
advantages or different really
for a Trader that has to sit down look
at the market and determine it's going
to run from where we are right now at
the market price to some previous
support level so what you expected to go
lower or is going to go higher to some
previous resistance level
okay so you're still met with that same
challenge of knowing what you need to
know where the Market's going to go
okay and there's so many people out
there trying to be Educators trying to
be an influencer trying to convince
other people they can trade
they are stating these terms here
you don't have to predict the market you
don't have to know where the Market's
going
and this to me makes absolutely no sense
okay it makes no sense whatsoever
because if you're looking at the depth
of market up here
and the idea is that you think that
there is a more likely okay this is what
you're going to have to subscribe to
using these types of tools what's more
likely that the market will start to go
down
feed into the orders that are below the
marketplace
or is it more likely to go higher to eat
into diggers that are above the
marketplace
well I'm not concerned about those small
little fluctuations in price
I mean if you're sitting here trying to
make you know two handles three handles
those types of Trades you know and
that's your mechanism to do those types
of things I'm not going to sit here and
try to shoot holes through that because
this is something I would never do that
okay I'm not interested in that type of
trading
I'm interested in knowing where the
Market's going to reach to and I teach
my students to focus on that primarily
in the early stages of their development
depth of Market or level two data
requires you still
to have an opinion
and that opinion may be incorrect
much like my opinion about the
marketplace using my own Concepts may be
incorrect just like anybody else we're
still met with the challenge of knowing
the first rule and goal that I teach my
students which is to know
where you trust that the market is more
likely to draw to higher or lower and
not just for the sake of a few handles
because the depth of market May imply
that there's more buyers
or sellers at any given time just
because there may be printing a depth of
Market ladder which is what these things
are called over here these are letters
there may be more orders stacking above
Marketplace
or below the marketplace and the idea
generally is
it's more likely doesn't mean it's going
to happen but it's more likely that the
market will gravitate towards where the
larger
stacking of orders if it's more likely
that it's going to go higher then the
justification should be made that you
need the depth of Market the level two
data that ladder should show a lot more
orders to the upside and then when it
gets there it should eat into that and
start eroding those orders
that to me
is something that is synonymous with
having a crutch and that's not to be
derogatory I don't mean it in a sense
that you know nobody should use crutches
you know while they're learning or while
they're using their model if you feel
like these things are helpful to you and
it helps you focus on sticking to one
side of the marketplace if you have a
bias if you have a draw on the code that
you feel is going to be booked for that
particular trading session or that day
and this helps you stay focused on it
then that's there's nothing to be
worried about there's nothing wrong
about that
in my opinion this is all it is and you
have hopefully you can permit me to have
my opinion here
but the idea of using this stuff
for the sole basis of whether you should
be a buyer or seller is a little bit
myopic regardless of whether or not an
XYZ trading firm or institution or bank
or whatever has them on their terminals
in their trading floor
it's irrelevant
the market still has that
puzzle of where is it going to go higher
or lower
and when I teach my students to focus on
where the most likely draw on liquidity
is going to be that's what you should be
focusing on
not all these little numbers in here
on a footprint or over here worrying
about
is there more buyers or sellers of other
Marketplace and it's likely to keep
going up and I I watch a lot of
YouTubers that use these types of tools
over here like the depth of Market the
Dom
it's dumb not dome
but the uh
the idea of using it
if you watch any YouTubers that have it
on their charts or they're live
streaming or maybe they recorded their
their trades and they still have it on
there
um
it doesn't appear at least from my
observations it doesn't appear that it's
all that helpful
you know even when I can see the market
is likely to go higher or lower and I'm
viewing them live streaming or watching
you something in the past when I can see
what the market has done because I've
either traded it or I can pull it up in
chart form
I can see how they can be tricked
into thinking oh this I think it's going
to go to this price because there's a
lot of orders around that price
and I want you to think about how what
it is I'm teaching you we're not looking
at the necessity for these types of
things to confirm anything
because
my assumptions are you're allowing the
market to be seen visually in chart form
and yes through a time-based chart
there's a lot of advantages if you
understand what is I'm teaching there's
a lot of advantages to using a
time-based chart
where some other individuals out there
that don't have a subscription to the
same view that I have may not like a
Time based chart and they have to
augment that data and create a new
format of a bar or a candle or something
to that effect
so just know going into this discussion
I will be
stating why I am not a fan of this
information or these tools do not let me
change your mind if it feels like it
helps you
if you're profitable and you feel
comfortable using them just because I
may be your mentor
don't let me pry these things out of
your hand
you may grow out of them on your own
over time or you may stick with them and
it may be part of your repertoire and
there's nothing wrong with that as long
as you're using them in the capacity
that allows you to focus and allows you
to trust your model if that's what
you're using them for there's absolutely
zero hindrances there's nothing I would
never say anything adversely about it
but for someone to come out and say this
is
this is how you read institutional order
flow this is this no you're reading
order flow
but institutional order flow is not this
is not institutional workflow to me this
is this reporting numbers that can be
spoofed that means that they can pull
those orders that means that you may see
them flash on the screen
but doesn't necessarily mean when price
gets to it that those orders are still
there
many trading firms in quote-unquote
institutions have been fined
many many times over
some of them are repeat offenders
some of these trolls I've had over the
years are actually guilty of this
and they were penalized
for spoofing
messing around with placing orders in to
make it look like there's a more
stronger interest to buy or sell a
particular vehicle or instrument
or Market
and if there's an opening for
manipulation to the data
and that can absolutely be done here
how can you really in my opinion this is
my opinion now I'm not trying to
convince you to not use these things but
this is my opinion how can you trust
the basis of this data if it absolutely
can be manipulated
if it could be manipulated to make it
look like there is a
fake
buying interest where orders can be
placed above the market price
or below the market price and the
interpretation of that would be seen
collectively in retail Trading
as there's a lot of a lot of orders
below or below the marketplace and the
tendency is the trust that it's going to
more likely go to where there are more
orders and that's not necessarily what
happens
now I'm sure some of you that use this
stuff that don't like me you're going to
come out with you know 10 different
examples of where look where it worked
look where but I I promise you I can go
on a live stream and show this stuff and
it not working where my stuff is
absolutely running circles around it so
permit me to say that in this video and
I promise I won't be any more
derogatory the net but now from this
point on I want to kind of show you in
comparing contrast what it is I'm trying
to focus on in my teaching so that way
you're as a student you're looking at
the right way and if you feel like or
you feel pressured by other people that
will say you're you're not learning
real order flow no we're not messing
around with these things here that's
true because it's not necessary
because I want you to understand
something
listen to the name
of this stuff here okay the footprint
that means you're looking at something
that's already happened
how many orders were in this part of the
candle this part of the bar
okay it's already happened
where have I ever told you to go into
charts and say here is how many buyers
and sellers have been so repeat what
they've done or use that information and
then you've never heard me say that
I'm always telling you to predict where
price is going to go
and then where you think it's going to
go that draw on liquidity
above the marketplace or below the
marketplace it's going to go up to take
out buy stops or it's going to go up to
reprice to an inefficiency
some kind of FVG or sibi
could be a volume imbalance it could be
a institutional overflow entry drill
yeah it could be a consequent quotient
of a wick
there's very specific things that we're
looking for but not every single Market
at that time frame in that chart fractal
that portion of price that you're
studying is going to have every single
thing that I have as a PD array
something that I teach you to focus on
but the ones that are actually there you
have to consider them and know what to
do with them and navigate them
so I'm teaching you absolutely how to
predict price because
how else are you going to use this
information and trust it
I'll post the question to you like this
if you are bearish on the marketplace
doesn't it make sense that if you're
going to be using these tools
that you're expecting
the depth of Market to show a lot more
orders below the marketplace
a lot more interest to draw price into
lower prices
because
you're bias
you're
directional bias your analysis you are
bullish or bearish so you're going to go
in into this data looking for those
things to justify what your your
analysis
so I don't go to the middleman these are
all middleman ideas to me and it's
helpful in the beginning if you don't
know what you're doing and how to
navigate price action and you want to
see the underpinnings of what the
Market's doing and how it books price
that's wonderful but my PD arrays are
always always
ahead of this
it's always ahead of it
look at what I did this week with the
analysis on the July 9 2023 video I did
on Sunday before the market opened up I
told you exactly what we would be seeing
I told you what would be expected in
terms of price delivery and it delivered
perfectly
flawlessly
no necessity on having any of this stuff
here so really
I want you to compare and contrast
if this is measuring minute by minute
second by second real events of
transactions because that's what this
all this is showing you is transactions
but just because there was a certain
number of buyers or sellers at a
particular price
at any given time
and just because there are more orders
above or below the market price in the
Dom has absolutely no bearing on future
prices
it has absolutely no bearing on the
future direction of price
the markets stay stagnant and stays
disconsolidating
when this stuff was a big buzz
when I first started using it when level
two became a thing and I'm old enough
and I watched the transition from open
outcry into electronic Trading
when these tools were made available to
us everybody was clamoring to it because
level two that was the thing you were
really informed if you had this
information
where's all the yachts
where's it where's all the billionaires
and the millionaires if it was going to
make you institutional
minded
where's all the rich people that came up
out of nowhere using it
right
so
not to discourage you
but when I say institutional order flow
it's not this
you know you'll hear people say
um ICD doesn't teach order flow I don't
teach this stuff
because this stuff I have no faith in
and I know how to use it but I
completely cut it out of my analysis
because I don't need it you might need
it you may find
helpfulness from it it may allow you to
feel closer to the marketplace and if
that's what you're feeling by doing it
that there's nothing wrong with that
absolutely nothing wrong with it like
I've already stated earlier I have
friends in this industry and I have
students that use this stuff in
conjunction
with what I'm teaching
and they're profitable
so I'm not here to say this doesn't work
okay what I'm doing is I'm drawing a
stark contrast between when I say
institutional order flow what am I
talking about in contrast to this stuff
here that's what we're going to do okay
so
let's move on into the discussion here
we're going to look at a case study on
NASDAQ okay and
I'm going to spare you level two data
because it's not required it's not
necessary and I want you to think about
how it is that I teach you and how I've
shown
a plethora of examples of before the
fact where the market is going to go how
it's going to get there not just here we
are at Point a I believe it's going to
maybe get up the point B that's not what
I say I say this is where I think the
draw of liquidity is that means I'm
cosigned
that's a directional bias that means I
have made my expectations known publicly
beforehand
and it's not a two pip or five handle
expectation these are pretty considered
price moves
and I'm not utilizing anything that is
classically lumped into order flow
because
folks that use that information when I
say
um
trading with institutional order flow
I'm seeing institutional order flow in
price action I'm going to cover that
again today I've done it in the past but
I want to present a little bit deeper
presentation about it and I want you to
think about the
the lack of
required tools
that other people other Traders feel
like they have to have when I have
nothing on my chart is simply a
Candlestick chart and I'm as long as I
can see what time it is and where we are
in the range
that's it that's all you need
so
the number one thing is draw on
liquidity so I was bullish
obviously I mentioned that last Sunday
and today is July 16th 2023 at the time
of this recording
so last Sunday
July 9th 2023 I had outlined my
expectation of higher prices on
e-mini s p NASDAQ
higher prices on euro dollar and lower
prices on the dollar Index and it was a
clean sweep everything delivered as I
expected they were not small moves they
were rather large
and I want to go into detail as to why I
believed that NASDAQ would go higher
and I want you to take a look at the
chart here
upper left hand corner this is the
weekly chart
this right here this candle right here
is a mitigation block now I don't talk
too much about it
but it is basically the opposite of a
breaker but they are still both
mitigation in essence
now
we have a high a low and a higher high
no
lower high you see that that low between
it is a mitigation block if this High
here
was taken out with a higher run here
then that would be a bearish breaker
bearish Breakers are much more stronger in terms of resistance than a mitigation block
a mitigation block can be traded through
- so in terms of how I use mitigation blocks,
- I typically side with using them as targets more so than entry
- because they can be traded through
Breakers are kind of like they're
they're pretty formidable in the path of
price action it doesn't mean that they
can't go through them it doesn't mean
I've never had a losing trade using a
breaker because I have but
mitigation blocks are better used for
targeting purposes I was using this one
here with the expectation that the nasda
could try to gravitate towards that if
it were to go any higher this small
little if everybody got there and
obviously the buy side above it so I am
not called a high in the NASDAQ or ES in
fact you've heard me emphatically State
many times throughout the commentaries
and or Twitter
that I am not calling a high
and it's important for you not to try to
do that too look out just keeps drilling
higher it's grinding people down anybody
that wants to sell short this Mark and
believe me I'm in the opinion as well
that there's no justification for the
markets to be where they are at least
for equities your stocks should not be
trading where they're at but
we have to trust order flow what kind of
order flood the things I started to show
you in the beginning of this
presentation I don't subscribe to those
things
I don't have any faith in them
my faith is based on where I believe the
Market's going to go so yes I believe
I'm pretty good at predicting where
price is going to go because I have
experience doing it and I have tools
that help me to do that and I also can
see where orders are going to be anyway
before your ladders your depth of Market
before your footprint confirms what I
already and my students already expect
in terms of price delivery
we already know there's going to be
buying and selling between the two price
points that we're at that that's a given
so knowing where the market is going to
go to that's a directional bias you
listen at some point folks unless you
trade options in your delta neutral
have a directional bias
there's no way around it you have to
otherwise your writing options
so if we're trading futures
and we're
trying to be a buyer or seller I mean if
you're going long
then you have a bias that's going higher
so why why argue with that why call it
something that it's not you're
predicting Christ you're trying to
predict price then say
we don't need to predict the future
price Direction well yes you do if you
want to be profitable or at least
consistently profitable
like you have to have an understanding
of where the market can gravitate
towards and that's what I teach my
students that's the first thing they
come out of the gate with with me is
knowing where price is likely to go if
you don't have that skill set you will
not be consistently profitable period
end a story there's nothing else to
discuss
so my opinion was in the beginning of
the week
I wanted to see us gravitate towards this MB
it would be above the REHs here that had already been cleared through here and we Consolidated
markets don't talk like that
okay and it was more likely that we're going to expand higher
it did
it reached into the MB
it actually closed right on it so that's
that's rather decent isn't it
so ahead of the week open
on Sunday July 9 2023
we were expecting price to go higher
and we have
this candle right here now on this
candle stick chart here in the lower
left hand corner this is a daily chart
of the NASDAQ everything that I'm
teaching you here folks you may be
primarily a Forex Trader okay
everything that I'm teaching you right
here works on every asset class
I would not do anything different so
that way if you're frustrated because
I'm not talking about Forex like it did
a lot
before I'm teaching through this medium
here because this is where actually got
started in 1992 I was a commodity Trader
so this is where I started
later on in my career I moved and
transitioned to Forex
there's a lot of things that
prevent me from wanting to trade Forex
so that's the reason why I'm teaching
with this medium here everything that
I'm teaching you here with Futures index
trading Works in 4x2 it works in
commodity trading it works in Gold it
works in metals and my students I can't
swear by it because I've never traded
crypto but I have students that have
been profitable trading crypto using
this information so that way
at least you know that somebody else out
there other than me has some experience
with it because I don't have any
experience trading crypto
so if
we see this down closed candle after if
you look at the weekly chart here
there's a small little Fair bit you got
right in there
that's this one here on the daily
so the market traded higher there and
then we have this down closed candle
which is
right above and digging into this down
closed candle this is an older Block
it's bullish this is a propulsion block
PB are OB by themselves but the way you differentiate what they are and how they're used is
this down-closed-candle digs into a previous down-close-candle
so an OB that has another OB that digs into it
PB you never want to see a closing price below MT
MT on our OB is the 50 level
we Wicked down through it but then closed here this one here
we Wick down through it and closed right here
we Wicked down through it and closed up here
so yes we had the movement through the MT but we didn't close below it
so that still keeps this down closed candle valid as a PB
I promise you we're going somewhere
Friday Thursday Wednesday Tuesday
Monday's Trading
all of this movement here
was just returning back into this Gap
this tail and this Candlestick we treat
Wicks and Tails on candlesticks as gaps
midpoint of that Gap or tail on that
candle is consequent encouragement
extend out in time you can see that's
exactly where we were trading on Monday
it did not violate the rules that make a
propulsion block invalid
market closes here
and now we open the next day we open the
trade down
rally back up and have it I'll close
so the next two days we had news
we had a pretty good uh economic
calendar events for the rest of the week
and it's sent price parabolic above the
REHs so the draw on
liquidity is the weekly chart
mitigation block
okay so we're not going to say that the
actual price was 15 693 but we're just
going to use it for the sake of
discussion because
I don't know it off the top of my head
what the actual price was I haven't
noted here
you're invited to do that in your own
study don't just take what I show and
talk about in the video you need to go
in there and weigh out whether your
charts show you the same thing because
you want your own proof you don't want
to just take my word on anything in fact
that's the best way to do it challenge
yourself and challenge my observations
was it really there in the chart because
you know just taking my word for anyone
else's word for anything is is not
something you should do especially
investing in financial advice
so
this movement here this was fully
expected we are expecting this
bullishness in higher prices on NASDAQ
when you're expecting it and yes as well
you mean s p
but we look for things to start or
instigate a price rally higher or a
price decline lower
and we frame it on the basis of where
are we at right now versus where is it
likely to go
so if we think that the price is going
to gravitate
up to this area here
and we'll call it fifteen thousand six
ninety three and
0.75 if we start the week here Monday
and then Tuesday and Wednesday and
Thursday and Friday
we expect each daily candle to gravitate towards that level even if you didn't pick that level
if you felt that this FVG was a reason to keep going higher, that's fine
that's nothing there's nothing wrong with that
but this mitigation block is below that FVG
and if you are using the REHs as a drawing liquidity there's nothing wrong with that either
remember the only thing we're doing is
primarily looking for the expansion
either higher or lower
on the weekly Candlestick that sets our
bias for the week so is it more likely
to see where price was consolidating
here is it more likely it's going to
drop down after we've already went into
this Fair Bay Gap here we already did
that and then we Consolidated here the
previous week and then we start a new
week here trade down a little bit and
then reject it
which is all that rejection is based on
this consequent correction this daily
candle right there that's where the low
of the week was formed
so this is primed to just obviously
expand higher and aggressively above
these REHs on the daily
chart so there's buy orders resting
above that
markets don't top like this folks
they don't do it and since the weekly in a daily chart are showing this pattern
it's more likely to go higher especially since we were bearish on dollar
not just bearish a little bit but we were exceedingly bearish expecting it to reach for a larger pool SSL
so if that is the case that means it's
definitely a risk on scenario meaning
all assets have the likelihood
to go higher Euro
pound gold
all other asset classes are free to move
higher because it's risk on and we saw a
huge risk on event this past week where
most asset classes went up
while the dollar crashed
over here on the hourly chart I want to
to notice this little shade layer here
that's the propulsion block
that's this whole range here but visible
on a hourly chart
so we have relative equal lows here we
drop down into it we trade above this
short term high right there that's all
it needs to that that's a shift in
Market structure it doesn't need to
close above it
it just now sets the thing in motion
that we're going higher
doesn't mean you can't have retracements
but look where it retraces if you take
this
propulsion block right here and you
divide it in half that's MT
that's what this drop was going to right
there
it's going right there and it's also
cleaning up these smooth edges in the
bodies
wait a minute that's not smooth edges
ICT look at this Wick right here or this
tail and look at this right here
look at the bodies the bodies tell you the story
that's the narrative
the Wicks do all the damage
that's the stuff that everybody gets hurt by
you get stopped out and you don't want to go back into the marketplace
that's their purpose
reading price action with a time-based
chart and focusing on the bodies of the candles
if you just saw these right here like this and there was no Wicks or tails on their candlesticks
if you took that completely off your chart this would look like Smooth edges
and that's all this was trading down
into MT which is the entire
range from high to low
split that in half
that's this level right here
that's occurring
right in this level
digging into it after we had a shift in
Market structure so what am I saying
here
at this point
right there that's slightly higher high
than this one
because we've had cell side taken there
now we have buy side we're bullish so we
have now met the minimum criteria for
high probability directional bias
so now we can absolutely predict higher
prices we can trust that higher prices
are likely to go where
up in here
this mitigation block
so if we're looking for a 15 693 level
and we're down here and we drop down to
MT at that point does the
market want to Rally away from it sure
looks like it does to me
tries one more time
digs into it but look where the bodies
are showing
they're showing it's respecting that
propulsion block right there we've
already did the damage we're going down
into it
and here bodies are supporting the high
end of the propulsion block that shaded
area and then we want to see does the
market want to Rally well here's the
thing if you're looking at depth of
Market or if you're looking at footprint
you're going to start seeing
all the things
that would justify
the market wanting to go higher
we already knew that
we already knew all those things and
from here
as soon as we get these candlesticks
showing this and this Candlestick closes
the next candle here and it drops down
and touches this the high of this blue
shaded area which is this candle that
range on the daily chart we're working
with the hourly chart here now
I know
that we're likely to go higher where we
have all this sell side imbalanced bison
efficiency so basically this candle
sticks low and then we have the buy side
above this High here there's buy stops
resting above that
but this also is another pattern
it's a breaker
so I know that everyone that uses a
depth of Market uses a footprint they're
going to be looking for justifications
to go higher or lower the folks that
would be looking at it with the
expectation that the Market's going to
go higher the evidence that they're
seeking will be there
every instance of it
would be reflected in those tools I
don't need to see that I already know
that the Market's going to go towards
these levels it's driven that way not
because of buying and selling pressure
I have already arrived at these ideas
before the markets even opened up
before the market even printed its first
book
on Sunday's opening
we had already codified the expectation
that these markets were going to go
higher and to where
there was no need there was no way for
me to look at depth of Market or a
footprint to justify those things
because the market hadn't already done
anything yet
so while the markets were static
using experience using institutional
order flow reading the tea leaves okay
reading price action so for the folks
out there to say you know if you're
reading the tape who said this is
reading take folks you're watching price
and how it gyrates off of my PD arrays
that's reading the tape when someone
says show me your order book show me
your order book that's the stuff at the
beginning of this video that I don't
need
before your order book before your depth
of Market before your ladder in your
footprint tools start telling you
anything I have already I'm light years
ahead
the footprint
that's something that is happened
this is where the buyers were this is
how many orders were bought and sold at
these specific levels okay that's
wonderful that's wonderful history I
loved it when I was in school
but who has a better perspective folks
okay someone that's ahead of you on the
path
that you're walking right now
someone that is
a quarter mile up the road
they've already walked this path
multiple times many times they know the
terrain they know where the sticks are
out and the Thorns are and who has the
better perspective you as an
inexperienced student of the marketplace
someone that's new maybe you started in
you're looking back
and wondering can you trust these tools
when I'm ahead of you in experience and
I can read these charts without any of
that stuff and I know where you're going
to see new buying entries you're going
to see retracements that take out
liquidity you're going to see
inefficiencies and how they're going to
use those inefficiency and I've proven
this numerous times with live executions
I've called the market minute by minute
live on a live stream not pre-recorded
you have all sat there and watched me do
this that is reading the tape I don't
need these gimmicks to talk about what's
happened already
I don't need to see that order book I'm
going to tell you where the Market's
going to go before the order books talk
about it
that's what my students are able to do
you may not have that skill set yet you
will over time it doesn't happen
overnight it doesn't happen real quick
but I promise you the idea of these
things that are being promoted as this
is institutional order flow it's not
institutional order flow
all you're seeing is a glorified time
and date stamp
time and sales that's it
that's all you're seeing it's a it's a
repackaged edition of that same
information
that's wonderful that's wonderful for
data collection and and studying okay
it's wonderful
but you still are left with the puzzle
of where is Price going to go higher or
lower
and in between where we are at market
price how will it behave
well let's talk about that
if this is the propulsion block and
we've already seen it dig down into here
I'm not looking at ladders I'm not
looking at depth of Market I'm not going
to look at that level two data I'm not
looking at anything harmonic I'm not
looking at animal patterns I'm not
looking at Elliott wave I'm not looking
again I'm not looking at anything
but this price action right here
now what's more simplified
trying to determine the efficacy of of
footprint a depth of market and then not
trading with the expectation of
predicting price to me that's
that's Insanity like how could you
possibly know what to do
and then it's not surprising when you
see everybody out there that are trying
to live stream and use these tools they
fumble or they're not very confident
when it is discussing what it is they
want to do
and one of the things I get challenged
with is you know I I'm arrogant no I'm
confident and my students that are
profitable that know what they're doing
they're confident and it seems like
arrogance the people that can't do it
and I'm just trying to communicate to
you in a manner where I don't want you
to view me as trying to be arrogant I
want you to learn how to do this
yourself if I was trying to hold it back
from you then I could see your argument
but I'm trying my best to teach it to
you and I'm trying to disarm you for
those that are standing here trying to
arm wrestle me and say you know this is
fake or you don't know what you're doing
and it's always hindsight when I have
literally scores of executions and live
streams where I've called these things
before they happen
and your ladders and your depth of
market and all this footprint stuff
hasn't even spoke to you yet
I'm light years ahead I'm ahead of you
in the path okay and I'm looking back at
you I know where I've come from I've
been exactly where all of you are I've
been there
and I understand how confusing it is and
you're trying to determine what you're
supposed to do with this information
it's a lot of stuff to understand I
understand that's normal
I didn't say it was going to be easy
but I will make it easy and how I'm
teaching you this year there's no other
way to simplify it
there really isn't it says you have to
keep doing it for a while and you'll
learn how to do it but when I look back
at you as someone that's starting
I have the advantage of knowing how
price will deliver
I know how Market structure will use
specific things that I've dubbed PD
arrays you don't know where they're
going to form or how they're going to
form I do
and I've proven that with live streams
live with the lowest latency that
YouTube can permit
so there's no excuses there's absolutely
no arguments there's none
order books are not advantageous to me I
don't need those things and if you're
learning how to do what it is I'm
teaching you you don't need those tools
either but if you want to use them to
help you and you find advantages in
using it that's wonderful I'm not going
to tell you to put it down
but if we're expecting price to go up to
this blue line and we're seeing evidence
that all these things down here stops
have been taken is swept we have all
these bodies here which is relative
equal lows forget the Wicks go back into
the bodies they're telling you the
narrative that's the storyline that
means they're going to want to sweep
through it there you go it's happening
right there so when this is a full my
bearish candle I would be buying that
you probably wouldn't most people on
YouTube Twitter and Instagram and
Discord and things like that wouldn't
buy that
they would be too afraid they had no
idea price would react that way
but I'm leaning on this being a
propulsion block this is a order block
that's already confirmed that it is
we broke through
this candle's closure here which is
rejection Block it's showing a
willingness to want to go higher I don't
need this High to be taken now
it's went above this one here while I'm
bullish this down closed candle is a
propulsion block so that range I'm
shaded here I'm putting that and
transposing that onto an hourly chart
so I'm watching price action on an
hourly basis how it performs see when
I'm doing my live streams or if I'm
doing a execution and I'm recording my
trades
I don't have four laptops folks okay
I've had laptops you know numerous
laptops over the years and I kill them
I burn them out and once they're done or
close to being done I take all the
information off them and they're dead
they're thrown away there's nothing I
can do with them
but I have many monitors in front of me
on my system and I've showed you that on
my YouTube
I showed you my displays I showed you
what it looks like
and I'm watching different layouts and
one of the layouts I use has very
similar to what you're seeing here where
we have multiple time frames and I'm
watching how price delivers on all of
them I'm not just staring at a one
minute chart
can I trade with a one minute chart
entirely all by itself yes
but I'm not teaching you to do that
because you're going to miss a lot of
the information that I'm showing you
here you would not have the context of
using everything I'm talking about here
without having the daily chart
without having the weekly chart the draw
on liquidity this blue line here
so when I'm looking at Price whether I have it on the chart or if it's on my notepad
because I'm using a notepad unless I draw it out on the chart for you
because you're going to watch the video later on
there's no there's no annotations on my chart
because I want my focus on where we are in that range
so on my notepad I have the high the low and the MT price point of that Candlestick
right there on the daily chart and I have on
my notepad daily propulsion block hi
MT low so I'm watching price
when it's Meandering around in here I'm
watching time of day
and how it responds at those specific
levels because I'm predicting I'm
anticipating I am not reacting to
anything
the only time that I react is if I'm
wrong and I see the evidence in price
action that I'm offside or and likely to
become offside then I'm going to react
to that new information and say okay I
got a bail on the trade
that's the only permission that you're
ever going to get from me to react to
price because everything else we are
absolutely predicting price you are
doing that you're predicting the future
that's what this is It's future it's why
they call it Futures Trading your lip is
in the name and why are you arguing
saying you're not trying to predict the
price or you shouldn't be trying to
predict the price you are if you are
bullish that means you are predicting
higher prices if you're bearish You're
Expecting and predicting lower prices
how are you reacting to anything
if you're reacting it means you're
chasing price I'm not chasing price I'm
waiting for very specific things where
price will walk into my crosshairs and
when it does
it's going down
I'm going to pull the trigger and I'm
getting my entry I have 81 ways to get
in there trust me I'm getting in there
if trading was like a a cat burglar I'd
be the best one at it because I can get
in that so we have the mean
threshold here rallies back above
REHs have been cleared
here and now the bodies are showing that
there is an interest in seeing no
further decline
or how do I know that because the bodies
are not closing inside that blue shaded
area it's already done the work of doing
what
trading down into MT
one more time shifting higher so Market
structure is now again one more time
bullish
so where's their inefficiency Above This
price point right here when this candle
closes
this one right here
when it closes where is the draw on
liquidity
from that price point there well you
have this short term high so do you need
do you need a depth of Market ladder to
tell you or a or book map
or some kind of order application to
tell you there's going to be buy order
stacking above this this High here do
you need that because I don't you don't
need that
that's reading tape do you need to know
that that all throughout this decline
here while price starts going up you're
going to see
all the orders above the marketplace
being eaten into because that's expected
we expect that we anticipate that we're
not reacting to that we're not surprised
at saying wow look at how the depth of
Market ladder is showing how all the
orders keep getting eaten and consumed
that that's expected that's reasonable
we expect that we're not surprised by
that
we're not surprised to help we don't
care what the number is either
I don't care what the footprints sound
how many people bought this level and
versus that I don't care because my
focus is on it's gonna
roll right back up this inefficiency
which is a sibi so I'll send a balanced
by sound efficiency it's a
classification of a fair value guy
but then once it goes to this level here
it's not done in my opinion because my
focus is up here so I'm reading the tape
I'm watching how it delivers
all through here
once you get to this price point here
I'm going to anticipate I'm going to
predict this is where I would be in my
live stream this is where I would be
in my recording of my execution I'd be typing out "Big Range Candles Incoming"
when it gets right here right to that price point low
right there I would be typing out
we're going to anticipate
we're going to expect
we're predicting
we're not going to be surprised by large up close candles
why? because it's going to make a quick run for the liquidity resting about this high
that's what the algorithm does folks. that's what it does
you're not going to know that from the depth of Market
you're not going to know that from the
footprint because that's it doesn't have
the ability to show you that experience
reading price action does so tape
reading is where that skill set is
derived from watching price action how
it behaves
I don't count the number of buys and
sells at a specific price level to me
it's irrelevant information I don't care
that doesn't doesn't mean anything to me
that's like saying how many cars passed
me on the left lane going to my
destination this morning I don't know
I'm focused on a destination which is up
here
I don't care how many cars pass me as
long as I have air in my tires gas in my
tank and my engine running fine
I'm getting there that's my focus I'm
looking through the windshield I'm not
looking in a rear view mirror which is
what footprint does
depth of Market it's so short-term in
perspective you don't need that
it's it's built in the idea that if you
know that you're trying to be
long on a Marketplace it goes without
saying that the orders above the
marketplace should be eaten and eroded
into
so where's the advantage in that
it goes without saying it's part of it
if the Market's going to go higher well
there you go I don't care how many
people are actually buying it because
the volume
how many buying and selling has
absolutely no bearing on my belief
system and why price goes where it goes
because it's algorithmically delivered
that's the problem
that all of you have with me you're all
wrong
and you're wrestling you're arm
wrestling they saying no no this is what
it really is but you're not even coming
close to the results I'm showing you you
can't even come close to the same
Precision that I'm showing you you can't
even call the Market to the degree I'm
doing on a weekly basis now
at some point at some point
you have to sit down
lay down your pitchforks and your
torches and say you know what
let me just listen to this guy and see
where it takes me that's all I'm asking
you to do
you don't have to do it
but everything I'm telling you happens
I'm telling you what goes on the
marketplace and why it does
I'm literally teaching it to you
I'm not demonstrating toys I'm teaching
you how to do it
what you have to do to develop this
skill set it takes work it's not
watching a video it's understanding what
you're supposed to do
and then go out and do it yourself
and it's going to feel like you don't
know what you're doing in the beginning
but showing up every day and from the
charts reading the tape that means
studying how it behaves without putting
a demo trade on without putting a live
trade on without trying to pass a
combine on a funded account it means
simply studying what price does based on
the time of day and day of the week
knowing in advance which I tell you
where the Market's going to go
it's going to go up or it's going to go
down to a very specific level not range
not Zone
and you use that 30 years experience to
trust while you're studying
so we have an ICT bullish breaker here
these are the instances where you see
classic support resistance ideas come in
and this right here this is one of those
videos where someone's going to come
back in the future and say see all ICT
is doing he's showing you classic
support and resistance and this is
nothing new on Nissan
no no
trust me we're going to go deeper I want
you to think about why this level would
be sensitive anyway
because there's other highs to the left
of this and I talk about that on my
market view that I did yesterday so on
July 15 2023 there's a market commentary
or market review video and I talk about
that very instance
so
I'm not going to take it any further
than that because I've already talked
about it yesterday
but I want you to think about how
- the market from this high traded down
- and then traded up
- and then threw it
what does that make this range from this low to that high
once we broke out Above This High here which is what we were anticipating
we're not breakout Traders
we're not reacting to price
we want to see that but what makes this a very specific range: this becomes a BPR
what makes it balanced? we had a high we traded it down so sell side delivery has been offered not SSL
SSD is any price run from a high to low
we have had SSD from here in here that that range
now when we run right back over that entire range again
from that low up to that high which is what we're doing here over time
as soon as we break through here this High to that low is now a BPR
there is absolutely no reason to anticipate expect or want to see price come back down below that low
why? because the focus is up here folks
we're expecting we're predicting we're
anticipating the market the footprint
it's as radon up to that level
we want to see that we're expecting that
so where is the mile markers that going
to be where's the where's the rest stops
along away well when the market runs
above this area here it's more likely to
do what treat this level here as a
breaker or a springboard to go higher
why
because this High has a lower
low that's higher than this low over
here I'm not showing it to you because I
want you to look at the commentary from
yesterday
I talk about this on the hourly chart
so the market comes back down
does it Wick through that high
absolutely and that's permissible
that means it's allowed we expect that we anticipate
that we're not reacting we're not scared
by it either
look where the bodies close right here and it opens right there
so there are Wicks that are going down
into this bison and balance I'll sound
efficiency which is busy it's a fair
value guy but what specifically stands
out here
what is that
what's the segment between this high
on that Candlestick right there to this
candlesticks home what is this area
what is that
it's inefficient but then when we see
this Candlestick here trade down into it
it erodes some of this inefficiency so
it starts from here to here this becomes a breakaway Gap w
e don't want to see that we don't want to see that filled in
are you telling me the ICT is teaching
how the see anticipate and work with
Breakaway gaps yes
now did I say ICT invented Breakaway gaps no
when I first started learning how to
look at Price action and uh John
Murphy's book which is the retail Bible
for Traders everything in that book if
you knew how to really trade based on
what I'm teaching you could turn it
upside down if you see that pattern
that's taught in that book and my
concepts are called for the opposite
that pattern in that book is going to
fail
don't take my word for it
and buy the book and challenge it so
by the way I don't have any affiliation
with John Murphy So when you buy his
book I get new Kickback so there it is
but it should be in every
every Trader's library because it really
is the retail Trader's Bible all that
stuff in there
is literally exploitable
if you understand what price is really
trying to do
so we have
this area here is a break wake up the
reason why it becomes a breakaway Gap
and why we would never expect
the depth of Market the Dom even if
there was bigger orders below the
marketplace here okay if there was a
stacking of orders below that that were
really large okay big big interest to
draw into that area down there they're
not going to go down there those things
are not going to fill
what yeah yep no Footprints are going to
be found down below that that low right
there
because it's going to go higher because
this area is going to stay open
why should it stay open? because it's running out of this range
right here it's already done the work of
digging into
this daily propulsion block this is why
you cannot look at one Candlestick chart
one time frame and follow the narrative
you can't you can't be done folks either
you're taking the information from the
HTFs and transposing them
that means placing whatever ideas that
you think is supportive or
counterproductive for your trade from a
HTF whatever makes that
trade idea you're under the
I guess expectation is going to pan out
whatever those ideas are from a higher
time frame weekly and daily chart
they have to be on your tradable chart
either
in
some kind of annotation some kind of you
know line or you know some kind of you
know mechanism that draws your attention
to it because if you don't have this
information if I didn't have the
propulsion block shaded over here you
would not know what it is I'm talking
about down here what makes the context
behind why it would be trading the way
it is you wouldn't know that that's the
only reason why I put this lipstick on
the charts because you're learning from
me so I don't need this but because I
don't need it doesn't mean I shouldn't
put on the chart because if you're
learning it will help you it's a crutch
it helps you stay organized from one
time frame to the next
but my focus is up here
I want this to go higher
so I'm gonna watch price reading the
tape and look for all the evidences all
the signatures and price action that
support that very thing coming to pass
I want to see periods where it's going
to run aggressively higher if I get that
then I'm gonna be really trustworthy
that I'm on side that means I'm on the
right side of the marketplace and stay
with the idea
do we get that confirmation with the
bodies thing at or above this high
here
yes does this stay open
it's not trading back down into it so
where's the advantage they are using
depth of Market or ladders or footprint
you would never expect this if you're my
student you're never expecting this area
to be printed into anymore
but I promise you and I've seen it
Traders are looking at those things and
they're expecting to go down because
they think this is an inefficiency now
because ICC has talked about it
no no this is why you should not be
listening to Dollar Menu mentorships
okay
you're going through the ICT drive
through just like they are
okay you're having the same experience
they are they're putting a price tag on
something that they don't even know how
to do yet
learn how to do it independently you
don't need to pay for this stuff
so the market should be rallying higher
where should It Go
well where's the next draw on liquidity
near term yes this is it up here but
what Above This High exists in terms of
liquidity buy sign
so your book map
or your depth of Market will start
reflecting as we get closer to it
there's going to be a lot of orders
resting at or just above that high you
need these tools to tell you that
because I don't and my students don't
need that either this is reading the
tape this is what reading the tape is it
has absolutely nothing to do with the
things I opened this presentation up
with
so when you read or see or listen to
these people out there they'll say
you're talking about institutional order
flow we're talking about reading the
tape show me your order book no no no
show me you using the information from
those tools and you calling the market
precisely
because that is lacking I don't see that
anywhere I absolutely do not see that I
would love to see it I would be
entertained by it and I would love
watching the person whoever it may be
that would be willing to do that
I am a person that loves to study a
traitor I don't want to relearn anything
there's nothing else out there that
would ever interest me that would ever
be better than what might have what I
have here is the market
but I love watching how Traders navigate
the marketplace themselves they manage
themselves or mismanage themselves it's
unfortunate sometimes but it's very
entertaining also when they're
discovering themselves
and truth be told sometimes I try to
counsel them and tell them where they
should focus their attention on how to
correct it and then many times it's not
received in in good spirits I'm
ridiculed or you know not
given any regard for it but you know
everybody has their own prerogatives in
their own choices they don't have you
don't have to you don't have to listen
to me
but I'm the guy calling all this stuff
before it happens
so the market right here has buy side
the market draws up into it what happens
before it gets to this run right here
right here this run right there what
happens
you see this Wick right here
you see that Wick half of that is what
consequent encouragement interesting how
it goes right down to it right there
interesting how we have a gap right
there with a wick
so if we have a gap like this with a
wick always trust
and allow for it's likely to go into
this CE not just
filled in that Gap right there
so it can trade down even though it goes
over top that Gap the the candlestick's
hybrid here if it went through that live
I would not be unsettled by that
I would not be scared by that
I would look for this candlesticks Wick
right here
the midpoint which is consequent
encroachment we treat that as a gap the
Mark goes right back to it there
then what does it do right back up here
all right so when the next game opens up
I would be looking at that and saying
okay now I want to see it start
expanding towards this High here
and I want to see it
aggressively run through I want to see
speed
oh we get it there
we come back down in what is it doing
it's working inside this Wick which is
what a gap we do gradients on wicks
75 of the wick 50 of the wick we never
want to see in this case here lower than
50 or CE so any
respect of this Wick should be limited
to the high 75 percent of the um Wick
and then consequent equation which is
half so in my mind when I'm watching
price action over here I don't want to
see it Go below half of that Wick
find that in Steve Nielsen's book go
over here look what it's doing
it's going down but it won't breach on a
closing basis midpoint of that Wick
which is consequent encouragement that's
tape reading you can't see that in Dom
you can't see that in footprint you're
not even going to look for it there's no
reason for your look for it because it's
not in that theory
Dan's not talking about it white cup
doesn't know anything about it either
so the market does what it rallies Above
This High here what's above that high
buy side buy stops someone is chasing
that lower when it's green this is an
hourly chart so inside that week
this in the hourly candlestick
someone's going short where they're
gonna place a stop
about that high so the market does what
it gravitates up to it here
and we drop down
respecting CE there
and we rally
what do we do now we start expanding
aggressively towards that Weekly
mitigation block
this level right here
and we trade up into
that level there and then we consolidate
markets do not top like this
so we have what is this
what is this area right here become once
we trade through it here right there
what does this area or fractal and price
action become
the same thing I told you this becomes a
balanced price range from this
candlesticks High here
up to this High then back down once we
clear this High here this whole shaded
area becomes a balanced price range I am
not
concerned about price one at any time up
here going back down inside this range
so for stop loss management your stop
loss can be anywhere in this range and
feel pretty confident that it's not
going to get there so how would I do it
and sleep good at night
75 of that range if my stop is below
that I'm comfortable with that
some of you get crazy about how I'm
using my stops sometimes they get really
close to what you might be scared to do
at the time when you're watching my
executions and you're seeing it you're
thinking man this is crazy I wouldn't
feel comfortable because you just don't
know I'm teaching you right now
these are long videos these are very
dense very
demanding of your attention
to learn
and that's expected I didn't tell you
it's going to be easy and watch a video
and you know how to do it I've warned
you ahead of time it's going to take a
lot of work but it's something that it's
worth doing because once you have this
skill set nobody can take it from you
they can make jokes about all they want
but they're never going to be able to do
what you can do once you master this
so let's go into
now we have the hourly chart over here
and we have the balance price range
there
and now this chart here is a 15 minute
time frame
so we have the market
trading sideways ahead of Friday
so we have this consolidation here and
then we have a market report that's due
out
on Friday
we're anticipating what the Market's not
going to top like this
so we anticipate the Market's going to
do what
spool higher going higher run higher
so at 8 30 when the news comes out on
Friday here's the five minute chart here
we have the market rally aggressively
here which is a buy side and balanced
sales sign efficiency which is the long
name for bissy b-i-s-i this is a fair
value Gap by classification specifically
buy side imbalance cell side
inefficiency that means it's
buy side imbalance it's more upside and
it didn't go back and forth
to offer sell side delivery we get
partial sell side delivery with this
drop right here in this segment in price
action where I told you it's a breakaway
Gap that's what I'm zoomed into here
showing on a five minute basis but I
want you to think about what
is occurring here at this time of day at
10 30 after the news driver
we have this swing low here and it
breaks below that
this segment of price action right in
here
is a fair value guy it's a sibby sell
side imbalance by side and efficiency
which is the opposite of this over here
so it's offering the market on a sell
side delivery but there is an
inefficiency on buy side so we would
anticipate markets like this to re-price
up into this Candlestick or higher
and then reprice lower why what time of
day is it New York lunch macro so Above
This High we have buy side liquidity and
it's entering a time of day where the
lunch macro which is going to do what
it's going to run for liquidity where is
the liquidity at for this time of day
looking at in this area here it's below
the lows of the morning
what is that
right here
this is your your swing low right after
the news driver hits the marketplace
first swing low here
everybody that went long or was long
before this market report was out they
have their cell stop resting right below
that that's exactly what the lunch macro
will do it'll run from this fairbag app
here
drop down aggressively
leaving what
most of this portion of this open which
is what I've already talked about in the
couple minutes ago this is a breakaway
guy
this line right here
is this line right there it's the
breaker so this high that line is this
line right here on the five minute chart
this little segment of price action
right there and it's a breakaway Gap
that's this little portion right here
below that low
okay so that way you can
find your way through the charts of what
I'm showing you if you're not doing this
with your own analysis and toggling
through
you know scrolling through each
individual time frame while you're
watching price action having every
expectation the Market's going to be
going what going higher
so we're seeing even on the five minute
chart look at the bodies of these
candles here are they closing below
that breaker line which is this
candlesticks high right there
even on the five minute chart it's
showing you what that this is being
respected there's no necessity for it to
trade back down into this area so that
will be a what a breakaway Gap
that indicates that we're going to see
continuous upside delivery
and it's going to draw towards the buy
side that's the next significant pool of
liquidity
so throughout the afternoon we see the
market treated higher
come back down in
trade higher
come back down in some random fair value
Gap here and then gravitate start moving
towards the higher high again which is
this here okay we run out of day
during the day session so all this
consolidation when we resume at 6 PM
because the market takes a an hour break
between 5 PM Eastern Time to 6 p.m when
that occurs when markets start trading
again the same premise we would have in
our expectation we're not reacting we're
anticipating and predicting price that
will eventually gravitate towards this
High here so if you're an overnight
session Trader say you want to trade in
Asia say you want to trade in London
you're using these ideas in conjunction
with the day and time that you're
trading so where's liquidity the
liquidity is not changing because you're
trading in Asia the liquidity is not
hiding itself and becoming something
different and morphing into something
else because you're in the London
session liquidity is there and it's
going to gravitate towards that level
and if this context is here we focus on
moving higher
so let's go a little bit further in this
here's that five minute chart
you can see how we gravitated here
higher and now
the end of the day and now starting a
new day
so we start working towards what all
throughout Asia and then we get to
midnight interesting enough going into a
new day at midnight New York time we ran
the buy side here right there boom
then we do what we come back down
what's below here
South Side stops
but I want to take you before we go any
further here I want to take you back
into this area here focus on this little
segment of price action right there what
time frame is this chart
are you looking up here
it's a five minute chart
look at all the things here on this five
minute chart do you see anything that
stands out we'll come back to it but I
want you to see in comparing contrast
the price action on the five minute
we're gonna drop down to a four three
two and one but we're going to focus on
this little area and why am I focusing
on this area here to shade it in
from this high down to that low and then
how we start to deliver going back up
because the the trust is that there's no
necessity to go back down into this area
which is a breakaway Gap because this
line here
is your bullish breaker everything is
indicating that order flow is supporting
that idea
I don't need a ladder I don't need a
depth of Market I don't need a footprint
I don't need any of that stuff you don't
either the time based chart will tell
you everything you need
it's simple it really is simple but
you're trying to bring every concept
that I've ever introduced into every
discussion
I'm not doing that
I'm not bringing everything into this
fractal here only things that stand out
in this fractal I can only deal with
whatever PD arrays exist in this shaded
area
so watch this shaded area this is the
five minute chart now we're going to
transition into a four minute
okay notice any changes here this is the
part of the video you're going to want
to go back and study independently or
look at it from your own chart
preferably I don't know what time you're
going to watch this video maybe years
later but I'm doing this for the purpose
of that because you may not be able to
recall this information on your chart at
the time so yeah you can use my charts
here and screenshot them and
do whatever annotations you want to do
now we'll look at the three minute chart
okay that is all this here what is price
dealing I don't need a depth of Market
to show you what I'm about to show you
it's a two minute chart
same range but it looks different
doesn't it
and then finally down to the one minute
chart
now this
green line here again is the hourly
bullish breaker that high
we dig into it here one
one two three times and then we have a
swing High
broken to the upside
the last down closed candle prior to
that shift in Market structure that down
close candle is a bullish order block
that opening price is a change in the
state of delivery now huge leap forward
for people that want to learn order
blocks okay
for the record
order blocks have zero notice I'm not
talking about that the market here
notice I'm not even pointing at a ladder
I'm not talking about footprint I didn't
even talk about volume I don't care how
many orders were purchased or sold short
in this candle it's irrelevant
that has nothing to do with my order
block my order block which is codified
and created and authored by me nobody
else is the author of it I didn't borrow
it from somebody else and any supply and
demand
this candle right here the open of that
candle the change in the state of
delivery is when that candle sticks
opening price is crossed right there for
the first time
when that happens then and only then
never before never another time in the
future that validates this down closed
candle as a bullish order block
now why
what makes that an order block the fact
that we have this bullish
hourly breaker
the fact that we traded down into it and
then we see a shift in Market structure
then we go back to the down closed
candle the last one prior to a run
higher that has a shift in Market
structure there that is not a change of
character
rebranding
stop it this is not an Fu candle this is
not an engulfing King I don't care if
this candle started here
it opened here and went down or if it
opened here and went down I would draw
it right on the opening price
it has nothing to do with engulfing it
has nothing to do with anything else
except for what I'm teaching you right
here folks anybody out there trying to
teach order blocks unless they're
parenting exactly what I said in another
video lecture they don't know what
they're talking about
period and the story that's just the
facts
this becomes a bullish order block as
soon as that candle crosses it
what the opening price that's the change
in the state of delivery soon as that
occurs this low
should not be violated
so you can now start looking for bullish
PD arrays that are in discount well
everything's in a discount now because
we're so far down but
we have a down close candle right here
so we can use that opening price extend
it for anything in there buying this
anywhere in this area here buying buying
that you can buy that with a stop loss
right below there
well that's a little bit too wide for me
then don't take the tree
wait for another run higher and look for
an inefficiency wait for a fair value go
wait for a breaker wait for a
institutional order for entry drill wait
for whatever your model is suggesting
you should use
but look closer
we are now looking at that price range
from this high up here all the way down
to that low we trusted that low will not
be violated why because this Candlestick
was crossed right there now what happens
let's pay Depot's Advocate what happens
if it breaks that low okay then you have
this continuously study price action and
wait for that same instances where we
see a shift in our construction to it
upside in the last down closed candle
we'll mark the opening price and if
there's a candle that goes above it that
validates the down close candle as a
bullish order block
this is only one form of my bullish over
block there are so many of them and yes
for the folks out there that have a
problem with me having all kinds of
weapons in my repertoire I'm sorry that
I'm not a one-trick pony I'm sorry that
there's a whole lot of things out there
but you don't have to know everything
I'm teaching you you just need one thing
one thing one concept one model and you
can be profitable and you don't have to
worry about anything else I've ever made
videos about I don't know why you guys
are complicated you're complicating it
not me you are so
we have the ranges here 75 of the range
is the gradient 50 percent
and then 25 percent
so I want you to notice how as price
works very close to 25 of that range
again the range is the high to that low
we are trusting that it wants to go
higher now because we have a change in a
state of delivery and when that candle
starts moving above that opening price
now we have it it's in place
we have a shift in Market structure all
lights are green for going higher how do
we use this information how do we read
the tape how do we discount the
necessity for reaching for depth of
Market ladders and footprints
you'll need those tools
look at price.
order flow
what kind of order flow?
institutional order flow
easiest, right to the chase no bones about it
easiest thing is if we're bullish we want to see down closed candles support price
if we see a short-term low taken out, we expect to see that as a stop run and then price should revert right back into going higher right away
and everything I just said reverse it for when the markets are bearish
it's that simple folks watch we have a
down closed candle here draw it out in
time does price support at that level
yes yes yes does it start moving higher
yes does it take out short-term highs
yes
down close candle is price supporting it
as a bullish order block yes it's not
going below it does price go higher and
take out High yes it does we have a down
closed candle does price go down into it
and reject that area and leave it and
break a high
yes do you need a depth of Market ladder
to tell you that we expect the depth of
Market the latter to start eating into
those orders above the market price
that's expected folks we anticipate that
we are predicting that to happen
we expect that your candlesticks and
your raincoat bars and your algo bars
and whatever the hell you're going to be
using
they're going to start going higher
that's expected folks
we expect that
we're not surprised by it down close
candles here why am I picking this one
because it's above this High here and
it's high here so does it support price
look at it what happens when it hits it
starts going higher does it take out a
short-term High yes it does so is order
flow bullish or bearish if
what is it reaching for
a premium relative to what the range
which is this High to that low
that is determined by this level here
which is equilibrium
at that level or below it is what
discount
at that level or above is what premium, so when we get above this 50 level
it's far less probability, more risk if we start taking order blocks and buying them Above This level
because we're in the premium range of this high to low
doesn't mean it can't keep rallying it
just means that we have to do all of our
buying below equilibrium or less while
we're on a discount that's the framework
for high probability
short-term lows being taken out we
expect that to be rejected and start
seeing price go higher we start to see
it run higher here because it finds
support on this down closed candle here
yes sends it higher does it take a short
term High yes and yes
we have a down closed candle here right
around equilibrium
no return back to here that's fine
because that we're in an area where it's
a short-term premium
down closed candle here
look at the body supporting that idea
and then the Rally's higher Highs are
taken out down closed candle does it
support it as bullish yes higher
so when I'm watching price and I'm on one side and I'm expecting prices to go higher
I'm looking at every down closed candle as a means or mechanism to support price
or any swing low is a potential stop run so I'm not in a hurry
if I'm long to ram my stop loss between some random swing low
because that's exactly what the algorithm is going to do, it's going to sweep below them
like it does here like it does here and like it does here
and then once it does that a round
equilibrium then it's going to go into
another price leg higher and then we
enter a consolidation
what's below here cell stops
now we can go higher
notice also that we have all of these
FVGs right here and all this
in here
when we have a change in the state of
delivery and we enter a buy program
which is where we are from this point on
there
well what's going on here Michael it's
just retracing that's all it's doing
it's allowing for a Deeper Discount with
that low staying intact
when this high is taken out here notice
that we have another return back into
this order block when we have this
retracement back in the over block here
that's when we start seeing the more
pronounced run higher but look what's
occurring here all of this imbalance
here
what is it lacking buy side delivery not
liquidity buy side deliveries when there
is a run higher in Price look what it's
doing it runs higher look at the bodies
respecting what the inefficiency is high
right there this city that candle is low
wasn't respecting this candle's low
here now what is it dropping down into
CE midpoint of this
candle's low and this candle is high
there rallies where's rally two the fair
Bay Gap right here
so what how we use this information
their inversion FVGs
these are like a mountain climber
and the mountain climber is climbing up
the surface of the mountain and he's
looking for those little pockets that
stick his fingers into and stick his
toes on to find footing and grasp a new
finger point or holding point to pull
his body up well we're in a bullish
market now
we're in a buy program we're climbing a
mountain what's the mountain this is the
Mountainside here this is the most sheer
drop-off
so this is the smoothest part
in that drop-off so we have to use these
areas to find what footing
there's little pockets we have to wait
for them to form that means consequent
encroachment
short term low trades below what's it
going to do trade back into this order
block and take out that short-term low
for sell stops I'm not freaking out when
I see that I want to see it react at
that order block and then also that it's
taken out liquidity and there's also a
volume and balance right there
that's tape reading you watch price
whether you're watching it live or you
have to watch it in Market replay which
is not going to be the same folks unless
unless you can watch price delivery
every individual fluctuation which
trading view is limited it doesn't do
that
um it's better for you if you can't
watch live price action to to Res you
know record your screens I use Camtasia
which is a application from
techsmith.com
t-e-c-h-s-m-i-t-h Dot c-o-m
and that is the
the program that I use to record and
make these videos you can set it to
record the marketplace while you're at
work while you're sleeping while you're
at school whatever and then when you
come home you can play back the
recording and watch real-time price
delivery and it's a wonderful way to do
journaling if I had that resource when I
first started that's how I would do my
journaling I would make it in video
format and yes it takes a lot of time
yes it would take a lot of time to
manage it all yes but all that time
would shorten anyone's learning curve
but you don't want to put a lot of work
into it and you wonder why you're not
getting the results you're looking for
so FVGs like this if we're
bearish we expected to go up there and
sell off but when there's a change in
the state of delivery
we expect the market to go up so all
these down movements here it's lacking
what by side delivery so it's going to
want to gravitate up into them
if it ever retraces into them once it
closes them in
we treat them as what inversion fair
value gaps
so we see this CE
which is midpoint of the Shaded area
midpoint between this low and this high
here we rally up to what
this Gap we're treating it as an
inversion paper you get does that mean
it's going to trade right here and go
higher rate from there no we have to
wait and watch what is this here this is
a buy-time balance outside efficiency
what is this right here it's a swing low
we've had a nice move outside of the
range of these REHs and
we're into two inefficiencies this one
and this one and now we have a short
term low it's
probable not guaranteed it's probable
that it's going to run for short-term
sell-side liquidity stop hunt that's
what we're getting from here it drops
down takes out that liquidity also
respecting constant encroachment of this
Fairway Gap
then rallies it rallies to this high and
through this inversion FVG
comes back down
support support rallies back up what is
it creating
what's it creating here
short term low so what's going to be
trailed up right behind that sell side
where are we at in the range
from high
to low
here's equilibrium we're right there at
equilibrium when this occurs equilibrium
is where you're going to anticipate
you're going to predict you're going to
expect
a stop hunt
that's what the algorithm will do don't
take my word for this folks do not take
my word for it you go back and look at
old price moves you're going to see this
every single time 100 of the time every
single time and that's what you're
seeing here a run on stops this one is
two times
but returning back into what this fair
value gap which is an inversion for
everybody got you would take this extend
it over
what is it respecting
this order block still that's a
reclaimed order block but it's also in
concert with this candlesticks low
it's respecting that old Gap so that
makes this an entry off of what this
inversion fair value got right here
the market finds support here
rallies
takes up high takes up the high And
Trades up into what
the next Gap over here which will be
treated as what an inversion of airbago
so I'm looking at like a mountain
climber here
I'm looking at all the potential finger
holes where I can grab a hold too pull
myself up higher that's what price is
doing that's all prices doing folks it's
so easy to understand when you try to
lay down all the other stuff you're
trying to bring into this you want to
bring in
Elliott wave stuff still you want to
bring in harmonic animal patterns that
have absolutely no reason for expecting
price to go higher or lower that's a
fantasy that's a religion
don't bring Gan into discussion white
golf
it's let the man rest okay he's not part
of this conversation I promise you he's
not
when we drop down we're taking out
Southside here
and we're doing what for rallying off of
the low of this okay Vega
so this candle sticks High that's what
we're respecting everything look at the
bodies it's telling you the story it's
supporting the idea that that is still
the underlying narrative
thoughts have been taken
control mechanisms are in place the
algorithm is absolutely respecting that
old fair value gut right here that again
Samsung we are cutting through candles
because that's where the narrative is
derived from
the inversion pair that you got for the
win rallies order block touch it does it
rally higher yes does it stay at a high
yep
do you see what tape reading is now
do you understand how we're working with
time frames and we drop down to the
lower time frames and we do not need any
gimmicks to see what price should do
it's liquidity and inefficiency it's
discount and premium time of day all
these things come together to make a
beautiful tapestry and you're never
surprised
once you understand all this stuff
you're not surprised you want to see
these things form and you're waiting for
them to form
my profitable students see these things
before they happen
the only thing that happens when they're
watching price they're not saying oh my
goodness where did that come from why
did that just happen they're grinning
before it starts to deliver they know
it's coming
they are grinning right now as they're
listening to it because they know
nodding their head yup yup because if
we're all on the same river now and I
said raise your hand if you've been
there before all kinds of hands will be
raised up
but you can't experience it until you
had that experience
and you'll never have that experience
until you go in and watch and study
price action like this
I promise you all the things I'm
teaching you they keep repeating
but you want something that's easy go
out there in one two three get me and
get me out never have a losing trade and
I'm sorry
but there's no way to do that
I get it wrong sometimes
sometimes
all right so here is the back on the 15
minute time frame so what happens once
we clear this balance price range here
remember we hit the bullish breaker line
here
we have all these inefficiencies in here
what happens when we get above it what
can we do now well we have a Target up
here that's a drawing liquidity and then
we have now this Old Market structure
high so now we can take that range and
draw a fib from that high up
to this target now we have gradients so
now we're grading a future price point
that has not happened yet
as soon as this Candlestick right here
closes now we run from high to Target
and we run gradients and now watch what
happens around the 20 I'm sorry I have
it backwards here 75 or the lower 25 of
the range between the draw and liquidity
and the high that was broken we don't
think that the Market's going to go down
here why because this is a balanced
price range
so we anticipate every instrument out
there every little gimmick every little
toy is going to say oh look orders are
getting eaten above market price
the footprints showing that look it's
it's bull it's just absolutely bullish
of course it is it's gone higher
so we have relative equal lows and they
sweep that where does that occur in the
lower quadrant of the range from this
high up to that Throne liquidity which
is the weekly mitigation block that's
what this level is up here
then we have consolidation where does
consolidation form ICT although I said
it in the core content lessons back in
2016 and I taught it to everybody that
was my private one-on-one student back
in 1996.
at equilibrium 50 level right here
that's where consolidation is forming
and then what happens
a stop hunt
lower time frames look in there you'll
see it
rallies up
another time here and what happens here
at the upper quadrant
from the draw in liquidity
to this high
we're anticipating new price points that
surge higher that's what that's what I'm
showing you here
we rally up then we take out the
liquidity above
that Weekly mitigation block
then we do what we find some support at
it
and then we consolidate going into
Friday
New York session
that's where we're at now this is a
15-minute time frame on Friday
and we're consolidating
markets do not top like this folks
especially ahead of
news drivers
so a market report
we're expecting prices go higher
we've Consolidated we're part of a
bullish run and we're expecting
capitulation to come in and that's what
we're seeing here Market rallies
aggressively
what are we what are we seeing here see
this Gap right there
extend that through that's what you're
seeing that's an inversion fair value
explosive run to the upside
retracement
failed to run higher
back down into the cell side here for a
TGIF tree
let's take a closer look
five minute chart on the NASDAQ
here's that price run here
then we have this by Center balance
outside and efficiency we'll get to that
in a moment and then we run up we have a
blow off move and then we break down
where's the fair value here
there isn't one in here not on this side
of the curve the curve is here and then
damp
so you have to use the imbalance on the
left side
that's going to be an inversion of
everybody go
extend that through all the price action
that's what you're seeing here
then you have a small little Fair bag
out there that I didn't want to draw any
annotations on because we have the
inversion frame rate I can pull it out
like I'm doing here trades up into it
here then we break
this area here is a breakaica
we want to see it stay open
so why should it become a breakaway Gap
because we have had a shift in Market
structure there
we have a bystanding balance outside and
efficiency why trade the NASDAQ and not
the s p ICT I'm telling you right now
relative equal lows blow off move after
the market has been going straight up
all week as we were expecting it to do
and then we have the inversion fair
value Gap is it respecting that yep and
then we break below the short term low
here below this short term low here and
where's liquidity at below here sell
sign
but then we have this bison efficiency
so any Rally from this Candlestick open
up in to Above This High we want to see
it stay open what happens if it closes
in it's okay
I would still want to kick a short up
there if I was watching live
and the market breaks down
doesn't get below the what the bodies so
we still have this Wick to contend with
so we retrace higher
up close candles consecutively that's a
bearish order block
breaks down through it
extend the opening price over there
that's a change in state of delivery
returns back into a here and all of this
consolidation is time Distortion it's
not time for the market to do anything
it's not going to do it it's already ran
the low here which is the lunch Macro
for New York it's already did that but
we're not done we have TGIF
it's Friday so thank God it's Friday
it's likely to do what 20 to 30 of the
weekly range in terms of a retracement
from the high of the week where's the
high of the week over here when can we
trust that's the high of the week when
we see this element here and then we
start seeing everything start breaking
down this high is intact
but what happens if it runs up and goes
higher then you're wrong how's that for
logic you're going to get it wrong
sometimes
but you have to have rules and things to
work with to grow in your understanding
as a Trader and this is what I'm sharing
with you what time does time distortion
stop
what did I teach you post New York lunch
we start seeing two o'clock to four
o'clock that's your PM session time
then all of a sudden what happens the
market delivers a run through
low
or low
very bad you got
trades up into it
CE of the low on
this Wick
boom
sells off hits the SSL
And Trades to 20 level of the weekly
candlestick
so from the high to the low measure that
and it retraces 20 of the weekly range
in here
blow out the cell cell side and then
close real close to which is not noted
here but look at the commentary I did on
July 15 2023 the video right before this
one
and you'll see the TGIF levels and how
the fine Diamond markdown on your chart
this is all the details and that was not
in that presentation
this is what was in my trade idea that
uh
wasn't cherry-picked I elected to use
the NASDAQ because it was
more exposed to inefficiency here
and it was much more energetic on the
upside and much more energy on the
downside so it had a better structure
than that of es that was the reason why
I did DS es got real close to doing a 20
retracement of its weekly range
if you still traded ES
you still would have been able to find
profitability doing it so it's not an
argument about you know es and NASDAQ
which one you should have been in
because they both offered the
opportunity but NASDAQ I was in and
NASDAQ was just a beautiful delivery
thank you
right and here's a one minute chart of
that time of day here's
the PM session and I want you to see
that
inefficiency that bison let me take you
back up so that way you know where I'm
pointing your attention to this range
right here okay we're looking at a five
minute chart we're going to drop down
into a one minute chart and look at
Price action from here to here okay
that's what we're watching but in this
shaded area right here I'm going to put
the gradients in 25 50 and 75.
we're going to look at this return back
into that
shaded area here okay so here's the
lower quadrant or 25 percent of the
range that's shaded here
so here's the high 75 of that range 50
of that range 25 of that range and the
low of it
so the market trades up into that and
we'll come back that in a second let's
go back up into here and look at some of
the details
right away this should jump off at you
that's a breakaway Gap why why should
that be a very wake up because we are
under time Distortion that means all
this back and forth price action is just
marking time that's the benefit of
knowing how to use a time-based chart
I'm not getting fooled by candlesticks
I'm waiting for time when does it start
right there two o'clock in the afternoon
New York local time because the market
is driven by an algorithm there's a time
for everything
a beginning and an end
a pause a consolidation and Distortion
where everything you try to do will chop
you up
so you wait wait for what two o'clock
and then wait for displacement what does
that look like right here
takes out that short-term love boom but
now we have what we're late in the day
this shaded area here is the Bots animal
cell sign efficiency we have moved away
from the high and we moved aggressively
away from the 75 percent upper 75 range
of this shaded area so I don't want to
see this area come back into I don't
want to see it come back up and trade
into that but if it does I would treat
it as an Institutional order flow
integral in other words a partial entry
and then sell off
either way it makes it a breakaway Gap
so we don't want to see it trade back up
above 50 or consequent encouragement on
this shaded area here and now we enter
into another time of day
the 250 to 310 macro my algorithm starts
at 250 to 310 and we'll start spooling
price running for the liquidity that has
not been purged yet what is that
liquidity the liquidity below the lows
the 7 A.M New York session time
the 830 lows the 9 30 to 11 lows all of
that is the draw on liquidity
and or in this case 20 of the weekly
range that would be anywhere in this
area here
but we start to see this energetic price
run aggressive dropping lower that's
algorithmic
this
right here just like I talked about
earlier when we ran up
you can use the FVG on the
left side of the Curve and we've seen
that happen right there if it would have
been opening here trade it up right
there if I was wanting to trade short
and I hadn't already been short that
would be an area where I would go short
right there too
then it breaks this is a measuring Gap
we don't want to see that filled in just
like we don't want to see that what
makes this a measuring cup
well between this High down to this low
we're expecting that run in about
halfway
we're expecting a gap to form when it
does and it moves away from it we are
not expecting it to come back into that
that's a measuring Gap you have to know
where the market is likely to draw too
if you don't have that skill set you
will not be consistent in your ability
to find or classify a measuring guy
Breakaway gaps are just gaps when you
want to see an energetic price run away
from an area you anticipated prior to
it running away
so you're expecting it to move lower
great
when it finally does and it creates a
gap like this your first thought should
be okay the first favorite you got after
it starts to run that should be a
breakaway Gap we want to see that
especially if we've been in
consolidation or experiencing time
Distortion time Distortion is simply a
matter of time between segments of time
of the day where markets will start
spooling that's it that's a very simple
thing it doesn't mean that you should
understand it right away because I said
that but over time when you come back to
these lessons like this or refer back to
new future lessons that I'll talk about
it it'll make perfect sense to you
because you haven't been exposed to it
enough times to know exactly what I'm
referring to
the market finally rips below the sell
side liquidity does it multiple times in
here and then consolidates at the close
going into 20 percent of the range of
nasdaq's weekly candle
all right folks so
I covered a lot of stuff here and I will
admit rather openly that this is not one
of those easy go out there and I can do
what ICT has taught me okay but I'm
showing you many things here I'm showing
you a Amplified version of what we do by
reading the tape I've rung in macros
I've rung in time of day I've rung in
how we use Breakaway gaps and measuring
gaps and how we anticipate price action
and we don't look for ladders depth of
Market footprint or anythings because
we're anticipating price performing a
specific function
we understand order flow what kind of
order flow institutional order flow
institutional order flow is going to be
based on the things I'm showing you here
price is the thing that's the that's the
context that's the that's the prize that
we seek the better understanding of that
you can take the Open high low and close
of every interval
and beat it up torture it with number
crunching and have it come out with all
kinds of supposed insights
some kind of mathematically derived
indicator or you can take the past and
say okay this is how many contracts were
bought or sold at this price and
therefore I believe this or that or you
can look at a range above the
marketplace price or below the
marketplace price
and determine and there's a larger range
of
or number of orders above the
marketplace than that of below it and
you might think that that is indicative
of wanting to go higher not always
think about it what happens if you're in
these types of situations here
where you're right before the market is
going to start going lower
but your depth of Market your latter
suggests that there's a lot of orders
just above the market price
you might be convinced by looking at
just that tool thinking that okay it
should start going higher and eat into
that number no that might be just a
large pool of smart monies stop loss
that isn't going to be tripped that
isn't going to be eroded or eaten into
and then you watch price run away and
you're thinking yourself wow look at
that rip wow look at that where'd that
come from what just happened somebody
must be talking all these things folks
all these things come out of the mouths
of people that just don't know how to do
this yet
and I want them to learn that's all I
want them to learn just like you I want
them to understand how they can capture
these types of price runs and not hurt
themselves in the process
so if we found this one insightful
hopeless
edifying for you until I'll talk to you
next time
be safe