what can you say when you lose somebody
like David Paul God he enriched the
lives of everyone unbelievable the
thousands of people that he met I mean
it was incredible the most amazing thing
about it from my perspective is the
depth of knowledge and the humility by
which he presented it I mean there's not
many people like him around folks and
he's not here anymore but his legacy
will live on forever because he trained
one of the best traders that I've ever
met who was a great Trader Tom who guard
and David Paul turned him into one of
the greatest Traders I have ever met
he's done things that I didn't think
were possible it was mainly because of
the work of David and he was almost like
a father to him and it worked out great
for both of them he will certainly be
missed I was able to trade with David
one day and I was absolutely impressed
about how simple the methodology that he
used worked his whole idea was when you
find something that you really like and
you know it's going to work and you have
a pretty good idea what your risk is you
have to a bit big and that's what it was
all about is risk little and bet big and
he did this with an incredible amount of
success
David's personality is what really
brought everybody together because of
his love of the business the way he
handled people and he didn't have any
strangers anybody that came up to him
absolutely loved the man and he he will
really be missed he he was a really a
stand-up guy
and I can tell you this that by golly I
I will certainly miss him I only got to
know him for about 10 years but uh it
was really something to really know this
gentlemen so if you ever see any work by
him pay close attention because he was
the real deal and he was a stand-up guy
in anybody's book Larry pessimano
signing off folks and may God bless
uh so I I don't know I've told you guys
this story but uh
when my son started to trade I told him
to
did I tell that on Friday
when my when my son started to trade I
uh told him to watch videos of Tom at
saxo bank that were done 12 15 years ago
of that order and his trademark of the
day was a a three-piece sit you know
with the old west coat and that dreaded
black tie that he used to wear
everywhere so
uh Mike watched us any uh
text me back he said he's the James Bond
of trading
and to this to this day and Friday uh he
sent me a what's up message he says give
my regards to bond
so it's a compliment I assure you so a
compliment ah so and I believe Daniel
Craig is giving the job up so you could
be in the running I'll
I don't well I don't know I don't know
where those
so folks let's let's let's go into some
charts but you've been in lots and lots
of charts what I tried to do in the last
two hours I believe from the bottom of
my heart uh dealing with literally
hundreds and thousands of Traders uh
that
that's what they need and
unfortunately the more they resist
the stuff that I just spoke about that
will be directly proportional to their
failure as a Trader
I'm afraid okay
coming to terms with uncertainty is
difficult really really difficult
especially if if you're from the
professions and in Chicago they sort of
use a dentist for uh the the classic
professional and you've got to say to
yourself a dentist wants to trade what
does he know about risk what is the
chances of you getting past that dentist
receptionist without showing your credit
card to pay for the bill
I don't know what Danish risk dentist
receptionists are like but the ones in
the UK you wouldn't stand a chance
there'll be one grizzled battle ax
sitting there
and she'll want her lit before you leave
uh soap
rule number one the good trait is a hard
trade
you know who taught me that
delightful old man he was one of the
first Market Wizards Michael steinhardt
do you know him Larry
I know him so well he's 90 these days
91. he's still trading my word he's made
a hemp he trashed those uh indices for
25 years uh and he was the inspiration
for me in fact buying oil right at the
Lowe's I was just that classic Michael
steinhardt trade and please Google uh
Michael steinhardt uh he was one of the
original Market Wizards uh he has got
cast iron you know what's in his day uh
he was something uh uh a really
privileged to speak to him on one
occasion uh rule number two guys the
good Trends are hard to it I'm not
saying it's intellectually difficult
okay in fact as I said in Friday the
thicker you are the better but it's just
difficult to do the Market's roaring
down three big red bars
put Sophia God into you I know some
idiot tells you you must step in and buy
it it was really really difficult
okay
very difficult to do uh so uh
that's a characteristic of a good trade
uh if the thread seems easy there's a
good chance you're just about to be
sexually violated and that's fine if you
like that sort of thing okay uh
rule number two I want to feed the
short-term Trend in the direction of the
long-term trend
he's smiling do you like that sort of
thing
okay
we've heard all about you Danish fellas
yeah ripping and pillaging
uh so fade the short-term Trend in the
direction of the long-term Trend so what
I'm saying is that I've got a long-term
Trend in place and I want to buy a
pullback uh and Let It Go Again guess
what that is
AV blessed CD okay so I wonder where I
got that from
and uh then the third row
I want to put my entries where the
masses put their stops how's that
on your way home
I want you to pass
a building site
and on the building site you pick up a
brick
okay you take that back home
and tomorrow when you're about to put on
your first trade
decide where you're getting in
just before you press the button you
pick the brick up and you go smack it
against your head
that puts you into the present moment
and here's what I want you to do
rather than buying the market at where
you thought you were going to buy the
market buy them put an order in at where
you were going to put your stop and see
how often the damn thing goes to your
stop okay
so uh
place your entries where the Masters
place your stops and this is another
thing I learned from Larry is that the
best traits occur when the masses have
been stopped and trapped
so even if you don't get in at the cusp
of the turn if you can look back and see
that a whole just obvious on the chart
that lots of people would have bought
there and then the bloody thing went
down again nailed them and then reversed
if you get in after those people have
nailed then you're on a much better
place
okay
and of course that's difficult because
we're scared of missing out at least I
am
okay uh so uh
so I'm going to talk about a little bit
about Richard Wyckoff and I know uh many
people say that volume doesn't work but
uh volume uh especially in the stock
market is a great great Edge
and if I have the discipline
if I have the discipline
to in the stock market to wait for a
volume coming to the party I can get my
head rate up to 80 percent
uh when volume hits me between the eyes
so uh Richard weichel died in 1934 his
work was carried on by many many people
I bought this original course in the
early 1980s and I went through it and
please do not buy a white golf's works
and this course unless you're prepared
to put a great deal of effort into it
I'm not saying you won't do that but
it's certainly not something that you're
going to take in on a Sunday afternoon
while you're putting back three or four
frosties okay that's not going to work
he writes in the uh like the king
James's version of the Bible it's all
these and the eyes really really
difficult going as ganned it so his
three laws supply and demand
uh cause and effect effort and result
so I'm I'm
my slides are not as good and I've
so the the rule is it the price action
and the chart must reflect the volume
action below it
uh if the volume demand is large and the
price a move is large then price is
acting rationally
if they don't then that in Wyckoff
terminology is known as a non-validation
and that's a leading indicator
uh and an opportunity for profit so uh
for example a large change in price and
low volume so we got a breakout on low
volume uh then that's a known validation
and
markets on any time frame rising and
falling volume need to be carefully
watched
uh
and all of this came from the old fellas
Livermore Wyckoff and a whole host of
traders of that era just reading the
tape the only thing that was on the tape
was price and volume
so what Wyckoff tried to do in his chart
reading and his course was to try and
give the retail Trader the ability and
the education to be able to read the
tape
in terms of price and volume
uh and I love the wake of stuff I really
do and it's a complicated Theory uh
fella in the stock market there's a
gentleman called Stanley Weinstein
that's written uh quite a few books on
the longer term uh aspects of the
Wyckoff technique uh no
when I presented this before at the
institutional level to a bunch of
quantitative Traders they were not happy
because they wanted something that they
could quantify exactly and wake up is
not like that and he said in this course
look at the last 20 bars of trading and
any time frame and make a judgment
on the Range is it high average or low
the position of the close is it near the
high mid-range near the close and volume
High average or low
that's what he looked at now you're more
than welcome to quantify that even more
and certainly some of her VectorVest
people quantify volume around a 50-day
moving average of volume
higher or lower than a 50-day moving
average volume and we can scan for that
on VectorVest so let's just have a crack
can you see the black bars on that
uh before Tom does it I'll put those in
a different color but that's wide
average and low as and that's close on
the high close in the mid range close on
the low I I thought that would have come
out better when I did it at home uh uh
and there's volume high volume meddling
volume and low volume so you just look
back on the chart and you judge what's
low volume what's high volume what's
average volume that's how Wyckoff did it
that's how I do it
by all means quantify that a little bit
better but
in terms of validation folks
if you've got a a big range bar
with above average volume that closes in
the top 80 percent of the range or the
top half of the range then all is good
and in that moment whatever that moment
is five minutes one hour one day one
week one month then you should do your
best to let it run
uh and and similarly if you've got a
narrow range bar
maybe you could put those lights down a
little bit sir at the back there uh
there's not
I I should have made that a different
color I'm sorry about that it looked
fine on my computer screen at home
if you've got low volume and a very
small range that's also good
that's fine
so small
result small effort that's good
everything's in sync
now
where you get
a non-validation is that if you get a
big bar
on low volume
now that can happen easily at a Breakout
and it can happen easily at the end of a
trend where the the price keeps running
on low volume now let's look at the
housing market at the moment certainly
in the UK and from discussions with
Kathy in the US as well we've got a
situation where our prices are rising
and volumes Rising I don't know what
it's like in Denmark
now sooner or later you'll find that
volumes will stay up there
and prices will go flat
well that's the next step and that can
happen very quickly
so we'll get a if you if you examine the
results carefully you're going to get a
non-validation between the volumes of
homes sold and the prices at the moment
everything's going Rosy but it changes
very quickly indeed at the top of a
market
that's the next step just watch out for
that any of you that are involved in
property
just look at the monthly stats at the
minute volumes are rising prices are
rising certainly in the UK that's the
case
The Next Step
will be that volume stay up there but
prices just don't go in other words
you've got to flood the sellers into the
market all that volume can't push the
price up anymore
and then all of a sudden you get a turn
that's a non-validation happens in every
Market uh so uh
now
this is an interesting one and this
happens frequently at at the end and
this is what many Traders call a volume
climax
well you get lots and lots of volume
and no movement
nothing than the next step in the uh
housing market in my opinion no what's
happening here now this is going to be
easy for the Danish people let's say
that you're in your car on a miserable
cold night
right
and there's lots of snow around
and you're going up a hill
use your mind's eye here you're going up
a hill and you put foot as they say in
South Africa and you're moving up
and all of a sudden the wheels start to
spin
on the ice yeah
and you put foot again
and you go a little bit further but you
can't make any traction and then you put
foot again but it doesn't matter how
hard you put your foot you slide back
and that's what's called a volume climax
lots and lots of volume
no action in the price that's that's I
think that's probably a quarter to two
quarters away in the housing market
in my humble opinion okay uh so that is
a non-validation and that can certainly
give you a heads up on what's Happening
so and then that's a bar by bar
non-validation now it gets more
interesting because we can now look at a
multi-bar
and if you've got let's say three bars
up uh you've got
um
good ranging bars the the range is
getting bigger on the bars and volume is
rising all is good all is good
and the same on a down Market uh uh but
you can get a non-validation quite
easily
there's the price Rising uh we've got a
big big range bar but the volume can't
come to the party that's a non
validation I'm not saying that there's
something up here you've got to be
careful now the mistake that I made
at the outset with volume is that I
actually try to react to the volume and
volume is not like price you can't react
to it immediately it is a subtle warning
of the future
that's all it is the heads up you so it
could take three four five bars for the
change similarly in the housing market
it could take many many months for it to
top out before it changes Direction
but it's close in the housing market
what do you think Larry it's close
um my professional opinion is setting to
my right she is never wrong on the
housing market if you ask her okay
I will later on
[Music]
okay all right well that I'm watching it
carefully at the moment because I I'm as
I say I have a love of horses I've got a
horse in the country but I need a place
in the country to keep my own horse uh
and uh a man is lost without a horse and
a border collie uh so there is uh this
is a little uh stock and that at the
last it was going up nicely and then at
the end we've got a
at the end we've got a bar and as you
can see it couldn't close at the top of
that bar on huge volume that's a heads
up that's a heads up
it was a great deal there's a lot of
volume but there was a great deal of
Supply at the top of that bar
all these things are are heads up you're
not going to trade them you're not going
to put orders in based on this but it's
a heads up and if I see a a
non-validation it's uh a reason not to
add to a position it's in fact a reason
to actually lighten a position
so during the day
I and I'll show you
a a better schematic of this now this
drawing that I hope you can see more
clearly uh I did at my first technical
analysis seminar at the University of
Cape Town in 1989 I had a full head of
hair at the time uh
as price Rises folks volume should rise
with it
and as price pulls back we should see
volume drying up
simple as that
and at this low believe it or not in
that low there's no volume at all
right at the turning point
so
the great question of course
and you all you all must have said this
to yourself uh the rule says buy
pullback but when the pullback is
occurring your little mind is moving to
the Future and then saying to yourself
well this may not be a pullback at all
this could be a change in Trend and I'm
going to buy it and I'm going to feel
like I write proper
plonker
so if you see the price pulling back on
falling volume
that's a very good sign that we're still
in a bull market and that's the primary
definition of a bull market
Rising range is expanding on Rising
volume pulling back and falling volume
if I see that then I'm quite happy to
buy into that market and and you can see
that as clear as day so those of you
that give volume a bit of a hard time on
an intraday chart if you see a couple of
bars pulling back on falling volume
that's a great place to add
see a couple of bars pulling back
tiny little bars pulling back on low
volume
remember a low range bar should be
accompanied with by a low volume
pulling back tiny little bars
great place to add if you see a pullback
and Rising volume then the game can be
up no that's
a sign that we've got more likely
not a retracement but a change in trend
I'll show you some examples of that in a
second uh and uh this I took out of
wyckoff's 1929 course and I had the
artist again done in 89. I had the
artist put the color around it and if
you can see it broke and it broken
Rising volume
and then it pulled back on falling
volume
that's what a market should do
uh
in these if this is accumulation
you should see Rising volume in the
upswings and falling volume in the
downswings
we just the VectorVest people we've just
had an example of that on Bloomsbury
publishing where it went sideways for
the last year and an upswings good
volume and the downswings no volume at
all and Bloom 3 produced very good
results the other day and it flew up by
a third so the real world is something
quite different
that's an American Stock a new core and
it
uh
this I'll explain the setup in detail
but I think Dr Brooks did a good job of
talking around it it came back it traded
this double bottom
or uh as we'll see in a second of spring
uh pushing up and Rising volume
and at this turn here you can see that
it came down and took out the law and
reversed and above average volume that's
a very good sign uh there was a little
bit of uh trouble here I then went
sideways on medium volume and then
pushed back up again but that was the
Clincher for me uh this uh trade here on
the long side uh and that's uh so that's
that's new core uh
this is an intraday chart of the s p
again I'll explain the setup in some
detail
and we uh the market pulled back
uh to this low and then reversed and
then takes off and Rising volume and
then it goes sideways
on falling volume
that's a great place to add
as you can see this trend is now in a
little bit of danger because we could
get nowhere near the same volume uh
okay
but it has another go
has another go in there
that's been my best trade of the quarter
CF Industries these are the people that
are responsible in the UK for all of the
uh
CO2 in our cool drinks and beer and
there's a shortage of it again the
British government they've got a plant
up in the north north of England and the
government had to bail them out to keep
them here otherwise we would have run
out of CO2 uh and I at the moment
there's a shortage of mineral water
again or fizzy water again
as you can see we broke up on Rising
volume and we went sideways on falling
volume that's assert uh and then it
breaks and Rises on high volume that's
just a certain now there's a big Trend
there uh the fundamentals on VectorVest
were great
and it's in the throes of a long-term
Trend uh and Tom if you'll remember I
still use an 89-day moving average uh
for the trend uh 21 55 and 89 although I
don't put them on the charts that often
because I've been looking at them for so
long that I know where they are but uh
if you need a hand to define the trend
21 55 and 89 where they all cross I call
that a bow tie where they all cross okay
uh so uh now this thing moved up and
this is a bit of a worry here you see
look at that huge volume couldn't that's
where we were at the moment couldn't
close at the top I'll show you the rest
of the chart in a second uh uh so uh
that's an example of of trade entry I
took all the trades that I'm talking
about here I've taken them myself
and there's where we were uh remember
the the bar that closed uh halfway up
its range on big volume and it came back
after that
and then one thing that happened which
was a heads up that worried me is that
the price fell on Rising volume and that
was a heads up
I still took the Breakout
but on the last little bit of the trend
the price is rising but the volume
couldn't come to the party and then the
bloody thing fell out of bed
so that that last bit there was two bits
of evidence here uh they uh
maybe where's that pointer go to I
wonder
uh
the price fell and those red bars
and Rising volume that was saying this
trend looks complete uh then it breaks
and has a last hurray on falling volume
and then a gap Stone
so there was and that's what volumes
like folks it's a subtle signal
it's not something it took me a long
time to work this out I I was actually
taking action on volume very quickly
indeed but it's a subtle signal that the
trend is in a bit of trouble
okay and that's how it should be looked
upon
that's correct yeah
that's a warning so you need to be
careful when you see that you don't want
to be you can certainly hold the
positions you have you don't want to be
adding to positions in that environment
that's what I do so I want to add to
positions when I say price increasing
I'm pulling back or going sideways on
falling volume and then I'm reasonably
happy that it's going to break again
good place to add but when I see uh
evidence of non-validation
then uh then I get a little bit worried
about adding to the position
that's all I'm saying and it's
relatively subtle uh and uh that's why
many people give it a hard time uh
that's uh also in food sugar flour grain
Archer Daniels uh had a great trade on
that uh it uh runs up
on Rising volume and then it pulls back
and falling volume now here's what I
taught my son
the very first set about Autumn and
there's probably an a b equals CD uh
Market runs up as this is a stock it
should run up by 30 percent in six weeks
to three months right
should run up on Rising volume
and then it should pull back
enter some form of consolidation
triangle flag rectangle
by the Breakout
that's it tight little stop loss try and
make uh three times as much as you risk
and we find he find by doing that that
the the share would run from for hard
after the if it worked it would run hard
after the breakout uh for five days
let it run for five days get your stop
to entry
and then do your best to let it run uh
until a b equals CD
that's the set that's the only thing he
does he's got 50 million pounds under
management
it's the only thing he does
so that's that runs up
needs to move up by 30 percent let it go
sideways let it break again
um
this is ccj folks and it's a great
example the share hasn't done much yet
for me but I it's setting uh this is a
uranium stock and you can see clear
accumulation here uh big bar up out of
that Gap and then uh as you can see it
good volume there but uh a lot of
selling volume it then pulls back goes
side pulls back on falling volume runs
again on big volume runs again on big
volume runs again on big volume it's not
going sideways and falling volume you
can't do that with that level of
certainty without volume analysis in any
market and any time frame
the relationship between price and
volume tells you who's running the
market whether the Bulls are running a
market where the Bears are running a
market
and I'm I'm more than happy to admit on
a five minute chart it gets very noisy
indeed and uh much much more difficult
on a daily chart or an early chart uh so
uh and that's what I teach at VectorVest
and I do a webcast on blue in the face
on that sort of stuff uh again that's a
stock that that's a trade that I took a
little while back as my standard trade
folks it moves up and Rising volume goes
sideways and falling boom then it goes
again it couldn't be simpler uh
I love these patterns and this is Lucy
Mike's uh
that run up must be 30 in the share
price from the last base
right uh
that should take place in uh six weeks
to three months that thirty percent it
then pulls back into this case a flag
and then it breaks again uh and he then
takes a b equals you know what CD for a
Target that's a setup now the difference
between what I what I the difference
between
what's been presented so far and what
I'm trying to motivate is that you
should see a noticeable increase in
volume in a b
and a noticeable decrease in volume in
BC
to give you the strength
for it to go again no that's easy in the
stock market it's easy
and probably volume is much more
reliable in the stock market uh
but you can see it in all markets in all
time frames and that's the basis of the
white golf work and that's the only
thing that Mike doesn't say that's the
only thing he does
and uh he does it very well doesn't look
at anything else
now that's I own the share uh it's told
to Gala it used to be called Amco it's
not together resources and this is an
interesting one you can see the little
flag here this is it went up by 30 it
went from four to six not by fifty
percent in that run then go sideways
now it moves up that last bar was in
good volume and then we've got these two
red bars
and the red bars as you can see uh
produced very very little results we had
uh big volume but they were down bars so
lots and lots of volume going in but the
market couldn't get down that's what
Wyckoff called bag holding uh then go
sideways and then it breaks up and big
volume that's the classic trade folks
that's just classic that's a beauty that
share is going from three pounds four
that was listed at three pounds it's
gone from three points to nine pounds
now in uh
what
uh nine months uh if that it was listed
anglo-american had to get rid of it when
that conference was on up in Scotland
you remember the cop conference up in
Scotland it's called they had to get rid
of it and they listed it in a fortnight
uh and uh then all of a sudden coal goes
from the Antichrist itself now to
something that people need to keep the
lights on uh so uh that's uh quite a
simple little trade uh and uh
that's
a pump for my VectorVest program that's
earnings per share that's the VectorVest
valuation of the share and those of you
that are technicians all of you are
technicians you should see the classic
cup and handle pattern before that as
well but at the end I only traded the
flag pattern uh
and this back in the day that Zoom
that's one of my best trades uh that's
back in the day it's given all this all
up again uh there's my moving averages
that's earnings per share
flying up on Zoom uh we had this big run
up the gap on big volume
and then it goes sideways I didn't trade
that first bit and then it rises again
on Rising volume and now it pulls back
on falling volume and then away it goes
again and it flew from there so that's a
classic setup folks uh uh and they're
the two that's 21 and 55 and it's it was
at that stage significantly undervalued
by VectorVest and that's a very simple
way to make a living uh finding those uh
and that is Tesla is that a flag setting
up in Tesla
I'll be trading it
push-up I don't know what's going to
happen next push-up happened and Rising
volume get a couple of see this get a
couple of small little bars on average
volume that's good and now it's going
sideways on falling volume that's going
again
let me take Glory by association can I
take this Hemingway
he said he that he liked to take Glory
by association that was one of his
Expressions uh my two sons went to the
same school as Elon Musk how's that
I'm taking Glory by association so I I
think that that's going to go uh uh so
the bear Market folks as the Irish
should say is the same only different
whereas that man I spoke Kieran
he's going home I think
the price and the bear Market the price
should fall and the volume should rise
and then we get a rally on falling
volume and that's where you want to
short it now that's one of the most
reliable trades in the world if you're
gonna trendone and a rally on falling
volume that's the only time I would
consider shorting a stock
Rally's on falling volume and the last
two bars you'll find will be really
narrow range bars before it changes its
mind again and then it should fall on
Rising volume there's no non-validation
there again this comes out of wake UPS
1929 course or 28 course a break on
Rising volume
and then a rally on falling volume then
it goes down again on Rising volume uh
now I was
I remember yeah Friday uh way back on
Friday uh I was short the uh s p x but
that's the spider and I like the volume
figures on the spider much much better
uh and you can see a way back here
uh in the first wave darn look at this
huge print here at that low and you can
see that uh that's an end-of-day chart
as well you can see that this Market in
fact uh opened went right down I'm
closed huge huge bar huge huge reversal
enormous demand at that level uh we
actually get the same thing here it
takes out the level huge now these are
the two biggest volume days uh for the
last five years on the spider at that
level
uh and then it runs and as it runs up
over the last week or two the last 10
days it's run up and falling volume and
that's why I was looking for any reason
to short the bugger up there on Thursday
or Friday on Wednesday my first trade
was uh was two the stop was too tight I
got stopped out but I made it all back
plus on uh Thursday and Friday but nice
I'll show you the trade in a second so I
run up and falling volume like that
folks uh that's a heads up and you don't
want to react to the darn thing straight
away you need it clearly a a a a signal
from Price action
but uh it's a heads up and that that's
the uh uh that's the uh
fresh that's the cash Market uh uh chart
that was my attempt on uh Wednesday I
think I was a 15 minute chart it broke
down and Rising volume at the open
and I always like to watch the open bar
on a 15-minute chart there's always a
lot of volume obviously it just has
opened and uh just see what the first 15
minute bar looks like and that one in
fact couldn't uh it went right up and it
couldn't stay up there it was certainly
Supply came in up there so that was the
basis of my trade and then all of a
sudden it rallied on falling volume and
I thought I was quid Zen
but no alas alas there was noise up
there and I got stopped a very small
loss but I I was quite I I I thought
that maybe that was going to be a big
one I had to wait for the next day again
the same sort of thing uh on the stock
market I want to see a 30 fall I want to
see a rally
and that's pretty much what we had on
Friday on the S P 500 and then I want to
see it fall again and you've guessed it
a b equals CD but rally down should be
on Rising volume
sorry the move down should be in Rising
volume the rally should be unfalling
volume and that's one of the most
certain trades that you can have and
there was an old fella out there called
Cohen and he had a company in New York
City called chartcraft and he was one of
the original Founders after Wyckoff on
point and figure charting and I met his
grandson some years back a guy called
David Cohen and his granddad had made
this conclusion that markets are
significantly more predictable on the
downside than they are on the upside and
as old as Grandad had proven that over
many many years have you met old man
Cohen chart craft
yeah chart craft in New York City is run
by David Cohen the original chaps uh
grandson first class fellow so
you don't have to make it complex you
know what and I don't mean any
disservice to people who didn't grow up
my ex-wife told me once upon a time that
I complicate The Lord's Prayer uh so I
can make life very complicated for me
and I mean no
harm to anybody that wasn't dragged up
the same way as myself uh but I I tend I
can't make things far far more
complicated than they are uh I for a
high probability trade I want to see
evidence of a trend up or down I want to
see then and a bear case I want to see a
rally on falling volume
and then I want to sell the hell out of
it simple as that uh tight stop try and
make three times as much when I'm right
as I am when I'm wrong uh I've got some
more examples that's a a classic short
that's JD Sports it's a High Street uh
sports shop uh this is a while back
folks but it's just a classic one I
rarely short in stocks I'm happier
shorting the index but we can see this
big print on the downside
and then it rallies on falling volume
can't get up at all and then it falls
out of bed again uh so uh this one is a
a stock that I'd held I was out of it
well before this I didn't short it but
you can see that this is no rallying and
this flag this thing uh Rising wedge or
uh three drives pattern that Larry talks
about uh and as you can see uh right at
the Apex of that there's just nothing
there at all nothing apart from right
rats and mice and then it fell through
the bloody floor so uh and again I
guarantee if you do an a b equals CD
you'll find the target pretty much
all right so uh uh
we made a heap of money at VectorVest on
this one last year I mean a heap of
money we were in it from these lows and
then I added again uh when I got that
breakout on huge volume that's always a
great sign a big big bar on huge volume
uh and uh then got out of it up there
then this you see this Rose for a couple
of weeks and volume on that week pretty
much zero that's a huge non-validation
and then we get the outside bar and the
bloody thing falls out of bed uh so and
it's still falling out of bed uh
this is on an hourly chart
price rising and falling volume uh and
that's and then it fellow to bed again
that's uh ages old I think uh I did that
these for Tom's last seminar
so let let me go on to my final little
bit it's according to five uh and
four years and before I met you Tom I
had a little the book had fallen apart
uh sorry sir
remote client to take that shot than you
would uh follow up no I would take but I
will take both and I'm probably better
on the long side in the stock market
okay uh happier on the long side uh
I I rarely short stocks themselves I'm
more than happy to short the index but
uh if you want to short the stock market
uh a rally on falling volume in a
downtrend in other words an a b equals
CD Down uh where the a b c
c b c is on falling volume that's As
Good As It Gets in this line of work in
my humble opinion it's a more reliable
trade than the long trade yeah
okay more reliable yes sir
I can't hear you sir
uh that is uh Wall Street yeah
uh I I I I I took a e-signal volume uh
for years
uh uh um and uh from the index yes
from the Futures Market yeah that's
where they get it from I took uh
e-signal volume for up years and then I
found out that the trading view volume
was exactly the same as the e-signal
volume so I stopped trading I stopped
e-signal okay
on trading View
you've got it yeah
yes that's correct yeah that's where
they get it from yeah uh so uh it's
exactly the same I tried it forever and
e-signal is a temperamental sword uh
foreign
so this little book of wyckoffs it fell
apart in my briefcase
and he said so beautifully
that you can make a living by trading
Springs and up for us training these
setups represent the essence of My
Method it involves establishing trades
at the danger point where the risk is
least in the profit potential is
greatest
and schematically that's how I've drawn
these things so ah
I trade most of them with the trend
although you can't pick bottoms with
them but I don't need to I I'm not
hungry enough to do that I'm looking for
Market to come up
to find resistance
to pull back and kiss that resistance to
push up again and then come back and
clip that low and run now it can be the
same as a gartly pattern but it doesn't
have to be it just needs to get its nose
down below that low
similarly enough thrust is a it finds
support
or demand and wyckoff's language a
couple of times it then breaks goes up
kisses comes down and then goes up and
takes the old top boat by a tick or two
and that's called an up thrust
and there's the theoretical part of it
uh
you can trade it with a trend or you can
try and pick bottoms with it I only
trade it with the trend now when it
breaks this little bit at the bottom Mr
gam called Lost motion
now when it breaks up
40 percent of the time it comes back and
kisses the level 40 percent of the time
sixty percent of the time it goes
so forty percent of the time you get a
test now there is uh uh a classic this
is on Platinum and That's a classic uh
uh Wyckoff uh spring technique we've got
resistance
it comes back to here
runs up
to here and this bar should this
reversal bar should occur on Rising
volume
and I I would be a buyer on there
at the next open stop loss under here
and you can see how I came back and
kissed you see that forty percent of the
time it does that it'll come back and
kiss that level
uh some people say that you should in
fact buy the test and of course that
means that you miss the 60 that don't
test
40 percent of them test uh uh I tend to
get in on a close above uh the level
uh you can buy the level if you want but
uh that was a particularly good one
because this is an outside bar and you
know what
I know I'm a bit of a one-track pony but
I don't do much more than that and I get
enough trades around the market to keep
me well uh well fed and watered by doing
that now
this is an example that's setting up
that I'm going to be talking to the
VectorVest people about tomorrow
afternoon uh this is gold fields
uh and you can see there's run up on
Rising volume and now it's pulling back
on falling volume hasn't shown a great
deal of volume on the breakout as yet
but it came down and I like this bar
because it reversed on uh pretty much
average volume bit more would have been
better but uh that to me is a classic
white golf spring and that's something
that I should be personally Trading
uh
okay that's gold Fields that's the 21
moving average if you put the 55 on
there the 20 ones above the 55s above
the 89 and that means the trends intact
and unvective S the fundamentals are
great uh uh there uh I think we looked
at these on Friday
this is last week
on the S P that's a one hour chart which
is where I try and look for most of my
trades because when that's that's not
called a spring for nothing folks
when it if you sit and wait for them
you're going to be very happy because
they spring
and they go like the clappers
and you're not sitting there and angst
they either go like the clappers or they
don't go at all there's nothing worse
than setting in a trade that's going
bloody well nowhere remember the tail
must never Wag the Dog
you're there to make some money
to buy resources
it's the only thing that life's about
maybe the odd Border Collie
a border collie is the price of a good
car do you knew that
twenty thousand pounds for a decent
Border Collie
dog
twenty thousand pounds
there's a cue there's for a decent
well-bred border collie you're gonna
have to put your name in and wait for
six to nine months
they're they're they're they're they're
worth waiting for uh so uh
[Applause]
you're not okay all right all right okay
uh there's nothing more uh
Pleasant than a dog uh that's the one
thing I haven't got a dog at the moment
but it's the one never I'm never gonna
have a wife again but I'm gonna have a
dog ah okay
I mean I don't mean that in any nasty
way at all
uh but uh and I've been pricing dogs and
that's why I know exactly uh the price
uh for a decent border collie yeah and
they're people scrumming over them at
twenty thousand pounds uh so here's the
we've got resistance folks and the damn
thing goes up can't get up there and
then it pulls back and kisses that and
then it reverses and that's it there's
nothing more to it than that
the white Gulf Spring and then the
bloody thing Springs
now this is another one
maybe some people would have got in
there and that happened in the morning
about 10 o'clock I didn't take that one
but that's at the open and uh it moves
up here and then it comes back and you
see the test there's the level and it
comes up comes back Tess and then goes
again I got in on that one after the
test
now where are you going to get out well
you can use Larry a b equals CD that'll
be perfect
absolutely perfect or you can use a a
1.618 extension of the pullback of your
Fibonacci fan but you've heard Larry
yesterday uh and speaking from the
bottom of his heart about the power of
the ab equals CD so that's a good place
to be looking for a Target where a b
equals CD okay
sir what is the lowest time frame you
would use volume as an indicator to make
a decision
you can use it right down to a five
minute chart that become you're gonna I
would suggest that to get your
to get your interpretation correct that
you would look at a gnarly chart for the
next week or two until you get the feel
of it but by all means you can look at
but works pretty well in a 15-minute
chart
okay uh uh but it's noisier in a five
minute chart and probably more it's like
any any form of stats the more
the more observations you have the more
accurate they become so on a longer time
frame The Edge effects get canceled out
especially in this in any Market people
buy and share things for no other reason
for for example your granny dies and
leaves you a quarter of a million pounds
you go out and buy stocks you've bought
stocks for no other reason than your
granny left you the money and and
all of a sudden you run up gambling
debts to 250 000 pounds and you've got
to go out and sell stocks to pay the
gambling debt uh there's nothing to do
with the stocks themselves there's all
sorts of edge effects in there all sorts
of noise in there people buy and sell
things for all sorts of of reasons that
have got nothing to do with the actual
instrument itself so the longer the time
frame the more reliable start with an
hourly chart
or even better still start with the
daily chart and work your way down if
you're trading the indices keep your eye
on the spider the Spy the volume on the
spiders are real good leading indicator
for any other index in the world uh so
that's two good examples that's last
week I haven't Cherry Picked them but
they do come like London taxis folks you
know you you get six and you stand there
for hours in the rain and then six taxis
come at once all right that's just the
way it is uh so uh let's go a little bit
further and then I promise I'll let you
all
that's
I think that's the same
one that's a Spring Beauty down there
now this one there's no shoulder I took
it in a way it didn't work that well I
but it worked finally but I I got out of
it didn't get back in here but that's
textbook there's the shoulder resistance
here there's no shoulder and those are
always dodgier
I like that I like to see a resistance
support support and the way it ran this
low that's a clear stop running exercise
look at the spring just a beauty
absolute Beauty uh so uh
that's a five minute chart Works in all
time frames
uh
that's another five minute chart worked
perfectly there
uh
maybe a bit more agricultural but not
bad
down here on that's in the Dow Jones uh
there's another one uh came back once
because right there and that's at the
open they frequently happen in the first
hour
a couple of hours where it runs up comes
back once has a go and then comes down I
think Dr Brooks showed a couple of
examples this morning where that
happened this morning he was I don't
know two or three times but I'm I'm more
than happy to wait for the spring okay
uh
and sometimes of course they just go and
you miss it that one's good down here
but the second one I was waiting for it
I remember Vivid I just kept on going uh
that is another five minute chart uh
that was a judgment call folks because
it actually didn't take out this low so
it wasn't everything else was perfect
and we could see the volume shooting up
here on this first bar and I took the
trade anyway but maybe I was
scared of missing out I'm more than
happy to admit that uh
and now the opposite is the upfrush
that's the schematic of the up thrust uh
and uh that's a good example I think
that's in Forex uh their support comes
up once and goes right up and then you
can see the capitulation at the top huge
amount of Supply coming in at that old
top we chart one of those what's it
called shooting stars and then uh it
falls and Falls like a stone uh
that's that's gold the other day now the
VectorVest people I was trading this
last Monday afternoon if you remember in
the uh 1 30 session uh and
that was I got in underneath that low
and I had that order I put the order in
before I went to bed on Sunday night and
uh I got that taken out
Larry when you talk about pets
it's good man it's good it's good it's
good at one stage I had I was trading
the poem to get the dollar against the
Yen and I had one of those projectors
and I had the dollar against the Yen
projected against the wall
on the bedroom so I could wake up in the
middle of the night and have a look I
was much more I was much Keener I was
much Keener in those days and maybe
that's why the wife left but
I had to I was much hungrier on those
I'm 66 folks and I'm I'm I don't need
that much money uh everything that I
used to spend money on I've given up so
um uh
I finally had to get rid of the
projector because the Border Collie that
I had uh she stayed around after the
wife left and the border of Cali would
bark at this bark at the wall during the
night because it was interfering with
her Slumber so I had to finally get rid
of that ah so this was last week uh and
I think that this is an AB equal CD here
in fact I'm sure it is and I think it's
a 38 Protestant as well I don't know uh
but it went up took out that top and
then It reversed it tried to get down
rallies and then it broke that level on
uh first first well in the first four
hour bar of Monday and then it goes back
in tests in fact my very words to the
VectorVest people last Monday afternoon
I hope that the test is over
okay and then uh it uh fell and fell
very nicely indeed until I did this uh
and then when I yeah it stopped at this
low on big big volume it was demand came
in at the low uh and I'm the tricks in
between now and on gold itself
that low that we see here right that
1900 there's a big high on the daily
chart six weeks ago so I thought maybe
gold was going to go back to about 1850
uh but we've now seen very determined
support at the 1900 level in Gold so uh
we shall see what happens tomorrow uh
that let's see what that that's that's
uh glencore that's uh up thrust on
glencore uh frequently folks you'll find
that these things get run in the news
and that I don't know what the news was
there but it went right up and clipped
the high and then reversed again so
that's news trading and likes I I avoid
it like the plague uh
and uh
that is another up thrust and I'm
finished now but I've got
I want to look at uh trading view I
think I've got it open for the that was
Friday
and
I was in
uh this trade I was looking for any
reason to short it and I shorted it on
that bar
where it fell on Rising volume and had
broke there's a trend line there as well
uh I was looking for any reason to short
it and I know that's not good to talk at
a seminar but uh uh that's because at
the 4-6 level we had that big up thrust
on The Daily charts I was looking for
any reason to short it and as it broke
down
uh on big big volume that was my reason
to short it then went back and tried to
test and then it fell out of bed uh and
I held it overnight
and
I should have
there's another little spring here
sorry up thrust
there's no shoulder but it does this and
it's in a b equals CD as well and it
does this and uh I should have added to
that position here I didn't because I
was I was in fact on my way I was
wandering around outside uh because you
guys moved here uh without letting me
know uh now uh the Target in this and I
took profits on this when I was sitting
up there uh uh listening uh uh and I I
if you draw a fib extension there's an
old high here on the chart there's a
range here uh and uh as you can see I I
always draw a fib uh
and extend from there to there and
looking for that Target and I took
profits at four five one five on that
which was the construction that I had in
place and then all of a sudden we got to
move up into the close I think that on
the indices folks we've had five waves
down uh and five waves down as uh is an
Impulse wave I think now that we've got
uh probably uh a bit of a correction to
go that'll take us up for two or three
days and then we'll see what happens we
really will see what happens it doesn't
matter my count on the doe is that that
high at four six naught naught was a
wave five of wave three and what we're
in now is a week four and uh We've now
got away five to come so I think there's
another new hide that could take us up
into May in the stock indices and then
we'll see what happens you've all read
about the two and the ten inverted there
was a PMI report on Friday one did that
come in that does anybody know
the uh my looking at this generally for
many years the uh the last PMI the the
210 inverting invariably forecast a
recession but forecast a recession about
six months out uh uh the PMI the last
PMI was 60 and PMI industry was 61. so
if you get a PMI coming down under 50
plus the 210 becoming inverted then
that's a much more serious signal so as
long as that PMI sits up there at about
60 level uh
I think we can get a more upside there's
no bears there's people are still too
bearish so I think that the last bear
needs to
be silenced before it goes down uh so
I'm still optimistic but I'm overly
optimistic uh folks that's me finished
uh I I kept you far far too long uh and
I hope I didn't bore you with the
trading psychology stuff please humor an
old fella like me and do your 30 trades
okay more than help you happy to help
you any anyway it's Trader Davey d-a-v-y
gmail.com Trader
d-a-v-y gmail.com
anybody that wants a trial at VectorVest
folks uh I'm going to set up a special
group for people who sign up at this and
I'll Mentor you on the uh swing trading
uh setups
95 and if you go to vectorvest.co.uk you
can take that trial and I'll do my best
to Mentor you in swing trading in the
stock market over a few weeks or a few
months it's quite easy money uh and uh
it'll cost you a fiver for 60 days so if
you want that uh you can either sign up
online or just email me about it and
I'll do that for you with the greatest
of pleasure uh I said I wish I could
give it for free but I count the
Americans would freak it's 5.95 uh so
thanks very much indeed take care