hey folks welcome to lesson five of the
April 2017 ICT mentorship ICT day
trading model this teaching is
specifically dealing with intraday
market profiles
the intraday market profiles the first
we're going to go over is
the Sell profile of London normal
protraction
and what you want to be looking for for
a classic Sell day for intraday trading
there's going to be lots of different
Deviation and and subtle
variances in in these specific themes
they won't look exactly like I'm
outlining here obviously that's what
makes the trading somewhat difficult
because you have to look for
similarities across the board so they're
going to have a great deal of
similarity among many Sell days and the
ideal scenarios will look very close to
what I'm outlining here
but you start with the Central Bank
dealers range and for a classic or high
probability London normal protraction
Sell day
the CentralBankDealersRange is going
to be less than 40 Pips now as soon as
you see a CentralBankDealersRange
that's greater than 40 Pips this is not
going to be that profile so you'll have
to either go to the next one we'll teach
in this lesson or you just going to
consider whether or not you're gonna be
trading on
the Asian session
range between eight o'clock and midnight
NewYork time we call that the Asian
range
this is going to also have a classic
range of 20 to 30 Pips if it's larger
than that again this profile will not be
existing
typically what you're going to see is
the market will rally up after 12 AM
NewYork time to 2 AM NewYork time now
think about what I'm explaining here
you're already looking for a bearish
move you're already bearish on the
HTF the dailies indicating
lower prices so what we're looking for
is the London High to form
classically the high probability
scenario for this profile to unfold is
you have to see what time it is in New
York at midnight and then you're going
to be seeing price immediately start
trading up from that point
if it does not start trading up into two
o'clock in the morning
NewYork time that is not this profile
so right away you have a filter
you have essential Bank deals range has
to be less than 40 Pips check agent
range has to be 20 30 Pips check now if
those two conditions are there but yet
we do not see price rallying after 12
AM NewYork time into 2 AM if that
does not occur again that is not the
London normal protractionary Sell day
the protractionary stage or Judah swing
will be one to two StandardDeviation
of the CentralBankDealersRange
now let's recap what I just explained to
you
the ideal scenario the one I like to
trade the one that makes me sit on the
sideline and wait for these specific
criteria
everyone wants to know when I'm trading
London this is what I'm looking for this
is my money making day this is the thing
that outlines the whole thing for my
Sell day for London this is my go-to I
like this profile if I do not have these
ingredients if you will I'm not bacon in
London I'm just not going to do it so
again let's consider what this is
outlined if the Central Bank dealers
range is greater than 40 Pips there's
been a whole lot more later afternoon
NewYork session price action so that
means it's been extended further
if they have allowed the price to move
further and arranged greater than 40
Pips
after 2 PM NewYork time that's going to
mess up their model for allowing the
float to build
you want to see a consolidation between
two o'clock PM to 8 PM NewYork time
if that does not exist right away you
have a warning sign that you're probably
not going to be wanting to trade London
now that can change
what makes that change is if the Asian
range goes down to a 20 to 30 pip range
and stays very tightly consolidated
so CentralBankDealersRange can get
wider than 40 Pips but it the Asian
range does not move down into a small
consolidation of 20 to 30 Pips
you can't take the London session
because you've already seen a lot of
volatility both in Central Bank dealers
range so it means late NewYork going to
bonds close there's probably been
something going on and they are not
allowing float to build up and you have
to wait until 8 PM for the Asian session
to begin and then between 8 PM NewYork
time midnight NewYork time we'll be
looking for consolidation in a range of
20 to 30 Pips
if they can consolidate the Asian range
20 30 Pips after a larger than 40 Pips
CentralBankDealersRange
then we can go back to electing to look
for this profile
now the market again has to Rally
immediately after midnight NewYork time
and you want to see that sustained
movement higher moving up into towards
the two o'clock hour in NewYork time so
what that's doing is it's creating that
initial move that protractionary state
you are looking for the move to be going
up but the entry can occur as early as 1
30 AM NewYork time one o'clock in the
morning NewYork time
you want to see immediate movement up
after 12 AM now it might have a small
little move down after 12 AM but it'll
be modest you're expecting that to turn
up shortly after midnight then you have
to be looking for Price movement at 1am
to 1 30 it should have made a higher
high than that what was seen in the
Asian range or the Central Bank dealers
range
that's the protractionary stage in the
marketplace but ideally it will trade up
from 12 AM to 2 AM
that movement up is IPDA expanding the
range with a projectionary state or
sucking in buyers or squeezing on those
people that have stops just above the
marketplace they're already short
when the progress when the protraction a
stage or due to swing occurs we're
looking for one to two Standard
Deviation of the Central Bank dealer's
range if all these criterias are met and
then you end up nailing the high of the
day between two o'clock and four o'clock
in the morning typically
for your classic Sell profile London
normal protection
as an example this is what it would look
like
as you can see here we have a small
consolidation Asian range and we have an
immediately after midnight time frame
price goes straight up
and then from there creates the high
today and trades down
creating the LOD around the
monthly closed time period and then
coming off the low into consolidation
the projectionary stage is seen here
immediately after that midnight candle
okay intraday market profiles continue
to our Sell profile with London delayed
protraction
the market may or may not have a
favorable Central Bank dealer's range
that means it could be
an ideal stage set it could be less than
40 Pips or it could be greater than 40
Pips this profile can go either way when
we're using the Central Bank dealers
range
the DirectionalBias is going to be
bearish but the protractionary stage is
going to be delayed in the day in other
words we're not going to see the rally
right after
midnight in NewYork time it may just
erode and go lower right after midnight
IPDA will enter a protectionary stage at
or shortly after 2 AM NewYork so what
you're going to be doing is you have a
vertical line on your 15-minute time
frame and you're looking for price to
Stage a rally at or just shortly after 2
AM
that rally is going to be a intraday
inside the range it's already existing
or inside the the height it's already
formed for the day it's going to be
creating a smaller little Judas swing
it's going to Rally up from two o'clock
and making your
London entry comes in fruition
you'll be looking for an intraday
premium PD array to short on inside that
retracement now again that retracement
is going to occur at or just after 2 AM
when do you look for that when the
market does not create that 12 AM New
York time rally in other words the price
does not go into a pretractionary stage
higher after midnight it just rolls over
goes soft and this makes a progressively
lower move going into 2 AM not a
problem draw vertical line at 2 AM wait
for a retracement higher that will be if
this protractionary stage it will not
want to make a higher high and price
will go to a premium PD array bearish
order block close the fair value Gap or
liquidity void and then you'll be
selling short on the day and again the
primary premises is you already have to
have a bearish Outlook
the daily is respecting resistance ideas
and it should be seeking sell side
liquidity if you have this criteria this
is the London delayed protractionary
profile that you look to trade off of
but the key is having that two o'clock
time frame there must be a rally up at
or just after 2 AM trading up into a
premium PD array in the time frame
you're trading on which is the 15-minute
chart
an example that would be seen here
price rolls over just doesn't make any
higher high
then we have a protraction a stage rate
after two o'clock on this time frame
this is  seen with 70 Mt which would
be two o'clock in NewYork time price
creates a rally trades back up into a
bearish order block and then creates the
London session High trading lower
and you can see the projectionary stage
here
after 2 AM
okay intra market profiles continued now
we'll look at the buy profiles
now this is the one I like to trade when
I'm looking to buy in the London session
this is the London normal protraction
stage CentralBankDealersRange again
is going to be less than 40 Pips
the Asian range is 20 to 30 Pips again a
narrow consolidation
the Market's going to decline lower
after 12 AM NewYork time into 2 AM
NewYork that's the fingerprint if you
will that if does doing what we're
outlining here in terms of
characteristics so if we do not see an
immediate decline from 12 AM NewYork
down into 2 AM NewYork
this is not going to be a London normal
protraction BuyDay
the projectionary stage or Judah swing
will be one to two StandardDeviation
of the Central Bank dealer's range
so what we're looking at here again
CentralBankDealersRange is going to
be less than 40 Pips
so they are consolidating the late New
York session going into Bond close
then an Asian range has a small narrow
20 to 30 pip range as well so they are
allowing orders to build up above and
below the marketplace
the market starts dropping immediately
after 12 AM NewYork time at midnight
and it trades lower down into 2 AM now
again the London low can form just ahead
of 2 AM but we're looking for a price
to be trending towards or making lower
lows going into that 2 AM time period
the market can start with an initial
move up very modest little move after 12
AM but it has to start trending lower
after 12 AM or shortly thereafter and
it has to consistently move lower past
ideally 1am 1 30 AM and right about
then you have a confirmation that the
London normal protraction by profile is
unfolding
you're gonna be looking for that Judas
swing or protractionary stage in the
marketplace to reach down one to two
StandardDeviation
in the CentralBankDealersRange and
that'll be your projected low
an example that is seen here
the market enters a small Central Bank
dealers range and Asian range is also a
respectable
range in terms of Pips
then price drops
lower right after
the midnight candle
finds the LOD and expands up
for higher close
as you can see here this is the
protraction stage
immediately after 12 AM NewYork time
okay intraday market profiles continuing
with our buy profile of the London
delayed protraction
for this we're going to be looking for
the market may or may not have a
favorable CentralBankDealersRange so
it can happen either or it can be in a
day where the CentralBankDealersRange
is less than 40 Pips or greater than 40
Pips the filter moves over to the Asian
range that is also a defining Factor it
helps build this a little bit more as a
favorable trading profile if the Asian
range creates a small range
but it's not necessary because the
profile could be seen with or without
the Asian range being in a range or the
Central Bank dealer's range being in a
small consolidation as well
main premise is the DirectionalBias is
bullish but the protraction is delayed
IPDA will enter a protraction stage at
or shortly after 2 AM NewYork
and you're gonna be looking for a
discount PD array to buy at during a
retracement that will occur
at or shortly after
2 AM NewYork time
so what are we saying here we have a
market that has a questionable Central
Bank dealers range that doesn't mean
that we just toss it out we have to look
at what's going on at midnight so we
have to get up or make ourselves
available at midnight and see okay we're
going to be looking for the
characteristics that's being described
here if we have wider than 40 Pips
CentralBankDealersRange okay then we
probably are going to be seeing a London
delayed protractionary stage
the DirectionalBias has to be clearly
bullish
and if we don't see the characteristics
that we saw for the London
protractionary Day for buy profile then
we have to look for these types of
things for the delay
so if it will enter a protractionary
stage at or shortly after 2 AM so what
we can do is if we see all those
indications are there at midnight we can
either take a nap or we can stay up and
wait to see if there's that delayed
protractionary stage or due to swing
that begins at 2 AM and will retrace
lower and it will seek a intraday
discount PD array
and you'll be buying that during that
retracement so basically it would be
like a classic intraday optimal trade
entry long
or a bowl of shoulder block closing in a
fair value Gap below market price or a
liquidity void
that movement lower
that will create that London entry for a
London delayed protractionary day
an example seen here the market starts
up and it doesn't give us a real clear
picture right away it starts moving
higher doesn't give us that big move
lower
or initial drop down so we have a
questionable
CentralBankDealersRange or agent
range scenario
we can be looking for
our DirectionalBias to unfold which is
a bullish day IPDA will enter a
processionary stage at or shortly after
2 AM NewYork that's the blue line here
Market drops down and dips into an
intraday discount PD array in this
example here you can see it trades down
into a previous down closed candle or
bowl of shorter block creating the
London setup to unfold for the rest of
the bullish close day
and the rest of the template is seen
here making the high today in
London close trading off of London to
close High
into consolidation for the daily close
so we have two dominant profiles that I
like to trade and look for the
characteristics are highly specific
they're not ambiguous
they have specific criteria that we look
for
if the first one which is the London
protraction whether it be buy or sell
profiles con characteristics are not
there then I look for justification for
the delay in the protractionary stages
of
the London session so the key is 2 AM
NewYork
so we're looking at 12 AM for a classic
London protraction or Judah swing
if we don't see that movement in favor
of our up close day with a down move
after 12 AM at due to swing lower if we
don't see that then we're going to be
looking for this scenario here 2 AM
so here's the criteria
you have to be up if you're going to be
a London Trader the ideal scenario is
you're going to be up at 12 AM
NewYork time
all the way up to at least in my opinion
2 30 AM to 3 AM that's the that's that
three hour window once you see what's
being outlined in both of these profiles
whether you're a buyer or seller I'm
only looking for four types of
conditions and I should already have
just two conditions set for London
either I'm going to be bullish or
bearish that's going to be this
determined by looking at the daily chart
and where are we trading off of recently
are we moving higher or lower if we're
going to be expanding higher then I'm
going to be looking for bullish
scenarios in London and I'm going to be
using the two criterias for the buy
profile either it's going to be a London
protraction or a London delayed
protraction day that's it nothing else
is slipping through the cracks nothing
else is going to surprise me I'm looking
for two criteria I'm looking for a
scenario to unfold at 12 AM going into
2 AM if that does not happen then I
know what I'm looking for at 2 AM I'm
looking for that delay of a Judah swing
the only difference is I'm going to be
either a buyer or seller based on my
HTF premise that's it
there's no magic to it than that I
understand that if they will do these
scenarios
and it'll also keep you out of Trades
there's going to be times where it won't
provide you an entry the market will
just probably keep on going up and it'll
probably be a 90 pip day it might be a
150 pip day and you aren't getting in
with either one of these profiles and
guess what that means that's a trade
that you missed you can send me emails
and complain about it I'm just telling
you some days I miss it too but by far
and large if you look for these two
characteristics for a buy or sell
profile intraday when you already have a
HTF notion that price
should be higher or lower based on that
daily chart
your criteria for trading the London
session is simple as this there's
nothing else that you're looking for
the framework we're going to give you
from the HTF down
obviously in later teaching but for here
you're only looking for two things a
movement after 12 AM going into two
o'clock in the morning and if that
doesn't happen then you draw a vertical
line at 2 AM then you expect it there so
between two o'clock and 3 AM that Judah
swing should occur
now think about I just told you I just
loaded your 50 caliber
Barrett ready to take down big game
you're able to find long and open setups
now with very specific criteria and
filters
go back and look at your old charts and
you'll see that these are going to be
the two dominant forces to outline all
of the best London open sessions until
next lesson I wish you good luck and
good Trading