welcome to March 2017 content for the
ICT mentorship this month we're teaching
short-term trading this is lesson one
combining higher time frame monthly and
weekly ranges
okay folks short-term trading this is my
cup of tea if you will my go to
discipline trading Style
um in this month we're going to be
teaching in great detail my one shot one
kill approach to trading not just the 4X
Market but all the other uh asset
classes will be touched on in scope as
we get to those later discussions uh in
the middle of the summer we will be
teaching bond trading uh index trading
stock trading and commodity trading and
I'll touch on this specific trading
model in higher detail when I go into
those respective discussions
and just so you know it's uh the month
of June we go through that that Gambit
if you will of those four different
asset classes
all right so what is short-term trading
it's the practice of trading a duration
of one week or a few days
we use both the monthly and weekly
charts to frame the setups
we trade in the direction of the present
or next week's probable range
it's essential that you understand that
the weekly range is going to be the
backbone to your success in short-term
trading and I'm going to go through a
lot of teaching and Concepts as it
relates to producing consistent results
when you're looking for forecasting the
next week or current week's range
a short-term model can be both Trend or
range-bound Trading
trades that are clear to see forming are
the goal again specifically with this
trading model try your best to keep from
forcing yourself to take a trade if it's
not obvious it's simply just
you know not clear enough on on your
charts just simply sit on your hands and
wait these types of setups form every
single week there's absolutely no reason
for you to rush if you do believe me you
will have psychological tug of war going
on you're gonna have emotional issues
and the bottom line is your ultimately
probably going to lose some money
short-term trading in my opinion is the
highest probability discipline
it offers frequent setups and with
consistency it provides a plethora of
Trades
now before we get into this discussion
about short-term trading let me preface
it by saying
it's important you go through your notes
from the January long-term trading model
and from February with the swing trading
model notes because those notes will
complement this specific
whole entire month it'd be very easy for
me to load you down with rehash of
everything that was discussed in January
and February but what I want to do is I
want to keep things moving along number
one I want the lessons to be fresh and I
also want you to be
forced if you will to go back to your
notes it's simply me giving you the PF
File is not enough you need to be
referring to them every single month you
get something new when you finish that
new month go back from the previous
months and go through all those lessons
again and yes it takes a lot of time
that's why we're doing a 12-month
mentorship it takes a great deal of time
to go through this information to digest
it to retain it and then to be able to
use it it's simply not enough to give me
this and then I'll know what to do it's
not it doesn't work like that and
obviously some of you already realize
that and it's requiring you a great deal
more work but the ones that are doing it
guess what you already see the fruits of
that so while many of the folks on the
internet think they understand how I do
one shot one kill
believe me there's a whole lot of things
that I did not reveal in the first four
lessons of this month will look somewhat
like you have already seen it already
but there's subtle nuances especially
with one specific uh component that I'm
going to release at the very last slide
in this presentation I want you to be
really focused on because it really is
in my opinion one of the telltale signs
that you got a tiger by the tail in
other words you have a big move still
and I'll get to that when we get to the
last slide in this presentation but I
want you to know that when we go through
short-term trading this is my favorite
form of trading if I can't find a setup
for one shot one kill the next thing I'm
doing is day trading and guess what we
teach that next month but this month and
next this is where I excel as a Trader
because of my personal unique uh makeup
as a Trader and as a person my
psychology about things in nature is
very short term I can change my mind
very quick I can make a decision rather
quickly so that means that I can do very
well in this specific discipline of
trading and with intraday day trading so
while this may not be your particular
style Trading
trust me I'm going to teach you things
in this month and next month that will
help you really really Excel as a
long-term Trader or a swing Trader
everything Blends together that's why we
have to do these things from a higher
time frame down and we go back to the
higher time frame and fill in gaps that
were left there intentionally some of
you have scratched your head saying well
wait a minute I feel like there's some
things missing from the swing trading
model the things that are missing will
be helped by filling in with the short
term because everything is modular
everything is complementary as we go
through deeper study on this mentorship
so as we get down to the smaller time
frames everything fills in and then
you'll go back in the higher time frames
and say okay now I know what I'm doing I
know what I'm looking for and everything
fit together like a dovetail perfectly
okay as a reminder every discipline we
will always be re referring to the PD
array Matrix and I want to not just go
over everything that you've seen here so
far and I'm not trying to you belaborate
but it's important we understand that
as a short-term Trader especially for
one shot one kill which is the like the
flagship of this month's content
that's what I'm that's my Hallmark as a
Trader I mean that that's what makes ICT
Woody is you know I I can trade the
weekly range and get pretty close to
what the high and low is for the week
and you've already seen many examples of
me called the intraday highs and lows
before the fact within one or two Pips
and sometimes rate on the PIP
those same components are applicable to
the weekly range which if you really
stop and think about that
think about the Sunday open to Friday's
close how many Pips is offered over that
time period a lot tons so if you can
really focus in on what we're teaching
this month even if it's not going to be
your discipline of choice or style of
trading
it will give you a greater Insight on
how you can reduce your risk trading as
a swing Trader and or a long-term Trader
but
as it relates to PD array Matrix this is
again the backbone to what we look for
and how we frame our trades okay so it
ends up in every one of our teachings as
we go forward in each new discipline
this slide will always be there because
I want to ingrained in your brain okay
because this is what I do from an
Institutional mindset I look for how the
institutions will move from a premium to
a discount array or from a discount
array to a premium array you have to
understand that and just an example
let's just take a look at one real quick
it's saying we looked at the market and
it just recently filled in a fair value
Gap okay and we think the Market's
bearish well we go through this uh
process of looking for potential future
discount PD arrays and we look and we
can't see anything in terms of the
bullish mitigation block we don't see
any bullish Breakers there's no
liquidity void but there is no fair
value gift either
all of a sudden it reduces us down to a
bullish order block so if we're looking
at a monthly higher time frame premium
array we're looking for a
opposing weekly discount array
so in this case we'd be looking for the
movement from a fair value Gap that has
filled in at a premium level we're
dropping down and looking for a weekly
discount array and if our analysis leads
us to only a bullish order block below
us in the weekly format or time frame
that's the range that we're going to be
looking for that's your potential range
that's how much you can frame your risk
to reward model that's the range you're
trading that's not
um to be broken up and looked at as okay
well if this range is 300 Pips I'm just
going to take 20 Pips and be done with
it no you're going to look to frame your
trades as you scale out you're holding
for these longer term objectives
throughout the week you're going to be
learning to take some profits along the
way but you're holding out ultimately
with that last portion of your trade to
get down to that bullish order block
this is just one example it could be any
combination of how a premium moved to a
discount array or a discount array moves
up to a premium terms of reaching for
how the market May reach in terms of
moving higher or lower
and I'll say this in simple terms
all we're doing is looking for a monthly
PD array whether it's discount or
premium based on our next logical price
move has it gone most likely higher or
lower from where we're right now and we
move from a monthly PD array now if it's
bullish obviously we're gonna be
focusing on a monthly discount array if
it's bearish we're looking for a premium
monthly array
from that monthly array
you're going to look for an opposing
weekly array so if we're starting from a
premium and a monthly basis you're gonna
be looking for a weekly discount that's
your target you're looking for that
range to close in or the market to be
drawn to that level
now
if you're not really paying attention if
that didn't hit you hard believe me when
you go through all your charts go back
and look at every major move that's
what's been going on that's what makes
my ability to call the markets from one
level to the next and be pretty solid in
terms of why I think the Market's going
to go One Direction over the other when
I'm not confident about that it's
because I don't I don't know which
PD array is going to be used next so I'm
waiting for more information or the PD
arrays have been expired they've already
been traded to so you have to look for
something new and that means you have to
wait but guess what that does it gives
you context and also gives you patience
it gives you the ability to wait now you
know what you're waiting for because
right now I can't do anything
so when we go through this process of
eliminating or what's available in terms
of active PD arrays
we start from a monthly where what is
the monthly PD array that we're most
actively traded from is it coming off of
a bear shorter block okay great so
what's the weekly discount already it's
going to be reaching for there may not
be a mitigation block there may not be a
bullish breaker there may not be a void
or a gap there may not even be a bullish
order block that you could Fame around
confidence
it may be a series of all Down Candles
so what does that mean you look for a
rejection block or an old low an old
High
another example would be if we were
looking from a discount monthly array up
into a weekly premium array we could be
looking for the market moving from a
bullish breaker for instance and we
could potentially look for the market to
possibly run to an old high or an old
low
again that would be your potential range
this is the maximum you're leaving your
portion of your trade on to reach for it
may not get to these objectives but if
you leave a little piece on many times
you're going to find that if you do this
you can actually make more than the
trade if you had on the full position
and left it you know to your first
objective and just simply took it all
off there that small little portion if
you leave it on and you hold it for your
maximum potential that little portion
many times will be what you would be
making entirely if you just took first
profit at a smaller lesser objective
okay higher time frame sequence we've
seen this slide before but now we're
making one more addition and we're
making some additional notes as well
when we're looking for shorting
opportunities we're moving from a
monthly chart cell program it means
we're looking for the market to move
away from a premium array
and we're moving down into the lower
time frame which will be the weekly
chart and we're looking for it to become
a cell program as well so we're looking
for the market to move away from its
premium arrays down into a lower time
frame daily or watching for price to
move away from its
individual premium arrays down into a
four hour chart looking for a cell
program as well moving away from its
premium raise down into a one hour chart
where we're again looking for the market
to move away from their premium arrays
so if we look at the slide here to the
right
we have the monthly the weekly the daily
the four hour and the one hour and we're
focusing on the monthly chart is we're
looking for a premium array to trade off
of North that's going to be our point of
origin
from the monthly weekly daily and four
hour these time frames you're scanning
searching and trying to determine all of
the PD arrays not just premium and not
just discount we're looking for all of
them from each time frame because all of
them will give us potentially new setups
short-term trading or one shot kill
setups
and also
if we're looking for a move in this case
a selling opportunity and we're framing
it off of a monthly PD array from a
premium level that means we're in
basically an overbought condition and
we're going to be watching and expecting
the price to move lower to trade down
into a weekly discount
so if we're going to look at the monthly
the weekly dealing for our own both
premium and discount basis as we've
already talked about in previous
disciplines and teachings
in December and January when we do this
if we're bearish if we're looking for
the monthly premium arrays to influence
price to go lower
why is it important to look at the
monthly weekly daily and four hour
discount arrays
because we're looking for these arrays
in the discount form to break
we want to see them break
and we want to see them continuously
keep breaking until we get down to our
weekly
discount array
so for framing a monthly premium PD
array
we're expecting lower prices from a
monthly level
and we're trying to get down into a
weekly discount now it could be any one
of the discount arrays
whichever one appears on the chart or
the market that you're trading not every
pair or Market has every single discount
array
there's only a few that can exist very
rarely have you ever seen more than
three
so if you focus on what you're looking
for in terms of monthly down into a
daily
it gives you a very clear-cut thing to
look for there's not a a plethora of
things to choose from or well there's so
many things that could be Michael you
know which level is it no it's very
obvious
we're framing the market contextually
and conceptually so it gives us a way to
break down the marketplace and Define
where that market May most and obviously
likely reach to
so we're Scouting For opposing PD arrays
from the monthly down into a weekly
discount so again monthly premium level
and we're trying to look for an opposing
weekly pdra
in the form of a discount
from that monthly premium array
we drop down into a weekly
daily and four hour at every premium
array for each one of those time frames
and we're scanning for all of the
premium arrays where we can take
short-term trades from as a short
every one of those at the weekly daily
and four hour if we find a level like
that we refine it all the way to the one
hour chart our one hour chart is our
executable time frame for one shot one
kills or short-term Trading
once you have that executed what we're
doing is we're aiming for that Weekly
discount PD array
there's your cycle that's your process
that's your whole uh outline if you will
what we do with the information we
learned from January and February and
what we're learning so far is we're
taking all this conceptually and
breaking it down into a user-friendly
format
we want a monthly premium array
and
we start there we're looking for a
opposing weekly discount
whatever that range is it may be
hundreds of Pips or it could be a
thousand Pips I don't know it's going to
be unique to each market and environment
but we may have missed the real
opportunity to trade off of that monthly
premium maybe you just sat down the
insurance said oh look at this it's
coming off of a monthly bearish order
block so it's already moved away from it
you can't really use that to trade off
of you just know that it's moving lower
so what do you do next you drop down to
a weekly what's the weekly premium
arrays there may be one it trades up to
later on or a daily chart it may trade
up into a daily premium array or a four
hour
one of those four time frames is going
to give you a setup
based on the fact that the monthly
premium
is overbought
most likely are going to trade lower and
we're going to be looking for a lesser
time frame discount array what's less
than a monthly a weekly
we execute regardless if it's on a
weekly daily or four hour premium level
from a one hour chart
we get down to the discount on a weekly
that's our objective
throughout the time from that execution
if it's a weekly or it's a monthly level
we could potentially see multiple
short-term trades form
if it's from a four hour basis you won't
see that many charge setups form but
nonetheless there's still gonna be high
probability
okay for buying opportunities the same
thing is this repeated this in opposite
we're going to be looking for a monthly
chart by program so we're going to be
looking at a monthly discount array
and we're gonna be looking for it to go
into a buy program in which we're
expecting higher prices
weekly chart we drop down into it and we
start looking for all the discount PD
arrays as well
and we look for the daily chart to also
move away from its discount arrays and
then dropping them to a lower four hour
and then alternating down to a one hour
chart looking at all of the discount PD
arrays to offer support and price but
ultimately we're framing it off of
whatever the monthly chart discount
array is that's the beginning basis
point
so we're starting from a monthly level
we're finding a discount if we're
oversold or for any uh really deep
discount Market in other words it's
traded for a long time lower and we
found some old institutional price
models for bullish
institutional order flow for instance a
bullish order block an old high or an
old low whatever is caused the market to
trade higher in the past all those are
potential scenarios
we're looking for a lower time frame
opposing PD array
in this case we're looking for a weekly
premium array we're scouting opposing PD
arrays but we're starting from that
monthly basis for a discount so the
Lesser time frame from a monthly is a
weekly and the opposing from a discount
is premium so we're looking for an over
sold condition on a monthly to a
higher time frame premium array that
would be seen on a weekly chart so that
would give us a relatively intermediate
term overbought scenario it helps us
frame the model without using any
indicators
once we arrive at discount monthly PD
arrays we go down through the monthly
the weekly the daily and the four hour
to reference all of its individual
unique discount arrays
every single one of these even if we
missed the monthly discount array
and prices already moved away from it we
can't use it but we can refer to it as
an indication that markets wanting to go
higher so therefore we're identifying
that Weekly premium level as a Target so
whatever that range is that's what we're
waiting for it to trade up to between
them two points there may be thousand or
hundreds of Pips in terms of the
difference between the monthly discount
level and the weekly premium
so we drop down to the weekly the daily
and the four hour for all of the
discount PD arrays but which order
blocks bullish Breakers bullish
mitigation blocks liquidity voids below
current market Action Fair Value gaps
below current market action uh rejection
blocks old candle bodies with long Wicks
below it uh maybe want to reach down
below that or it could be just a run on
an old low or return back to an old high
historically
those are all discount arrays we look
for them from the monthly and then drop
down to a weekly find whatever they are
there on that time frame then the daily
and the four hour any one of those time
frames okay we're searching and
determining whatever the PD arrays are
from the discount basis but we're
framing the directional move from the
monthly
we time all of those potential setups
with the one hour chart
aiming for that Weekly premium array and
again it could be multiple short-term
trades forming between the monthly the
weekly and daily
getting to that Weekly premium array
again if we drop down to a four hour
chart once we get into the four hour the
trades start to fall off a lot in terms
of the frequency or multitude
okay if we look at how we can use the
same model dropping down from a weekly
chart
we can start from a weekly premium
looking into a lower time frame daily
discount
and we're gonna be scouting opposing PD
arrays respectively
and from a weekly from to daily to a
four hour we're looking for all the
premium arrays that we could short from
and we key off of whatever they are we
wait for price to trade to them and then
we use the one hour chart to sell short
from that's our executable time frame
aiming for that lower level time frame
daily discount
this my friends is the one shot one kill
setup
this is my bread and butter this is the
one that has consistent setups every
single week There's Something to trade
off of but you have to go through the
process of waiting for it to give it to
you
the opposite is same here when we're
looking for a weekly discount
ing an opposing PD array for daily
premium level
we drop down from the weekly the daily
and the four hour looking for all the
discount PD arrays executing on any one
of them
from a one hour chart
and again this is the one shot one kill
setup for longs
okay we talked about the swing trade
progression
and it's important to bring this back up
again because
without this understanding it's going to
be a little
too vague
but I gave you a model at which we
thought that maybe this is a six month
outlook on price okay maybe it's a
little aggressive to say six months but
just sort of sake of argument and
discussion let's just say this whole
entire range of higher highs and higher
lows is six months and we had the
benefit of forecasting the potential
move to see this unfold each one of
these price legs has a impulse leg and
it has a retracement then it's an
expansion swing
inside of each individual impulse swing
there could be smaller impulse and
expansion swings
each expansion swing again just like we
saw in the impulse swing could be broken
down to a smaller time frame seeing its
own individual unique impulse swing and
expansion swing
and this is repeated throughout the
entire fractal that is seen in price
as a short-term Trader with this alone
there is a plethora of many many setups
and signals that you can find just
trading with one market one pair
if this is a whole
landscape if you will of six months of
price data this could be every load that
it trades from And Trades higher every
single time it makes a loan moves up
graphically that is a potential
short-term trade
so just from this chart alone if you
take a moment and count every time it
creates a move up
use that lowest point at which you could
frame a short-term trade count them I'll
give you a moment to do so
there's potentially just on Longs
there's eight short-term setups here
just by breaking the fractal down one
scale
but we can go further than that
and break down the smaller swings into
their individual impulse swing
retracement and expansion swing
and it's smaller expansion swing can be
further broken down
each individual fractal
can be broken down to a lesseractile now
if we count how many opportunities you
could be a buyer when you're bullish and
you can frame the marketplace correctly
how many opportunities do you see here
in terms of potential buys
there's potentially 16 buying
opportunities in this overall fractal
that's not counting any short-term
trades that you could have done on all
the retracements
every little red section in here they
could also be short-term trades as well
if we couple those with the buying
opportunities there is a great deal more
trades that are available as a
short-term Trader
okay the general concept Revisited
we're looking for a market that is
poised to trade higher on a higher time
frame now we're going to be looking for
seasonal Tendencies to help us we don't
require it but they're always going to
be a bonus and we're looking for
interest rate driven conditions in other
words is there the
bond market is it moving is it stagnant
it's going sideways preferably we're
looking for a market that's moving
around uh dust commitment Traders
support the hedging program about the
commercials are they buying are they
selling in this case if we're looking
for a bull scenario we're looking for
commercials to be lessening their short
positions or aggressively adding or
already net long
and we're using inter-market analysis to
support bullishness that could be in the
form of supporting
with
smt Divergence or
correlated pair
smt
we're looking for a market that rallies
higher than retraces and this is going
to occur Monday through Wednesday so now
we're getting more time specific
and then we look for the market to
expand up into higher highs
so before we do anything we're going to
already have our point of origin in
other words that's going to be the
reference point from the monthly
standpoint and or dropping down to the
weekly daily and four hour
and we're going to know what PD array in
the premium we're aiming for
so we see that impulse swing
Monday Tuesday or Wednesday we were
looking for an up move to suggest it is
in fact buying
so that impulse swing is The Telltale
sign that there are smart money players
in the marketplace pushing price higher
that's what we're looking for underlying
we're expecting higher prices anyway but
now we're seeing it
we're waiting for the retracement that
retracement is going to come again
between Monday Tuesday and Wednesday it
could happen directly right off of
Sunday's rally and then Monday may be
the retracement or it could just start
right from Monday and have a very
shallow retracement of one day
between Monday and and Wednesday
during that retracement we're going to
be looking for or anticipating the next
move higher driving its
move higher into that premium array that
we're looking for
that expansion swing is where we're
looking to be profitable
framing the retracement from the point
of origin that's where we're looking for
our executable time frame hourly
four hour
daily weekly monthly discount PD array
we're looking for all those potential
levels as price starts to drop down now
it looks like graphically it's only on
Wednesday but for the sake of discussion
and keeping the the slide clean this
retracement and the discount PD array
Matrix is applied through the entire
range across the days of Monday Tuesday
and Wednesday so in other words what I'm
saying is from Monday Tuesday and
Wednesday during any retracement lower
we're looking for a monthly weekly daily
four hour
discount array the trade-off of
aiming for the weekly
premium array
and it has to drop down into
a Killzone
now
what kill zones could you be trading uh
obviously you all know that I like to
trade the London open and I like to
trade in New York open
ly trading the Aussie kiwi or Japanese
Yen you want to be including the Asian
session Killzone okay so you can go into
my free tutorial stuff and see what that
actually is but for a quick down dirty
uh time frame what you're looking for is
2300 hours to
well basically you're going to be
looking at 6 p.m to 9 P.M
New York Standard Time
whatever time is in New York
6 p.m to 9 00 p.m there's your sweet
spot for Asia okay there you go nothing
nothing easier than that now and many
times it can extend to 10 o'clock but
usually you don't want to be doing
anything after 10 uh the closer you get
to 10 that's kind of like their lunch
time so you don't want to do anything
around 10.
and ultimately if price drops down gives
you retracement into a discount PD array
from a monthly weekly daily or four hour
level
you can see that also can be used from
an hourly executable time frame so if
you get a hourly discount PD array
they could be executed on as well inside
of a Kill Zone again you're looking for
that Monday Tuesday and Wednesday set up
but you're aiming for the weekly PD
array if you don't watch online kill
you're looking for that daily PDA right
but framing off of a weekly discount
okay the general concept Revisited again
in bearish markets we're looking for a
market that's poised to trade lower on a
higher time frame we're looking for any
Market that would potentially move lower
seasonally but it doesn't have to we
don't need to seasonal fancy there again
it's just always a bonus or a plus if
you will if we can use a market that has
a bearish seasonal tendency
our interest rates moving are they
stagnant uh preferably we're looking for
a market that has the bond market moving
all around the
tenure notes are moving around that's
held in consolidation
and commitment to Traders are we looking
at a Lessing of long positions by the
commercials or are we seeing a heavily
net short position being built or are
they already net short those are the
conditions we're looking for from a cot
standpoint and inter-market Analysis
supports the bearishness that means smt
diversions is indicating weakness or
correlated pair smt suggests that there
should be a overall sympathy move lower
for foreign currencies or for trading
stocks you'll learn all that as well
with the indices versus the leadership
issues
and we're looking for a market decline
lower than retrace higher during Monday
into Wednesday
and then we're going to be looking for a
market to expand down to lower lows
so we have our point of origin
from a higher time frame monthly premium
array
it trades lower
impulse swing and then there's a
retracement again this is all occurring
between Monday and Tuesday and Wednesday
any one of those three days this
scenario or condition has to be here
that retracement has to come up to
a level of Premium
and then the expansion swing is what
we're looking for to be profitable in
aiming for the discount array
we're framing our trade with premium
array Matrix so we're looking for a
monthly weekly daily four hour and one
hour premium array to Short from
in a Kill Zone
for time the analysis
okay monthly ranges
our price is fractal and higher time
frame analysis benefits us as a result
we note the high and the low of every
month candle
we note the present range in terms of
premium and or discount
we consider where price on the monthly
will or could draw to in other words
what's the most likely Direction
there is generally four weekly candles
in every monthly candle
every week we study where the monthly
will likely trade next
again
all we're doing is looking for
probabilities there's nothing that I
teach with 100 iron clad this is the way
it's going to happen every single time
there's no absolutions
there's only probability so we're
looking from these higher time frames to
look for where is it most likely
reaching for it because if we're trading
off of a monthly chart and we can pick
the most probable Direction chances are
even if we're wrong you know the lower
time frames that we're going to be
executing on still might give us
opportunity to be paid
and in usually monthly ranges we frame
trades on the weekly range
all right so what's a weekly range
uh again price is fractal and monthly
analysis Builds on the weekly
and we know to high in the low of every
weekly candle
we note the present range in terms of
Premium indoor discount
we consider where price on the weekly
will or could draw to again what's the
most probable Direction in terms of
where the weekly chart is trading and
where it may rage up or below or two
there's generally five daily candles in
every weekly candle
and every week we study how the weekly
trades inside of its monthly range
using weekly ranges we frame trades on
the daily chart
we're watching to see if the weeklies
continuously expand and make the larger
monthly candle
move in the direction we thought they
were going to go
so each week we're looking for
Confluence and confirmation that will be
anticipated seeing on the monthly is in
fact unfolding because the weeklies will
be pushing that direction hopefully in
our favor and then making that Weekly
range expand every higher or every lower
uh weekly candle we'll build that bigger
monthly candle in respective Direction
okay so let's take a look at an example
all right so here we're looking at the
Japanese Yen this is a monthly chart and
you can see from 2015
Springtime going into June 2015. we saw
the Japanese Yen
or dollar Yen pair trade up into around
the 125.80 level or thereabouts
and we moved from a low formed back in
and then we dropped from the 125s into
around June of 2016.
if you look at the total range we have
obviously moved into a discount market
and we look at the markets
old support levels found at
the February 2014 to June 2014 there was
a lot of support seen in there
so products came all the way down into
the point of origin where we think the
market will and with the benefit of
hindsight here I'm not going to be
slicing and dicing charts because we
called the Japanese Yen lower which is
dollar Yen higher all through the uh the
months in 2016 as we see here
but looking at this example we have a
point of origin where we think price may
want to go higher and once we see that
we start looking at all of the monthly
discount PD arrays I'm framing the last
down candle right before the Big Move
starts to take place that is a monthly
candle and we start looking at the
monthly range but that's not the monthly
range we're trading in that's just a
monthly range so don't be this don't be
confused when I start talking about
monthly ranges I may interchangeably
refer to a monthly candle where it's
individual or independent range that's
not the monthly range that we're going
to be referring to I'm actually going to
distinguish the two
okay so we have that one month's candle
range defined
and we're going to go back to on the
monthly level where are our monthly
premium arrays well you have a breaker
here
so we frame that so there's a move that
we can look up to for a monthly level so
we have both our monthly discount and
premium arrays
this is our monthly range
this is our
range for trading the monthly range in
other words what's our probable range of
probability or profitability where would
we expect to see moves take place
we take that range and we apply it to a
weekly chart and refine that down into
this individual weekly
PD arrays in terms of a premium array so
we have here weekly premium arrays
outlined I didn't put every single one
of them on here just to keep the chart
clean so that way we can go through and
have many examples for your study go
through and find out where all the other
ones are okay go through the individual
weekly chart and monthly chart and you
can see how price had respected a lot of
the other ones too that aren't being
used here if I just gave you the obvious
ones I use rejection blocks here for
weekly and premium arrays
so when price broke away from that 104
35 level and started expanding reaching
up into that 1860 level
that Weekly premium array
it had three lesser lower weekly premium
arrays old lows
seen through 2014 going into 2015
and then we saw
rejection block around the 111 level
then we saw another rejection block
around the 106 Big figure as noted here
so they're all objectives are where
price should reach up to so if you look
at that it's still a great deal of
opportunity between just those four
premium arrays on a weekly chart
dropping down into a daily chart
you can see a little bit more detail and
how price had reached from the 104.35 up
to each one of those weekly premium
arrays
all being
catalysts for higher prices
now we got into a four hour chart we can
start applying all of the order block
Theory and rejection block Theory
and we're also incorporating now the day
of week
filter which is Monday Tuesday Wednesday
so I've shaded where every Monday
Tuesday and Wednesday's range is
and I'm also highlighting order blocks
for bullish buy and I'm also
highlighting mitigation
and also highlighting rejection blocks
all of these are discount
arrays and the red shaded area up is a
70 level or thereabouts that's the
premium array on a weekly basis that
we're reaching for
so how many buying opportunities did you
see here
six
one each week
let's break it down a little bit more
detail
again taking all the unnecessary things
off the chart and you can see how price
has moved rather uniformly and
systematic each new week giving you
buying opportunities
and I will add all the individual day
dividers and I want you to take a look
at something
as the weekly ranges defined by the
double line vertical dashed lines okay
that delineates the Sundays so
everything to the right of those double
vertical lines
that are dashed that represents a
Sunday's Trading
to the right of it you have Monday
Tuesday and Wednesday shaded
notice how the lows of the week are
generally formed in Monday Tuesday and
Wednesday in this context
also notice
that when you see the high that's formed
between Monday and Wednesday say for
instance that there's a high that forms
uh during the Monday through Wednesday
range when that high is taken out intra
week
this is significant
because price will tend to expand
aggressively towards the monthly and or
weekly premium array
and it's reversed if it's bearish so
what we're doing is we're looking for
the Monday through Wednesday range every
single week
when that is bullish underlying in the
market and if you break that range
that's defined by technically Sunday's
opening but just for the sake of keeping
things germane and and consistent
because I did mention how we didn't
really refer to Sundays anymore
you can use Sunday for completeness sake
but from a Monday's opening
to Tuesday and Wednesday's range
whatever the highest high is when months
when when the markets are bullish if
that high is broken intra week say for
instance on Thursday or uh you know
Friday generally that is indicative of
an aggressive confirmation that we're
going to be moving to our premium array
that we were looking for or identified
ahead of time and everything you see
here would just be reversed for bearish
markets
Monday through Wednesday's range if that
is broken
when it's bullish the high that's formed
between Monday and Wednesday that is a
confirmation that you are in a buy
program and the markets will expand
aggressively to reach for your higher
level premium array
when the markets are bearish
the low that's formed between Monday
through Wednesday if that is broken on
an intra-week basis
that is confirmation that you are an
aggressive sell-off or sell program and
your long-term higher time frame
discount or rate that you're aiming for
it's a high probability condition that's
going to reach for that may not happen
that week but you're going to keep
looking for the next week to be bullish
or bearish respectively based on that
information
so hopefully you found this teaching
insightful we're going to be building on
a lot of these ideas in a lot more
detail leading into the ultimate
delivery of one shot one kill in a
process oriented rule-based breakdown
what you do from the beginning to end to
execution and until next session I wish
good luck good Trading