welcome to lesson seven folks of the
short-term trading module for ICT
mentorship
this teaching is dealing with intra-week
reversals and overlapping models
okay obviously in every one of our
teachings we have to remind you that
we're working with time and price
and one of the questions I want to lead
in this teaching with is
obviously I've shared with you specific
weekly profiles and when I was teaching
for free
I taught that there were Market reversal
profiles intra week and Inter day
and we'll talk about intraday when we
get into day trading but for short-term
trading there's intra-week Market
reversal profiles that
for the uninitiated or the uninformed
there are many times caught off guard by
the likelihood of a potential reversal
and early on in my career I had these
events as well and it plagued me it was
one of those things that just kept
coming up all the time I'd have a trade
it was profitable it would be working
for me and then something would happen
midweek and it would completely reverse
and I would hope and pray that it would
get back in sync with what I was
expecting to see as a long-term trade
and
it didn't happen it came back and rolled
right up against me and either stopped
me out or pressured me so much that I
had to get out of the trade
if you've never experienced this
you will eventually
so it's important we cover it now one of
the hardest things for me to teach when
it comes to Market profiling is the
market reversal profile
because I have to teach
not just one element of trading or
discipline of trading but I have to
teach a multiple approach either swing
trading short-term trading day trading
or position trading swing trading and
short-term trading something to that
effect so it can't be
understood as efficiently as it would be
as if the student or the trader was well
versed in more than one trading
discipline so when I was teaching on the
forums years ago and I was sharing my
information on YouTube and on my own
website uh the problem I was well aware
of but I wanted to kind of like lay some
foundations to the folks that were
really involved in learning and studying
they could have
not get to the what I'm going to share
here but you know come to the conclusion
that there are certain guidelines and
approaches that leads to
a potential intra-week Market reversal
profile
and we're going to cover the components
that leads to that in this teaching here
okay in our example again we're going to
be using the British pound
and this time
by having RPD arrays again
okay
I want you to focus on this low right
here
this actually happened the week of this
recording and it created what we're
going to be talking about in this
teaching
I was kind of waiting for this uh
week to close anyway so I can actually
use this as an example
but if you go through the notes in this
teaching you'll be able to go back over
historical data and see where they
manifest themselves and the criteria I
teach in this lesson you'll see that a
just like script it follows it almost to
the to the letter
so what we're looking at is the low that
was formed on cable
and the intra-week reversal and what led
up to that and what are the
characteristics that generally are a
part of this phenomena
first we have to identify the fact that
the market was in a premium Market
classified by the large trading range
that we talked about and outlined in
lesson five
so we're in the premium range of the
pdra Matrix and perhaps you saw that the
market was trading up into the weekly
rejection block or traded up into Old
bearish order block on The Daily charts
therefore we could potentially see the
market trade lower as we were
anticipating potentially seeing this
week but it trades down into a lower
level PD array in the discount it
doesn't do it over the course of the
entire week no no it does this in a
matter of 24 hours
so
as the market in this case the cable
British pound USD
trades over 200 points
in a period of 24 hours the market
reaches for a level with speed for a
particular reason
and when you look at the daily chart
here we've outlined the PD arrays and
you can see that there's a daily bullish
order block mean threshold
and
price reaches right into that
on Wednesday of the week of this
recording
when we see a fast Market
we have to immediately assume that
they're reaching for a level
institutional order flow that is highly
critical for efficiency on the interbank
level
now that may be in the form of Commerce
globally or it could be in the form of a
repricing at the Central Bank level
either one of those could happen
rather quickly and while it took some
time to gradually drift down over the
24-hour time period for that whole
entire range to form between
Tuesday going into Wednesday's low
the idea is
you're going to anticipate at the
beginning of the week a certain outcome
and it's prudent that you stick to that
okay because over the course of a career
you're going to get caught in a reversal
like this once in a while it's not going
to plague your career obviously after
learning what's being taught in this
lesson but you also have a checklist on
things that may lead to that type of
scenario and if you go back over to the
Chart index and look at some of the
examples we were talking about as it
relates to the cable
there were telltale signs and I gave you
a little marker telling you that there's
a potential area of Bounce likely in
this pair
what led me to that are the things that
I'm going to teach you in this lesson
because I understand multiple dimensions
of trading whether it be position
trading short-term trading swing trading
day trading scalping all that business
I am versed in understanding and reading
price
universally it's not one type of time
frame to me that makes sense it's all
the time frames I know how to blend them
together
that part comes with experience and
after a measurable growth in your
experience and working within different
disciplines of trading this is the
reason why I tell you regardless of
whatever you think you want to be at the
beginning of the mentorship it's going
to graduate into other things
but I'm forcing you across all of them
if you're willing to submit to all of
them and stay with the mentorship
again it's not a plug you decide whether
you're staying here or not but by having
a well-versed approach and understanding
across all the disciplines you
inherently have a advantage over those
individuals that just stick to just one
format or discipline or trading I'm a
scalper I'm only going to worry about
scalping okay well then you're not going
to be that good at scalping because you
have a limited myopic view on price
action so having a well-rounded approach
to price action what multiple time
frames different disciplines you will by
default be a better Trader at whatever
discipline you focus on as a career
so we're going to look at this little
range in here
that's not so much of a little range but
we're gonna look at the move in this
particular decline down into the daily
bullish order block mean threshold and
what what the Catalyst that led to that
reversal
first thing you want to notice is that
price is unwilling to leave the premium
so we're in the upper portion of the
larger trading range defined by in
lesson five
so while we saw initially in the
beginning of the week the market want to
decline and it was doing it aggressively
and speedily if you will by seeing that
we could have if we didn't understand PD
array Matrix discount arrays we could
have easily expected this Market to keep
on trading lower maybe even going down
to the fair value Gap or if you're a
classic support resistance person maybe
just that old low made back in January
myopic I know but nonetheless this View
leads to what many times breaks accounts
and careers it dashes the hopes of
would-be Traders because they aren't
informed you're learning the mechanics
of how price is delivered we're going to
look at this range here and Define it in
a context that would otherwise not be
available to you
so we'll look at the first
two days of the week
going into Wednesday's low
and I want you to understand just how
much that price range is it's
extraordinary it look at the the length
of that candle
for the most part it's many times larger
than the general average of all the
candles here
now obviously there's a few of them here
that are larger but in general terms the
candles slightly before and the candles
to the right of it that large down
candle on Tuesday
it's
pretty much a dominating candle
so it was speed at which it moved in one
trading day to get down to a specific
institutional order flow reference point
we're going to take a closer look at
this and we're going to look at a four
hour chart and we're going to refine it
and give it a little bit more detail
the yellow area is that same range
defined across the entire week
from when these rallied Tuesday's
decline in the Wednesday's low
and price returns to a discount pdra
reversing enter week now we we can see
it clearly here it's hindsight it's
perfect it's 2020. we can see it but we
have to go into it with the details
because that's what's going to help you
see what it looks like going forward why
did we anticipate a bounce there why did
I give it to you in your chart Index
this week the things I'm going to show
you here
I want you to take a look at the low
here and it forms on Wednesdays
Market low and it's trading at a daily
bullish order block mean threshold
after the bounce at the daily bullish
order block mean threshold
ipta draws price up into a four hour
bearish order block premium PD array
notice the efficiency how it trades
right up into it it's exactly right to
The Logical area where price should
reach for if it's going to a premium
Market
there's very little movement below the
level that's identified as the daily
bullish order block mean threshold and
it trades right to the four hour bearish
order block you can't get any better
than that in terms of price delivery
clearly seen with the four hour order
block traded here
so now we're going to take it and refine
it down to an hourly chart and give it a
lot more flesh on the skeleton we're
outlining as a market reversal profile
I want you to note the large decline
from the first of the week now obviously
I'm I'm beating this in your head
because this is the classic Telltale
sign that you have a potential Market
reversal profile think about it every
time that the market quickly starts
trading on Monday or Tuesday
aggressively and speedily that's usually
a Telltale sign it's in a hurry to make
a weekly range or it's going to go to an
Institutional order flow reference point
that could potentially cause it to
reverse and go the other way
so now we can see Monday starts as a
potential high of the week profile
rallies initially right from Sunday's
opening declines a little bit and then
we have another rally into the London
session on Tuesday and it aggressively
trades lower trading rate into the
changeover from Tuesday into Wednesday
creating the low of the week and then we
have an aggressive move off that low
this
right here this price decline the speed
at which and the magnitude of which it
moves is The Telltale sign that's the
characteristic that leads you to okay
we're really moving quickly and we're
covering a lot of ground in the
beginning of the week
whenever that happens you immediately
start looking for higher time frame PD
arrays that may cut cause or be a
catalyst for intra-week Market reversal
profile
if you do not do this and you fall into
the the thought process that okay
it's moving quickly it's moving fast so
therefore I'm going to make a lot more
money in double time and it's probably
going to have an equal leg you know
lower later in the week in the same mood
no don't think like that okay don't
think like that at all
speed in price is indicative
of them getting to a valuation point
when price is in a hurry to get
somewhere think about when central banks
reprice for instance when they do
interest rate announcements okay there's
very little time from where right before
the announcement
then the news comes out and then the the
rate changes
that is not attributed to buying and
selling okay that's a repricing based at
the Central Bank level it's a sudden
thing and that's why there's such a wide
disparity between where price is at one
moment then all of a sudden it's
somewhere else
that repricing
is a
response to a central bank intervention
or interest rate announcement
when there is no Central Bank
involvement and price is just
aggressively and speedily moving okay
that's based on evaluation through
speculation so they're taking the market
down through ipta in this case down to a
daily premium
to Discount range in other words it's
moving away from a premium down into a
discount PD array
but we're still in the larger premium
range so if you were just looking at
price and you understood or what were
sold this would look like it's probably
going to keep going lower it's going to
continue going lower but no the only
thing it's doing is it's showing and
willingness to get back down to a
discount level okay think about how I
showed you in the previous lesson how
you can grade
modular smaller ranges in terms of
premium and discount arrays
that same thing is being used here but
just in scope of keeping it in the upper
portion of the premium range on that
daily chart that we've broken down in
lesson five
so while we're still overall in a
premium Market longer term
short term it can continuously move
higher and keep making higher highs
think about it like when you trade with
bearish Divergence just because the
momentum indicator is diverging barracy
doesn't mean price is going to say okay
well I'm going to turn around go the
other way because the stochastics are
macd it continuously can keep moving
higher up that same element takes place
when we're looking at just price action
alone so while we are in a premium
Market the market is showing a
willingness to not here's the key not
move out of a premium Market in other
words why didn't this continuously go
lower Wednesday into Thursday going into
the discount Market because it needs to
go higher it wants to go higher so if
it's not going to go lower and it wants
to go higher where do we focus we focus
on premium PD arrays
now Wednesday breaks a short-term high
and then we start seeing evidences of
institutional sponsorship on every
bullish order block
every order block that forms with the
down candle or a series of Down Candles
we extend it out in time you can see
them capitalizing each one of them with
new long positions and we're seeing a
positive confirmation because prices
quickly surging away from that level
every instance we see new evidences of
institutional sponsorship
and up into a fair value Gap premium PD
array
now intra-week reversals
will many times look to return to the
previous balanced price range or
exceeded now what does that mean
think about the market maker cell and
buy profiles okay or Market maker cell
and buy
models in this case here this could end
up becoming a market maker by profile
we have the consolidation known as in
this example as the price balance range
or it's price is in a small little range
and then it leaves it on Tuesday
aggressively sells off
we have the smart money reversal into
Tuesdays Wednesday overlap
then we have a low risk Buy
on Thursday then we have a continuation
for reaccumulation on Friday but prices
traded up into that price balance range
all over again it's right back up and
again so when we see that this could be
the end of the move it can be this could
all that's been necessary is for them to
trade right back up that price balanced
range
but we always have to have the
likelihood on our mind that price May
exceed it and go past it which is what
the market maker buy profile really aims
to do it take out the liquidity above
and on high in this case we have a lower
high formed on Tuesday than Monday so it
may not necessarily need to go above it
but personally between you and I I think
it will
so here we have a British pound naked
one-hour chart
now if we were just given this example
here in price action maybe some of us
would be able to see that low down there
and see some evidence to support why it
should go up
and then maybe not
whenever we have a storyline or a
potential outcome in the marketplace in
our mind that we we formed an opinion we
have a plan that we're going to try to
execute on
it's important that we we're mindful
that the setup may not pan out for
instance the beginning of this week you
may have seen this as a potential high
of the week and you expected to see
Friday's close be lower than Wednesday's
low
guess what just like I do sometimes
you're gonna get it wrong
the evidences of the fact that the
Market's moving quickly at the beginning
of the week this is Monday and Tuesday
Monday and Tuesday okay or one of the
two if we see sudden quick movement in
price and magnitude here's the key word
here it's got to cover a lot of distance
what's average uh average distance of
the last few days if it exceeds it a lot
whatever the average daily range is for
the last five days if it gets well above
it
chances are you're probably going to see
a market reversal profile it doesn't
mean it always will happen it just means
that start considering it okay I
mentioned in the commentary through this
week that we were probably going to see
the weekly range form in one day and we
did we pretty much ended up seeing that
with the exception of a small little
tail noted here on Monday's high uh the
whole range for cable was really formed
on Tuesday so
that's indicative it's characteristic of
a market reversal profile intra week
so the main thing I want you to
understand in this lesson is that at the
beginning of the week we anticipate the
higher low the form period that's that's
a given that that's that's the nature of
ICT Concepts because as
humans were generally good starters and
the week starts with the new hopes and
aspirations to make money in exchange
and commerce but
opinions can change
directives can be changed and the
central bank and the banks themselves
they can make policy changes and or
fundamentals may change that we're not
aware of and yes you heard that right I
don't know what they are that causes
price to change at the Central Bank
level I don't need to know it I can see
the evidences of it in price so
when we move forward and going through
price action study it's important that
you understand that knowing the higher
time frame PD arrays will Aid in
failures that means when you have a
trade that doesn't seem like it's
working out for you even though you're
profitable chances are it's probably
better for you to get out of it and look
for another entry point
if it doesn't give you a strong entry
point chances are it's probably going to
be a market reversal profile
Wednesday or Thursday reversals
generally form every month so no matter
what pair you're looking at there's
generally some kind of a a reversal of
sorts that can form so by going over
examples and looking at Price hit
you'll see many more examples in just
this one here and everything we're
showing is reversed when there's an
intra week Market reversal profile that
goes higher and then sells off
so
it's a generic concept it's very simple
things that leads up to it the classic
telltale signs are the magnitude at
which the price moves on Monday and
Tuesday okay so it's only two days you
have to focus on how much is price
moving on Monday and Tuesday
so if you're seeing a lot of movement in
your favor and it's really covering a
lot of distance and it's doing it
quickly many instances you're going to
see it like this week really built in on
one trading day when it does that
consider the higher time frame PDA race
because it's probably going down to
evaluation or a higher level valuation
point and then it's going to have a lot
of sponsorship come in and then those
flows are going to turn the market it's
going to turn it the other way and if
you fight that it can beat you up or
dare I say it break your account
now consider swing trading model overlap
possibilities
and we've talked about the likelihood of
using short-term trading Concepts in one
shot one kill and now we're going to
blend or overlap trading models so it
helps you kind of formulate a better
understanding
here we have that same area price action
and what I've done was I've outlined it
in terms of a premium and discount PD
array Matrix
so we can see in the green area that's
the discount area and I have it graded
as well with four grades or four
quadrants and the premium area is posted
and it's divided as well
notice that on the daily chart
we have a daily bullish order Block it's
trading down into that so if we look at
this model here think about what I
taught you in the swing trading model
this is a swing trade entry this is
exactly what you look for for a swing
trade now if you're not a swing Trader
if you don't think like a swing Trader
then you're not going to see this as a
swing trade entry you're not going to
see it as a potential
setup that could many times pay out much
more than what a one shot one kill would
if you're only focusing on I'm going to
be a short-term Trader or I'm going to
only be a day trader I'm only going to
be a scalper these types of setups will
evade you and by evading you it's also
going to become a pitfall for you you're
not going to know when there's going to
be these potential reversals they'll get
you'll get caught off guard
so now we're going to take that same
element everything we saw in the daily
chart that is just applied we're just re
viewing it from a one-hour standpoint so
we can see the intraday price action on
a day by day division
you can see here reversals intra week
they occur here's the secret they occur
in overlapping models
every Market reversal that happens enter
week will be a overlapping of two types
of trading disciplines they'll be at
odds with one another
here's the rub
the higher time frame discipline will
always win
that's why we have to focus on monthly
weekly and daily PD arrays that's why I
beat it in your head that they are the
most important ones anything less than
that four hour that's about as low as
you want to go anything less than that
is all day trading stuff and if their
day trading things are not in alignment
with a higher time frame daily weekly or
monthly no less than a four hour you're
really not trading high probability
setups
so it's important that you understand
that the reversals
are not
always going to surprise you now because
you have some characteristics to look
for and now by having an opinion of not
just one shot one kill short-term
trading or
swing trading but you have position
trading as well and by blending all
those elements together it gives you a
greater understanding about price action
and now because you have these
characteristics in each discipline
understood
when you see a opposing view if a swing
Trader's approach saying it's a buy when
you're looking at a One-Shot one kill
sell-off
chances are your weekly range phenomenon
that you're trying to trade is going to
have opposition to the degree where it
will cause a reversal as it's being
shown here
so daily Swing model overlap example
shown here will hopefully ground you in
your understanding about how intra-week
Market reversals occur
takeaways from this lesson again are
the speed at which price moves on Monday
and Tuesday the magnitude at which it
moves there's your number one
characteristic Telltale sign you're
probably going to see a market reversal
and your week
and look for overlapping opposing
trading models if one is suggesting a
Buy on a higher time frame while in a
lower time frame it's looking like it
may continue going lower the arm
wrestling match is always going to be
won by the higher time frame
so hopefully you've learned something
that brings you closer to a greater
understanding of price action and
intra-week reversals and blending and
overlapping trading models