foreign
welcome back folks to lesson six of the
May 2017 ICT mentorship
ICT amplify day trading and scalping
this teaching is bread and butter by
setups
okay bread and butter buy setups daily
opportunities in scalping
now what you're going to be focusing on
is consistent small price movements that
can be harvested
not every day but just about every day
now in buy programs ifta will perform
one of two price engine models
the first is accumulate sell side
liquidity by repricing under an old low
cell stops will be triggered inducing
counterparty sellers to pair long
entries with
price will seek a higher short-term
premium array to offset positions so
offset accumulation is the first price
engine model
the second is re-accumulate fair value
in retracements lower at discount arrays
week-long holders will be squeezed in
the retracement lower so otherwise
anyone that's already long
when you see the retracement intraday
many Traders are usually using way too
tight of a stop loss and they'll be
squeezed out and I'll be providing
short-term sell-side liquidity to pair
up orders with
and price will seek to expand higher to
a short-term premium array to offset
positions
all right engineering sell side
liquidity
offset accumulation
ifta Will reprice the Market below an
old low to promote sell stops that will
be residing there for current
longholders now this is in essence
Engineers sellers at a deep discount
price
the open float which is the existing
orders that are actually in the
marketplace above and below the current
market price
the open Flow below that old low may
also have cell stops for breakout
systems that wish to sell on weakness
this model is called offset accumulation
its primary purpose is to offset current
long holders or induce more sellers at
discount pricing the model is seen
frequently in bullish market conditions
and while higher time frame
institutional order flow is suggesting
higher prices
typically offset accumulation models
unfold quickly and you must learn to
anticipate them at Key lows intraday
thank you
all right providing Banks new long
entry points or pricing
with reaccumulation
if they will reprice the market lower to
a fair value price array to provide
smart money discount pricing for long
entries
the market will be bullish from an
Institutional perspective and many times
unfolds after a recent sell stop rate
the retracement lower in price will
place pain on current long holders and
tends to induce selling thus providing
sell side liquidity to pair smart money
long entries with
this model is called re-accumulation its
primary purpose is to reaccumulate new
long entries and or induce more sellers
at discount pricing
the model is seen frequently in bullish
market conditions and while higher time
frame institutional order flow is
suggesting higher prices
typically reaccumulation models unfold
quickly and you must learn to anticipate
them at Key discount arrays intraday
okay realistic objectives
the trade duration when we look for
scalps are going to be typically one to
two hours or less many times a lot less
but usually about two hours is the
maximum
Pips portrayed
usually you're going to see a low end of
15 Pips to 30 Pips on average
timing the market we're gonna be using
the five minute chart
now the frequency of setups
per week you get as many as 15 or more
yes 15 or more
per day you get about two to three
setups typically
per session you generally get about one
per session that means
one in London one in New York one in
London close and one in Asia doesn't
mean you get one every single session
for every single pair it just means if
you look across a handful of pairs get a
basket of four or five you can watch and
see that there's a scalp usually setting
up in one of these sessions and one of
those pairs or another there's going to
be more volatility in one pair over
there so if you look at for instance the
the majors across the dollar
if you look at all those Majors paired
with the dollar if you look at every
major at London obviously London's so
volatile you'll get something there
obviously but New York the same thing
but usually running clothes in Asia both
will have uh something crop up in either
one of those major uh crosses with the
dollar but not all of them just one of
them
now you risk the reward typically it's
going to be one to one which isn't hot
but sometimes you can get a little bit
better than that but generally if you're
thinking scalping think one to one and
that's about all you're gonna get
ideal risk for trade is a half percent
to one percent and one percent may be a
little high but as you start to get
better at it you can start seeing more
setups
and obviously you can graduate to the
one percent but I wouldn't do anything
more than that
now this is the offset accumulation
model basically it's a stop run on Cell
stops
the buy profile
for offset accumulation so in other
words this engineering sell side
liquidity knocking out cell stops to
take it higher
and for reaccumulation using fair value
or reaccumulation by profile
for the price engine model this is what
it is it's typically the optimal trade
entry
all right consistent small price
movements are going to be specific to
kill zones all scalping should be done
during ICT kill zones
since the duration and style of trading
is so short-term in nature we need the
most volatile times of the trading day
to ensure that we get a move
there are times when using limit orders
an entry May execute outside a Kill Zone
this tends to happen in London lunch
that means between 5 a.m New York time
to 7 A.M New York time
or Post New York open basically around
10 o'clock and later in the afternoon
so it's best to be actively following
the market if you're going to be
scalping yesterday in other words what
am I saying
try to do all your scalping with Market
orders you can get fancy if you want to
with limit orders but my opinion is if
you're going to be scalping just use
Market orders just get in there use
Market hours and use limit orders for
your exits
I'll give you here a little
chart for the major sessions and you can
see how they overlap with GMT time and
Eastern Standard Time
the kill zones aren't
completely lined up with this so you
have to use the lesson that gave you in
earlier months where I actually give you
the specifics about what each killzone's
time start and end is
all right up close days or bullish days
and we're gonna be revisiting the daily
range here for completeness sake
when the market is poised to trade
higher based on higher time frame
institutional order flow in essence we
expect the open to be at or near the low
of the daily range
there can be a small decline below the
opening price so you're probably asking
yourself well Michael what's the opening
price you're referring to remember we
look at both zero GMT open at age is
open and we're looking at midnight in
New York
so higher time frame institutional order
flow that means that monthly weekly
Daily 4 Hour we've done our analysis
we've done all of our
directional bias studies we looked at
the iptodata ranges where is the
quarterly shift most recently is it
looking to go higher it's looking to go
lower are we recently trading off of
daily bullish discount arrays are we
seeing bullish order block support
pricing bearish order blocks breaking
away are we coming down and filling in
liquidity voids and rallying or are we
filling in Fair gaps and rallying what
that's telling you is institutional
overflow is bullish you don't need trend
lines for moving averages to do that and
you just need to see what price is doing
how is it supporting
are up candles up close candles being
broken
and down closed candles finding support
for every time price comes down to it
that's institutional order flow so if
you're looking at it on a higher time
frame monthly weekly daily or four hour
and you see those evidences in price and
you did your PDA array Matrix and you
see where those PD arrays are where's
the one that you're mostly most likely
going to see
facilitate a long entry it's the next
one that price trades to once you get in
there obviously you're gonna be looking
for something as a premium
to be counterparty to so that way it
frames your trade you have to have an
entry point you have to have number one
you have to have a consensus of whether
the Market's bullish or bearish and we
don't use anything except for
institutional workflow to get that that
means we're looking at Price action that
tell us what's what's occurring our old
highs breaking but lows not being broken
or are those lows being broken quickly
and the price snaps higher right away
what that's showing you is the price
engine model was reaccumulation they
took it down took the cell stops
announced going higher these are all
fingerprints or Hallmarks of ipta
showing institutional order flow is
bullish
London open posts the initial leg higher
intraday then waits for New York open
typically you'll see that London Open
Swing
pretty volatile pretty aggressive move
one-sided
and usually does about anywhere between
40 and 60 of the daily range
before we get to 5 a.m New York time
and then there's a small period between
5 a.m and 7 A.M which is the London
lunch and usually you'll get some
measure of retracement or consolidation
there
and then you have the New York open so
New York open sees a continuation higher
when we're bullish
it usually tends to expand up to 10 a.m
New York time usually it'll start to
consolidate there or
create the high of the day and retrace a
little bit or it could be a complete
Market reversal but in this case what
we're looking for is bullish
environments for the higher time frame
institutional workflow is bullish and
we're expecting a big range day where we
can get some scalping done
price should trade up into the five day
average daily Range High now that's a
little indicator I can give you it'll be
attached to the Forum so that way you
can download it I'm not going to give it
to you until we do the
Bread Butter cell setups so that way
you'll have a complete understand what
you're going to do with it because I'll
give you an additional instructions
about that in the cell setup teaching
and once the 5-day average daily range
is hit and then we go into London close
time of day
usually the price will be posting its
high and then it'll start retracing off
of that high so between 10 a.m and noon
in New York time we expect a high of the
daily range to form
and at or above the five-day average
daily range projected High
price will normally retrace lower and
close off of the high of the day now
normally does it mean every time
okay some of the folks in our membership
okay take a statement that is not highly
specific and rigorous about its uh
uh context okay it's
a normal thing but doesn't mean it's a
Panacea okay it's not a be all involved
it's not a absolute
price will normally
retrace lower and close off the high of
the day
what am I supposing there without
actually saying it it can go higher
sometimes can go a lot higher so just be
mindful that while we understand the
daily range is typically formed like
this on highly explosive up moves
10 o'clock isn't going to stop price 11
o'clock is going to stop price noon
isn't going to stop price one o'clock is
going to stop price it can rally all up
to bond close at 3 P.M in New York time
all right the London open we're gonna be
scalping the London session
over some details about that
obviously when the higher time frame
institutional overflow is bullish we're
going to be anticipating the London
session low of the day formation
the open at zero GMT or 12 a.m in New
York can see a protraction phase lower
in price
this can be scalped from the open or
just above it prior to the 1am New York
time now what am I saying here you can
look at Price action on a bullish day
and if you're going to be scalping
you're going to be really Nimble about
this you got to know exactly what you're
looking for for a discount array in
other words you're going to really be
confident
that your convictions are
so strong that you think that when price
drops down to create that Judah swing
creating the low of the day where you're
going to be getting out at and where the
opening is if there's a large enough
range there that can be scalped
I teach people not to try to do that but
more
appropriate would be to wait for the Jew
to swing and then buy it down there okay
but
for scalping some some of you guys are
really excited about being Nimble in and
out both sides of the marketplace again
I'm I'm not trying to promote that idea
but I'm just giving you a complete array
of tools and guidelines I I came up
through the market using all these
things but I gravitated away from doing
that just highly specifically looking
for the Judas swing down on days that's
bullish and I expect it to be up close
I'm trying to nail down that low we'll
get real close to that low
the classic London Judas swing lower can
be scalped even easier if you're looking
at the midnight candle in New York uh
that move that drops down from that
candle that in my opinion is a little
bit easier to scalp even if you're going
to be seeing a higher close on the day
but age is open that can be a little bit
tricky because you can have a really
tight Asian range and it doesn't do
anything
the market retraces between 5 a.m and 7
A.M New York time and this can provide a
long scalp entry
once a discount array is hit
now think about this hormone
there's times when we looked at the
price and after the London Kill Zone
closes okay and there's that little
quiet period of time okay where my
Rockets generally go quiet and it's in
consolidation and that's waiting for New
York open around seven o'clock 6 30 in
the morning seven o'clock in the morning
New York time is the New York session
open for ICT so what's going on between
that time it's it's the lunch but
just like in New York sometimes Traders
can work through lunch they can say well
the markets are really hot right now
I'll eat lunch when I go home so if the
markets are really busy many times you
can get a retracement
into the London lunch that creates an
early entry and it moves before New York
open
and that's going to happen sometimes and
you can get mad and cuss at the screen
all you want but sometimes you if you're
really seeing a very volatile Market in
London or it was quite early in London
and then towards the 4 30 time period
when news comes out then it gets really
active usually it'll cross over into
London launching you'll get maybe a
small little uh 15 or 30 minute
consolidation and then you get the
retracement back into New York and then
it runs but
not always but it's very very
infrequently you'll see setups that
occur where the entry point would be
really good if you're trading between 5
a.m and 7 A.M but it's better just to
not even trade that time if you're don't
even look at it and think that you have
so that having you know the expectation
there's a quiet period in the
marketplace which means 5 a.m and 7 A.M
just keep that as a general rule of
thumb but unless the London session is
quiet the beginning and then gets really
active after three o'clock or four
o'clock then you'll probably see a
little bit of bleed over into post 5 a.m
New York time
even after the initial Judas entry point
has passed that means in other words you
missed it you couldn't get in when it
dropped down many of you are too afraid
to get in there because I say
you want to be buying on the Judas swing
down or below the opening price and
don't chase price so some of you are
holding fast to that rule and but you
don't ever do anything
but there's opportunities if you use the
five minute chart you can use a scalping
technique to get you in sync with it now
the reason why I didn't teach it to you
sooner because it's scalping we're in
that time period where we can use these
tools now
up until recently we haven't even looked
at a five minute chart you know we were
always higher time frame and sticking to
the rules of each parameter for each
Style Trading in scouting we look at a
five minute chart now
I'll comment on the markets with a one
minute chart a few times before we close
this month out but generally five
minutes what I'm working off of
okay this is an example of a London
session scalp
okay you can see the price
trades back down for a fair value gap
for re-accumulation
fills in the gap
in the London open trades up
edr's hit
in London open
and it's a 30 pip scalp it goes a little
bit more than that obviously but that's
all you would be looking for for a scalp
and it's over done
scalping the New York session when
London opened confirms institutional
sponsorship on the long side and posts
the daily low we expect to see New York
open to continue higher unless a higher
time frame premium array has been hit
intraday and or ADR is reached
we look for intraday swings higher to
determine discount
range arrays to go long at in the New
York Kill Zone basically think prices
got to move higher then it starts to
retrace I think optimal trade entry long
okay that's basically what I'm
describing there so you'll be looking
for a discount
array either a bullish order block a
fair value Gap or a liquidity void
using the 8 20 am New York time for CME
Chicago Mercantile Exchange that's when
the commodity Futures contracts start
trading
open to anticipate the New York Judas
swing to fade
targets will be the five-day average
daily Range High and the next higher
time frame premium array found on a four
hour or 60 Minute basis
if ADR high is reached prior to 10 AM
take 80 off of your position
and leave a small portion on to capture
any range expansion that might fill let
me rephrase that again
if you're long in New York okay and you
have a move that's quietly moving higher
but it goes up and hits the average
daily range before 10 a.m that means it
fulfilled its average daily range early
usually London close creates the highly
high today but if it does it before 10
am
still take 80 of the trade off but leave
a small portion on there because you may
end up getting a rather large range day
and sometimes ADR can be doubled
okay so you can see an example here of
the New York open trade very similar in
the way we looked at the London open
price comes down fills in a fair value
Gap trades into orb block and that blue
thin line with the CME open the price
drops down after that that's the due to
swing for the New York session so that
every session has a protectionary market
stage
if you're bullish
in New York you're looking for 8 20 and
a due to swing dropping down after 8 20.
if you're bullish in London you're
looking for New York midnight candle
and price trading lower after that to be
a buyer and price should expand higher
in Asia it's your GMT eight o'clock in
the evening in my time right now if you
look at that session you want to see it
trade down
right after your GMT it doesn't go down
very much that time of day though but it
can go down just below a previous late
session swinglet like we talked about in
previous lessons that is the Judas swing
at zero GMT where age is open
at London close it can happen but it's
the opposite you're looking for the
range to create a for a bullish day
what's going to happen is it's going to
go up a little bit after 10 o'clock in
the morning so you have a line on your
chart vertically 10 o'clock New York
time and then the rally that takes place
Post 10 a.m that's the Judas swing or
protraction a state where it creates the
high of the day
and then you'll be looking to sell that
if you're going to be a London closed
Trader which we'll talk about next
K scalping the London clothes
uh before I get into this I did a
teaching
um way back I think it was in 2010
the uh trading the London clothes and
really what I gave was a lot of the
rules I used for my s p trading because
there was a lot of Trades that you can
take trading spoos which is s p futures
the uh
when you're trading day trading the s p
you're really trading two sessions the
morning Trend then you wait for launch
to go sideways or retrace and then you
have an afternoon Trend okay usually
it's about 10 30 to 11 o'clock in the
morning New York time that's the the end
of the morning session or the am trend
for the uh for the spoos market
um usually Traders go to lunch uh
between 11 o'clock and one o'clock and
that little bit after one o'clock you
have a PM Trend that goes into the close
at four o'clock
but the characteristics that you see for
London clothes for Forex is the same
thing that day Traders do for s p
so it's that time of day uh influence
where London Traders a trade s p they're
going through uh you know they're going
home too
so when the New York and London sessions
have moved in tandem that means they've
moved in the same direction and the
five-day average daily Range High has
been reached and it is at least 10 30
a.m now it's a little different now it's
a filter 10 30 a.m in New York time
expect a retracement off the day's high
again between 10 30 a.m and 1 p.m that's
what you're looking for for that setup
for London close
ideally price should exceed the five-day
average daily Range High it should be
more than what you expected to see in
the five day average daily range because
then you haven't really overbought
really stretched out range
look for a five minute failure swing at
the High and a bearish order block to
enter on so basically what you're doing
is you're waiting for it to create a
high start to back off and then rally
one more time up to it into the last up
candle and it has to occur between 10 30
a.m and 1 pm
you're gonna risk 10 Pips above the
day's high and you're going to Target 20
to 30 percent of the total daily range
in a retracement lower and I'll show you
what that looks like on a fib
keep in mind this trade can be very
difficult to see pan out some days as
the range can and could expand far more
than the average daily Range High
remember
the average daily range is not a
barrier it's not a force field it's not
going to stop price all we're doing is
getting a calculation of what's the
average expansion we've seen over the
last five days
well if you're looking for a big move on
the upside wouldn't you really expect it
to go beyond the average daily range and
that's the problem we're trying to buy
in a preconceived idea that the market
should go up So eventually you know if
we take everything off at five day
average daily range highs when we're
bullish you leave nothing on to capture
these double ADR days they can happen
so with that in mind just understand
that
just because we have both New York and
London sessions moving in tandem One
Direction
doesn't mean that there's going to be a
retracement of any measure that you can
trade short that's why I don't trade
London close anymore I used to do it a
lot but it just fell out of favor with
me because I just didn't get enough Pips
out of it or I'd get stopped out you
know just keep on going against me so
I teach it for completeness sake here
because I've done lessons in the past
but when we get an s p it's a little bit
more favorable trading that it's an
index
ideally take one to one risk to reward
targets based on required stop and try
to get no more than 20 Pips okay and I
mean that don't try to get 65 Pips or
don't try to get a one shot one kill
haul 111 close it just doesn't do it
um typically I should have it in my
notes here but it should be about 15 to
20 Pips if you get 20 Pips be thankful
moving to the sidelines
okay here's an example what a London
close looks like it comes down into an
enclosed time period and you want to be
buying it on a failure swing and you can
see here it actually went a little bit
lower and if your stop would have been
just below one or two Pips you would
have got knocked out but again we're
using uh temp hips below the low
and looking at the uh
price on not the price but the Fibonacci
on this chart here you can see that
where it says London close
objective that's 30 on the FIB 0.30 just
add that level and you'll have that and
point 20 is the lower level so in
between those two lines that's usually
where the market will reach up into on
retracements and that's a good rule of
thumb for day trading also because if
you haven't uh expectation the Market's
going to go higher and you know what the
average daily Range High is going to be
you can use that projection from the
daily low or the London low and draw all
that FIB all the way up to and anchor to
the five-day average daily Range High
well before price even gets there and
you can actually see using this 20 to 30
level on your FIB that's usually where
the close is going to be on the up close
day or it's going to close right on the
high but generally when it trades off
the high it'll it'll trade off the high
and close in between the 20 and 30
levels on your FIB if you add them I
don't keep them there I just know what
20 30 looks like oh my
my range is because I've been doing it
so long but for a crutch while you're
doing it and you learning it's a good
idea to have it on your uh your
Fibonacci that we can use it
okay trading the Asian or scalping the
Asian open
when the market is bullish we can enter
long at or just under the zero GMT
opening price and expect an expansion of
15 to 20 Pips
and as I said 15 to 20.
higher as the Asian range is established
Asian sessions can traditionally be very
narrow and while this trade has proven
profitable in the past nothing is
repeating in terms of promised gain so
what was done in the past is not
indicative of the future so like London
closed trades we are looking at the
lowest volatile periods of the daily
range formation
so while I'm talking about it here for
completeness sake and that way I'm
teaching you a well-versed perspective
on how daily ranges are formed and how
ifta Engineers to daily ranges using
time of day and the characteristics that
go along with them
Asia's opening and London close are the
two smallest tiny little Windows of
opportunity and it doesn't pay out
enough in my opinion to take on the risk
but if you just want to do observations
and study and you want to do some
crunching on the numbers
you have at it man but just trust me if
you're looking for you know more bang
for your buck and your study time and
seeing movement in price
you want to be focusing on the New York
in the month of sessions always aim for
15 and 20 Pips in this session as the
range can be limited on the basis that
it will be the Asian rains formation
remember typically we're looking for a
really tight narrow range on the Asian
range so if we're looking to be a
bullish buyer of the day and you're
trying to day trade and we think it's
going to go higher
yeah you can scout that but what you're
asking actually trying to do is demand
that the agent range pays you when you
really hope that it's going to be a
small range so it's there's a
confliction between the rules so
while you may sometimes get lucky and
you get expansion in the Asian range and
it gets like a 30 pip or 35 pip uh Asian
range you might get something out of it
my question to you is why are you
worried about it and you're probably
asking why am I including it then
because I'm going to get questions about
trading Asia I'm going to get questions
about what about London clothes you used
to do uh teaching about that yeah how
many times have you seen me trading
London clothes you don't see that in a
lot you don't see me doing unless it's a
reversal time of day if it's going to be
a reversal Market profile then I'm all
over London close same with Asia if I
think it's going to be trading down to a
level that would be a high time frame
discount array but it didn't quite get
down there in New York and it's just
hovering above it I would look for ages
opening to facilitate that entry and
then that would be the low of the day
then and start rallying up
take full exits on scalps in this time
of day in other words don't leave
portions on
and again it's not optimal to expect a
second leg in price avoid greed here and
if you are fortunate to get 20 Pips be
content and exit
is just a weird animal and it's usually
very quiet so again my or our
understanding about if this uh true day
is that we're forming the initial high
and low of the day during this time so
again you're really having to be nimble
and I know what's going to happen you're
going to get in here and start monkeying
around with this trade and you're going
to see it shoot up and it's got 27 Pips
you didn't put a lemon odor in it but
automatically it shoots out 27 Pips and
you're in profit what do you think is
going to happen
you're gonna start thinking wow this is
the low of the day um I'm gonna I'm
gonna hold this thing and invariably
it won't be
it'll end up being a Judas swing later
on after midnight go lower and then it
stops you out and then what happens is
it freaks you out and you get mad and
you miss the actual mood that you should
have been looking for all along
did mean Judas swing dropping down to be
a buyer on that bullish day
so
I've given you some rules I've given you
some context about how I look at scalps
how the price engine models deliver
price
the offset accumulation and the
re-accumulation models that take place
for buying
Bank Traders will look for these
opportunities to pair up their orders
and that's how we can do the same thing
on scalping even if we think that the
Market's going to be quiet many times
you can get 15 20 Pips you know in a day
a couple times a week
that's it's all that's necessary to do
well remember we talked that 25 to 30
Pips a week doubles your money over a
year and we can actually start doing
that with scalping
until next lesson I wish you good luck
and good trade