now hooks welcome to volume one of three
for mastering high probability scalping
now this is a video that's going to be
kept on my youtube channel and generally
anything that's predominantly linked to
just my youtube channel will have this
intro and I'm going to ask you as the
trading community to help me out a lot
of times folks will take my content and
re-upload it on their own YouTube
channel and if you see that just let me
know and I'd like to be able have that
taken down I put the work into these
presentations so I'd like to be able to
get to credit and the benefit of edie
revenue off of it
so if you see it just let me know and I
appreciate it you don't have to be
public about you can send me an email
that inner circle trader at gmail.com I
greatly appreciate it thanks
all right so before we can I'm gonna ask
you a question what is high probability
scalps every one of us would have a
different definition I'm certain of it
but for me as I CT it's ten to thirty
pip price wings now I don't do a lot of
this type of trading it's only recently
because I've come back online and it
gives me an opportunity to give a lot of
set ups a lot of results a lot of things
to study I guess it's you know probably
one of the easiest things that get
people excited and I know that going in
and that's the reason why I adopted this
style of showcasing my talents but I
don't want you to think this is the only
way you can trade the markets because
it's not there's certainly ways you can
do it front end the day standpoint but I
want you to know that what I teach has
consistency and it also has the ability
to prove right away that the markets are
not in fact random at all they're very
very organized they're very specific
about where they're trying to get to
intraday and even on a weekly basis and
I would probably argue the point on even
longer term basis but I just haven't
made my precision that long term yet I
don't think I ever will first thing it's
not my cup of tea
I like day trading and short-term
trading one shot one kills what I'm
known for which is trading the weekly
range so daily highs and lows are my
specialty
and weekly highs and lows are my
specialty so I try to trade inside those
ranges and I get the meet or hopefully
the meet of the move not trying to get
the very high or very low but I know
where those parameters are and as long
as I haven't met those extremes I know I
have opportunity or life in the battery
if you will all right so we're gonna be
focus on specific things in this
presentation it's not going to be very
long I want to keep them concise and
short and again it's three volumes so if
any questions come up by why you're
watching this it's important every time
you watch any of my videos have a
notepad in hand turn the radio off go
into a quiet room listen to what I'm
saying because I'm packing 20 plus years
of information and experience and very
very small bandwidth so
just write down your questions I'm quite
certain there's going to be able to find
the answers to them in future
presentations for this one we're we
highlighting the many opportunities in
scalping the Forex
I'm gonna be teaching you how to learn
directional bias for higher timeframe
institutional sponsorship and I'll
explain what that is when we get to it
and how to determine the highest
probable times of the day trade
and we're gonna be learning how to frame
high probability setups for runs on
liquidity sounds pretty fancy I know
alright so high probability scalping now
this is an example of a high probability
scalp and this is in the dollar cad now
right away some of you are gonna be
watching this video
months and years from the time actually
presented it trust me
I tweeted live and people watched this
actually be shown to them live ok this
actually was a weekly high at the time
of this presentation but I was calling
them a weekly and daily high looking at
this specific range everything that's in
here is all that is necessary to know
how to do short-term scalping intraday
now because it's scalping there's gonna
be times when these setups overlap with
longer-term conditions now I'm not
teaching one shot one kill here I'm not
teaching swing trading or position
trading but I will drop that little
nugget for you to study
it's obviously found in my free
tutorials you can find that on my
website about inner circle trader.com is
a free form you can join that it's
absolutely free to get in there and you
can watch all my pre tutorials that I'm
releasing and you also be able to see
some things I share in trading journal
entry so you can give me an opportunity
to speak to you by way of how I
interpret and reflect on what has been
seen in the marketplace when I take
action or if I take action and I lose
you kind of get a vibe on what it is
I've either felt or what I was thinking
during the day when I was looking at the
marketplace but a short term scalp here
is a very simple approach to running out
previous day's highs or previous day's
loads that's all it is we're targeting
by stops above the previous day's high
or a day or two ago in other words we're
always gonna be looking back the last
three days okay that's your there's your
range okay you're gonna be looking back
at the highest high and the lowest low
in the last three days now you're
counting today as they want so for
instance at the time that's recording
day of the week is Thursday so we would
be looking at Wednesday's data and
Tuesday's data very easy rules right so
we know what the daily high and the low
is on Tuesday and on Wednesday and we're
monitoring what's going on intraday for
today that would be Thursday of the time
that's recording in November 2nd of 2017
now what we're aiming for is exactly how
banc traders trade now I know a lot of
folks on YouTube claimed to know certain
things and they use a lot of buzzwords
but I'm going to show you something that
no one else teaches because they don't
know it ok but I'm going to show you in
recent weeks since I've been back on
social media everyone's noticing a tone
or difference in my presentation it's a
lot more concise a lot more accurate a
lot more specific in nature and that's
because I've spent the last 14 months
with people on a day-by-day basis and
I've been able to share with them
they're really openly about what I've
learned over the last 24 plus years and
it's not retail retail things get you
into this business I'm gonna show you
how to leave that stuff behind you and
think institutionally that's like my
tagline now I want everyone that follows
me to leave that retail mindset because
it's not going to help you in fact it's
actually gonna be a hindrance or snare
you're gonna find yourself not finding
consistency at all and if you ask
yourself right now are you consistent if
you're following retail stuff you're
probably not using the things I'm gonna
teach you in this 3 volumes you will
quickly find consistency now I did not
say profitability I cannot promise that
some of you are going to break the rules
where you gonna do things early so
you're gonna do things late you're gonna
risk too much okay and you're gonna do
too many things at one time
that's what's gonna cause the adverse
effect and I don't want the credit for
your wins and I don't want to credit for
your losses so be responsible it's only
for informational purposes only
all right so when we look at high
probability scalping now this is an
hourly chart on the dollar cad and what
I've done is I've highlighted the
individual daily highs and lows now it's
important that from a scalping
standpoint your time frame you're gonna
be following Mon mostly is gonna be on
the daily because it's gonna give you a
bias and I'll show you how to do that
it's really simple but for looking for
liquidity you're gonna be using the
hourly chart because it gives us a real
nice framework to see where previous
day's high is or the previous high two
days ago okay for instance right now at
the time of this recording right over
here this is Thursday's data in the far
right of the chart okay and yesterday's
Wednesday's data you can see the low
it's been highlighted here and the high
and then Tuesday's high and low okay so
I want to draw your attention to the
fact that we have traded below
Wednesday's low today and we've also now
traded below Tuesday's low so that to me
is a significant point I'll talk more
about that in volume two but I want to
kind of like bring your attention to it
right now because it's going to be
salient to what we see going into
tomorrow's trading okay and you'll see
all that in hindsight but I'm drawing
your attention to it right now but each
day daily highs and lows okay when it's
bullish when the market is bullish and
I'll show you how to define what's
bullish and what's bearish not requiring
any indicators no trend lines and moving
average and the oscillator none of that
stuff okay
just using purely price action only it's
all that's necessary but when we're
bullish on price action we think the
higher prices are in order let's to say
we come to that conclusion right away if
we're bullish an institutional mindset
is running liquidity on the previous day
or previous days prior to yesterday's
high okay and the reason why is there's
a lot of speculations about capturing
catching highs in the marketplace okay
and especially if we have a day that saw
a retracement the day before or two days
ago lower that means there's going to be
built in positions that are short okay
folks that
I tried to sell short on the marketplace
they're gonna want to try to capitalize
on movement lower where's their buy stop
going to be above the most recent high
what's the most recent high yesterday or
today before now why am I having you
look back two days ago and include
today's range because every swing high
on a daily chart and every swing low is
comprised and created by three
individual bars you have to be
monitoring these daily highs and lows
because you want to be able to forecast
eventually as I teach you in volume
three swing highs and swing lows before
they actually materialize and start
breaking down because sometimes the
markets will turn on a dime and they
don't give you the setup down with an
outline in this volume one but this is
the bread and butter easy way approach
it's not going to give you a set up
every single trading day and that's
exactly what I want you to avoid trying
to trade every single day now there's a
reason to trade a demo account every day
to practice the setups but do not try to
force your live account into a condition
where it must trade every single day day
trading is not every day trading so I
want you to take a look at when price
has moved higher every previous day it's
high has been violated okay
generally folks won't pay attention that
simple
phenomenon it's a very simple approach
but it eluded me the first six years of
my trading I didn't see this element to
trading until about six years into my
bond trading now I started as a Treasury
bond trader and SP futures trader those
were my two markets of choice either I
was in spoo's which is SP or I was
trading the Treasury market or bonds I
was rarely ever in both because they are
basically diametrically opposed think of
it like the dollar index and a foreign
currency okay I didn't do anything else
I didn't trade agricultural anymore I
just focus on those two pairs or not two
not pairs but I focused on those two
markets why because I didn't need
anything else if you are watching
multiple pairs right now stop just do it
for one month humor me for one month I
promise you if you give me one month of
your time and focusing on one currency
pair it doesn't have to be one that I
suggest pick one any one of the majors
that's crossed with a dollar I promise
you you will learn you'll learn more by
doing that than trying to do all these
other things with other different pairs
if you're trading multiple assets and
you're now starting to learn forex stop
trading the other asset classes and just
focus one month with me use the
information I give you and again I
guarantee you you will understand price
far better than you ever have before
and it can be very simple approaches so
you got me and want to guarantee there
so now if we're bullish what we want to
be thinking about is where price is
going to be drawn to okay that's called
the drawl now when we look for where the
markets going to reach for in terms of
bullishness it's the previous day's high
or an old high that's gonna be in the
form of buy-side liquidity or buy stops
so the market will draw up to that level
okay and dip into that liquidity pool
where there's existing buy stops for
instance if you were selling short your
buy stop would be above the current
market price at what level whatever the
previous high was that's what the books
tell you right so if your stop
hit what that becomes as a market order
to send a buy order right away in as a
market order so your buy stop transforms
into a market order to buy at the market
and the market is going to be driven up
there from an algorithmic standpoint I'm
not going to get into that here and I'm
not trying to convince you of it just
just suspend your disbelief if you don't
believe it's algorithmic and in terms of
how the markets move think of it as just
you know supply and demand if it helps
you right now okay
but when price goes above an old high
it's going there to force buyers to come
in at a higher price
instead of buying low okay they're
forcing buyers to buy at a higher price
so smart money has at some point
accumulated a position at a lower price
and they're driving price up to
formulate an opportunity or condition
for participants to have existing orders
or real interest at buying at a higher
level to be forced into or out of
positions okay and that's all it's it's
all basically framed on now I'm framing
this whole discussion tonight on the
basis of looking for by side liquidity
or by stops or running out by side
liquidity pools okay so when we're
bullish from an institutional standpoint
what we're looking for is the draw the
draw is above where market pricing is
now in the form of cold highs now we're
using for scalping we're using previous
day's high for a very simple little day
trading approach to capture 10 to 30
pips inside of one trading day now every
pair out there does this several times a
week not every day does one singular
pair create this condition so it's
important you have that in your notes do
not anticipate this forming every single
trading day in say for instance the euro
dollar okay if you don't see a setup in
the euro dollar then once you understand
the setup okay then you can go into
other pairs like pick for majors okay
maybe a cross and that's like your
little basket of currencies and you go
through that I'm not inviting you to go
through 28 pairs
okay don't do that but
you can find a setup that I'm going to
teach you tonight every single trading
day to practice on if you have learned
what's going to be presented to you in
the first well you know the first second
and third volume completed once you
understand that and you've practiced for
at least a month then you have my
permission to go into including for
majors in a cross and then start looking
like that and you'll see that there is a
set up every single trading day but it's
not my invitation or my goal to inspire
you to try to trade every single day
don't do that my hope is that you learn
to find one or two trades like this per
week and then force yourself to be
disciplined did not trade any more
because every time you trade you're
opening the invitation to lose money and
the closer you get to Friday's close
with a losing position it's just gonna
make your mister make you miserable over
the weekend and it's nothing worse than
having made money in the beginning a
week or sometimes during the week and
then go in one more time and lose it
going in the weekend it's frustrating
I've done it many many times over the
last two decades you don't want to do
that it's avoidable once you make money
in your demo account okay I'm not
promising you make them live funds that
could because I'm not licensed to do
that but I'm teaching you how to
practice in a demo account that's all
I'm doing here if you use this
information and a live account it's on
you win or lose 100% of the
responsibility is on you okay so in this
hourly chart we are looking at two
timeframes the daily which gives us our
bias as I'll indicate and the hourly
what sets up where the markets going to
most likely reach for for the draw okay
that's what it look what it pull is so
if we're bullish again we're looking for
an old high to run to that's it very
simple strategy nothing more than that
okay so now we're looking at a daily
chart and I want you to look at the
patterns I have here because it's gonna
be very important to understand what
these are because it's gonna give us the
context to define when the market should
be bullish and when it should be bearish
over here in the left-hand corner this
is a swing low and this is a crude
depiction I didn't add any color because
I just want you to think about the
overall pattern itself now either any
one of these three candles can be up or
down close in nature in other words it
can be a bullish candle or a bearish
candle all three of these it does not
matter okay all we're looking for is the
generic formation of these three candles
okay one having the lowest low and a
higher load to the left and higher low
to the right it's only three candles or
three bars needed to find this pattern
okay if you look at Mt 4 there's a
little indicator you can click on it's
called a fractal and I really wish they
would have never named that and it's a
Bill Williams thing I'm not a fan of
Bill Williams material I'm not trying to
be disrespectful but what I'm teaching
you is what I learned from my mentor
Larry Williams
I think he's proven himself he's made
millions of dollars and it's documented
you know he's took 10,000 to over 1
million dollars in 12 months and you can
see that on the rapid trading contest
website you can see he's no one's even
come close to his his record but his
approach to teaching market structure
starts with this simple concept of a
swing high and swing low so when we see
a swing low it's three bars or three
candles okay once that forms what we in
the old days will call that would be a
ring low okay because we didn't have
charge we had to really just write that
down on a notebook and the lowest of the
three candles or the lowest in recent
week or the month we would we would put
a circle around that that number okay on
our little binder and that's the way it
was it was it was like that in old days
so we would know that that wasn't
important well why because it had a
higher load to the right of it and the
higher load to the left of it okay so
when we see this formation on a daily
chart okay what we're looking for is
this to occur after this is important
you need to anticipate this forming
after a swing high has been broken
now probably just took a huge leap
forward and probably lost a few of you
so let me say it again we are only
really interested in looking for daily
swing lows after a swing high which is a
high that has two lower highs on either
side of it okay in other words we've got
one daily candle or bar with yesterday
or the previous day's high being lower
than today's and then tomorrow's day
should have a lower high okay so notes
this is what we're seeing a three bar
pattern you wait for this to occur in
the price action and if price trades
through the swing high you are now on
bullish alert you wait for the swing low
the form what you have done is you've
waited for institutions to get back in
line with the momentum on a short-term
basis and the algorithm once it creates
that swing low again after the swing
high has been broken momentum is now
bullish and you're waiting for this
short-term pattern here when that
happens your focus is going to go
immediately to the high of this number
three candle and I mean I mean I mean
number of these candles so that way we
can track it and know what we're looking
at so this is for directional bias these
candles now have numbers on them and
it's always moving left to right
number one candle number two cannon
number three candle what we're doing is
we're watching once the daily swing low
forms we want to see the high be traded
through one day number four okay once
day number four does that we know that
day number five we can be looking for a
run on previous day's high liquidity you
can be aggressive
once this formation occurs if we open
below number three's high you say Noren
Doren London or New York if we're below
that low if we have a condition that
presents an optimal trade entry you can
go along and look for a run on number 3s
high for run on liquidity above number
threes by stops that's a little
aggressive and I'll give you rules to do
that in volume number three but tonight
I want to keep it very simple and very
very Elementary
so as a recap what we want to do is we
want to see a swing high this formation
form and we see that here okay we see a
swing high it has a lower high to the
left of it a lower high to the right of
it and we want to see it trade through
that high it does it here right here on
this large wick candle when that happens
we start looking for this formation on
the daily chart
it happens right here okay we have a
long whipped candle it has a higher load
to the left of it a higher load to the
right of it and the very next day we
want to be looking for runs on previous
day's highs for a resistance of previous
day's high it's going to give them in
the retail world the false sense of
security that the previous day's high is
gonna stop price and it's not going to
so we can see how markets that have this
condition have a tendency to
continuously move higher each day look
at how the previous day's high is
violated to some degree okay and then
when we get these inside days and I'll
talk about that and volume to inside
days are going to be important but not
so important for the first of all you
might just want to understand the basic
premise on how we get the directional
bias and why the swing highs and swing
lows are important so each previous
day's high is taken to some degree every
day has a varying amount of pips and
again I'm not trying to promote the idea
of knowing exactly how many pips you
next week's gonna have or three days
from now it's not important there
there'll be tools and things that you
learn in volume 3 to help you get to
that but for now just be content with
learning the general rules of how to
determine whether the market is bullish
or bearish if you do this okay this is
not mentorship level bias but it is a
real quick down and dirty approach and
this is actually how I learned it the
first time in terms of finding basically
daily momentum it's all of this and it
doesn't require you to have any kind of
momentum indicator to do it no moving
average and none of that stuff okay you
can read it just from price so again
simple rules are we want to see a swing
high broken to the upside okay we see it
here with this swing high so now we have
momentum on the bullishness pulls back
wait for a swing low deform that's this
pattern here and then we start watching
number 3s high okay we want to see
number 3s high be violated in this case
here we see it violate right there with
this kind of like of a indecisive candle
and in the very night
today we see what it opens it trades
down and then blasts off through the
previous day's high now when you have
that type of move it can happen the
following day and it does it opens okay
and trades above the high a little bit
that in itself as a scalp there's
nothing wrong with that little bit of a
move but I want you to focus on finding
one good set up so if we have a move
like this chances are I would probably
look at another pair only because I
understand the conditions and I know the
set up so it may have burnt itself out
on one pair which I see if it's a big
move if it's just a marginal move then
they'll probably seek follow-through on
the next day and maybe the next day
after that so we have it again here it
opens okay trades down a little bit and
goes higher running out the previous
day's high again and again that's the
trade that's all is it's a scalp we are
not trying to get the weekly low at this
we're not trying to get the daily low
and holding to the close all we're doing
is looking for an opportunity to run a
previous day's high or a high from two
days ago that's the context that's the
premise behind the system that's the
method okay why does this work I'm sure
you probably asking yourself when you
know why is this why this does have any
validity to it when bank level traders
are working they are trying to turn over
liquidity okay and what I just taught
you is the draw
okay the draw is previous highs and
previous lows referencing daily highs
and lows banks target those liquidity
pools more than anything else in forex
don't take my word for it go through
your charts and you'll see that's
exactly what goes on when you have
things that are bearish okay we're just
you know flip the script for a minute we
want to see price trade below a swing
low once that occurs then we start
waiting for a swing high to form why are
we doing that because we're waiting for
a retracement it's gonna go to an
overbought condition we don't need any
critters to do that or derive that
information when we have this short term
high here or swing high form we start
watching the daily candle number three
and we want to see it trade through that
low if it does we know that we are in
bear territory and we're probably going
to see each previous day's low be
violated and that's the setup
that's condition and that's an it's seen
here okay we see a swing low broken here
and then we wait for a swing high to
form that's here we have a high with a
lower high to the left of it a lower
high to the right of it we wait for this
number three candles low to be taken out
it does it here so now what we do is we
target a run on this candles low
it opens trades up creates the high
today and slams them okay that's it
that's the setup it doesn't doesn't have
a whole lot of sexiness to it but I'm
telling you right now it's got a whole
lot of consistency to it and a lot of
you probably don't have any consistency
whatsoever or what you're looking for
and this is a very easy bread-and-butter
approach now again I am NOT trying to
package this in a every day approach for
one individual pair this works in stocks
it works in futures it works in bonds it
works in just about anything they can
trade so when we have this momentum on a
daily chart and we know we're either
bullish or bearish it stays that way
until we get a break in opposing market
momentum I'll give you an example what
that would look like here we have a
swing low form and then price comes down
and breaks that swing low that upsets
the momentum at this point we have to
see a short-term high be broken okay a
short
hi has to be broken and then we have it
here we have a high with a lower high
and a lower high to the right of it it's
broken to the upside here so when we
have that now we go back into cycle of
looking for a swing low swing low forms
here we have a candle to the left of it
that's high or low below in the middle
and the next candle is up so we want to
see price trade through number three
candles hi it does in fact do it here
and we trade through the next day
running the previous day's high and it
continues that cycle again okay so all
we're doing is monitoring a break in the
swing highs and swing lows giving us a
bias on the daily chart why am I looking
forward on a daily chart because
momentum that begins when the daily
chart tends to occur and be lasting for
at least a few days it could be two to
five days in duration so if we have a
mentum working one side higher or lower
it tends to stay in that direction for a
period of a few days and that's all you
need to have a really good scenario for
short term trading intraday scalps
so again in summary when we're looking
for the swing low this is only being
stalked or looked for in price action
until we see a short term swing high
being broken when that happens then we
start looking for this pattern okay for
daily swing highs this only is being
hunted or stalked in price action after
a swing low has been broken
that gives us a break in market
structures but it's basically giving us
a definition of and then afterwards it's
going to be a retracement and when we
see that retracement occur with a swing
high we know that we can start looking
for sells running out previous day's
lows when we see the swing high broken
and we find a swing low form later on we
know we can look for kendall number 3s
highs to be rated and look for the buy
stops to be ran out or intraday scalp
that's a very very simple approach is
very easy and if you're not
understanding it just watch this video
again I promise you you're probably over
complicating it and it's not necessary
so I'm going to focus our attention on
this little segment of price action here
in the shaded area and we're actually
gonna walk through on a narrow a chart
and look at the framework of each one of
these respective days and how it targets
liquidity runs on previous day's highs
okay folks we're looking at the a lay
chart at the beginning of that shaded
area to show it on a daily chart for us
CAD and I want you to just see these
lines down here okay these are just
delineating the ICT kills them and the
red area is delineating specifically
aiming at around two o'clock in the
morning to four o'clock in the morning
New York time everything I say in terms
of time you're gonna have to translate
that into your local time relative to
New York time okay so if I say two
o'clock in the morning New York time
wherever you're at globally just get
yourself a clock set to New York time
and then look at that time in reference
to your local time and you'll be able to
decipher what it is you have to do and
make the adjustments I do not want to
get into conversation about time because
it's very confusing for me admittedly
I've done this many times in the past
and
erroneously said something and confused
a reader or viewer so it's better for
you to just do the work in transferring
and converting your local time into New
York time okay so London is basically
two o'clock to four o'clock in the
morning that's the sweet spot or the
best time to anticipate a higher load of
form and the New York is going to be
seven o'clock in the morning to ten
o'clock in the morning we'll just give
you a nice little one day like that it
can be refined and defined in my
tutorials but for now just for the sake
of this method just use those times all
right so we have our beginning of our
shaded area when we're looking for
bullishness as defined in the first part
of this presentation and I want you to
look at how price moves running out
previous day's highs okay and here's a
previous day's high right here and I'm
going to try to do this as as quick as I
possibly can
and keep things moving along but the
a high on this particular day here you
can see one to start of this candle here
it starts and immediately runs through a
little bit doesn't go by much but then
it eventually trades through it here
that in itself this little move here
that's actually a trade it doesn't seem
like much it doesn't feel like much but
that's a trade now you're probably
because your eyes looking at in the
benefit of hindsight you're gonna look
at this high and this move down and say
well that's what I really want to
capture if you're going to think like
that about everything I'm going to show
you in these tutorials I'm not gonna be
any help to you okay because what you're
gonna be doing is trying to have
perfection and I can't promise and I
don't promise perfection at all I do
provide you resources that's going to
help you get better at your price action
analysis and that's the only thing I
promise okay
so we have a low here and a daily high
and the expectation is we want to see
the high be ran out we want to see the
the expectation of moving through this
high why because there's going to be
liquidity a bit above that high why I'm
not going into it here just trust me
the banks make runs on previous day's
highs and lows and if it's bullish
they're gonna be targeting previous
day's high okay so the way we frame our
setups is we use our FID and we find the
lowest bodied fortunately the candle
that's going to be this open here and we
drag that up to here okay why he just
jumped off the level I wanted to have it
on sorry
you
I want on this candle right here because
it's gonna be the highest body before
this little retracement okay and at this
point we're gonna be anticipating
because it only this briefly violated
the previous day's high we want to see a
retracement our mind is waiting for it
to trade lower okay once it trades lower
we're going to looking forward to go
down into the optimal trade entry okay
that's our price pattern it doesn't do
it until after this little movement up
now on a smaller time frame we could
probably see something in here that's an
optimal trade entry but I'm going to
save that for volume too but in here I'm
giving you the big setups for your scalp
setup okay so using the our chart we're
gonna see it here and we're gonna be
targeting previous day's high now even
this day when it trades down to here we
could be targeting a run back to
previous day's high and now what have we
included
we have a higher high here in the same
day so intraday we have a higher high
and we have previous day's high both of
these conditions are candidates for run
on liquidity
okay so we have this one and we have
this one so as price trades down here we
want to anticipate a movement higher to
run to this level which it does here and
eventually back to this high here which
it doesn't do until this candle here
notice that price trades down in the
bodies of the candles respect the 79%
race own level okay
back up to this high this is why I say
you want to take profit okay at old
highs and at your first scaling here
this is target one you can take profit
there notice it never takes the high out
yet has to retrace all the way back down
to precisely the seven times it hurts me
again then rallies through taking out
intraday high previous day's high and
again two days ago okay
this is your run on previous day's high
liquidity now this candle on a daily
basis its high is here
same scenario in here it rallies up
takes out that high which again we're
gonna have to see that on a lower
timeframe we're not going to do it in
this volume but as it runs through we
want to see a retracement okay we have
the bodies of this run here why am i
using this one because it's the most
dynamic recent rally and we want to use
it on the highest body open or close
which is here price trades down into the
sixty two percent recent level right in
here we're do be targeting previous
day's high which is here and we also now
we have an intraday high here so we have
two reference points to look for so
we're anticipate the banks making a run
on both of those levels they initially
it's this one okay so on the next day it
trades back down again giving you
another opportunity to go long if you
were trading here you're outside of the
kill zone okay I want you to notice that
every time that we create signal and
setup if it overlaps with one of these
colored levels okay or lines that makes
it high probability if it's outside of
one of those shaded time windows it's
less favorable it doesn't mean it can't
eventually move to profitability and
your demo it just means that it's far
more likely to occur if it's occurring
during one of these shaded time windows
okay so
and again the blue one here is the New
York kill zone and the red one is London
so we have a setup here it trades back
down into optimal trade entry here and
it does so at the time of New York
okay so New York and London both have an
opportunity to create a buying
opportunity London will give it to you
that you probably got stopped out same
scenario unfolds for New York New York
explodes runs through previous type days
high of two days before and previous
day's high here runs right through it
that's the trade and it's over it's done
there's nothing else to consider there's
nothing else to worry about the trade is
over okay so now in here we've had a
couple examples nice little payouts not
barnburners not Grand Slams
but bread-and-butter setups just using
one pair in the course upside inside of
a week we have nice little setups and
it's given us a really good opportunity
to target a logical level which is the
previous day's high and under the
context of a retracement to a logical
level which is the FIB using a framework
of
bodies
two bodies in terms of the swing highs
and swing lows and also as a quick note
habits in your notepad easy way to go
for what swing high and what swing low I
draw my fit from I use session highs and
session lows so whatever the highest
high and low was during London and or
New York I used those reference points
and then I just used a body's either the
open or closed whichever is the lowest
for the low point of the fifth and the
high point is whatever the highest is
open or the close inside of the high
okay and that's all there is to it each
each new day you're waiting for an
opportunity for it to retrace back down
into what would be otherwise standard
optimal trade entry which is a 62
percent 70 percent trade level but
targeting previous day's highs now
notice once we hit this previous day's
high here the mark goes into some of a
of a consolidation now we do get a
little bit of a run here but not to the
degree where we can really brag about or
go to great lengths to justify it we do
have a nice retracement here okay and I
want you to take a look at that because
when we have a retracement of a day or
so that usually puts the cycle back in
rotation so we have a retracement here
price comes back down to the 70.5 level
which is a sweet spot o te okay and it's
happening at the time of New York so
that's a good scenario we could see a
buy there but look it rolls over into
the next day in London it hits it again
so your stop would never been hit but
you're holding on for a long period of
time so this is where it's gonna stretch
your patience as a scalper which is the
reason why I like being short trying
because I know these are the conditions
it's most likely gonna happen hits the
62% shape 62 percent retracement level
rather and once it hits that in London
then it explodes what's it reaching for
previous day's high it runs through that
with no resistance whatsoever and blows
through previous day's high back here
okay so really nice little opportunity
there and whenever you see a full day's
down close that's like a big red neon
sign say start following me especially
if you're in a bullish scenario
that markets primed to have an optimal
trade entry long and start running out
previous day's highs
okay on this one particular day here
price moves 3050 almost 70 pips or so
okay really really quickly and this is
all mostly inside of one hour big
explosive price move here and that was
seen on October 5th and this continues
on going through price action and when
we have scenarios that present
themselves with the highest form of
probability and not seeing any breakdown
on a daily chart it gives us framework
context and specifics about what we're
looking for when we're looking for it
kill zone
what price level Osmel trade entry what
are we targeting previous day's highs or
the day before it so yesterday's high or
the day before yesterday's high that's
what we're targeting more bullish very
very simple approach nothing more to it
than that
I'll amplify it in volume 2 and I'll
wrap it up with concise more or less a
trading plan in volume 30 hopefully you
found this insightful until next time we
should good luck and good trading