welcome back folks this is
lesson five of january 2017 ict
mentorship
i'm going to be discussing money
management and higher time frame
analysis
okay we're going to be just talking
about
a broad brush
perspective on this
view of trading in other words long term
analysis
we're going to assume for a moment that
uh everyone that's learning the concepts
from january
is
contemplating
uh the
medium of long-term trading or position
trading now that may not be your cup of
tea that may not be the
disciplinary trading that you are going
to adopt as your career
but i would advise you to at least
work in this time frame a little while
at least try to work it at least for a
year
and the reason why i say that is because
some of you
may not be
contemplating managed funds
in other words managing other people's
money or working for a firm maybe
working for a prop firm
and
while you may not have a large equity
base to start with
um it's not important now
but what is important is growing your
understanding over a long period of time
and when that means getting experience
in the marketplace
there's no better experience than
actually applying the things that you
practice in a demo account with positive
results and then segwaying into a
live setting where you're using live
funds
it's not important you have a big
account
because what you're focusing on is the
control over drawdown keeping it
manageable keeping it tolerable with a
tolerable level of drawdown i think i'd
say about uh 15
annually is a realistic objective um
most folks would uh
would start to cringe over 25 or so um
but if you can
control your draw down to around
15 as a maximum that's absolutely
amazing uh but 20s it's probably okay
and if you can still maintain a
positive
outcome for
the annual return
but
thinking about managed funds i want you
to think about the
possibility that while you may be
thinking about only managing your own
individual assets and moving your uh
your wealth forward
independently apart from using anybody
else's money
for some of you that may not be the case
maybe
you came into this mentorship with every
expectation of learning to do that very
thing
well it starts here you have to have a
realistic expectation coming in
and knowing that you don't need a whole
lot of money
if you can show a consistent equity
curve that's improving very little
drawdown very very
infrequent uh erratic or slow periods in
your trading uh that is very good for uh
for investors when they see things like
that
um and it doesn't have to be high rates
of return
but having a steady increase of over a
calendar year
that really attracts investors uh
there's you have no idea how much money
is sitting out there just waiting for
people to say hey look you know i'll
take that money and control it for you
and turn a profit
now you also don't need to use the
entire equity base that you start with
um many times ten thousand dollar
trading account and they assume that
they have to
maximize every possible dollar in that
account to get a respectable rate of
return and i don't teach that i actually
have a very conservative approach
when i'm trading
my view is i don't want to
allocate every possible dollar
to the marketplace what i do is i limit
my allocation to only 30 of my total
equity
that may be shocking to some of you but
it's the truth so let's say for instance
i have a hundred thousand dollar trading
account
or let's say you have a hypothetical one
hundred thousand dollar trading account
that means i'm gonna be using thirty
thousand dollars to meet whatever margin
requirements or trade
parameters that i use
for that trading
in other words if i'm going to be doing
a percentage basis of my equity
and let's just say for instance that i'm
going to be
using this standard in the industry of 2
that means i'm gonna be using two
percent of thirty thousand not two
percent
of one hundred thousand
and the reason why that's done is
because i'm never going to have to worry
about
margin calls i'm never going to be over
leveraged i'm never going to have
uh wild dips in my equity but i can
still manage to
carve out a very nice equity curve even
just using 30 of my equity
investors like to see that they like to
see that you're not 100 exposed they
like to see that
you know
having a a good reserve of cash
in the account
that way you always have opportunities
that you can still take
that if they're really too good to pass
on you have never extended yourself too
much and spread yourself too thin so
that we always have an opportunity to
take something that may otherwise not
have been
on your radar screen something comes up
in the chart something comes up as a
an opportunity you always have equity at
your disposal to take advantage of that
that move
so what you're doing again is you're
determining your maximum risk exposure
and a percentage basis on 30 percent of
your equity
so you're really really really drawn
down in terms of risk you're not
maximizing the risk for maximum return
you're looking for a very low end risk
exposure
with the expectation that you're going
to have consistently
pulling in
percents of return that are respectable
over a calendar year
again you're ideally set one percent
as the most risk per trade
that means
one percent of 30 percent of your total
equity base
okay so you have 10 000
in your account
and you're going to be using 30 of your
account that means your account
trading is going to be based on three
thousand dollars
not ten thousand dollars over leveraged
not looking for the maximum return
you're looking at only using three
thousand dollars for your trading
account to be meeting those margin
requirements for your trades
one percent of that is going to be 30
so 30 is your total maximum risk per
trade and i already know what some of
you are thinking michael i can't get
rich doing this
and that's right you're not going to get
rich
right now you're not going to get rich
tomorrow or next month but you're not
thinking like that right now i want you
to consider and i'm not trying to force
you into managed funds but i'm trying to
broaden your perspectives okay on a lot
of things
and allow yourself the opportunity to
even
just
think about the possibility and again i
personally know from experience it's not
fun
to manage other people's money it's for
me it's very stressful
but for some of you it may be exactly
what you'll need to get over that hump
and you can make a lot of money managing
other people's money rather quickly and
then you can take that money and seed
your own investing and then you can do
your own speculation how you'd like to
do it and if you want to take a little
bit more risk on not that you should but
you can do that in that medium where you
get other people's money to pay you
fill your account up with funds not out
of your own pocket you can independently
trade apart from other people's money
and then you can close shop on trading
other people's money and just focus
primarily on yourself
let me target three to one reward to
risk or higher setups
now again some of you are again totally
completely turned off to actually
trading a lot higher time frames but
for some of you this is going to be
perfectly designed for you it's going to
be your cup of tea if you will
there's still three to one setups that
are offered on these higher time frames
charts and that's what you're going to
be focusing on
now having low risk high reward permits
very very low accuracy
you don't have to be accurate all the
time
but
you do have to be patient on this time
frame
and the other benefit is low risk allows
equity
for more setups
so numbers you're going to see more
possible trade setups by not having
all your money in one trade
okay expectations
again you want to be focusing on a
hands-on annual percent return now what
is this
what's an annual return that's
respectable
um i think
to 25 a year which is like an industry
standard for managed funds if you could
do that every single year
i can promise you you will never have a
shortage of people that will want to
hand you money
and manage their money for them
now
as we get deeper into this mentorship
i'll actually tell you how you can
well up
other people's money
and reach out to other people through
different mediums
and build business
relationships with folks that would want
to do that type of thing
again it's something that you'll have to
make the decision on
your own
but
using higher time frame analysis like
this i want you to go forward from this
point on
and contemplate taking long-term trades
once we complete january's content i
want you to think about
operating at least for
the remainder of this mentorship for
next eight months or so you want to be
uh you want to be focused on doing that
very thing looking for hard time frame
trades and letting them
pan out don't try to get in there and
take a little bit of the marketplace and
move to the sidelines real quick
and remember
when you're managing money with higher
time frame trades
there's very little in terms of
frequency with higher time frame setups
so long-term setups form very
infrequently annually so there's not a
whole lot of trades throughout the year
on a hard time frame charts
when you're trading this higher time
frame you're going to have to learn to
allow short term drawdowns in profits
that means
that while you're in these long-term
trades and they pan out because many
times you're going to see that there's
going to be retracements
that you're going to have to weather
you're going to sit through several days
maybe a week or two where the market has
actually given back some of your open
profits okay they're not realized
profits until you close the trade
so by allowing that mindset early on
saying that okay i know that there's
going to be
some give and take in these trades
sometimes
over a period of time when you start
trading larger
this give and take can be rather
large it could be you know emotionally
charging if you've seen tens of
thousands of dollars coming in and out
of your account over the course of
several weeks if you're not used to that
actually makes uh it makes it hard for
you to think about being objective about
the trade
so the reason why i also talk about only
using 30 of your equity getting back to
that i know some of you probably
snickered and said there's no way i'd be
doing that
but by having your account only
allocating 30 towards long-term trades
that gives you equity and margin to
trade short-term trades so that way
while we cannot in the u.s trade
like a hedger in other words we can't
hedge our trades
we can trade markets that are closely
correlated or inversely correlated
dollar yen
if your short position long term
starts to have and you can anticipate
these types of things when it starts to
have a retracement against your short
position
you're going to give back some of that
open profit or paper profit before you
realize it and close it and
move that profit into your account
that give and take on your p l is going
to be
bothersome for some of you most of you
in fact so the way you can counteract
that is if you're going to be a
long-term trader or position trader
if you're short on dollar yen
if there's an opportunity for seeing a
bounce in your short position on dollar
yen you can actually go in
and trade the euro dollar
it's an inverse related pair and you
would do the opposite
whatever you're seeing uh retraced in
the dollar yen you would trade the
opposite in euro dollar so if you're
getting retracement higher on a short
position on dollar yen
you can actually go short euro dollar or
maybe british pound dollar
and capitalize some more money
in the marketplace while your long-term
position is in somewhat of a drawdown
and you're giving back some profits
you can actually hedge that by trading
other pairs that are inversely related
so that's one way you can beat the
north american hedging rule but you just
have to understand simple
inter-market analysis
which we just covered
in previous lesson
so having
an understanding that they're going to
be a give and take you're going to have
to have that in the forefront of your
mind saying okay either i'm going to
trade
shorter term
swing trades or short term trades to
allow myself to
compensate for the drawdown in open
profits on my long-term trades and then
when that retracement takes shape and
comes to completion when your long-term
trade then it starts to resume
you're back in there and you've made
more money once you get back to that
old equity high in your long term
position so you're able to continuously
make more money
and also cover those draw down periods
on open profits on your long term trades
now stop-loss orders are not a measure
of ability now
obviously you know most of us in this
mentorship are predominantly male and
males have a tendency to like to pull
out the measuring stick
and see how they measure up against the
next guy or how they measure up against
you
stop loss orders for whatever reason has
over the ages okay of a technical
analysis
it's become a way of knowing how good
you are and if you can trade with a
10-pip stop-loss you must be elite
that doesn't belong in any way shape or
form in long-term trading
long-term trading
it's not it's you don't limit your your
trade idea or opportunity based on a set
number of pips like intraday trading i
like to have about 35 maximum that's
about a safe safe number for me
30 pips is a general rule of thumb but
about 35 pips is about
the number one go-to number for me
because generally if it's 100
pip daily range average adr
not that everyone is or that it
maintains 100 average
but
a third of that would be 33 so i rounded
to 35 pips and that gives me a a real
good round number to go for
but you can use what i've always said
before about 30 pips
but on long term trades uh 30 pips just
isn't going to do it sometimes
especially if you're only trading off up
and keying off of the daily time frame
so if your daily chart is your
executable time frame which is what
you'd be using if you're trading with a
monthly and weekly chart and you can't
use intraday charting because of your
business or your your home life doesn't
permit you to be up or in front of the
charts or you just have a job i mean
let's just face it some of you in here
they have jobs and there's nothing wrong
with that i came from a world where i
had to go to work too but
you have to understand that your stops
are going to have to be
proportionate to the time frame you're
trading in
which leads us to the next point here
now you know when you're trading a trade
that has a setup that requires a 200 pip
stop loss on it that means you're
risking 200 pips for some of you that's
mind-boggling there's no way that you're
gonna permit yourself to risk 200 pips
of price movement against you
because you're so used to and ingrained
in looking at those lower time frames
but just because it's a 200 pip stop
loss on a setup on a daily time frame
assume for a moment that you're aiming
for a 600 pip win
that's still a three to one reward to
risk
ratio there's nothing wrong with that
you're still gearing the same way you
would
you know to be in line with a very low
objective in terms of win rate you can
still do very well with that gearing and
obviously that's the minimum so you want
to be looking for higher
levels of reward to risk ratios on these
higher time frame charts
okay and then another thing you want to
think about when you're managing your
money trading with these higher time
frames is
resist the impulse to move your stop
loss to break even or even reducing the
risk
on a lot higher time frame long-term
position trading you're going to have to
suppress that desire to reduce risk
right away
position trading requires a great deal
of patience and unfortunately there's no
way of forming that for most of you you
either have it or you grind it out and
you develop it over a long period of
time it just doesn't happen overnight so
if you don't have a whole lot of time
to develop patients
position trading is probably not going
to be for you okay and that's one of
those things you're just gonna have to
live with um
if you need to be in front of the
markets a little bit more and you're
trading these lower time frames then
obviously we can move our stop loss
sooner to break even and lock in profit
on these lower time frames higher time
frame just forget that all together
because you want to be waiting
for the market to really be moving a
significant measure of
pips before you even consider moving
that stop loss from the initial point at
which you
enter the trade
you're gonna have to learn to exit at
logical targets and
look to re-enter at a later time
we can take positions off at logical
areas of resistance when we're in a
long-term trend
and instead of sitting through a measure
of draw down on our p l what we would be
doing is actually exiting the position
or maybe some of the position and we'll
talk about this when we go into trade
management we're actually going to
specifics this teaching here is just to
get your mind thinking about some of the
things that's going to plague you as a
long-term position trader
but you know if you're looking at a
long-term trade and you're bullish on
for instance the dollar yen
and you get to a level where you would
reasonably in with high probability
expect some resistance or some
retracement um
you may take some of your position off
you may take half your position off you
may take three quarters your position
off a third of your position off you
know uh you know one quarter of your uh
position off
and allow that to you know
be in your account as a profit and then
once it retraces back to a level where
it would be logically timed to see
another uh move higher in your long-term
trade then you can add back that
position or maybe a little bit more than
what you profited
when you can't when you took off a
quarter maybe you'll put back on
a third maybe you'll put back on um
a little bit more than a quarter okay or
you'll just put back that original
quarter you you took off
for some partial profits and then you
can add it back and you can get a larger
position built on
and see that next lake price
higher where you would make more money
than you would have if you just would
have kept the original gearing and entry
point at the
point of entry
and finally long term is not get rich
quick but get rich steady
so before you go into
the next series of teachings
and where we actually go into a little
more detail about what it is you're
actually doing with long-term position
trading
just know that
you are not going to see velocity
for your money trading these higher time
frames it just isn't there now velocity
is how fast you put your money at work
and it makes a profit for you and you
get it right back right away that's
velocity that's why i like day trading
because i can compound my money very
quickly
some of you cannot do that and don't
feel that you can't be profitable
because you can't do that disciplinary
trading so therefore you can't be
profitable that's not true
you can make very very handsome returns
on just long-term position trading
but it has to fit your psyche it has to
fit your in inner trader that person
inside you that makes who you are as a
trader it has to
fit that that criteria of that inner
person because if it's at odds with your
thinking process
you can't no matter how you slice it
it's going to be at odds with you you're
not going to be able to sit through the
trades you're going to force things
because you're impatiently waiting for
something to come to fruition
and it's just going to be a problem so
the money management aspect will become
harder for you
if you can't get yourself in alignment
but every one of you in the mentorship
should be trying to apply long-term
position trading
to some degree
for the remaining portion of this
mentorship
and you'll see how you don't really need
a whole lot of
skill in terms of entry technique okay
the entry technique you're actually
going to learn is rather simplistic
and some of you will practice probably
start using it a lot more frequent than
i do if i was long-term position trading
but for long-term position trading this
you know it's the style
of entry that i use and when we get into
all the entry techniques and concepts
you'll learn it there
but
before we get into trade entry and stop
loss orders and you know how much money
should i risk and all that business
you have to have some broad brush ideas
about money management and
that was the core
point of this teaching because i want
you to have the mindset going into it
with
yes you're managing money no it's not
going to be a whole lot of trades it's
not going to allow you to parlay that
account quickly and it's a pretty common
sense but
some of you are so new and you're
naive to the fact that these time frames
require a great deal time
and by having that submission to time
it will allow you to number one improve
your overall analysis because what you
see on these higher time frames
that's what directs the lower time frame
to move as they do
but your objective if you're going to be
a managed fund trader and you're going
to be trading other people's money
opm as they call it other people's money
that uh
that career is very lucrative
especially if you are consistent with
your rate of return and if you can
consistently pull 20 or 25
every single year
and you're only doing a handful of
trades now think about this
we've already mentioned that there's
very little trades going on on this
higher time frame so if you have every
three months there's a there's a
potential trade that could theoretically
form every three months it doesn't work
like that though folks
i would i look personally for two and if
i'm lucky three
good position trade setups a year
so that means over the course of january
to the end of december you're probably
going to see two very s very simple easy
to find long-term trade setups
maybe if you're lucky and you're really
dialed in and the market's really
working well and it's very symmetrical
you may see a third set up for the year
generally
rarely have i seen four setups in in a
full january december where i've
actually been able to participate in it
so
unless you get you know to the degree
where you know you're able to see it
better than i and it's the goal here
also you want to be better than ict
and also the market
profile for that calendar year is just
so
conducive for a
four move
set up where you have every three months
or so you have a quarterly shift
that would be
you know
that that'd be great for you but just
know going in the expectation should be
it's not going to most likely be there
for you okay so we're focusing primarily
on two really good setups a year and
really milking those positions and if
we're lucky we'll get a third okay and
you're probably doing the math on this
and thinking okay well if i just did
three to one and i'm risking one percent
the best i can make is
three percent on each one
okay grant yes i agree and if you get
two
that means you're only making six
percent right
that's correct
but you're also only risking one percent
per trade so that means if you have a
setup that's
moved into profitability now you have
new equity
so that equity can be put to work as
well so on new trade setups and just
because you missed the lowest possible
buy for a long term long position
doesn't mean you can't get into the
position in that long-term trend
with a long-term mindset
and still make more percent return and
we'll talk about that when we get into
execution and trade management so don't
think you're just going to make well i
could only make about um
if there's only two a year and the best
i can make is three percent return that
means i'm going to make six percent for
the year that's not attractive michael
that's only if you're taking one setup
now if you take
two trades
and your maximum exposure is going to be
at two percent and you change the rules
here then obviously that gives you a
little bit more leeway but
it's not
it's not meant for you to go in trying
to maximize how much you can earn what
your goal is is how much can you
manage
in terms of
drawdown keeping it low
and still carve out a rate of return
over the full calendar year
that's the goal that's the homework for
the rest of this mentorship you want to
have
at least
one long-term trade where you were able
to execute on
and hold it through a long period of
time at least three months so if you can
do that
you'll have what it is what i personally
believe that it takes to take put it to
work where you can turn a profit over a
whole calendar year now if you're going
to manage other people's money
okay and you become better at your
trading you understand what you're doing
and you're risking two percent of thirty
percent of the total equity
if you make two percent
your total maximum risk
per trade
and you have
several
opportunities throughout the year where
you can take the position then you
should short term trade or swing trade
any drawdown periods you can maximize
that you can very easily get to that 18
to 20 rated return on equity for the
year
you're not going to be doing a whole lot
of trades you won't be forced to be in
front of the marketplace every single
trading day
you're actually going to be very
free with your personal time
that's the reason why large fund
managers are always on vacation
they're always doing that because
they're not trading every single day the
idea is that you want to put other
people's money at work for you
but under the guys that you're doing it
they're you're doing them a favor rather
but really what you're doing is you're
trying to do as very little as possible
because you the more times you take a
trade with other people's money
the more times you're exposing them to
risk
when you expose a client to risk enough
times eventually that risk will grow
teeth and bite you
now you're going to feel it emotionally
and psychologically and monetarily
the client is going to feel it
monetarily and they're going to be mad
they're going to be upset especially if
that drawdown continues for a long
period of time it eats and erodes into
what their equity base was when they
allowed it to you
so if
you can keep your frequency low and
focus on very
high odds potential setups and keep the
risk light
and carve out that rate of return 18 to
20 percent per year
people will dog pile on you throwing new
money at you
and as you have a management fee
all the
percentage
bonuses that you would establish and set
up when you make your prospectus and you
sit down with clients
all those things
are in your favor
the client would be making money too
obviously as a result
but you're not working yourself too hard
to get that that money for them
and therefore because it's going to be a
large degree of money hopefully a pooled
account where you're having other people
pull money into it not just you and one
client you want to work with a fund
level that has a ability to bring other
people's money in and when you do that
it builds that equity base a lot larger
so that way if you're making a 25 rate
of return on say 10 million dollars now
we're talking of something about a
little bit more significant and then if
you have a two percent management fee on
top of that
you're getting two percent management
fee regardless of what you make and then
you get a performance bonus that you
would set up
all that goes into your pocket so yes
in your mind you're probably thinking i
want to push it to the limit and get a
better performance incentive you know in
terms of paying myself
but that's not what your goal should be
you should be having a steady eddy
approach
only aiming for that easy low hanging
fruit the clients will absolutely love
you they're going to talk about their
their their fund manager you every time
they go out they're all going to be
asking you know who is he can you can
you talk to him for me and new funds
will always find their way to you
so your account
that you manage would continuously be
growing
allowing new funds to you come in and
that just by default keeps pushing your
pay every single time this happens your
pay goes up
so it's not about how much money you
have right now
it's how you can manage money
right now and going forward and the goal
is not to see a lot of drawdown drawdown
happens by way of a lot of action
because no matter what it's a numbers
game you can be good all day long okay
but you if you play the game enough you
get up the bat
enough times you're going to strike out
when you deal with other people's money
and you're managing that money you do
not want to have a big long drawn out
strikeout period you don't want that
they want to see
consistency and if you're consistently
infrequent with risk exposure
but you're showing rate of return that's
handsome over the calendar year they
will love you
and love in the form of managed funds is
money
lots of money it comes by way of new
funds they put more money into your
hands because they've seen that you've
proven yourself
a lot of folks will test you out and
i'll put a small amount of money okay
i'll see what you do with this and if
you show consistency and a rate of
return it's
very
sobering and it's not over the top
you're not trying to swing for fences
managing this money
okay will invite and by default
other money to come in by either the
client you already have or clients that
you have
and by their word of mouth because they
will invariably talk about what you're
doing for them
new money
is very talkative
it dislikes the chatter so when it talks
to other potential clients they by
default will reach out to you and you
will see your your fund management
business grow
and that just puts more money in your
pocket and again nothing changes just
because there's more money coming in and
you're managing you don't want to change
the idea of what you do about your
trading you're not trying to impress
anyone you've already made the
impression that this is the rate of
return you're aiming for there's no
guarantee you're going to get it but are
they going to be mad if you made 16
no way they're not going to complain
about that if they made 16 on their
money
and they had very little period of
drawdown where they didn't have any real
exposure to risk
but
they had 16 rate of return 16 return on
10 million dollars is respectable
you can't find that rate of return
anywhere in the marketplace right now
they don't get it in cds they don't get
it in equities they're not getting it in
you know money markets or anything like
that so
what they're doing
is they're allowing you to work for them
by managing that money
well in their eyes you're working really
hard
and when you're managing money you don't
want to be working hard you want to be
working smart and smart means you're not
doing a whole lot of work to make that
money you only want to put it at risk
when it's very favorable and you'll see
when we get into the execution stage and
the
management stage of long-term trading
you'll see this it takes very little to
do very well on these higher time frames
until next time wish you good luck and
good trading