okay so um
let's take a couple uh
looks at
the dollar Index and let's begin with
a daily chart
how many of you in here watch the uh the
video link I sent out
now In fairness it's
it's uh it's really pointed at um
showing the the strong contrast to
what I teach what I trade with
in relationship to what is commonly
known as supply and demand
um
supply and demand is not an ICT order
block as much as the pundits would like
to say they are they're not
the way a supply and demand zone is
created and the way it's perpetuated by
Sam sedan or
there's Online Trading Academy guys or
whoever else subscribes to the view of
supply and demand they get you to a Zone
okay and the way the ICT order block
works is it gives you a specific level
to look at and then you round it to the
nearest Round number or institutional
level and that that's why it's so
precise it's not leaving you to discern
or guess as to where in a Zone you want
to trade at and that's the fallacy in it
all and if you go if you take it down to
the Bare Bones of supply and demand
they have
a large subscriber base to it and while
there are some that will show
profitability and I've said this in the
past supply and demand Concepts
by and large will get you to an area
where trades will likely form okay but
it will not give you
the trade levels to trade at it will not
give you the X-ray view on how to
um
narrow down to a specific price level
which is really necessary necessary for
obviously defining risk keeping risks
small manageable and also what level to
shoot for in terms of a profit objective
so when I get uh tweets I get emails and
I get other folks that'll you know come
in and say well you know you're
repackaging reap
regurgitating and relabeling just
to uh you make myself look good
uh I've been doing this 23 years okay
and I can tell you what I do isn't out
there except for what I do
the way I teach it is all me
um it's not uh I didn't look at supply
and demand say Let me let me even try to
improve on supply and demand I didn't I
didn't do that supply and demand was
actually shown to me by a guy on um baby
Pips with my baby Pips days
um they uh he was really trying to push
hard and heavy about it and I kind of
always I can't think at him saying look
you know I understand where you're going
with it but I don't subscribe to that
because it's too vague okay remember
when you first got involved with uh
trading in the concept of support and
resistance was introduced to you and
suddenly because someone's showing you
an example of a chart but it doesn't
make a difference what time frame it was
but if they showed you a chart and they
clearly show that the resistance worked
in the past and look how perfect it went
right to that level again and turn
around went down and then you tried to
apply that shift to your charts and your
trading and what happened you Blu-ray on
through it and you had no understanding
of why it did it okay and that's the
same fallacy that goes along with supply
and demand because really all you're
doing is applying trend line analysis
okay and the theory that price will
bounce off of a trend line okay uh
sloping up or sloping down but you're
just applying it to a Zone okay there's
no reason
to base your assumptions on future price
uh moves I want to Zone a Zone has
absolutely no basis in your trading
except for highlighting a potential uh
killing ground okay an area where a
trade most likable form but that is in
no way narrowing down what your
your job is and and fulfilling the role
of you as a Trader because you have to
select where you're going to get in at
and it has to be a level that makes
sense obviously it has to be a level
that is
um
building on an idea that there should be
institutional sponsorship at that price
level okay it's not that you look at a
Zone and say okay well
and I I want to finish this thought
because I kind of already moved away
from it when you looked at support and
resistance okay supply and demand is the
same thing to that but it just made it
even worse because you can look at a
chart and say okay well look
um I looked at this level here
okay and looking at this we can see the
price clearly went up to that level in
hindsight perfect 2020 we can see price
went up there and then it rejected and
went away okay so everyone knows that
this right here would be deemed as a
resistance level
can you guys hear me
I got a couple people asking if uh
yeah
um
yeah I'm sorry if you can't hear me it's
going to be on your end guys but it'll
be in the uh in recording okay
so looking at the idea of support and
resistance okay
yes I have a module that teaches
specific levels and how to apply support
and resistance but again
much like you probably discerned on your
own uh as a fledgling Trader you found
out that support resistance isn't the
be-all end-all it's not it's not the
Panacea of trading okay
the understanding of why the market
should find support resistance there is
the missing link okay and supply and
demand gets close to it it gets you in
the neighborhood but it never gives you
the address okay it doesn't give you the
access to the price level that you need
to see where
the institutions are going to come in
and actually do the buying and selling
okay so if you really break it down and
weigh my work the ICT order block which
is based on real institutional trading
and and I've done it I've been in that
I've been in that field okay I know what
I'm talking about I prove it I show it
to you and the whole context of the myfx
book which we'll talk about and we're
actually going to pull it up is to show
you that there are folks out there that
will teach you and promise you future
riches but they don't ever teach you how
to get out of the hole you dug for
yourself before you found them if you
did in fact find a good Mentor okay many
of you already know what it's like to be
in drawdown and have had a hard time
getting out of it despite having good
skill sets again given to you and shared
with you the psychological barriers the
um routine in the process you got to go
through to get out of it okay and the
thought processes that's necessary to to
adopt to get through that it's it's
that's something that's not taught by
anyone okay so when you get out there
and you start looking at stuff and you
see these guys come out there they want
to you know sound like smart asses uh
well you know you're repackaging
relaying that stuff has been thrown at
me for 20 years okay and honestly I've
always encouraged it go out and really
weigh everything I teach in the balances
okay I didn't come out and say I
invented support resistance I didn't
come out and say I invented Fibonacci I
didn't say that I never said that I said
I had all the access that you have as a
new Trader okay with all the retail
stuff and indicators and I weeded out
all the and stuck with the
things that worked okay I found that the
Fibonacci level 70.5 Midway okay and I
was just flirting around with it okay I
noticed it didn't go to 79 a lot of
times or 78.6 and a lot of times it
wouldn't just stop at 62. okay it would
just go right in the middle and the 50
level is kind of like a real weird
um
phenomenon really it's like it likes to
go halfway somewhere okay and that's why
also I like to take my profits early too
because I don't like to see myself hold
hard and fast to a specific level even
though I think it may trade to that
level I want to get out before it gets
there okay so
when I talk about things and when I
teach things okay you'll probably see a
Fibonacci overlaid on my chart not So
Much Anymore recently okay but if you
look at my work you'll see Fibonacci
okay and it was a tool to help
illustrate returning back inside of a
range that's all it taught it just gives
you a little crutch to find that little
sweet spot to look for but once you
understand price action you don't need
any of that stuff on your chart you
don't need the moving averages to
discern where institutional order flow
is on the higher time frame because you
know by looking at the price action what
it is it's going up or down okay but
when I see these asses get on there and
they say you know you're repackaging or
re-labeling okay first get one thing
straight I'm not selling you anything
secondly I don't care if you like what I
teach
I don't care if you make money or don't
make money I'm doing this because I have
a record of it for my children you just
are witnesses to it okay believe me if
it was all about me
making money selling books which I made
a smart remark about because some
um goofball okay on there yeah I made a
snide remark which everybody knows I
don't sell anything but he ran with it
thinking I'm going to be uh you know
selling something down the road I'm not
selling anything okay I don't want
anything from any one of you okay but I
am interested to see what uh all of you
do with it and that's all I've asked for
so
but I'd like to come out here and answer
some of these things a lot because
I love my trolls as much as I think I'm
upset or mad or anything like that I'm
not I love them I absolutely love them I
hope they stick with me because
if I can convert one of them that's what
I'm looking to do and they may do it in
secret but I know I'm going to get
somebody eventually they're going to be
like you know what this guy he really
does tell it like it is okay but their
feelings are going to be hurt up to that
point
but looking at
the tools and applications that I I
teach okay I have to take you out of the
retail World okay but we have to find a
Common Language okay all of us know what
uh stochastic is we all know what our
PSI is we all know what support
resistance is and supply and demand okay
all those types of things all of them
have their place in trading
now what I'm about to say is going to be
the distinction of whether you stay in
the retail world or you move out and you
go into a professional level mindset
all the retail tools that's on your mt4
platform or your uh
ninjatrader or trading view platforms
all these things that are out there we
have all these toys at our disposal okay
and just like a child if you throw them
in Toys R Us and you let them run wild
okay they're not going to stick with one
toy they're going to jump and jump and
jump and jump and they're gonna have a
tantrum when you try to take whatever's
in their hands at the time out
so I had to take every one of you
from the baby Pips days through this
process of going through all kinds of
retail tools just like I did and then
finally showed you the fallacy in and
all now
if I would have told you from the
beginning take everything off your chart
we're going to look at things like this
half of you would have been like no way
I need these things I need to have these
things these are my training wheels
these are my crutches these are my
things are my best friends and it would
have been a barrier to your
understanding and plus I need you to be
in the charts for a period of time and
that's not a little bit of time it's
going to be a period of time seeing
things repeatedly throwing at you talked
about
spoken of hinted out it's going to go
here it's going to go there look for
price to go here and then seeing it
unfold
that's where the learning comes from
it's not applying an indicator it's not
applying regurgitated horse that
everyone accuses me of okay everything
that I teach is completely alien to what
is out there in the real world okay of
retail Trading
the professional mindset that I
hopefully try to cultivate in the things
that I do
it largely is hinged on your ability to
spend time in the price charts yourself
okay my model isn't okay now look at me
now here's what I'm going to do I'm
going to do this and you're going to do
the same thing and only thing that does
is teaches you number one dependency and
I don't want dependency the whole thing
starts from my children I want them to
be independent of me
and when I go and move on to wherever I
go and the other life or if I choose not
to uh you know do anything with trading
anymore yeah the the resources that I'm
making available are for them they're
they are able to look at this stuff
there's a lot of things that I'm not
going to make available but it's just
for them so
you're you're just part of a witness to
the things I give to them okay so I'm
not trying to sell nothing I'm not
trying to put something out there
eventually have a you know a a fund I've
asked I've been asked about that too am
I going to eventually try to pull
people's money and and trade for a fee I
don't want any of that stuff I don't
want any of that okay so I enjoy doing
this but I don't want it to be
misrepresented by some
goofballs that think they know something
they don't and all the while they're
over here trying to sell my stuff and
relabeling it themselves Okay so
ICT order blocks are completely specific
levels okay they're not ambiguous zones
and when I shared that link excuse me
when I shared the link on Twitter it's
not a knock against Vic Noble okay
because Vic Noble's in business he's
trying to make money he's he's a he's an
instruction instructor educator whatever
it is okay
but the guy that he's backing now is
saying that he worked for a bank and he
made the software program for the bank
and I'm calling right away on
that okay first of all you're not you're
not the one doing it okay you aren't the
one doing that secondly you aren't the
one okay
showing real
institutional order flow
or quote-unquote banking levels on an
mt4 platform like that video suggests
and I'll I'll tell you what I mean by
that
when when they draw a level and this is
synonymous with supply and demand as
well and again don't take my word for
this go and look at this stuff okay so
when we see ideas like this this is
resistance obviously we know that
because price went up there and rejected
it okay and that's given no problem you
have no problem understanding that
everyone understands that
what leads to this level becoming a
resistance level before it gets there
and trades there it's completely utterly
independent from looking at it like we
do in textbooks or Educators telling us
this was resistance okay
the fallacy with Educators and gurus
okay and honestly a lot of my
subscribers fall into this group okay
they will hear me speak they'll hear me
talk they'll see examples of my videos
and I do a lot of lipstick and window
dressing with my presentations because
it's my personality you don't you may
not like Deadpool you may not like
sniper stuff you may not like some of
the things I say you may not like when I
occasionally drop a a swear word and
you're going to send me an email and
tell me I shouldn't talk like that I'm
real okay I'm not trying to be anything
but who I really am and I sometimes show
my real personality and I try to be as
uh you know cordial and respectful as I
possibly can but sometimes it just you
know you gotta get a little real world
sometimes and and Shake Somebody by the
lapels
but when you look at things
and you study price action
you have to know before it becomes
resistance otherwise it's going to be of
no use to you okay you have to have an
idea an idea rather or mindset going
into that price level that it should
offer a resistance level otherwise
what use is it to you you're going to be
able to point out on the other side of
your chart like we're doing here and
saying look here's resistance well Trade
It
can you go back there and trade that no
you can't okay it's already passed it's
a missed opportunity
but
supply and demand will teach you
that okay well there's a supply level up
in here okay there's a supply level and
it creates a Zone
and they'll draw all these boxes and
rectangles which will look by the first
introduction to it like an ICT order
block or an area which I highlight okay
where we move back into a up or down
candle and that's not the same thing
okay and believe me we're not arguing
semantics here it's very specific when
we look at
the mean threshold okay the middle of an
up candle
the body of the up candle that's the
level at which the institutions are
going to be trading at many times okay
that's the highest point it'll go
let me zoom in here
and let's take this
off
you guys you can hear my puppy snoring
but just deal with it so um we have
this up candle in here
and what we do is we measure the body of
the candle right in here okay now
an up candle prior to a down price leg
okay or swing away from a level like
this this is very easily concerned
because we see a very significant price
move away from it
the up candle is where the institutions
have to sell into that and this is all
rehash we all know this okay but I
really want to draw a distinction
between this because I still see this
stuff popping up and because it's fresh
today on Twitter I just want to rub
their nose in it the
the body of the candle here okay all
this movement up right into this move
higher that high creates the resistance
level that's the high of the price swing
okay or the swing High okay when we see
that
think about it you work for UBS okay you
are trying to get out of a price move
that you are trying to take profits on
okay you're a bank Trader your your job
is the speculation side of things you're
not in the business uh transactional
side of the bank you're actually in
there doing speculation and yes there
are uh Traders
let me get my get myself comfortable
here the uh there are traders in the
bank level that speculate for Pure
profit now it's not a large
um uh
openly discussed topic okay and some of
them will say well there's really very
little uh speculation in the banking
level and that's because they aren't
privy to it okay
that's the area I came from
that's the area okay or field that I
came from okay that's the area they
wanted me in okay and my my
idea was well if I'm learning how to do
this why would I want to work for anyone
else I could just do this on my own and
I left with a great deal of
animosity placed on me and it's still it
still follows me today but nonetheless
the bank has to unload that as the price
is moving up it cannot do it effectively
as it's starting to move away because
they don't get the
efficient uh exit points
for their potential uh profits because
their size of Trades are so large now
they're not in there leveraging 50 to
100 to 1 400 to one they're not doing
those types of things but their scale is
very large and they have to have
counterparties to the other side of that
so because they're trading on an inner
Bank level they have to find
counterparties of equal or greater uh
size to eat into that move so and then
we're not going to be talking about
pancakes so
the uh the up move in here okay this
candle is where all the selling is done
when you look at supply and demand
they'll say well look at this down
candle here there was some Supply here
they sold all here okay and they'll draw
your attention to this candle
or this area up in here and they'll draw
a rectangle around and they'll spend a
whole lot of time with the upper side
of the uh of the range okay or Zone
and that much like I've said in the past
about Ninja Traders uh quote-unquote
Dynamic support and resistance which is
a load of that really
as soon as I hear stuff like as soon as
I see things like that I already know
right away they have no idea what
they're talking about and I want you to
do the same thing okay because unless
you are anticipating a turtle soup
environment okay or false breakout type
thing okay
this idea won't hold water it won't work
okay it won't work
so and I'll explain what I mean by that
so I know some of you are questioning
what you know can you explain that I'm
going to just let me get through the
thought process please so the up candles
what we look at now because they have
they are selling into this move up
your eye your your eye needs to be
trained in okay well they started the
price move up in here okay so they're
selling all in this big bullish candle
so in this big bullish candle in here
the likelihood of them getting out from
the middle of the range of the candle up
to the uh the close of the or the the
bulk of the body here and let's
highlight that so you can see what I'm
talking about
the likelihood
of price
right in here
and we'll stick with orange that's good
the likelihood of price getting back
into this side of the body of the candle
and up to the high
is very very slim now I know what you're
seeing you're seeing the same thing I'm
seeing it well it did it over here yeah
it did there's going to be a few times
where it does that and that's where the
hook comes in for supply and demand
Traders will say well see this is right
here it went right back up into this
Zone and there's your cell and that's
great that's wonderful wonderful
one-time example
you have to idea anymore so you have to
subscribe to the idea that that's not
always going to happen
so my work was okay when the banks okay
are selling into this they're trying to
get specific price levels
they're not just selling just throwing
it out there and hoping someone you know
they're looking for counterparties okay
and they're very easily discerned in the
marketplace on the inner Bank level
they're common knowledge actually
because the banks are out there saying
look you know I need to move 200 million
I need to move you know a half a billion
dollars I need to move a billion dollars
I need to get this you know I need to
get this transacted so when you see that
on the institutional level what you
can't see you can't see it on mt4 you
can't see it on Market profile you can't
you can't see all that kind of stuff you
know it's completely outside of the
scope of what we can see on a retail
level you have to be in that environment
to see it you got to be elbows to elbows
with it okay and that's some of the
things there's a barrier for people like
myself that have had the experience have
seen it okay and I had to bridge that
understanding through what I see in
price action is it something that can be
seen repeating in a chart because if you
can see it in a chart the concept is
conceptualized and then you can pass it
on like I want to pass on on my children
so
what my work
was and this is all me this is not
someone else's rehash stuff I didn't
find this somewhere else okay but you're
seeing it all now I'm sharing the links
when I see my stuff pop up or if they
even hint to it I show it out there I
give it now if I'm trying to copy
somebody people that copy stuff don't
take you to other sources of it they
want to deny it or they want to hide
from it I will show you other people are
taking my things okay they're doing that
and they're selling it now my question
is why don't they just trade it just
trade it you'll make more money you
don't have to worry about subscribers
you don't have to worry about Services
you don't have to worry about any of
that horseshit make your own money you
can write your own check there's no
reason why you can't do that so when I
see folks out there well you know I'll
you know I'll start my own signal
service I'm starting my own analysis
thing why are you even monkeying around
with that I've given you so much already
forget Market maker 12 for a minute and
yes we're gonna talk about that you have
so much given to you already there's no
reason why you guys aren't on the
pathway to completely just leaving your
your job doing what you got to do to
live your own life you have enough now
why are you even worried I'm telling you
I did that stuff 75 000 a month income I
was getting that I don't I don't want it
I don't miss it I don't need that and
believe me if you are confident to the
degree where you want to teach other
people then you sure as hell I better be
confident trade your money if you're not
there's a problem
if you're selling it
that begs the question why are you
selling it that's a tiny little pissant
amount of money
it's a small little insignificant grain
of what's potentially available to you
as a Trader understanding the stuff I
teach
why are you selling it
seriously you know who you are there's a
couple of you and
to get on there okay and and sling oh
well you know this and that dude forget
about it okay if you're going to judge
this on my FX book that's ain't done
it's not done I haven't hide I haven't
hit anything I haven't done anything
except for let everything into a
drawdown I waited and I'm waited I
waited I waited and then one of you
stepped out yet not one of you not one
of you said well I'm going to show this
guy
I'm still here I haven't hit anything I
told you I was going to make an average
of three and a half percent and look it
happened this week every single day
do the average on it it's done and I'm
gonna do the same thing next week and
I'm gonna do the same thing next week
and I'm gonna do the same thing next
week and I'm promising you that my
effects book is going to show 150 000 in
inside of six months and here's the
kicker it's going to be a million
dollars for the end of the year so kiss
my ass on that one so getting back to
this
the up candle is where they sell so my
idea was okay well how do I how do I get
to drawing out the uh the selling that
they're really trying to get in here all
the uh the movement past the halfway
point of that candle this is all stops
this is all stops
this liquidity is reaching up air
expanding for the liquidity what's it
reaching for well look right next to it
see these two candles
this is down candle that down candle
folks are going to say good well it's
going to go down so let's put our stop
loss right above that level that high
so that's the reason why it expands and
snags that and takes them out the
institutions are not selling the largest
portion up here
they may get another portion of it out
with the liquidity offered to the left
over here
but by far and large you're going to see
that it's the low of the up candle to
the halfway point of the body of the
candle
that's the bulk of the volume okay so
now while we brought up volume
um I understand that the Foreign
Exchange Market is not a centralized
exchange and I think everyone else
trading it knows that too
um it's an electronic medium that you're
trading through your independent uh pool
of liquidity that your your broker
offers okay and
I came from Trading Futures so coming on
Twitter to try to tell me how to do it
with a monkey mask on is a little
ludicrous okay I've made millions of
dollars trading the commodity markets
and while you're scraping around looking
for slings to make yourself look funny
on Twitter I've already walked you okay
so I know more about the Futures Market
than I've shared with the Foreign
Exchange Market I cut my teeth on
Commodities okay and I can tell you that
the Foreign Exchange Market is by far
and large well beyond the Futures Market
way way better and if it was not the
case I'd still be trading commodities I
don't trade Commodities I have not
traded Commodities in a number of years
okay I don't trade bonds anymore I don't
trade S P 500 I don't trade yes I don't
trade uh gold I don't trade silver I
don't trade any of the metals I don't
trade any agricultural markets I don't
trade the sauce I don't do any of those
things anymore I found what I love and
it's the spot Market okay it's so liquid
and you guys just see what I talk about
in the retail World okay I have Prime
brokerage accounts where I'm Trading
cash level because there's no leverage I
trade millions of dollars
in a bank level I don't do any
leveraging
but I make so much doing that I don't
need to do anything else and it's so
liquid I can choose whether or not I
want the price that's offered to me can
you do that with your broker once you're
filled gets your price
I have an option do I want that price or
not
there's benefits to that okay and you
got you got a little bit of time to do
it you can call up and come back say
look you know yeah I don't want that
quote
try doing that in your retail world you
can't do that and again these are all
that get on here and they think
they know something and you're going to
try to call somebody out dude you have
no idea who I am you have no idea who I
am the only thing I've shared with you
is what I'm willing to share with you
but I've shared enough to know what I
teach and share makes tons and tons of
money okay I'm not trying to teach
people to be materialistic I'm not
trying to be uh an educator that uh
promotes egotism okay and you're hearing
a little bit of mine today and I'm
letting it come out but believe me I'm
thralling back because I could really
really do a whole lot more than this and
you probably are laughing you're
probably Snicker and saying well you
know look at him I got him you don't got
me you you do not got me I'm sitting on
my couch buddy you're at work
you're at work stealing time when your
boss is uh internet okay that's what
you're doing I'm sitting here on my
recliner okay relaxing talking to you
Schmucks okay not to not the subscribers
that I invest my time in but the goobers
I'm referring to right now you know
exactly who you are
Okay so
when you look at my things understand
there's a distinction between supply and
demand
and ICT order blocks the ICT order block
is this level right here the bottom of
this orange candle I'm sorry orange
range in here to this
the right there is the ICT order block
right in there
okay that's what you want to look for
and that's where the banks are trading
it's the low of the up candle product of
the down move up to the middle of the
range the mean threshold okay that's the
Midway Point anything above that is too
thin of liquidity
it's too thin
you're not likely to get that
but you have a 90 likelihood it's going
to trade into that right here between
the middle middle of the range down to
the low many times the trade occurs
right at the low
think about that okay so in your notes
if you haven't already established this
uh understanding that's really where
you're supposed to be at
now the question is is when you have
that information
let's contrast the two things here
and what I'm doing is I'm the
equilibrium line here that's the 50
level on the FIB I just highlighted what
I view it as I don't like FIB levels at
50 like some Educators use it like it's
a real meaningful thing I use it
conceptionally to illustrate where
um fair value is and a like this mean
threshold where it's the middle of the
range of a up candle for order block
this is the area at which we highlight
for an ICT order block okay this is not
supply this is an ICT order block so
inside of this area okay what we do is
we
look at the highest point and the lowest
point of
the block
oh I grabbed the wrong thing
okay so now we have
a range of
99.63 and 99.15 now it may be a little
bit off that but right now it's it's
going to accomplish the method
nonetheless my question is this so
between 99
.63 and 99.15 what institutional levels
reside within that level or inside that
range
okay because now we're going to talk
in similar vernacular as it relates to
supply and demand up to this point this
is where the distinction uh is
established there's a leap into well
well beyond the level of vagueness
that's shared in supply and demand to
now specific price levels we're going to
get very very specific right now okay
because the banks are not out there
guessing well I hope there's somebody
out there in this Zone that'll trade
with me I hope there's somebody out here
in this big vast range of uh you know
opportunity okay they have a specific
level in mind okay and knowing these
levels okay is a phenomenon it repeats
over and over again it doesn't change
this process is the same every single
time it doesn't make a difference what
time frame you're looking at okay but
obviously the larger the time frame the
better because the banks are not trading
on five minute charts and one minute
charts and tick charts and 15 minute
charts that's not what they're trading
off of you as a retail Trader can see
the order flow coming into the market
on a smaller time frame a little bit
more detailed but it's not them looking
at these smaller time frames and saying
well there's a level here on this five
minute chart I'm going to trade on that
all the things you see on a five minute
chart and 15 minute chart an hourly
chart
they're all subordinate okay to what you
see on a monthly weekly daily and at the
very least the four hour chart and I'm
going to say four hour chart with
tongue-in-cheek because the majority of
it's always on the daily chart Okay so
between 99.63 99.15 okay when you look
for is you want to see what levels
are residing inside of
these two price points okay and we'd
like to use round numbers
starting with the 80s
50s
20s and round again so you have a full
figure mid figure the 80s and the 20s
okay so we have
without a doubt 50
is definitely one to be uh
considering
and because I have this little go to
webinar thing on the right hand side I
have to
do it like this I apologize
and I just mess it up how about that see
what I can do
all right I'm going to stay away from
that level all right so the institution
level or mid figure 99.50 okay that's
the level that you would go to
immediately that's the first one you go
to okay and you can fine tune an 80 well
we're outside of the range because we
didn't get to 80 did we the upper part
of the boundary of this up candle
80 would be up here somewhere
so we can't we can't incorporate the 80
level okay the other level that would be
um
potentially uh
available to us for a trade setup
is the 20 level
and I'll go into more detail again why
we're pulling this actually I know I
know there's a couple of you in here
that have no business being in a level
of Education like this without having
gone through all the other stuff because
I see some of you asking what's an order
block
so here's the uh 20 Level the 99-20
institutional and then you have the
99.50 okay now I'm going to take a step
back I'm not going to spend a whole lot
of time with this but I just want you to
look at this for a second and you tell
me if anything jumps off the chart based
on what I just showed you
[Music]
cue the Jeopardy music
clearly the 9950 level okay do you see
how price kept
the bodies right and subject to the mid
figure you see that now
you see a wick that goes up a little bit
deeper past the mean threshold and
that's sometimes going to happen it does
it again in here goes a little bit
deeper and sometimes that'll happen
it does it again here and yes sometimes
that'll happen but the bulk of the
volume is always in the bodies of the
candle and look at the bodies of the
candle see that
it's this is the level they're trading
at they may have reached price up in
here they may have offered a smaller
block of orders to spread the price up
to Once once there's a trade at a price
level everything below it
is now I they're active in other words
they're pressing limit orders in a range
between like say where this candle opens
up okay if it trades up to here
everything from that high
to this previous candle if it was a
limit order in there it's all now become
a market order
now based on what those orders are
whether it being buy orders or sellers
is the the basis of how the liquidity is
being introduced to the marketplace so
if we understand that the backdrop is
over here that they sold it as a
resistance for whatever reason we know
what's the resistance because price
moves a significant level away from it
then it came back into it okay inside
the orange area is where you're looking
for your trade
you're not worrying about a specific
Zone you're looking for a specific level
you're looking for specific
Precision price points and we're looking
at a daily chart here okay so if I go
and I look at
um
it's not what I want to do
and that's not what I'll do either let's
see
I knew I'd grab that thing and mess it
up
let's leave it in there so we don't mess
them up and
I get the date on when that actually
traded into it
all right so we traded into these levels
on
13th of April 2015.
okay so we will
drop down into I'm not sure if it'll
give me it only it's dropped down to a
four hour
all right so here's that same price
action
foreign
a four hour chart okay here's that first
time it came up there and created the
resistance level price moves away and it
came all the way up into it okay now
here's where the PHD level of ICT stuff
comes in okay it's not enough simply
looking at the levels and breaking it
down it just draws your attention to
where the trades are going to set up
okay and it's going to be a deviation
between
um where you expect them to form and
where they actually format okay and I
think and I've done said this in the
past a 15 pip variance between what you
anticipate seeing happen and where it
actually forms I think that's a
realistic expectation okay especially if
you understand how to do a top-down
analysis what we're doing here okay now
obviously we see price moving away in
hindsight perfect we understand that we
can't trade that but we have to learn
from it we use these Concepts to build
our understanding okay and understand
there are specific price levels that we
have to look for not zones okay so and
again I understand some of you are
saying well fine demand is an area that
highlights zones and then you look for
Price patterns okay great I understand
that but
you're not going to see Banks basing
billions of dollars on
animal patterns
okay they're not looking at Price action
thinking well that looks like a zebra
pattern well there's a hunchback or a
platypus and there's a you know there's
a there's a blue thin crab and there's a
there's a rockfish pattern here and you
know look I've been there I've done it
okay I know some of you can well you
just don't know I did it I did it I
traded I traded harmonic patterns okay
quote unquote Advanced patterns there's
nothing Advanced about that except for
your Advanced waste of time okay you're
you're attributing way too much credit
to something that is really not doing
anything for price
harmonic patterns do not move price
what'd I just say what did I just say
it's Blasphemous I should have never
said that
I'll say it again
harmonic patterns do not
move
price
large Traders orders
move price
if you change the thought process when
you view price action to understand
where are those orders going to manifest
and or where do these large orders
materialize where are they resting where
are they going to materialize
where can they be taken in
where will they be introduced
it's as simple as that it's accumulation
manipulation and distribution there is
no Supply and there is no demand
period
I'll say it like this
if this was Supply up here okay
things can change on a fundamental basis
I said that word again fundamental yeah
I know there's something out there
fundamentally driving the banks to do
what they're doing but I'm never going
to be online to be able to figure that
out
and neither will you on a very long-term
macro scale yeah maybe based on interest
rates and stuff like that but honestly
just because you think you understand a
fundamental uh premise behind it the
bank can change their mind about the
fundamentals
just because employment numbers are a
big deal now
housing numbers may become a bigger deal
later on
manufacturing numbers may become it's
always like a flavor of the month okay
and it comes in in waves wherever the
the Hot Topic is that's where the the
the country's economies are going to be
focused on and they're never always
collectively worrying about one thing
I'm sorry on all of them they're worried
about one thing over the rest of them
and you're always going to have medium
impact and large impact drivers that
come in the marketplace with news but
you're never going to have this equal
distribution of sensitivity amongst all
of them there's going to be this
gravitational attention placed more on
one or maybe potentially two but
generally it's one you'll find out by
studying it all the major Market drivers
for um uh every currency and government
out there and and we trade they are
highly sensitive to one over the rest
okay and it like I said it always comes
in that fad uh there's something that
the countries are paying more attention
to than the others amongst all the uh
reports that come out
so when we have
this expectation as a retail Trader that
fundamentals and Supply reside up here
okay the banks can change the whole
script and say well you know what
um something is greater
on the lower end of the market okay and
those things won't ever become a factor
to get back up here and trade it okay
and by having the understanding of
institutional order flow not supply and
demand okay institutional order flow
you'll be able to see
that fundamentally they have changed
gears so therefore price action will
show you everything you need to know
you're not trading fundamentals on a
day-to-day basis you're not day trading
fundamentals okay you're not short-term
trading fundamentals now you can trade
with a higher level long-term
fundamental premise and only trade in
that direction and that's no problem
with that I have no argument with that
you'll never hear me say anything about
that
but you're not going to convince me that
you're trading on a day-by-day basis
largely on fundamentals that you think
are because I can show you reports
that'll show uh what we viewed as
bullish fundamentally and then there's
15 other guys that we're saying with
fundamentally it's bearish
so again where do you go where is the
pool that you're drinking from
because it's all
it is it all is because
it's not a matter of what everyone
thinks
it's a matter of what they're doing
I don't care what your opinion is in the
marketplace and you shouldn't give a
rats I ask what my opinion is either you
don't care about what I think I'm
telling you as the mentor in this whole
show don't care about what I think about
the market don't care about that you
don't care about what ICT thinks about
the cable the dollar the Fiverr the
Aussie Mooney don't care about what I
think
that's the worst thing you could do as a
Trader because what you're trying to do
is you're trying to read my mind
and you're not going to trust me it
changes all the time it's changed 15
times it's just in the presentation on
this video alone I came in wanting to
talk about something I'm already on 15
different topics unfinished so looking
at the you know when we look at
fundamentals like that or levels like
this implying Supply up here because the
banks are the drivers okay because
they're the big boys okay the retail
world's not moving price they're you're
trading inside of a little sandbox of
liquidity the banks don't even see you
they don't see you you're inside this
little tiny little fxcm oh and the Forum
okay of tiny little itty bitty liquidity
Banks can't see that they don't see that
but they know
that everybody does the same thing place
to stop above the old high place to stop
below the old low that's what they
that's what everyone's taught
okay it's the same thing okay you want
to know how accidents happen they cross
the yellow line and they drive too fast
it doesn't take a rock scientist to
finish a fix you know to come to a
conclusion that's how 90 of the uh the
accents and fatalities occur when you're
driving an automobile there's other
things factors like drinking and driving
and falling asleep at the wheel but
they're small little you know not trying
to minimize because I've had deaths in
my family with a drunken drive but you
know what I'm saying I mean there's
other caveats that lead to accidents
well there's other caveats that leads to
profitability and unprofitability in
trading but by far and large okay it's
the fact that they have a stop loss
available which is begging for liquidity
to be absorbed that's a stop loss when
you look at a stop loss and tell me if
I'm wrong put a put a one if you agree
in two if you don't in the room if
you're if you're watching live right now
obviously if you're watching recording
you can't but
if you have used a stop loss in the past
do you view that stop loss as protection
or do you view that stop loss as a
bullseye one if you view this protection
two is a bullseye
exactly exactly so
you're if I were to ask this question
back in 2010
all of you would say it's your
protection it's your Shield okay and I
will agree that is the only protection
you have
that's the only protection you have
you cannot protect yourself any other
way except or collapse the trade and
remove yourself from the risk entirely
but the only Shield you have in this
business is the stop loss
that's it
there's no other defense mechanism out
there except for what's between your
ears
but that's only useful when you put it
into operation you can look at the chart
and see it's going to take your stop out
you can see that but you probably have
been in this so many times where you see
it happening you refuse to take the
trade off and you take the full stop
the market will take your full stop
because you know you're looking at it
and you said okay well it's not going to
get there it's not going to get there I
hope it doesn't get there but if it does
at least I'm protective but you know
then what's happening is it's your mind
has a paradigm shift and it now becomes
what it's not a shield it's a bullseye
well Banks don't trade with stop loss
orders
and that's probably surprising to a lot
of you but they don't
they don't need to their pockets are
very very deep Okay so
when
Traders and fund managers okay are
speculating and they put a stop loss
order in there that is the very thing
that you're looking for when I jokingly
say when you're a new Trader or your
novice Trader a newbie and you sit down
with the price action that you're you're
studying okay and you're hoping to find
a trade you're looking for a neon sign
saying here I am okay the only neon sign
that exists is stops
that's it stop loss orders
and I'll I'll give you a heads up that's
largely what Market maker 12 is all
about
identifying that getting right to that
because that's what the banks do now
because they see the the literal orders
in the marketplace they see the open
interest that's available at those
levels okay it's a different animal like
we can see where they most likely will
reside above or below an old high or low
okay but
they may not be there by the time price
trades
and that's what I'm about to explain
here
if you believe or subscribe to the idea
that this is a supply level okay and
let's go back and highlight that
you know contrast it again when we get
to it if you if you're viewing this
whole thing up here
from the high in the middle part of the
range okay or
really let's do it like this because
this is what they would teach this is a
supply level of it or Zone okay and
price trades back up into that
they will teach that there is
a reason to believe it's going to go up
to here when it's no reason to expect
that at all
it's the least likely occurrence to
happen unless it's a turtle soup
environment
okay and
because that topic is so vast and the
parameters that go along with looking
for turtle soup versus staying under a
low and I know a lot of you ask that a
lot okay and that's really Market MC12
and the reason why I took a lot of
things out of 12 and re redoing it okay
there's 12 main things inside of Market
maker 12. and I made I'm making rather I
got two of them done two
two specific of
of
a collection of points that I went in my
opinion going back over looking at it I
I brushed over it way too quickly and I
was a lot more vulgar in the video than
I probably should have been I kind of
like warned some of you in the last
video it was going to be very offensive
because I was going after a lot of folks
that have taken my stuff and and sold it
um Steve Morrow and um
really went after them so I I kind of
like pulled myself back and and said
okay well I'm going to deliver us a
little bit more professional way
um that way at least I can close this
circus in uh you know a better light
than uh I would have if I did it that
way because I was kind of like kicking
them in the balls and anyone watching
that video would have been like wow wow
it would have been totally shocking but
um I I think that I'm doing it better by
doing it this way and that way it's a
little bit more modular so underneath
the link of Market maker 12. you're
actually going to see 12 subordinate
hyperlinks okay so it won't be marked
like a 12 click on it there it is it's
gonna be mockery 12 as a header and then
it's gonna be 12 individual links inside
of that so it kind of like breaks it
down
um I don't know how long it's going to
take me to go into it because like I
said I only got a couple of them done so
and no I'm not going to give them to you
until they're all done so deal with it
and I don't know how long it's going to
be so there you go the uh the idea of
this level being up here being a supply
level and fundamentals up there driving
it uh lower uh the fundamentals can
change by the time it gets to this point
here and it never gets up to that level
okay or it could trade up in there and
cause really no selling it could just
continue blowing right on through it
okay so again it's not you're not
getting to the the end of the game
with fundamentals
okay and there's a lot of folks that are
just looking at um a lot of online
marketing that's going on
Jared Davis is uh
ran with Chris Laurie's work
and that's really where he got his stuff
from he's full of telling you
anything otherwise
um the the guy's not self-taught he's
Forex Mentor okay he's Vic Noble's uh
new student and he did something with
some guy named Andrew Jenkin it was a
failed operation there too I bought a
couple of his courses and all it was was
pivots and Fibonacci and absolutely
nothing Market flow which it's all Nick
Noble stuff okay and again I'm not
trying to smack Nick Noble around but
um Jared Davis has got this big online
campaign right now that he's the second
uh top rated uh Trader rated by Barclays
and then Barclays stomped him in his
face and said don't you uh don't you use
us you know attributing us to uh you
know your work or whatever but um look
if the fundamentals if you want to learn
fundamentals the right way and a whole
lot cheaper and I believe what is being
shared is effective go to
chrislaurie.com okay or go to
protradersclub.com okay or just email
Chris Laurie or tweet tweet him okay and
just say hey look
um ICT said that you have a course on
fundamentals okay and buy it I think
it's like 99 it's not even that much
money but I I have openly said this in
the past I don't get anything for it but
I think he did an excellent job
explaining fundamentals as it relates to
trading especially currencies and it's
useful
um it's really how he was able to call
in advance he's the only other one out
there excited for myself that has called
Canadian dollar higher long term you
know I did videos I showed you by you
know by levels but he goes into great
detail and I'm not part of his Pro
Traders Club to hear his uh his
discussions as the you know all the
other things going behind it but um
I know that oil was going to be a large
contributor to it and it was going to be
a well and you know all that because of
my conspiracy rants that I had uh you
know two years ago and last year but the
uh
the fundamentals if you're going to do
that save yourself thousands of dollars
and wasted time okay and just simply go
to Chris Laurie and he'll teach
everything that I personally believe if
you want if you want a a sponsor okay if
you want to uh like a
um advertisement for you know something
to spend money on that's the one you buy
okay uh I think he did an excellent job
again it's Chris Laurie you go and uh
just simply get it and study it you're
not going to get it all one time
watching it you know I certainly
couldn't do it um and
I believe it was well well presented and
it's good so there you go
so uh you're welcome Chris
uh looking at the the idea behind it
though um fundamentals um relating on a
day trade short-term basis again I don't
believe it as any Merit unless you're
trading with the long-term fundamental
basis okay it's bullish embarrassing
you're only trading in that direction
then yeah but uh if you think you're
gonna swing back and forth on
fundamentals you're kidding yourself
you're certainly not going to sell that
idea to me and believe it so
the the idea is when we look at these
areas okay and now I'm highlighting what
I believe is the hang on puppy because
she's now snoring way too loud
Bella Bell
you're too loud girl
so uh
again these are all the things you don't
get to hear in my pre-recorded stuff so
there's a lot of editing
the rough cut so
this move above the ICT order Block in
here okay we reduced it down to two
specific price levels
based on the daily chart and this is
what you do this is how you incorporate
all the things that I teach over the
last five plus years okay the the brass
taxes this identify where there's a
likely
resistance and and price okay or where
selling should come in
and where the banks are going to be
trading at and how they're going to be
trading what they're going to be selling
them because they sold it here and where
specifically should we be aiming to sell
short well we label 9920 institutional
level inside of the range that's
discerned by the daily order block
because we don't remember we dropped
down to a four hour time frame right now
so this range is highlighting the levels
we look for inside that range we're not
trade this for Zone sake okay we're
looking for specific levels what levels
institutional order levels 50s 20s 80s
and full figures double O levels Okay
the reason why we like those levels is
because the banks trade with those
levels they're not throwing out well I'm
going to trade at 99.17 and let me get a
selling at 99.23 that's not what they do
they put their orders in in round
numbers or in increments of five okay
largely it's on on even numbers but some
some banks will put their orders in on
fives the bottom line is that's what
you're going to see in the charts if you
study it don't take my word for it
so we know that 99.50 and 99 20
and let's change these little
things here just to highlight that being
the case
okay so we have these two levels here
that we would almost automatically go
into the marketplace looking for okay
now again just so we're on the same
topic uh and same page of this topic
here as price trades up into these
levels here that's when you'd be doing
this obviously you can't do it in
hindsight but in hindsight this is how
you learn
looking at it
like this
zoom in a little bit more
so we have two price levels at which we
would start Hawking setups now we went
down from a daily chart to a four hour
chart so the the next question is okay
when price starts to trade off because
the four hour chart is going to give you
a whole lot of advance notice and I know
a lot of you guys want to have that and
need it okay and it's you know in my
opinion it's something I should continue
continuously advise you to do is trade
on these higher time frames because it
gives you
the buffer that you need
because if you're trying to trade on the
five minute chart and 15 minute chart
and sometimes really the even hourly
chart um if wow that was good grief girl
come here come on
hey
I saw him logs there girl wake up
simply um
when you see price turning like it does
up here
okay and starts to break down which is
what you see
here okay when you see that
the next logical thing you would do is
okay well what's the candle that it
moved up from where's the low on it and
where is the body of that candle
same thing we just did on the daily
chart okay is what we're going to do
here it's the same premises all we're
doing is top down analysis breaking it
down and looking at the institutional
order flow from the daily chart down to
the four hour chart okay and again
institutional order flow for those that
wear monkey masks the
idea is seen through price action okay
and yes I'm completely aware that this
MTV mt4 platform from Forex LTD okay has
zero
connection to the answer Bank levels
that are available on the dollar
I know that there's going to be
disparity I've said this on record
before but because you're going to be
hit and miss and when you listen to me
you don't have a full story but everyone
knows in my work that I say that there's
going to be a disparity between what the
interbank pricing is on a particular
currency versus what your platform is
going to offer and thereby they're
allowed to do that by law okay and your
agreement there's going to be a
disparity okay and it's well beyond the
spread that they offer too
and that's just all part of it guys I
mean you can't escape that you you all
signed on for that risk but when you see
price from starting to move away okay
starting to come down
you start looking at levels that could
potentially be
New bearish Order blocks which is what
this Orange area is highlighted on the
daily chart it's the daily bearish order
block ICT order block not supply Zone
but ICD order block now since we have
highlighted two specific price levels
okay
the next thing we would be doing is
looking for on a smaller time frame in
the four hour chart was there any
indication this part start the breakdown
okay once price trades up to these
levels in here you got to be aware that
these may be
new smaller short term uh bear shorter
blocks that could be utilized for trades
price starts to trade up and starts to
break down
the up candle part of this drop down in
this four hour candle you use the low
to the body of the candle okay now again
I'm going to use this opportunity
because I get folks asking you to doing
it now in the room
how do I know when to use the bottom of
the candle or the Wicks and the bodies
of the candle okay and in your notebook
I need you to write this underline it
and highlight it okay the big big
candles okay and when I say big candles
think about what we talked about back in
2010 on the baby pip States okay what I
learned from Larry Williams was the
markets trade in a rhythm it's small
ranges and big ranges small ranges and
big ranges okay
a candle like this
I would use the middle
to the low
not so much the body of the candle here
and the low reason why because there's a
whole lot more volume in here remember
the body of the candle is where the
majority of the ball the volume is for
the buying and selling okay so when
there's a smaller candle okay when
there's a smaller candle I like to use
the wick to the body of the candle for
for Bare shorter blocks okay and we're
going to highlight that here we have a
small little body candle
now I'm not going to use the 50 basis of
that candle I'm going to elect to use
the low
to the body and yeah I know some of you
pundits are saying well yeah because you
can clearly see over here again this is
the reason why I'm telling you this
because I want you to go into your
charts and you'll see this phenomenon
taking place big candles Big Body
candles okay you're going to use the 50
of that body of the candle or the mean
or the mean threshold okay that that
Middle Point is about half of uh well it
is a half but it's the it's the bulk of
where all the uh institutional airflow
is going to come in and I it'll be
self-explanatory as I go
looking at
the up candle here
using the body
down to the low
there's your institutional order block
bearish not supply Zone okay Supply
they'd have all kinds of business up
here I'm highlighting we don't do that
okay so inside of the range created here
okay let's just borrow these
there's that
I knew I'd do that
okay and
I'm just going to put it on this side
over here it's the same thing so we have
uh
99.72 and the bottom of it over here
99.64. so my question is is what
institutional level or levels
exist between those two price points now
yes it's a smaller little range but
nonetheless the process is still the
same
we have
99.70 round number well wait a minute
Michael you didn't say 70 earlier yeah I
know institutional levels are double O
80s 50s 20s and back to double up
smaller round numbers okay can be
utilized in between those other levels
if there is a premise or Reason to use
them which is what we've framed out here
we already anticipated selling inside
this range here
price came up a little bit stabbed
through it we allow for that and it
starts to come back down the price comes
back up into it we can look to be a
seller again it's not going to based on
what we identify as a bearish order
Block it's not going to go to 99.80
institutional
likely not to do that let's just
rephrase that
based on the fact that 80 would be
up here
on the other side of the body of the
candle which is not what we look for
okay Supply would say look you know up
here there's some Supply up here there's
some flying this down candle okay so it
could go up as high as this this candle
here no it won't why would you expect
that you know not on a consistent basis
it's not going to do that
now there's you're going to send me 20
times this did it but I can send you
thousands where it didn't
so inside here we have 9970 and we have
99.65 remember we they have to use five
rounded to the five numbers okay now I
know some of you also are thinking well
it's what is it's going to be 70 it
could be 65 it could be you know this
that kind of thing you're only going to
use the levels inside of the range okay
this is the range that's identified for
the ICT bearish order block okay so now
what we just did was refined it down to
99.70 you're going to sell at or
99.65 the round number
it doesn't get you can do 60 you can do
60 because this is below the market okay
and still very close to here there's
nothing wrong with that either okay but
if you want to be specific and follow
the rules as I teach my children you
would be trading at 99.65 or 99.70 or if
you want to be a fancy dance and try to
do like I do I want to make sure I try
to get in the move I'm not trying to
worry about 10 Pips I want to get in the
in the trade as many times I don't get a
trade because I insist on getting the
very very best fill and I've done that
well eight years ago I was really
insisting on that and I missed a
huge amount of spectacular entries that
I just really pissed away by being too
demanding on price action and I just
missed them and some of you seen it last
year and some of my trades when I did
live sessions where I just missed it by
a pip or two and some of them on X Okay
so
anyway uh looking at that
let's leave those levels there I don't
want to do that because we're going to
refine it even more
okay so we have price trading in
at 99.70
okay and it takes you right in here
another high on these come in at 99.71
good grief
and 65 we'll look at that
okay and clearly you would have no
problem getting in that in here okay and
price starts to trade off and does
another explosive move going down
if you are remembering that you have the
99.20 and
99.50 mid figure and institutional 20s
on your chart okay
price breaks down and then does what
comes right back up to it and gives you
the entry right in here right at the
level you've already identified inside
of a bearish order block on a daily
chart
it's been refined you have all the
conviction now that you need because you
see institutional order flow is
respecting where they should sell they
are selling and then we have a big range
liquidity void in here price comes back
boom right at the level you already
anticipate 99 20. 99 20 is based on a
daily chart where banks are referring to
this is not a five minute set up it's
not a 15 minute step it's not even an
hourly setup this 20 Level was already
based on the Range that was created on
The Daily ICT order block and we refined
It Down to What two levels are
essentially what you should be trading
at 99.50 and 99.20 okay so let's go down
further into an hourly chart
foreign
oh we'll have to stick with the four
hour
I went back a little too far for that
too ambitious of a
study
so let's zoom in
okay and we have
several things in here that uh are
indicative of what you would expect to
see in price so when we see price action
turning like it is here
okay you can see price action on Market
structure model
we have a swing High a higher swing High
a lower swing high and in between that
think like Head and Shoulders tight
formation okay it breaks down it comes
down I'm not looking at this retest back
to a neckline type thing because if you
look at it doesn't even do that it
doesn't retest the neckline if you're
looking ahead and shoulders but I'm
looking at it in such a way where it
shows a breakdown in Market structure it
does in fact do that
if you look at what goes on also
the ultimate High here okay the question
I like to do is when I'm looking at
Price action let's take this all because
we don't need that one anymore
let's zoom in
these are some of the things that I have
as an internal dialogue when I look at
Price action either real time or if I'm
looking at things in hindsight trying to
frame an idea want a future move or kind
of like forecast when I see things like
that uh like this high in here okay my
question is always this okay it could
have turned on this high
and it could have dropped right from
there but it didn't do that
it ran up one more time and then dropped
off so when I see that inside of an area
when I'm anticipating a sell-off okay
I view that as it came back and took out
early fare stops and they're gonna have
buy stops right above this High because
they're trying to sell it short and they
see these two down candles they get in
there thinking okay I'm gonna try to
catch the high and that's why I do not
trade like that
looking for the liquidity that's resting
above the high in here in the form of a
stop
buy stops on shorts okay they rally them
up take those people out of the
marketplace
to take the other side of the trade
those buy stops to come orders to buy at
the market which is exactly what they
want to use as a counterparty to get
short they're going to sell those buy
stops to them
that's the position they hold for a move
lower when price starts to trade back
down and makes this a little bit of a 10
it trades up into a bear's order block
and it sells off
your thought process should be
immediately okay
if they're selling back here and we're
in a daily setup inside this ICT order
blog a daily setup can see it retrained
back into it in a four hour two I don't
like to see it do it more than once but
in this area we're in that daily order
block right in here okay look closely
this candle right here
is the breaker
that they bought that takes the rally up
above this high it's the down candle
prior to the swing taking out an old
high this turtle soup set up
the foundation to it is in this down
candle right here okay and by
incorporating the bottom of that handle
okay let's show the low
if I can get it to highlight
the low comes in at
99.32
99.32 when price creates this big
liquidity void okay don't assume that
it's got to go back to this candle here
don't assume that
you have to look at the what has
happened this is all things that supply
and demand does not teach you okay
supply and demand says you can't cut
through candles
you can't look past through whatever
this is this is the you know you can
this is a fresh level or it's a fresh
Zone and they're going to look to try to
sell up in here and they're going to
miss the boat
they're going to miss the trade
Banks aren't looking at the same well
this is where uh the fresh level is
they're going to see
that the orders that were used to buy
the market up here and drive price up
okay and there's some of you think oh
your conspiracy theory
take a field trip okay take a field trip
out to Chicago Board trade take a field
trip out to the walls uh you know Wall
Street and talk to Specialists talk to
people that are actually doing it okay
and they'll tell you that there are
drives on liquidity in the marketplace
they'll run the highs they'll run the
lows because when it happens it creates
all this fever there's all this
excitement there's all this uh you know
in induction of liquidity in the
marketplace and because of that that's
where trades form and they love to do
that because markets are just
they're they're only out there to take
the liquidity that's what you're in here
to do you're trading liquidity you're
not trading price you're trading
liquidity just because you want a price
level you're not getting that price
I don't want uh you know I'm sorry I I
may want a specific price level on cable
or Fiber just because I want it doesn't
mean anything I gotta take the trade
and agree on taking the trade based on
the parameters that's being set up in in
the market
either the market price is offering
something that I'm able to live with in
terms of where it is and where I'm
willing to get in a trade or I pass on
the situation and take no trade at all
you have to look at
price action with that mindset okay
the retail platforms are going to be
very
very close but not to the tip of what
the injured Bank levels are okay the
overall Market direction is going to be
similar okay there's going to be a
disparity between what the interbank
pricing engines are and what your
individual platforms are showing and
you're going to have to accept that
there's no way around it you can argue
about it we can all agree it's crap but
they have to have a model that allows
them to be profitable whether it be
Savory or not that's something for
another day to argue about but bottom
line is this is your opportunity the
trade you have to use a retail broker
until you get more money you can trade
Prime burgers this is how you do it but
you have to look at why when this price
runs up and it starts to break down go
back to this you have to cut through
some candles you got to and it it'll
give you the basis of why things should
take place going forward
this run up
the down candle which is a ICT bullish
order block okay and
uh
primarily bullish conditions if price
came back down to that area we could be
buying expecting higher prices but
notice it was happening this is
occurring in a daily bearish order block
inside that orange range
so this is actually inside of that
bearish order block and it drove price
up
do not look at that as a new buying
opportunity
some buying took place in here okay and
maybe there's some out there that try
try to use supply and demand and they
look at this as a continuation maybe
they looked at this as support maybe
this looked at I don't know what they
looked at okay and that's not what I
view price like
my perspective and my thought process is
if they ran it up here and then it broke
down this was a stop run so where did
they buy the run the stops the down
candle probably don't move there's your
breaker so when you have that note to
low the candle okay and limited to the
body of the candle not the high it
cannot do that yes but your trade is
going to be in the body of the candle so
what am I saying I'm saying that if you
take
this range
the body of the candle to the body of
the candle okay so to open and close
extend that out
it does not get to the bottom of this up
candle prior to the down move because it
doesn't have to
all the orders that need to be mitigated
that they use to go long to drive price
up those Longs have to be taken and
canceled they got to be collapsed but
they're not going to collapse on down
here
when price gets back up to it they're
going to collapse right here they so
they are mitigating the open long
positions that have been utilized to
drive price up they'll liquidate them
here
then liquidating and new accumulation
for shorts is why there's only a short
little period of time where it trades
there and it runs away
because you're having two factors being
introduced at the same time you're
selling longs
that were established here you're
selling those Longs which is going to be
a an absence of buying okay and an
increased effect of selling which is the
natural order of things in the
marketplace it's always a seller's
market always a seller's marketing so
when you have that absence of buying and
you have a large introduction of new
selling why are they going to sell more
because they they collapse their lungs
because they don't believe fundamentally
that they're going to go higher so they
come back into this liquidity void and
this void which would be essentially
closed here is not necessary
to be traded up to you only got to go
back to the breaker
so that's how you use the breaker in
combination with liquidity voids there
are some times where it can come back up
in there and trade that and that that
may be detrimental for your trade or it
may be another opportunity to get a
better price entry it depends on how
much range is there and what you're able
to assume on the trade now you can trade
the four hour setup like this and create
a whole lot of uh Pips in terms of the
stop loss that's needed but guess what
the rest of the reward's still the same
just takes a whole lot more time for the
trades to pan out
and don't don't don't despair is the
whole idea of trading on a four-hour uh
time frame because if you can't be in
front of the charts on an intraday basis
you can trade these setups every single
month there's something out there and
there's a lot of a lot of Pips to be
made like that but you got to keep
things relative to you know the risk
so
again going back to this um this low
right in here
on this candle the load comes in at
99.32 so just like we used for the order
block okay my question is okay for if
the low on that candle is 99.32 and the
high is 99.50 okay and the open is 99.41
the body is the open and close so 99.41
and 99.32 is your range my question is
what's the price level you would use to
go short using the breaker
99.35
that's your mid Midway Point okay inside
the body at rounded to the five you can
go with 30 and be early there's nothing
wrong with that because we're only
talking about 40 was it 41 yeah 41
what's the high of the body of this
candle so if you're okay with that and
measuring your risk okay you can get
short at 99 30 which is the round number
going into that candle because you
already have the expectation that this
is going to be a breaker because of all
the backdrop the daily bear shorter
block the fact that we ran this high
right here and it's now broken down it's
giving you all indications that it's
going lower did you miss the opportunity
to get short up here yes did you miss
the opportunity to get short here
possibly
but this one right here
you're trading at 99.20 based on the
daily setup or you're fine-tuning it
using the four hour chart for a breaker
at 99.35 or 99 40 or 9930 okay based on
where your risk is there's your levels
that's how you that's how you as the
trader do it you see the difference
about teaching it like this versus this
is how you do it every single time
because what I'm willing to assume on
the risk is not the same thing that
you're going to be willing to assuming
risk and your Proficiency in trading
price isn't going to be the same level
that I have Okay so
I may be able to trade with a 10 pip
stop I don't do that but I may be able
to do that
you may not be able to
and you may look at what I'm framing as
a trade say well
I don't know about that and then you'll
argue if it makes money you'll say I
wish I would have did it or if you take
it and it doesn't make money and it gets
stopped out I knew I shouldn't have done
that it's too small of a stop loss I
never do that you see what happens it
plagues your thinking versus your
development
your choices on trade selection are
going to ultimately be yours they're
never ever ever going to be mine or the
guy you talk to online or your Mentor if
they are you're doing it wrong
because it's not your trade now is it
you're piggybacking and I know some of
you well it's making money I really
don't care I don't care it could be
somebody else's trade
I guarantee you if you have that thought
process you will not be doing this long
you're going to lose money you're going
to lose your account you're not going to
be Trading
and that's real world stuff right there
you can't get any more real talk than
that
but by looking at things like this okay
let's look at another opportunity of
using breaker because the last the last
couple times we had live sessions you
guys were really heavily beating on me
about well here's the breaker here and
the breaker there so let's take a look
at one more
and then I'm going to close this
portion of the topic
uh what did I want to do here oh
let's take everything off
I gotta make sure I remember to talk
about the cable tray because I prompted
you guys I'm doing this stuff now
because my wife told me that I will not
be doing any videos tonight
so uh I'm doing it now so I'm trying to
answer everything so I want to go to you
later on tonight we have an old high
back here okay and let's go out a little
bit one more time
okay we have an old high here
and I want you to think about as price
was Trading
in here
price made this high and sold off and
then resumed going higher okay and
my question is is what was the primary
trend
even right here
and when I was trading down what was the
primary trend
on a daily chart has been going on
not like that I'm going to show it but
it's been going up see higher higher
higher
so institution order flow
is primarily long
okay so price comes down moves back into
an area of order flow and starts to
Rally up
right here
let me zoom in
yeah right there
right here price made a down candle
right below an old high I love that I
absolutely love seeing that set up okay
it's very similar to uh when we talk
about
um optimal or high
odds bearish order blocks okay where
there is usually a high
okay a short-term High rate below an ICT
bearish order block
that's like a it's like a no-brainer
setup it's so very very powerful well
along the same vein this is what is very
similar to that when we have an old high
like this okay and prices traded up and
then it's starting to sell off okay what
you're seeing is weak bulls that think
that this is going to be resistance
so they sell it and
dare I say it potentially maybe there
should be some Supply up there maybe
there's some Supply Traders up here
trying to sell it because look what it
did There's Supply there and it's sold
off so we're back up to that level again
we're gonna sell it again there's some
Supply okay I love this setup because
what this is is they're they're
introducing uh a setup that allows folks
to do that very thing
and as the Market's dropping down
do professional Traders sell or do they
buy in those environments Down Down
Candles okay some four hour chart so
it's a lot of range
this down candle right here at the far
right of the chart I know I don't have a
highlighted on my cursor I don't have
the opportunity to do that with live
sessions like this but the down candle
okay
bonus four hour chart it's a down candle
just because it's before hour doesn't
make a difference but we understand it's
the the largest players in the industry
which is the banks okay they're going to
buy in down moves
they're going to be buying as the market
moves lower they have to do that to get
a better
uh
average price you know getting into the
uh the trade when I see setups like this
happen it's wonderful opportunity to set
up number one confirmation that we're
going to blow through this okay secondly
it sets up future opportunities because
there's a whole lot of
buying and selling interest on a level
like this because we are it's inside of
an old High inside of a range and it's
down so now think about what's going to
happen here there's gonna be a lot of
buying in here
when it blows through it like this okay
watch what happens as price goes on
price comes back down okay and then look
what happens look at the reaction rate
in here
this reaction right here trading right
back up into what we just described
earlier is the breaker
let me highlight that and put that back
on here
when I tell you guys look at the daily
and four hour chart I'm not telling you
that
I'm wasting my breath doing it I want
you to do it because every major setup
that you'll see in price is going to be
found on the daily in the four hour that
that's a given
you want sizable explosive price moves
everybody does
but you're never going to find them
outside of those two time frames I mean
you can obviously find them on a weekly
and a monthly chart that goes without
saying but
the dynamic price levels that you're
going to trade off of that you get this
real big explosive boom I mean it just
explode you don't have any time wasted
it it gets to those levels and then it
tears and goes the other direction to
another level that makes sense what do I
mean by that well we explained how price
reversed up here on a daily bearish ICT
order block
then price more you know makes it move
lower we marked off our breaker
and this is where price would reach to
not here could it have sure could have
but it didn't it didn't have to because
the buy orders that we used to run the
stops on this old high that's the reason
why now by itself right there that
argument right there this one
presentation just kicks supply and
demand right into nuts
you can and you must cut through candles
you have to look at the context of what
price action is telling you
but because supply and demand doesn't
teach you or even imply an interest in
showing you how the institutions are
trading they're just giving you one
little tiny little facet of okay it
moves from here so if it goes back there
it probably will happen again there's no
difference in that Fibonacci Trading
and I just nailed it right there supply
and demand
put a fib on your trades and it's the
same thing trade 79 retracement levels
and 60 tracing levels and you're gonna
get the same thing supply and demand
gives you done it's handled so it's a
gimmick but it gets you very close on
some instances but it really won't do
anything except for take credit they
won't be able to explain anything
outside of see we were right
my work gives you the X-ray view of why
price is doing it okay and by studying
hindsight examples of seeing it happen
on hot larger time frames like the daily
and four hour it will give you the
context to frame your future trades or
at least give you the framework to start
trading ideas and practice them because
until you start thinking like this and
like where we have to explain here
you're not going to get it
what is it consistently profitable
because you're going to have hit and
missed types of trading instead of
surgical strikes Precision in and out
knowing why you're doing it when to do
it when not to do it
that's what you need to know as a Trader
not reacting and wishing on regretting
and just being just totally upset
because you don't know what you're doing
and it's frustrating believe me I know
what that felt like okay but you were
expecting a Magic Bullet and you're not
going to get the Magic Bullet to give
you the Insight like that it's gonna
have to go through a process of doing
what I'm doing here and that's why the
that watch and troll they don't
they don't like it because they want
easy clicks they want an indicator they
want something to plug on a chart and
show it to them this is the indicator
the open the high the low and the close
and the reactions that it creates on
your chart and you're studying the
psychology in the marketplace that's
what price action is doing it's
measuring the psychological effects of
what other Traders and the only Trader
group that we care about is the
institutional Traders
they're the ones that move price because
our mindset is focused on what they're
doing and how they react well they're
they're they're the Predator they're the
apex predator on the food chain so if
you align your thinking like they do and
they view stops as opportunity their
bullseyes not protections and shields
believe me the banks are driving
bulldozers and you're standing there
with a little pinwheel that's your stop
but they're mowing you over there's no
they're not worried about what's going
to be the ramifications of you getting
stopped out you're just one more piece
of meat going in the grinder there's no
reason for you to view your stop loss in
any other way except for yes it's your
only protection and shield but it's a
bullseye in the form of the
institutional mindset
so bringing it
that you didn't think you'd hear those
types of things when you first got
started in trading you thought it was a
free opportunity to be everything's Fair
we all want to see you make money that's
they want your money they want
you to fail okay and they want you to
blame your indicators
they do they want you to blame it
because what that does it feeds the fire
for someone else's new book a new system
and new stuff and it brings in like PT
Barnum said there's a sucker born every
second
done
well
it's your choice if you want to stay in
that sucker Realm
do you want to listen to on
Twitter telling you the stuff you're
learning doesn't work or do you want to
put the time in and see that it does
and don't expect it to happen overnight
I told every one of you six months of in
the trenches dealing with this stuff on
a daily day basis now I know some of you
could say well I'm like oh I've been
following you since 2010 it isn't
clicking and you should have told me
this stuff from the beginning no I
shouldn't have
no no I shouldn't have and I'm gonna
tell you a reason why I shouldn't have
it if you can't if you can't get this or
understand or agree with it that's
between
you and your problem with it okay
because I can't fix it for you
you
have to go through the process of seeing
why retail Traders think like they do
not just simply reading in a book and
say okay yeah I get it no you don't get
it you don't get it okay you do not get
it until you see it in price action
when these yahoos get on there and they
say hey look you know this guy's talking
about this and that
believe me you're going to laugh your
ass off too because they're clueless
twits they have no idea what they're
doing they're out there chasing the next
best thing and guess what from for a
little while I was like that for them I
was the next best thing because I could
show something it made a little bit of
sense oh yeah order blocks oh yeah
optimal trade entries oh yeah they ran
on trading view oh I'm glad you showed
up ICT I've been I've been using the OTE
for months and it's just been phenomenal
hmm
it's not all OT
it's not all order blocks
it's how you look at the marketplace
and you judge based on what the chart is
showing you where has it shown a
willingness to sell off
why would it have sold off there
these are all thought processes that you
have to go through okay so there's a
dialogue that you must have with
yourself as a Trader it's self-talk
we all have it in all varying degrees as
a Trader we all have self-talk
self-talk in the beginning as a noob is
man I have no idea what the hell I'm
doing I need to find somebody who knows
what they're doing and just copy them
that's self-talk is that empowering or
is that self-defeating
self-defeating
you're in you're staying with a mindset
that is dependent and not independent
okay
or empowering at all you're you're
subscribing to the thought process that
number one a you're weak you're clueless
okay and that you need to have someone
else tell you what to do
now that's the reality of it yes but if
you don't change the way you think
you're not going to look at the
marketplace the right way
because you're going to look at and I'm
going to take one more step further in
this
think about when you first started as a
retail Trader you start thinking okay
where's the next guy in the line of all
of us okay that knows what he's doing
it's making money because you don't know
how to talk to a bank Trader you didn't
believe the bank Traders do this
think about it and honesty you didn't
know that you wanted to find someone on
internet someone on Twitter someone on
Instagram someone on Facebook someone on
an Instagram or infomercial someone
advertising something a direct mailing
okay telling you that they're doing it
and
maybe you thought it was horseshit maybe
you thought it was all smoke and mirrors
but the advertisement or the fact that
they ran their mouth as much as they did
and you've probably seen that happen
with me
man this guy he wouldn't leave you alone
it starts gnawing at you and you have to
just dig into it and see what it is and
it doesn't pan out
why why doesn't it pan out
because you have not taken it as your
own
you have not changed this whole
perspective on trading and made it your
own
now I'm not saying take my stuff and
take someone else's stuff and remarket
it and sell it that's not what I mean by
make it your own okay what I mean by
make it your own is internalize it break
it down into my new details where you
understand each component and then begin
to flush each component together and
then your trading model will materialize
from that
I've given you so many tools and I've
tickled when I see so many people come
at me in an email or they do direct
messages on Twitter which I really don't
like doing those things because I get so
many of them I have a lot of them on
there and I haven't even opened up yet
so if you sent me those by Twitter just
know that I don't like to do those and
I'm not trying to be ignorant to you I'm
not trying to just ignore you I'm trying
to ignore everyone
because there's too many of them so uh
looking at Price action you need to
adopt the mindset of okay
my trading is my Trading
okay and everything that I do in my
trading is going to be my responsibility
so the fruits of it or the
the bad events that take place I have to
own that and I have to take ownership of
the good and the bad and the bad I have
to be sober minded and learn from it I
can't be a victim and say well you did
this to me or you held this back from me
I I did I held back stuff yeah for your
better for your environment your you
didn't have the capacity to look at this
stuff like you did because you didn't
have the time looking at Price action
the way I look at Price action
you have to be able to discern the
distinction between how retail-minded
Traders and even back then in baby Pips
a lot of you didn't even think like a
retail Trader does you didn't know
anything you were just looking for the
next thing
there were retail Traders out there that
were hanging and banging still
unprofitable but they had a method of
what they were trying to make work but
they're trying to force a square peg
into a round hole it won't work you got
to cut some Corners off okay you got to
smooth out those rough edges and that's
going to happen by taking time and I had
to drag you across this spectrum of time
for a reason
if you look at Price action with a
single mindset that there's someone out
there that's trying to knock you out
there's someone out there that is an
adversary to you
someone out there is trying to
collectively work towards you not being
successful
if I sell that to everyone when I first
meet them
they plug their ears this guy's a
conspiracy nut he doesn't know what he's
talking about he's not responsible he's
blaming someone else and I'm the only
one in the whole room that knows what
the hell's going on
I'm the black sheep of the whole fold
and I got no problem being that because
all the other Lambs are getting
slaughtered
I'm still here 20 years plus and I'm
gonna be here hopefully Lord willing 20
more years
where are you going to be
are you gonna be in the same mindset as
a Trader trying to figure out what you
know what the next guy's doing instead
of saying I don't give a what the
next guy's doing
I need to know what I'm going to be
doing right now and I'm going to move
towards making it better for myself and
that way as long as I know I'm thinking
the way I'm thinking independently if
I'm wrong I'm not going to second guess
I'm wrong I'm going to know right away
I'm wrong and I gotta reevaluate what I
did there and try not to make that same
mistake again contrast that with
following someone copycatting their
trades
the guy's wrong ninety percent of time
he's not going to admit that he was
wrong he won't even admit to it he'll
suit you know he'll he'll gloss over it
or if it's a bad thing like he loses the
account or busts it or does something
really bad he just vanishes
yes the beautiful thing about the
internet people can pop up and be
millionaires instantly
but the real people hang around they
prove it over and over again okay and
they can take ownership of having
screwed up sometimes you miss an
opportunity you blow it you get stopped
out things like that's going to happen
but if you are tied to someone like that
whether they're a good Trader or not you
aren't going to come to the conclusion
that hey look this is wrong and no right
away you're going to be waiting on
baited breath to figure out what they're
going to say to give you the thought
process that you should have because
you've already subscribed to them being
the Brain Trust in the whole event
you didn't make the decision to take the
trade
so all these components that we have out
here as retail Traders all these ideas
and methodologies and applications and
processes and such unless it gets down
to the root
principle of you making the decisions on
your own and that's going to be whether
your Mentor thinks something's going to
happen in agreement or or
contrary to what you think
come hell or high water you're taking
that trade
you don't care what anybody else thinks
that's you this is you or you're owning
it and I don't care what the what the
outcome is going to be it's mine
because only you can take the spoils
from it
or the lumps from it
it's yours you have to own it so when
you look at Price action it's not just
simply looking at order blocks it's not
simply looking at optimal trade entry
retracements and tips okay it's not
liquidity voids and liquidity pools and
it's not institutional uh uh order flow
and it's not just
um Market maker Buy sell profiles and
fractal patterns and such it's not
animal patterns harmonics none of that
stuff
it all
gets back to this one thing
okay and
uh I watched a video a couple I think it
was a year and a half ago every time you
watch my videos you get these little
things that pop up as suggestions and uh
Jason Stapleton had one uh up on the
side here and I I don't know why but
curiosity this I clicked on it and he
was talking about the the one thing
you're all looking for that one thing
and it doesn't exist well that's
it does exist okay and I'm
gonna tell you what it is right now the
one thing is having your alignment
with institutional perspective
but because all of retail trading
Educators teach with a retail mindset
it's alien to them
and that's why they stay in the
education capacity they Market they sell
they make business profits on selling
education because it's a wonderful
opportunity to be risk free if they
don't make money for a subscriber base
they'll leave but they'll have the PT
Barnum effect if someone else will come
behind them and believe their horseshit
okay so they and I'm not trying to just
pick on Jason it's it's everyone really
the the idea of
sung this idea that there's not this one
thing because you don't know what it is
it just shows
with blinding uh you know
Clarity really it's not blinding it's
Clarity that they don't know what you're
learning
what I know for certain
there is a
method
how these banks operate and it repeats
all the time
they're small little variances when it
comes in and out of effect okay but by
far and large you're going to see that
these things repeat themselves all the
time
and if you spend your time trying to
align your thought processes with how
the banks would want to knock
individuals out why would they want to
come back here and run this high if the
overall premises is going to go lower
because it's going to be for stops
well that means when it's running up
here like this okay
maybe you get short
maybe look for a smaller time frame 15
minute turtle soup
over in here
expect a
unwillingness to continue higher
but because we saw this idea fleshed out
on a daily chart
it's going to be a lot of range still on
a five minute chart which is the reason
why you guys get dusted trading on five
minute charts without a higher time
frame premise because the daily chart
can trade a little bit past what you
think it can on a five minute
and sometimes 100 Pips or more
but unless you go through the process of
studying the higher time frame down the
lower time frame not the lower time
frame up to the higher time frame okay
it's the higher time frame down to the
lower time frame this is why I say and
I'm going to make this very clear
because
the one person I do respect in this
industry is Chris Laurie but I've been
very candid about how I do not like uh
the trading the volatility against the
institutional order flow I don't like to
do that because
new Traders
they don't have that understanding and
they are going to invariably take losses
and while that is
educational
by its by its very fact that they're
going to take a loss and they're going
to hopefully look into why they took a
loss
I know that new Traders don't go through
demo trading for months they'd maybe
open up a demo account to see how to put
a buy sell loader in and they made three
thousand dollars in five minutes so now
they're going to put their whole
checking account in their in their
trading account and they're going to
dust it really quick I don't I just know
human factor is they're going to rush to
get into trading live and while I do
believe the exercise of trading
volatility is just that it's an exercise
applied correctly with institutional
order flow it is wildly wildly
profitable so I want to make that
distinction I've said it on record a
couple different times where some have
taken and I think Chris maybe one time
said it in Twitter and I think it was a
veiled response to me because it says
there's some uh there's some groups that
say you know we should we shouldn't
trade this way or don't stand in front
of a train because that was actually the
analogy I used I I don't want to stand
in front of a freight train you know if
I'm if I see a primarily bullish Market
environment I'm sure as hell not trying
to get short in any capacity at all I
don't want to do that because the
largest expansion is going to be on the
upside and I want to hopefully be
positioned for that expansion
so when we look at for our time frames
okay you can use all those ideas of
trading volatility uh
liquidity pools and liquidity voids and
optimal trade entries and stop runs and
turtle soups all that stuff can be
incorporated but it's best utilized when
you can ascertain the institutional
order flow okay now watch I'm going to
put this into an example what it means
and why these levels are highly like
they are
the reason why I like this down candle
you thought I forgot about it didn't you
is because number one it's a down candle
which I know is buying on an
Institutional level
okay and I know that is true after after
we see the range expansion and it
engulfs this candle here okay now
granted you're probably saying well
that's wonderful it's already moved yeah
but you're already going to anticipate
it because it's below this old High
the trend is up it's a daily chart we
looked at earlier and it showed it was
moving higher we were just in a larger
consolidation but because we're in
looking at a four hour time frame
the moves that are going to be around
the levels we're talking about are going
to be dynamic they're going to be
explosive they're going to be Market
maker 12 setups
what yeah
this is how it works when when you see
price action on a daily and four hour
okay you want to know where price is
going where's the next setup is it going
to be a big move or is it going to be a
scalp how do I know if it's a day trade
and how long how do I know how to hold
on to a move when do I hold on to her
clothes and when do I hold on to a
larger price move
well they are all they're all answered
with a daily in the four hour
much the down candle we would have
anticipated this becoming
a buying opportunity right in here right
when that candle formed right here
with the expectation that it's going to
run this high
why would we expect this High to be ran
well we almost got equal highs to me I I
call this equal highs okay double tops
okay there's going to be a lot of
liquidity resting above that by itself
that's enough
but what's wonderful is keep going over
here
bingo
void you can use the low of this candle
or below this one it doesn't make a
difference it's both
above
or they are both rather above this this
High which is another reason why this is
going to be expectation for price to
move and start surging higher okay
price does in fact run through it
continues making a higher high And
Trades up into a level all this right
here was that bearish daily ICT order
Block in other words we expected selling
up in here okay just go back in the
beginning of the video where I before I
started talking about all kinds of other
stuff we had all this mapped out for uh
the 99 50 to 9920 levels remember that
that's what all this is in here okay and
then we further marked up this iced tea
breaker
watch what happens when price is coming
down say you were fortunate to catch the
cell in here based on this bullish
um I'm sorry bearish order block
and you caught this move when price
trades down into
that
you need to take some profits okay take
some profits don't expect it to
steamroll right on through and keep on
cutting through all these levels they're
going to be bounces around there okay
you need to expect that also notice that
because of this down move okay and then
price surges away what do you what do
you apply
to this model in price
Market make a cell profile because we
anticipate a selling an event up here
but until it can create that sell
scenario up to 99.29 950 level
it's got to trade up to it right so
overlay Market maker cell profile
consolidation it rallies away
reaccumulation smart money reversal low
risk sell
s off and then redistribution
where is it going to go it's going to
try to run below these lows it started
the consolidation which led to the
beginning of the market maker cell
profile
but
let me get to this point first
we know selling off here to likelihood
where is it going to reach for back down
to here
why there's a lot of orders down here
and it's in a primary uptrend still so
even if this is going to reverse or on a
longer term scale like we anticipate up
here
buying it here and filling in this void
or returning back to this breaker look
how much look how much range is there
we're going to use it very high so we're
going to get the worst case I'm sorry
the best case scenario for
low entry
I didn't say that right there the lowest
potential uh profit let's say it like
that
okay all the way up to there it's 84
Pips
hello 84 Pips who don't want 84 Pips
I've been doing this a long time I still
take 84 Pips
there's an exclusive move
trades into it you buy it now the rest
of the world isn't going to see that as
a buy they're gonna be like what the
hell is happening the Dollar's crashing
they're not going to see that as a buy
but when you buy it what are you holding
for
a return to the breaker and you're going
to take some profits there
do you anticipate continuing trading
through no why because the 9920 9950
level is a daily bear shoulder block
so you want to take your profits there
now guess what you can do you can go
short
what's the setup what's the explosive
Market maker 12 setup in this instance
selling it at the breaker
reaching for the liquidity below the low
here
it's that easy yeah
that's all it is
it's all it is why should it do that why
should you expect it to do this well
we've already mapped out the idea of the
breaker why it ran up here it took the
stops overall it's supposed to go lower
it shows the wellness to go lower this
is a reasonable area to balance why
because there's old order flow back here
hmm
sell it but now Watch What Happens
the orders that they bought here and the
orders they bought here
down here they're underwater
oh
that's going to be useful isn't it
how will we use that going forward well
we'll look at in a second going short
here up at the breaker
just getting the old low down here it's
97 Pips so we have 84 and 97. basically
200 Pips
two setups
one market
all inside of a day or two
the market runs down
below the low
and comes back up
trades in the body of the candle here
sells off what is it going to reach for
what it's going to reach for so
remember the last couple live sessions I
did last I think it was last week I'm so
out of touch I don't know if it was last
week or week four but I did a couple uh
live sessions and uh
I taught that there's primary questions
you need to ask it starts with two of
them really where is the where's fair
market value
and whereas institutional overflow most
likely going to take you to where's
liquidity okay well price had been going
higher right
So Below this low
is where stocks will be resting
once we cleared out this area here of
this order block
it's been violated here the only other
level of liquidity
below the market is here
you do have this bearish candle which is
of ICD bullish order block but you have
to look at it in context of where we are
on the grand scheme of things because up
here we framed out the idea that the
daily suggesting lower prices
so these bullish ICT or order blocks or
down cameras prior to up moves should do
what should they hold
or should they fail
they should fail
because the higher time frame daily is
going to have a lot more effect on and
we're going to talk about this in the
cable trade as a closer the this should
fail so it gives you a little bit of
prognostication value when you're
looking at order blocks when should you
look at a particular order block over
another well the idea of 99 29 950 up
here on a daily is suggesting lower
prices
and we gave up a key level here okay
because this is this is crucial because
we took out this level here with it and
we violated it here then we're unable to
get back above the bodies of the candle
here mitigated and then traded down we
blew the liquidity out here took out the
uh the stops
so where would the next level of
liquidity be
below these lows
equal lows okay so when price starts to
Rally up what's it rallying up to well
we went back to this level here
mitigated old High
should there be a a selling indication
well we'll see price starts to slide
down okay so now we have indications
that they're selling more so go back to
the up candle now here's where we got
that same uh question earlier
Michael when do you use the bottom of
the candle the wick or the body of the
candle when do you do that well let me
ask you a question looking at this
candle
is this a big beefy candle or is it a
small bodied candle
clearly it's a big beefy candle it's a
big body candle so this is when you use
the body
and you use the the middle of it okay
the mean threshold
you take your line
you draw it on there
right there okay see that it's the
Midway point of the body not the wick
the wick that's not what we're looking
at here guys we're looking at the body
of the candle and it's right in the
middle okay so let me highlight that
it's a little bit of a different color
because I want to make a strong
distinction between it and
the other lines I have on here that I
don't want to remove
uh yeah it's just gonna have to work
all right so price shows a willing to
sell off here so now our thinking is
this they sold it here above the halfway
point is liquidity that's too thin don't
expect that to be rated back into okay
expect the Middle Point down to the
bottom of the candle okay so what am I
saying I'm saying that we need to take
this into consideration
all right
there and that's how your bearish order
block
would be based on this Market
action in here
let's take this
save off
so when price trades back up into it
this is where you sell right there where
do you sell that well the low on this
candle
low comes in at 98.19 well right away we
know 9820 is inside that range those
institutional level 98.20 we got 98 30
small round number and we got 98.40
you see we highlighted 98.43 okay so we
could sell at 9840 98 30 and 98 20.
depends on what you want to find on a
smaller time frame dropping down in the
smaller time frames you'd have all kinds
of other setups but in here that would
be the cell right there
okay and what do you reach for
where's the where's the where's the two
things I ask you or instructed you
rather to look for when you're selling
or buying rather when you're looking for
your setups
where's liquidity
where's fair market value
liquidity is where the Market's going to
be drawn
based on institutional order flow it's
going to seek out liquidity and where's
fair market value
okay watch
the down candle probably this upswing
that led into the cell in here
that's fair market value right there
price you sell here
you get out down here
simple enough
now
if you have a strong conviction that
this is going to be a longer term High
you would just take some profits here
and leave someone but because we're in
what primary uptrend or downtrend on a
dollar
are you trying to catch reversals and
held for the very high and hold it for a
multi-year that may be what you want to
do I don't do that
you got to be aware that there may be
another deeper legged buying opportunity
for the dollar and I've been calling
dollar five dollar dollar two dollar
five on the Greenback for over a year
and I still believe it's possible to
happen
so
looking at that sung in here this is the
selling it up here we'll use the 30
level
halfway of that range
and just getting down to this level here
is 80 Pips it's a little hard to see it
yeah right there 80 Pips right there so
again explosive price action
trades down and then look what happens
it trades back One More Time Boom
take a look inside this beefy candle now
again are we going to look at the bottom
of the candle and use the wick only or
are we going to do what
are we going to break down the mean
threshold
big beefy bodies we do what we measure
the range of the body of the candle
you don't see this anywhere else
so it's not repackaged it's not
regurgitated
and then you take your line
place it right on the 50 level which is
all I did was highlighted again on the
FIB level
uh calibrated it just to show
equilibrium thank you Peter for showing
me that I spelled or misspelled
equilibrium wrong
the uh
the price action moves right up here now
look at the buys it it goes just a
little bit past
the halfway point but look how it
respects it now yes it Wicks through it
I'm not going to argue that it can do
this we said this before it can do that
but the bulk of the volume which is
always indicative and seen through the
bodies of the candle not the Wicks the
Wicks are going to always be the
thinnest price action it's reaching for
stops
this High here it runs through it and
then rejects it see that now
when you see this the next question is
what is this a liquidity void
from the low down here when it started
running up like we did here we did this
buying opportunity here where it runs up
we are in
a consolidation okay so the question is
did we blow through these highs no we
weren't able to blow through the highs
it's starting to break down so the
question is what where's liquidity
below the lows
so mark it if you sell it here you want
to reach for a move going below these
lows the market will look to take that
liquidity out
that's these loads right here
and it does it right there
then this rundown to get those stops
creates an opportunity
of candle inside of this void
price comes back up trades up into what
small little bodied candle it's not a
big beefy one right we don't even use
the FED now we do what we use the wick
to the body of the candle
I already see some of you smiling
already oh it's making sense now
see that aren't you glad you paid for
this with PayPal
best money ever spent
trades right up into
the dynamic resistance
this ICT Parish order block right in
here Midway point of it in fact also and
sells off
wonderful isn't it so
you have to have a storyline behind what
it is that you're trading and why you're
trading it you got to be looking for the
liquidity in the marketplace like the
banks do because they're pushing price
and they're buying and selling the drive
price on a short term to manipulate
price action okay because they know by
and large if they manipulate price to a
certain price level they they know
there's going to be a whole lot of
injection of action okay and that will
drive their price moves further they may
have more uh interest to sell higher but
they'll buy short term to push price up
just so the market price will print at
that level knowing that the funds which
you stops
will be triggered into the marketplace
or out of the marketplace respectively
and giving in the counterparty to the
trade the smart money or Banks do not
see your stops okay I am not teaching or
have nowhere have I ever seen myself
ever present a a a a case that the banks
see your retail stop in fxcm they don't
they don't see oh and does they don't
see etoro they don't see whatever else
uh you know these retail Brokers have
because they're outside that inner Bank
level they're inside of a small little
children's pool of liquidity and there's
a big vast ocean out there that great
big old sharks uh swimming and they know
that
the seals they hang out on those little
icebergs and they're going to be right
above the highs and right below the lows
and that's where the stops are and
they're just going to come in there's
like a killer whale they'll run up on it
and knock them off and just eat them so
either you either elect to be a killer
whale or you stay a seal there it is
there's your analogy for today so let's
take a look at the cable and wrap this
up because my stomach's ground I'm
hungry
um
surprise surprise the cable's lower
unless uh not sure how that happened
maybe because uh we said it was going to
happen
arrogance
all right so we have the cable
running lower let's take a look at what
I shared on Twitter real quick just for
continuity's sake before we get into it
I shared a couple levels on
Twitter
indicating specific lows and the low
comes in at 142.29
on this candle right here let me make
sure I'm getting the right one
yeah 4229 is the low
oh man I'm not going to get it like that
I'm gonna set it up
I can't see your comments but I promise
I will scroll through it later on to see
it
um
but I'm hoping that you guys are
learning something today because this is
really it really is higher level stuff I
mean when you when you learn these types
of things it's not indicator based it's
not mathematically derived it's the
psychology of the marketplace and the
institutions are the marketplace retail
is not we're fleas on a big dog so
there are the two levels that I tweeted
um 142.29 and 135 10 respectively these
are the levels here and because we were
in what type of Market profile what what
Market profile is this
is it range bound trending reversal
which one is it
range bound so in a consolidating market
like this the market will do what it
will seek liquidity above and below the
marketplace well we saw that happen here
it took out the old highs
and we traded down took out these equal
lows and then look at the nicer reaction
here this is a monthly chart
okay it took liquidity out and then
rallied up several months and then roll
back down
see that
look closely what do you see there right
in here what do you see right in here
now I'm going to go to the questions
section because I'm going to see if you
guys are actually saying anything here
that answers my inquiry
whoa It's got some long-winded uh
so uh I definitely will have to read
some of these statements after we close
this a lot of there's a lot of them
um
foreign
and if you look at hang on one second
okay sorry about that my
16 year old just came home
from school he does a part-time
works his job that he has to have for
credit and then he has
two classes in a day so he comes home
midday
I just want to make sure he didn't come
in and Holland so
we have a consolidating market okay and
we saw price take out the highs here let
me just throw that up so you can see how
it was
very good indication of a turtle soup
comes up blip hits it and rolls back
down what is it going to reach for
liquidity and fair market value
okay so price cleans out these areas
stops and then it bounces up where is it
bouncing up to
well ain't going all the way up here
there's no need for it to do that
because it gave a
reversal inside of the consolidation
okay because they the profiles can nest
we have a consolidation it takes out the
stops
okay and then it runs down if it's
reaching down for liquidity below the
marketplace it does it here
but there's no necessity for it to come
back up to that
but look close
look real close in here what do you see
I'm actually waiting for a response from
some of you
see that
this is the same thing that it just
described in the dollar
see the old high here
down candle right below the old High
see that
what's smart money doing here obviously
in hindsight we can see it but if you go
back in my market reviews we were
calling this thing higher all along
and it's all on video and I know you
guys have them recorded and downloaded
your computers call me on
Twitter if I'm not being honest but I'm
telling you we were we were long all
through here and calling for this old
High
but the smart money is buying on the
down move like that okay this is a
monthly candle a down candle okay so the
buy orders that they have here have to
be mitigated if it's going to go lower
they bought it this is how long term no
stop loss holding type thing they held
onto this position it multi-year
multi-year
you're not going to hear this stuff
taught in retail circuits
because they don't know it
Banks can sit on Long Long positions
macro view perspectives okay they can
sit on those positions they're hedging
that's one of the benefits they had that
we can't do that in America we can't
Hedge because once people knew that they
could trade like this you never lost
you never took a loss
not a net loss let's put it that way I
mean Physicians would be underwater but
eventually you could even work your way
out of it
the breaker right in here
trades right back up into it here
rolls over and then does what reaches
for the liquidity below the market here
and ultimately it still and is Will
going to take out the low here and if it
gets a lot of steam
which I expect a very I personally
expect a bounce of significance in here
I think it's going to be a sharp
reaction when it Trace that level but if
it continues to just mow right on
through it it's going to aim for this
low 135.02
uh what am I saying 135 is it 135.2
I don't think I did
the price level on that below 13503 so
yeah I have
to set this 13503
at least for this feed you'll have to do
it for your own individual platforms
to get your uh
your platforms uh price feed for that
particular level I'm referring to is the
January low of 2009 and in the low of
May 2010 or the two levels that I
suspect that cable is gunning for okay
and
um looking at a weekly chart
okay
we see price
let me get this I got I'm not I'm if
you're saying anything I'm not gonna be
able to see it so I will open up the
window in a minute where you're
commenting or questioning but I can't
see it for the next couple minutes
Z
equal lows in here
okay price sweat below it you can see
that very handsomely done here and one
more run below the low it created here
and rallied up rather aggressively where
is it reaching for
fair market value
sell off
big candle
use the middle of the candle mean
threshold
sell off
small little body candle prior to the
big move what do you use the wick to the
body
sell off
small little body candle
for the big move down what do you use
the body to the wick extend that out in
time you see all that distribution in
here sells off okay we have
a small body candle
right before a big candle here use the
wick to the body
sell off
price runs down and starts to break hard
taking out the lows here and reaching
for the liquidity resting at 140 29. we
go down to a
hang on I gotta remember what what I was
gonna say about this hold on
oh the most recent Traders did in uh
cable good grief
here's the daily
okay and price
um we talked about being selling or or
a selling scenario up in here
okay if you look at the beginning of
December I gave you I believe it was a
live session
I know it's recorded because it's it's
out there but we were talking about
um the market going lower here
okay and potentially reaching down into
this order block and whether we have the
the momentum to go through this low or
not would be have to be seen at that
time I think it's the exit uh
term I used and the way I was describing
it and obviously you can see it just
rolling in this steamrolling down I went
short make sure I've got a price here
I sold it and
[Music]
yeah I had a New York
session trade selling short
at
143.92
143.92 so let's go into a
15 minute time frame
and
show you
what I want to show you
143.92
now I don't have this mt4 demo account
linked to the one to my effects
otherwise I could just very easily just
pop it up there the one I I use that for
I do it with my iPhone so I'm just going
to go through the myfx book and confirm
everything I'm showing you is based on
what what you see here
so uh where are we at
um
and
1307.
all right
and that's on the wrong day
okay and
time is right here indicated by the
arrow
and we maximum
I don't know it could I mean I'm not
saying it will but I'd like to see it
drive down and hit that level live
that'd be awesome that's a little bit of
a range today not that it can't do it
but
still reaching
so we're in London close now so it may
not have the gas to do it but we have uh
price trading right in here okay and now
once you look close this is the candle
right in here I traded to that right
there
the big one that rallied up real strong
let me zoom in
my stomach is really really growling I
didn't eat breakfast today and I'm
regretting it now
so here's the candle uh
right
good grief
here it is
okay this is the candle I went in a long
one
and I want you to look at what you see
here
zoom in one more time because
this is very very important
we have this big rally up
okay big old rally
and price comes back down and slams
right into this what is this now let me
pull up the question segment up
I forgot to take this off
okay right in here price comes back down
into this liquidity void right here and
fills the range from here all the way up
here it comes right back down in other
words it looks like this
there's the range
explodes up takes out the stops here
rallies a little bit more
and then starts coming back down okay
and slams right into it
there right there okay
right in this candle
okay I'm thinking now
there's a tug of war on the setups
this time frame is a 15 minute time
frame
okay and it's exactly what I had on my
phone
Mike I'm I know I'm not saying I bought
it I never said that I bought it I'm
explaining something in contrast so you
know the benefits of why I did what I
did I never said I bought it
the uh
the the market rallied up here okay and
it came right back down into this level
right here what is this
what's this candle right here
bullish shoulder block
no problem no problem I appreciate your
enthusiasm though
the the fact that we saw a rally up like
this okay and a down candle
in normal market conditions okay if this
is a bullish environment this exact this
is exactly what you would expect to be a
buyer okay this is exactly how you'd
handle it it's in New York open okay
it's a wonderful setup and I I went in
with the idea shown and it's one of the
exercises I also teach that you have to
test one quarter block against another
order block
and this is the only way you you start
to appreciate the higher time frame okay
we're going to look at the higher time
frame in respect to what we're showing
here but I want you to see what I traded
short right into on a very very short
term this was screaming a buy
but it was a very short-term time frame
set up
nonetheless it could have paid out
handsomely but it's still a short-term
setup
I went short
rate at the time it was most bullish on
a very short-term basis
watch what takes place
rallies off strong
where's liquidity
above the high right does everyone agree
that the liquidity would be above these
highs or this High rather
I'm waiting for your response
you guys there
you still there
[Music]
can I get an audio check
you guys there hello hello
can you guys hear me
waiting for a response from one of you
guys to let me know
thank you very much I'm not sure what
just happened we had our lights this
Flicker and that connect our connection
from Comcast this was briefly cut
okay so I'm not sure how that's going to
affect the recording but if we're still
talking
um let me make sure it's still going
yeah it's still recording so you didn't
miss anything
all right so uh
as price is running up do we agree that
as prices rallying liquidity is going to
be above the high here
right so we know price is most likely
going to run up try to reach for this
high
and
price runs and takes out the high right
here
I sat through all this
without a stop loss order okay without
any protection whatsoever and no limit
order for profit objective
this is one of the things I want you to
do as well in your demo account this is
how you use the demo account okay you
want to see the effects of buying and
selling at higher time frame and lower
time frame
order blocks and you'll see the
reactions of it okay and by doing that
it will give you
input that you'll use for future trades
and either a demo account if you're
still on the development stage or in
live Trading
my question is this how could this be
used as positive reinforcement
even though it's in a demo account
how is this beneficial to you
by taking an exercise like this
and being short here how's that
beneficial to you seeing something like
this when it runs out like that how
would that be beneficial
well yeah Nino that's good trusting okay
trusting that uh
um you're able to see reactions and and
moves before you happen Okay but more
importantly if you do get caught up and
you take a trade and it starts to scream
against you you have to know where it's
most likely going to reach for and if
you're able to take the risk on
if you're able to take the risk on
and weather that okay and this is
another reason why you keep your risk
small because if you're only risking a
half percent or one percent
you're still within the uh the realm of
absorbing something like this now the
question is do you continue holding on
to it if it's rallying on through it no
but if you are willing to absorb
the move up to here and still stick to
your overall convictions that it's going
to trade lower
this is what you would this is what you
would take from it okay but I want to
show you the contrast between seeing a
short-term 15-minute bearish candle
which is a bullish order block seeing
the reactions of it like that but still
staying in the move
yes Brian you could have you could have
sold here on a turtle soup yes
Okay so
the price comes down and starts to roll
um
what do you see here
right here
and I am starving
look at the reactions in here see that
middle of this up candle
to go all the look at the biased candle
right there
sweeps in just a little bit above it
But ultimately starts to sell off
it runs
reaching for the order block right here
and
that's where we're at now
what's this
Fair shoulder Block it's up candle
though who sells in up candles
smart money Banks Deep Pockets people
with more money than icts for sure
the body of the candle
equilibrium
from the low up to the midpoint is where
you want to be seller
right in here
right there you want to be a seller in
anywhere in this in this area and only
if it's in a time zone that we'd like to
trade which is ICT Killzone for London
and New York open or London close
okay so
um have I satisfied the inquiry about
why I go back and forth with when I use
the Wix and when I use the bodies
okay if anything else
if nothing else rather at least at least
today we we've answered that and wasted
enough of your time doing it
um
yeah that's uh
that was the point of the uh the last
cable trade
um
obviously we know that uh in the last
couple times we talked live we were
calling cable lower
um
using a higher time frame setup
um holding on to the trade and taking
profits before
um because Average Joe's still in his
development State he's trying to learn
and Trust the order blocks and such so
I'm kind of give you a a real timeline
on what to expect what would be
considered normal in my opinion and then
you'll start seeing in a couple months
you'll see the stark contrast to doing
things a lot more
systematic could you comment on dollar
Bond decoupling uh yeah it's uh
something I'm not following at this time
uh because I do believe the interest
rate markets are about to crash uh all
debt instruments should be uh not traded
right now
um they're gonna they're gonna put a
whammy on everyone
um and that's one of the reasons why I
don't trade uh Bond Futures and I just
think that anyone in the instruments
right now
shouldn't be
um a 4X LTD 4X LTD Larry Tom Dick if you
do a search on Google for mt4 platform
Forex LTD they have the dollar Index
yes Patrick it's being recorded
uh uh the correlation s p and currencies
um
one that does really good with the s p
is uh Aussie dollar
do I always use smt for confirmation or
not
um
99 of my trades have some measure of an
smt
attributed to it yes
why do they manipulate the dollar when
so free retail Traders you trade it uh
well it's not that they're trading the
dollar per se but they're trading
against it uh when we're trading all the
payers the majors like the the pound
dollar
um if you're if you trade cable you are
trading the dollar you're just trading
it short
so the dollar is a barometer in my
opinion much like the stock indices are
like the Dow Jones NASDAQ and S P 500 if
the overall trend of the General market
and not the way I deem that is the
health or uh
strength or weakness of the overall
Market can be discerned by looking at
one
measure or device which being in my
opinion the dollar if it's
if it being the dollar is poised to move
higher uh that's like one of the best
scenarios for being a short seller for
foreign currencies it's it's really
simple
um it's not like rocket science but uh
it's one of the things that's very
foreign
often missed
mistaken for uh its Effectiveness or
importance
um okay
if you're looking for smt diverse if
you're looking for correlated payer s t
diversions okay
um
I didn't want to do this but it's really
good that I do it because it's going to
be a problem if I don't
um
Euro pound
I'm just curious did anybody else expect
this to go higher
did we not call Euro pound higher
we called this bad boy up okay so
with
when you look at this and this is what
makes foreign exchange difficult
admittedly
but when you understand it it works in
wonderful concert with three uh three
currency pairs
um the dollar always has to be a factor
in your trading okay and
based on what the dollar is doing is
going to be insightful what you do with
your foreign currency trades okay
um
the dollar is
in essence in
a consolidation
inside of a larger
uptrend
would everyone agree that that's the
case
okay so we're in a primary uptrend with
a dollar in a consolidation so they're
holding dollar
so by holding dollar
that gives the freedom for the other
foreign currencies to move rather strong
Okay so
there is two conditions that take place
and you can have the dollar trending
lower which would be a trending Market
higher in the foreign currency markets
but if they hold Dollar in a
consolidation you're going to see very
strong and sharp moves in foreign
currencies so there's a market maker 12
tip for you
if dollars in consolidation
okay it's in a holding pattern
that means that the accelerated moves
are going to occur not on the dollar
side of the currencies in other words
like uh
how would I say this
um
the dot like the British pound and the
dollar okay the British pound is going
to have a lot more freedom to move
versus the dollar seeing uh respective
mood like we see the cable
let's go over to the cable real quick
okay cable is
moving right along lower continuing its
primary downtrend
and looking at it
it's got a lot more freedom to move
lower in a trending environment whereas
the dollar is in a holding pattern and
it's still stuck in its range
respectively see that
we're going sideways
while the cable has freedom to go lower
in a trending move okay now
for the euro
let's go over to a four hour chart
now I know I'm going to open up a
Pandora's box with all this because it's
something I can't teach in one sitting
but euro is in a holding pattern as well
you see that we're in a very large
consolidation in which we called this
well well months ago earlier on in the
beginning of last year we said that when
we get down to these levels it may go
into a larger consolidation and trade
sideways for for a long period of time
it's in video you can go see it it's
there now you're probably saying what's
the big deal who cares it's you know
it's you can't think of any net well yes
you can because if you're in a large
consolidation in the euro
and you're in a consolidation in the
dollar
okay
think about what you got here
if you have a piece of paper and a pen
and if you don't have one shame on you
because you're watching a video with me
live you should always be taking notes
I want you to take
um on your piece of paper in like a
triangle formation okay I want you to
write uh the dollar
at the center of your piece of paper
lower left I want you to write Euro
in the lower right I want you to write
British pound
okay so you have the top of the triangle
is a dollar the lower left is Euro lower
right is the British pound
right now
Dollar on a four hour basis is
consolidating
it's in an uptrend but it's
consolidating you can see that so you
have to circle the dollar
the euro
is in
the consolidation as well
in a primary downtrend
so you need to circle the euro
now watch
British pound
ing lower
it's in a trending environment
okay
now I don't know if you ever studied
fractions or or whatever in school but
if you didn't study fractions this is
probably going to be a little tricky for
you but it's really simplistic when you
understand fractions the
the dollar in the Euro are in
consolidation they're in holding
patterns okay
the cable is being permitted to move
lower okay
the British pound is dropping while the
euro is sideways to up
now in those environments people like
Steve Morrow which learned my stuff
partially and ran with it and tried to
make money doing it I never explained
all the things that you're learning in
Market maker 12 or a market maker series
really until I just recently started
doing it so that's the reason why when
you watch his horseshit on YouTube he'll
say that correlation doesn't work
correlation works perfectly but you have
to understand why the banks are doing
what they're doing and holding certain
currencies in consolidation to allow
other currencies to run
and it's done by manipulating the whole
board
or
working the crosses
and what I mean by that is we have those
three currency pairs there okay I'm not
currency pairs or currencies you have
the dollar which is the king it's above
everyone else
you're on the lower left both Euro and
dollar are in consolidation
cable or British pound is allowed to
move it's been trending lower it did not
enter into a consolidation it's trending
lower
because the cable
or British pound is in a trending
environment lower dollars in
consolidation and fiber is in
consolidation
that means the trade is going to be in
what pair
draw a line connecting Euro and pound
on your chart that you just drew or a
picture connect Euro in British pound
if cable or British pound is dropping in
a trending environment and Euros being
held what reaction and price action what
direction would that indicate
or ex what you would expect to see in
Euro pound what direction should it go
up or down
now
you want to make millions of dollars
these are the types of setups that you
look for because they happen a couple
times a year
they are
unbelievable loaded deals I mean it's
like they are so telling that they you
can't miss it but you have to understand
the Dynamics behind it otherwise it'll
completely be oblivious to you
now
for those if you're just watching this
for the first time it's going to sound
like well I mean of course now the Euro
pound's been rocketing up I mean it's
been going up for hundreds it's hundreds
of Pips Michael of course now you're
going to come out and say this stuff
works like that
well if you were with me the beginning
of December
um I was telling everybody this thing
was going to roll and Roll and Roll okay
and
where we're at is Euro pound I know I
got this here
's Euro pound
and
let's go over here
excuse me
we have
the market
trading down into what
what's this right here
pull a shoulder block who buys in Down
Candles
Banks
okay
we have a small little range what makes
it a small range look around it there's
bigger ranges and there's a smaller
range there's a smaller range in
contrast to the bigger ranges okay all I
did was use something I learned from
Larry Williams my mentor small ranges we
got large ranges and large ranges we got
small ranges okay so this is a smaller
range I'm going to use the wick to the
body
and
we're cutting through candles guys so
throw all the supply and demand
horseshit out the window you got to go
through the candles and find out where
the primary Pro uh the the parent price
swing starts here
okay they come down and dip into the
door block here but what time frame is
this
daily
can eat into that order block especially
if it's going to be a sizable move
right here you go
boom takes off now think
what do you see here
they're all flashing it's a market maker
buy profile
foreign
a buyer okay the mechanics are dollars
in consolidation Euros in consolidation
we said you're was most likely going to
go into consolidation before it went
into consolidation how did I know that
why did I say those words because I
study Market profiling and I'm not
talking about Market profile where they
have all those bars vertically along the
horizontal I'm sorry horizontal lines I
guess shown volume or whatever around
specific price levels which I don't have
any faith in okay when I say Market
profile I'm talking about is it in a
market trend is it a consolidation or is
it reversing there's a three market
profiles
okay
JP
um I think you're probably the only one
that can't hear me
so if you're hearing this in the
recording I understand that everyone
else is able to hear me so it's
something that's
limited to you
but we have the Euro pound free to Rally
okay and if it's going to Rally how far
is it going to Rally what's the
structure behind all the rallying it
should take place well we have a
consolidation Market drops down into an
areas of buying smart money reversal low
risk buy inside of a bullish order block
rallies off
reaccumulation takes off the top of the
consolidation
if
you see trades like
um
well you can do the same process with
the kiwi and Aussie okay you just look
at the price action between the dollar
the kiwi and the Australian dollar
okay the same thing you can do with the
Japanese Yen
Euro and the cable
just replace the dollar with the yen
and you look at the difference between
our are you seeing the yen in
consolidation or is it trending
or is the Euro consolidating or is it
trending or is the pound
your consolidating or trending okay and
by having those three on there by seeing
which ones are being held the other
one's going to be freed up they're only
going to hold two
okay they're only going to hold two in
this Triad now when you're looking at
two pairs
okay because you can have correlated
setups like this as well where they'll
hold Euro sideways okay and they'll run
cable and they'll run dollar
so there's a there's a little bit of a
thing that uh has to come by experience
and that unfortunately is going to have
to be worked out for by you okay and
it's a knack type thing it's an
experienced thing I wish I could say
this is you know what you do every
single time but it's just an experienced
thing that you have to build in your own
trading okay but these are the building
blocks how you get to it because like I
said I can't see where the orders are on
the banks I can't see them really okay I
just know how they're most likely going
to be layered into the marketplace and
where they're most likely going to reach
for based on that and if I start seeing
signs that a particular currency is
being held in consolidation they're only
going to hold a currency in
consolidation to allow the cross to move
and the easiest way to describe it is
what we just did here with the Euro
pound okay and how you use that sets up
astronomical trading opportunities where
if you see it happening and it's only a
couple times a year it does it you know
it's not every single pair it does it
but there's a couple times where they
set up like these Mega trades and when
you see it it's just like man it's so
telling what they're doing so I'm not
sure where you are in your scope of
trading but if you could get into an
area of uh you know taking a trade
around the 70 level
down here knowing that the likelihood is
going to run up to here and clear out
that not so not even so much as this see
it just gets back to here okay if you
can find trades like that every year
just one of them and you use your uh
your money
management and your trade setups if you
can you set up a trade down here with
20 30 Pips risk to well let's see what
it is I'm not sure what it is really top
my head um
it's over 500 Pips and ultimately it's
gone now to set over 700 Pips
um they usually last several weeks to a
couple months because they're macro type
events that's being set up when you're
looking at a daily chart now these same
phenomenon take place on Lower time
frames too like you can see dollar being
held in a small consolidation on an
hourly basis where euro is ripping and
cables being held well that's going to
indicate the same thing we're kind of
seeing here it's wherever pair whatever
currency is being allowed to move
if the other one's dropping you got to
look at how that relates to like the
Euro pound euro is being held won't drop
with cable okay and it's going the other
direction or staying in consolidation
and if the cable is really tearing lower
like we've been seeing that's going to
be 100 bullish for Euro pound because
Euro won't be going down with cable it's
going to be holding up and because pound
is the second in the currency pair of
Euro pound it's going to allow Euro to
um or Euro pound to show appreciation
going higher and not see it Go lower and
it'll be dynamic it won't be this little
muddled little slow increase over time
it's going to be like boom boom boom
real hard like you see here it's
indicative that you see it right here
that's how you find explosive price
moves it's not seeing
um them both moving in tandem you won't
see these explosive moves that you're
seeing here when Euro and cable are
moving in tandem it can't happen it can
only happen when one's being held and
they're holding it to create these
environments like this
does that make sense
okay there's a lot of questions you guys
are asking and I really wish I had the
time to get all over them but the
wonderful thing about this uh this
platform is it logs everything that's
said to me in question format so that
way if I don't get to your question or
comment while we're doing the recording
or presentation it gives me an
opportunity to go through it and I can
sometimes answer it in a future video or
sometimes as easy as a tweet so if I
didn't get to your stuff
um or or question or whatever I
apologize but it really is a ton of them
I mean there's so many of them coming
they're still flipping by so yeah so the
uh the recording is
um obviously recording still with the I
will have to uh
cut it here I want to be able to make
sure I get this uh
this recording out to you before I go
out with my wife tonight so
um
give me some time to get it formatted
it's really quick usually when a format
to MP4 with uh this Pro with this
platform and then obviously uploading it
to my uh my server doesn't take long at
all so
um
I'm going to close it here
I'm starving and I'm not sure how long
we've been going at this but uh it's
been a couple hours I think but the uh
three hours thanks Mike it didn't feel
like three hours though I was thinking
like two hours but it's three hours good
grief
well
um I'm gonna let's say I'll close it
here
this is not one of those videos you
watch one time okay this is one of those
videos where you can listen to while
you're driving back and forth to work a
couple times a week okay uh listen to me
because a lot of it's a lot of jaw
boning okay
um only really watch it when it gets to
the charting stuff where we're actually
talking about examples but the first
part of the video is really good uh
commute discussion if I offended you
with uh my language please just that's
not my intent to do that but sometimes I
just get a little passionate about some
of the things I say and the human enemy
comes out so with that guys I wish you
good luck and good trading and give me
some feedback on Twitter if this was
insightful to you have a good week and
I'll talk to you next weekend
well actually I said that backwards now
have a good weekend I'll talk to you
next week how about that see you guys