welcome to the ICT mentorship short-term
trading lesson number six
we're teaching low resistance liquidity
runs in trending conditions
okay much like we mentioned in the low
resistance liquidity runs in
consolidations
the same thing applies obviously in
training conditions because we
understand that the market moves from a
time and price Theory
for looking back 20 40 and 60 trading
days for if the data ranges and
referencing time
and for one shot one kill or short-term
trading we focus primarily in the last
three months for the most Salient
institutional reference points
we key off of obviously the PD arrays
based on a premium or discount Market
and we're looking to trade from one PD
array to the next ideally from a
discount to a premium range that can be
easily defined
okay for our case study for liquidity
runs and training conditions we're going
to be looking at the pound again
and this time we're going to be looking
at a different fractal of the larger
consolidation so we're going to be
looking at a smaller segment of this
price action
and because price is universally fractal
what could be a consolidation on one
time frame can be a trending environment
in another
so we're going to add our PD arrays from
the monthly weekly daily and we're going
to use this information in conjunction
with the trending environment conditions
that we use to trade from a low end
discount to a high-end premium Market in
other words we're going to be looking at
an example of buying during a upswing or
a trending bull market
our case studies going to be focusing on
this price lag here
as identified in the Shaded area
and this is going to be our trending
condition
now before we get into it notice that we
are originating the
basis of that swing up
from a deep discount Market overall
the larger consolidation we can see
clearly that the market has found
support
and because we're in a discount Market
the market generally is going to want to
move to a premium either by a short-term
basis or any turn basis or a long-term
basis so since we're looking for
short-term trades we know that
predominantly the market in the March
time period
is in a oversold condition
in oversold condition
or defined as we refer to it as a
discount market so the market is going
to want to reach up into some measure of
a premium
if there's a displacement and the market
trades higher we'll know that because
the market is showing a aggressive
nature to trade higher and if that is
being shown in price then we know that
institutions are funneling money and
they're also building positions in that
up move now obviously if they are
building long positions and the market
is accelerating on the upside they're
reaching for some institutional
reference point where they can unload
that long position at a profitable point
they have to find willing buyers at a
higher level so we have to look for
premium PD arrays where willing
participants in the marketplace will
want to buy from a lower holding long
holder or in this case smart money
okay for one shot one kill uh we're
gonna be dealing specifically with the
four hour chart now the four hour chart
is in my opinion the easiest Trading
time frame for one shot one kill setups
or how to frame that's set up
uh because it's my cup of tea if you
will it's my forte my my go-to trading
model
um
I have learned that the four hour chart
can give us all the insights that's
necessary for using all the details and
and components to finding one shot one
kill or short-term trading with high
probability trading conditions
so by using a four hour chart
it's easier to frame a One-Shot one kill
or short-term trade
in this time frame because you can see
with a simple couple clicks of your mt4
platform and if your platform doesn't
use this whatever the equivalent would
be but if you hold down
control and touch the letter Y
it'll give you the date dividers
okay and specifically when you're in
four hour it's not giving you the daily
dividers it's actually giving you the
weekly dividers so every vertical dotted
line here represents the beginning and
end of a new trading week
when we look at Price like this and we
have the PD arrays on our chart it's
very easy to see where price will reach
up to notice that we're also looking at
this pair with the gradients shown
across all of the discount and premium
ranges so we not only have the discount
premium range divided
then we have the upper portion divided
and then we have those smaller divisions
in half as well so we can see how the
market has different levels of
progressive premium and Progressive
discount levels in other words lower
levels of discount and higher levels of
Premium
when we look at the four hour chart and
we can see a PD array for instance a
discount PD array this could be in the
form of a bullish order block an old low
a fair value Gap a breaker any of these
types of PD arrays
if we're looking to go long
if that occurs or forms near a
divider level or a quadrant level as I
call it you'll be able to see high
probability
movement away from that level and then
reach for an opposing level for instance
if we look at the market
in March
15th where price had come down into the
fair value Gap it also trades back to a
breaker
seen here
that move
trading to that level
gives us an ideal scenario to get along
we may have missed the entry at a lower
level
but we can see this return to a breaker
or
fair value
and Market explodes on the upside And
Trades higher
you don't need the absolute low in a
bullish weekly close or up weekly range
to be a One-Shot one kill you just need
one setup that you wait for that makes
logical sense that gives you a realistic
pip objective and I think realistically
uh for starters you should be looking
for 30 to 50 Pips a week those types of
scenarios and then graduate into 50 to
75 and then 75 to 100 Pips per week I
wouldn't try to go more than 100 Pips
and I like to live in a 50 to 75 pit
range myself personally but you do to
suit yourself I just know that you're
not always going to get big weekly
ranges sometimes you'll get small weekly
ranges and it's going to be harder for
you to get that 100 pit range if it only
moves about 150 Pips for the week so
you're going to really Define a perfect
entry and exit strategy to get that I'm
not saying it can't be done folks but
you know just give yourself some
flexibility on both ends getting in and
getting out and so if you're looking for
the lines portion of the weekly range
you know
taking a portion of that is all that's
necessary for your career
so if you look at the four hour chart
what we're doing is we're encapsulating
the weekly range and you can see this is
the entire weekly range for this
particular week
shaded in yellow
you can also see that the market reaches
up into logical areas of Premium PD
arrays and we'll cover that in a few
moments but look at this for a second
and think about the power three that I
teach where if the Market's bullish the
open will be near the low or the range
and the close will be near the high of
the range
you can see that here
the market has a initial move lower
in the beginning of the week makes the
low of the week and then it explodes on
the upside it gives a few not many a few
high probability entry points if you
missed a very low point it's not a
problem look at the four hour chart with
all of the monthly weekly daily PD
arrays obviously in the four hour to
keep this chart clean
I didn't add the four hour PD arrays you
can add them and you'll have more detail
on this chart and you'll have more
insights to trade off of but to keep
things germane and only on the higher
time frame we're just using the PD
arrays from the monthly weekly and daily
levels
and the subsequent week
is seen here same scenario the market
trades down initially making the low of
the week and look at the response off of
the divider between the total
macro consolidation that we did and we
discussed in the beginning of lesson
number five for cable
that removing
that movement down into the the Midway
point or equilibrium of the overall
consolidation
that is a high probability level in
itself now if you don't understand how
to break a range down or grade a range
or Price swing you're going to miss
these types of moves so you have to
always look at the trading ranges that
the Market's trading in look at the
highest high and the lowest low in the
form of the bodies not the Wicks and
Define that and then once you have that
that's like your master blueprint if you
will and you start breaking that down
because the algorithm is going to work
within that range it's going to go back
to reference points based on time and
price where price is already traded
where it hasn't been traded to in
reference to time so
we're looking for that same move that
originated in
March 14th uh
going into the 15th that low formed in
cable
that was in a discount Market the second
week that shaded in yellow here sees us
reaching up into a halfway point of the
upper portion of the total range or in
other words half of the premium
range that we defined by the daily chart
in its larger trading range
it moves from one level of logical
discount to another level of logical
premium it's very discernible you can
clearly see it
just by just grazing over this chart
real quickly you're not going to get the
benefit of looking at Price like this if
you just if you don't study it basically
and see the reactions how price is
moving and gravitating towards how I've
broken down the range
they act like
um magnets if you will there's a
component to trading that people like to
put on a truck I and I used to use I
used to trade with it as well
I used to trade with it as well they
were called pivot Points and well they
still are called private points to be
honest but they came from the four
Traders and and pit Traders where they
would do calculations based on the high
and the low and and adding specific uh
measurements to get the projected highs
and lows and supposed resistance now
that was like a self-fulfilling prophecy
but when you look at the the grades of a
trading range or a price swing it helps
you really discern where the market has
its highest probable support or
resistance without really having a
logical old reference point like when we
do support and resistance we look for an
old level we draw it out in time and
just because it did something back then
we expected to do it again in the future
and you've seen how that's worked out in
your own trading it doesn't have any
consistency so you have to look at what
the institutions are doing and look
behind the scenes and what's the
institutional order flow so if we can
grade A price swing from a premium or
discount measure we can see the market
was clearly in a discount range in the
14th of March so by trading down there
trading into the fair value you got to
shaded in green the natural response
with BC price trade higher it does that
and then it starts finding new levels of
support institutionally based
based on a discount
PD array in other words we're looking
for reasons to support price it could be
in the form of a bullish order block
fair value Gap a breaker a mitigation
block it could be a old low or an old
High
once broken now turning support all
those ideas okay lend well to supporting
price going higher and you you start
working towards a premium Market intra
week the more we get closer to another
level of Premium based on defining your
range and defining your price swing
and Grading it
you know it's breaking it down into
quadrants and then splitting in half
when the market reaches for these
measures okay it's almost like a mile
marker for the algorithm it will reach
for it and then give the participants at
the bank opportunities to facilitate
trade if it
breaks through a level okay and it
trades right through it you know that
it's going to most likely reach for the
next level up okay very rarely do you
see any Midway points uh between the the
grades that I've already given you here
in or it's the way we Define the market
breaking it down and cutting the the
ranges in half
the way we did that in lesson five
that's the same levels we're seeing here
so I didn't add anything new except for
the shading of the yellow the box I'm
just giving you the context behind the
market and why it was doing what it was
doing now clearly obviously one would
say okay well this is obvious you know
armchair quarterbacking it's a hindsight
but if you go through the charts it's
the same thing happening almost all the
time so by having the theory behind why
it's doing what it's doing we can look
for how
each week
this same component or element to one
shot one kill will repeat itself
looking closer
we can see that each week that the
market
we trade is going to seek to trade from
one PD array to another
it will trade from one quadrant to
another with the least resistance it can
move from premium to discount or
discount to premium Market valuation now
the determination of whether it's going
to move higher or lower is based on
where we're trading at at the time when
you're sitting in front of the charts if
we're in a premium Market it means we're
really pushed up and we are into a
logical area of where price has shown a
willingness to sell off before it's away
from its lowest levels of historical
buys or where old lows have formed
basically how we framed premium and
discount Works we've already taught in
this mentorship
but when we have the levels on our chart
and it's in a four hour basis it gives
us context it tells us how we can
anticipate the full weekly range because
these daily or in this case you know
four hours a weekly divider by hitting
control and tapping y you get these
vertical lines on mt4 what you'll end up
doing is each week before the market
starts trading on a Sunday and what you
want to do is just load up your four
hour chart have your PD arrays loaded on
there
and make notations on where you think
price May logically reach up to when
it's in a discount Market
or where it may reach down to when it's
in a premium Market
by looking at where the PD arrays are
in a four hour chart it's almost like
you can anticipate what the weekly range
will do
in a completed sense in order to what
the market looks like after the week
closes on Friday and in a good example
or exercise in this case would be to do
this every single week try to anticipate
what the weekly range will look like now
you're not going to get this all the
time it's not going to be perfect and
many times you're not going to be close
to it at all but what it will do is it
will help build your anticipatory price
skills which is necessary to start
seeing this stuff before it happens
we're trading in probabilities we're
looking at a statistical Edge that the
market if it's in a premium it's most
likely going to want to trade lower
where does it trade down to it's not
just looking for a support level it's
looking for an old area of institutional
order flow where was their old buying
where was their old institutional order
flow seen in the marketplace and it's
going to be in the form of a PD array
so we look at our PD array Matrix to
determine what are those PD arrays that
exist in your chart at the time and you
look at how reasonable it is for it to
reach down into or up into that level
between the two vertical lines
you only have Monday through Friday well
Sunday's opening until Friday so you
have an element of time that you have to
work within
so because it's relatively short term in
nature it's easy to predict where the
market may go between
a Monday and a Friday and you don't have
to have the highest high and you don't
have to have the lowest low you just
need to know what's the probable
Direction and what levels will it most
likely key off of that's the benefit of
using a four hour chart and using the
PDA arrays from the monthly weekly and
daily and
four hour if you want to have all that
on here but nonetheless if you key off a
daily weekly and monthly PD arrays on a
four hour chart you're going to get the
highest probable trade reactions and
that's where the institutions step in
now when you refine it down to a lower
time frame obviously in an hourly chart
you get more detail you get more
opportunities to you know reduce the
risk and you might get another
opportunity if you missed the overall
daily or weekly
PD array in other words if you missed
that entry it may give you one more shot
to get on it with an hourly chart but
it's better if you just train yourself
to work off of a four hour chart and
start to Envision
and kind of more or less predict what
the weekly range is going to look like
here's an example here where the market
trades down into the fair value Gap
we're in a deep discount Market
and for that week it trades up into a
bearish order block
the subsequent week we have the price
trading down into the equilibrium price
point
of the total macro range from the daily
chart that we showed in lesson five and
it also trades back down into an old
bullish order block from the previous
week
and then the market trades up and closes
in a fair value Gap
seeing back in February
now taking this information and refine
it even further down into a 60 Minute
chart you'll start to see a little bit
more definition in the market and
looking closely you'll see that there
are many times you'll see Breakers and
mitigation blocks that didn't exist on
your four hour chart
so
anything less than a one hour chart when
you're looking for one shot one kill
really reduces the effectiveness because
what you're looking for is that impulse
price swing to help facilitate the
weekly range or complete the weekly
range anything less than a 60 Minute
chart you're really just day trading or
you're scalping
so that's why you want to focus
primarily on a four hour chart for the
the levels you want to key off of but
once you get down into an hourly chart
then you can break the market down into
a day by day basis and then we can start
incorporating day of week phenomenon so
if we're looking for a bullish Market
moving from a discount Market to a
premium each week
what we're looking essentially for is
the low of the week to form between
Monday Tuesday and Wednesday they are
the highest probable trading days in
this environment so the criteria is in a
trending environment we expect price to
trade from a discount to a premium in
this case we would reverse everything if
we were expecting lower prices from a
premium down to a discount Market
but we have all our PD arrays on our
chart and our levels and our quadrants
on so we have all of our natural support
resistance which is the grading of all
of
the levels that we did in lesson five
and then incorporating the actual PD
arrays in reference to the if the data
range in the last 60 20 and 40 days
the low of the week in bullish
conditions in trending environments we
look for the Monday Tuesday or Wednesday
low to form
in the first week we see here Monday
Tuesday and Wednesday the low forms on
Tuesday notice the low forms off of a
logical PD array in a discount fashion
trades down to a fair value Gap that's
seen on the daily chart so price trades
up creates a high that's slightly higher
than Monday's high on Wednesday and then
breaks through it and creates a higher
high for the week so the intra week high
is formed on Wednesday notice on
Thursday it trades down into the fair
value Gap
into a mitigation block also from
Wednesday's intradays trading and the
market does what another impulse print
price selling higher all the way into
Thursday goes into consolidation and
then Friday it has a small little Judas
swing trades down into equilibrium
and then expands on the upside
going into the close
the second week or subsequent week in
our case study we see the low forms on
Monday after it hits the equilibrium
price point of the overall macro
consolidation as we defined in lesson
number five
and then Tuesday we have a read trade
back down into that same old low so we
had another retouch of
the equilibrium price point and then
acceleration on the upside
and then Wednesday we have another
opportunity to get long trading off of a
breaker that's formed on that week's
Monday so we have Wednesdays trading
trading down into a breaker
uh
a bullish breaker
formed on Monday's high Wednesday's low
is
formed off of that
trades higher and then notice also while
we had slightly bullishness on Thursday
and then a relatively flat close on that
week's Friday
um
one of the things I want you to see is
when we go through this com this process
you're going to quickly learn that
typically the weekly ranges they have a
30 to 50 percent of the weekly range
completed between Monday to Wednesday in
other words by London close on Wednesday
30 to 50 percent generally the range is
completed so what does that mean
if we have the willingness to to look
for Longs only we expect the market from
a discount to a premium to unfold for
the week
if we do not capture the long
either Monday Tuesday or Wednesday and
it has happened to potentially form and
we've seen some price actions that
suggest that that Weekly range is going
to be up close or bullish as we expected
but we didn't get to trade on
uh maybe we're stopped out maybe we
missed it all together
or maybe we were wrong and we found out
later in the week that oh yeah this is
probably what's going to happen now
because that's going to happen as well
uh you may expect something to unfold uh
for the week and then it doesn't do that
and you have to be flexible and change
gears and we're going to talk about that
in lesson number seven but
if you've missed the Monday through
Wednesday phenomenon
and the Market's already traded just
know that
it's important not to get PIP drunk
trying to get a lion's portion of a move
by Friday's close
because the weekly range may end up
being smaller or less volatile than
you've anticipated so just know that
generally a third or half of the weekly
range is done by Wednesday's London
close
and don't expect a massive move higher
or lower in in the last two days of the
trading week
generally if you get an explosive move
usually on Tuesday or Wednesday Thursday
May see a little bit of following follow
through but then Friday has either
retracement or does what you see here in
the second week where it's basically in
neutral close it doesn't really do
anything more stunning than what was
seen in Thursday or Wednesday's Trading
so we're going to build on the idea of
this and incorporate how to know when
there's going to be an inch or week
reversal
so until next lesson I wish you good
luck and good Trading