welcome back folks this is lesson 2.1 of
january 2017 ict mentorship
we'll be teaching
using 10-year yields in a higher time
frame analysis
okay 10-year notes in higher time frame
analysis you can see here on the right
hand side we have a seasonal tendency
for the 10-year treasury note
and i want to take a look at the
seasonal tendency chart for a minute
and try to
see where the most
significant price swings occur
and don't worry we'll be able to zoom in
in a moment but you can see primarily
there is a january february high
it trades down to a june low
and then a june low trading up into
december's highs
so there's two primary or dominant
cycles in the seasonal for
treasury notes
and it's bearish for the first half of
the year and then bullish for the second
part of the year
this teaching is going to give us an
example where that takes place
and we're also going to see when the
seasonal tendency doesn't have an
influence on
the market and we're also going to see
when the market actually performs
adversely or contrary to the seasonal
tendency
okay before we get into it some quick
notes for you when we chart the 10-year
treasury prices or the futures contract
we're using barchart.com
when we chart the 10-year treasury
yields
we'll be using investing.com both of
these websites are free
and some quick notes for you treasury
prices are inverted to its yield
as treasury prices
drop that means the futures contract for
the 10-year treasury notes when that
price drops on the chart
that shows a treasury yields increase
as treasury prices rise
treasury yields decline
as a general rule of thumb long-term
funds
seek yield that means money will be
placed or
allocated in areas at which it will seek
the majority or most
return on investment
okay the dollar index has it relatively
easy or it can rally when the yields
increase
and this is seen when the futures
contract prices drop on the 10-year note
and the dollar has its easiest or most
opportune time to decline
when yields decrease
this is seen when the treasury futures
price rise
okay here we have a zoomed in
seasonal tendency on the 10-year
treasury note
and i want to take your attention to the
first portion of
the seasonal tendency and this is in
january to february there's a high that
generally forms and it trades down into
around june
or middle of the year
and around june july
it's really like the last week of may
really if you look at it it's the last
week of may
and
rolls into the first week of july
usually it makes a seasonal low there
and in the 10-year treasury notes
usually rally the rest of the year
now
if we have
this seasonal tendency on the underlying
futures contract price in other words
on the treasury prices
this is not the yield the yield would be
inverted okay so in other words if we're
watching the june july low and prices on
the 10-year are rallying
that means interest rates are actually
dropping
so it's going to be an adverse effect or
inverted
effect on the yield
if we see this occurring
in the
10-year treasury
we should be seeing what in the
dollar index if we could show a seasonal
tenancy which we happen to have one in
the next slide by the way
if we have the dollar index as a
seasonal tendency
should this be occurring
at the same time that we see the june
july rally
should that be occurring with
a bullish or bearish move in the dollar
index
uh here's that seasonal tendency for the
dollar
and you can see
around the january february time there's
usually a rally that takes place which
is
contrary to what we saw in the 10-year
treasury notes declining
then we have a significant high forming
between
june and july
and then the dollar index typically
trades down the rest of the year usually
making a low around the last week of
october first week of november and it
creates a small little bounce on
november time period for
the dollar index
so the primary two trends in this market
for the dollar that is in alignment with
the seasonal tendencies seen in the
tenure
is there is a bearish tone to the
marketplace for the dollar index
mid-june
to july
and then we also see some rallying on
the dollar index the beginning of the
year
going into march
now there is a seasonal tendency for
dollar to decline march into may
but that would have to be in bearish
markets
and in bullish markets you could expect
to see november be a buy
may
be a buy
and january be a buy for dollar index
and the sales come in that
march june july
and there's one in uh september
and it usually creates uh some short uh
high in the latter portion of november
let's go back to the 10-year treasury
notes just for a moment
okay you see there's a strong
contrast between the two
and that means that we do have a high
probability scenario for if
the 10-year treasury notes are rallying
in the in the futures price
that means that the yield
will be doing the opposite they'll be
going down so interest rates will be
dropping
the interest rates are dropping that's
going to cause the tendency for
yield seeking traders or investors to
avoid the dollar index
because if the interest rates are
dropping
that's not going to
incite wanting to buy
dollar-based assets
so
the reason why we're seeing this adverse
effect here is because there is a direct
inverted relationship between the two
so if we have this blending of these two
markets it gives us a context to work
with if we're going to be looking for
quarterly shifts in the marketplace okay
here's the 10-year treasury note this is
the
september contract of 2015.
and remember that we saw the seasonal
tendency to form a low in june july
and a 10-year treasury node
contract for september because the u
in
symbols name znu15
left hand corner that u stands for the
month of september that's the delivery
contract of september
you can see that the contract prices or
treasury note prices started to rally in
june
that means that the yields are going to
be decreasing or declining and that's
going to be bearish for the dollar index
you see in june july we made a
short-term high traded lower we violated
the low in may
and then look what happens between
mid-june
into july and august
the dollar index actually has a little
bit of a rally
at the same time going back to that
september contract of treasury notes
10-year
the same time the treasury notes were
rallying
with its seasonal tenancy if we look at
the dollar index
it was slightly bullish as well so when
we see this scenario
we are looking at the likelihood if
they're moving in tandem that means
we're actually going to be in a large
consolidation
that means it's not going to be a
trending environment most likely and
that means we want to look for previous
highs and previous lows to be violated
and back to the middle of the range
you can see that was the effect here
after july and august
the late part of august we came all the
way down took out the may june lows
the market essentially for the dollar
index moved sideways
2016 september contract of 10-year
treasury notes again we can see that
last week of may going into june that
seasonal tendency for a load of form for
10-year treasury notes 10-year treasury
notes rally
all up into july
and that should give us a bear stance
for the dollar index the same time
[Music]
and as you can see we did have a bearish
decline in the last week of may going
into june and it gave one more lower low
in the lighter portion of june but look
what happens again
we have the dollar index rally one more
time and again we'll go back to the
previous slides you can see the 10-year
treasury note
see i have a slightly higher high going
into july as well
and then we saw that and we saw that
one more higher high pushed into the
dollar index in the latter portions of
july
again this is going to be an indication
that the markets are going to be in a
large consolidation
so think about what we've already shown
here if the market's showing the
tendency to be in a large consolidation
why
because both
yield
and dollar
ten year treasuries and the dollar are
moving in the same direction if that
occurs what we're looking at is
long-term indecisiveness and that means
because both of them are moving in
tandem
the likelihood of a continued
directional trade higher or lower for
either one is highly unlikely so we
would be focusing on looking for stop
raids
or looking for if the data range to look
back and see previous highs and lows to
be violated
when both
treasury and on the dollar index so if
we're looking at this condition what do
you suppose that does for foreign
currencies
it does several things number one it
puts you in a long-term consolidation on
foreign currencies because the dollar is
in consolidation and treasuries are
under consolidation
if we see times when the treasury market
is in fact moving in its seasonal
tenancy
and the dollar is supporting that same
seasonal tendency then we have a strong
probability of a directional long-term
trend
and that's where the large funds place
their money when you get into the
marketplace on those moves you have
these long periods of many weeks several
months in terms of
one directional
bias moves in other words long-term
trends
okay our next example
now we're looking at the march contract
of the 10-year treasury notes for 2017
and i'm using this contract because it
allows me to show the data
for
the latter portion of 2016 and going
into present trading day
you can see here
that treasury
market seasonal tendency to create a
high in november
and let's go back to that seasonal
tendency just so you guys can see it
okay here's the seasonal tendency once
again for the 10-year treasury note all
the way to the far right you can see
that green line that vertical line that
most furthest to the right
that furthest most right green vertical
line that delineates the beginning of
the trading for the march delivery
contract you can see that that actually
makes the high of the march contract
and it starts to trade off lower from
that price point
that seasonal tendency to create that
high for a march contract is going to be
influential
for us in that next slide that we just
looked at
so here we are back again that same
10-year treasury notes slide
for 2017's march contract
now we had the
presidential election obviously in 2016
and what we're looking at is that high
that
the election results shown for donald
trump
making our
president-elect at that
time of vote
the seasonal tendency for the march
contract could create a high you can see
that came into effect in november
so while we're looking at
the end of that uptrend for the seasonal
tendency on the 10-year treasury note
we're looking at the beginning of a
seasonal high
and that gives us that movement going
lower into the latter portions of
december and that's what you see here
that's transpired 2016. if we see this
occurring
okay and it's now trending it's not in
consolidation it's down trending for the
10-year treasury notes that's going to
provide the opportunity for the dollar
index to do the opposite but also do it
in a fashion that's in a trending mode
you see in november we had that same in
fact just in opposite terms where the
election shown the sell-off in the
10-year treasury notes
that sell-off shows an increase in
interest rates which means there's going
to be an interest to now buy dollar
because it's going to be going higher as
the 10-year treasury is dropping
interest rates are increasing which
means
that there's going to be buyers that's
going to be seeking yield by buying the
dollar index
and you can see the market did in fact
have a trending environment trying
trending higher then creating a
short-term low in december and finally
making its high
in the first portion of
december of this year
so the moral of all this is that if we
study the 10-year treasury notes in its
price action
it's either going to be moving in its
seasonal tendency or if the dollar index
moves in tandem with it that suggests
that we're going to be in a large
consolidation
if you look at all the currency pairs
that we
trade in the form of the british pound
the euro dollar those pairs were in big
consolidations all through the mid
portion of 2016.
that was attributed to the consolidation
that we saw in the 10-year treasury note
and the dollar index because they're
basically moving in the same direction
but they were
range bound that's going to translate
into range bound trading as well the
only caveat is going to be until we saw
the brexit vote
and that's obviously going to be the big
impact for
the latter portions of the summer months
but prior to that everything in the
marketplace we saw was all range bound
for currency trading so now one of the
things i said about this month that's
going to be helpful to you is when are
you looking for a trade that's going to
be explosive and trending
when the 10-year treasury notes seasonal
tendency is in effect you see it
happening and it's supported with the
contrary in price
action you see in the dollar index as we
described here
if they are not showing that chances are
we're going to be in a range bound
consolidation and that means you're
going to be focusing on very short-term
moves that means it's going to be high
probability for short-term trades and
day trades and
highly unlikely for long-term position
trades long-term position trades are
going to be favorable in the conditions
we've just shown here when we see
10-year treasury notes moving in
trending environments
that's going to put the dollar index
into a trending environment
also if we see the absence of the
seasonal tendency
the strongest in the form of the buy
signal for 10-year treasury notes around
june july
if that's not occurring then we're going
to be focusing on where the highs form
seasonally in the seasonal tendency for
the 10-year treasury units to get
ourselves in sync with the opposite
scope in other words just because the
seasonal tendency is the strongest as a
buy
in june july for 10-year treasuries
doesn't mean that when that is not the
case because the markets are not always
doing the same thing every single time
we can focus primarily being a bearish
10-year note trader which would give us
the november high as we indicated here
which lined up also for the season z4
our election this year
so we're going to build on this model
here in the next teaching and until then
wish good luck and good trading