welcome back folks this is lesson 2.2 of
the January 2017 ICT mentorship
we're gonna be looking at qualifying
trade conditions with the 10-year yields
okay the previous teaching 2.1 we had
looked at the 10-year node seasonal
tenancy where it has a strong tendency
to Rally in June and we're looking at
the 10-year note for September 2015 here
you can see how during the month of June
of 2015
10-year note did in fact make a low in
June
and while the seasonal tendency
is in force
how do you know the seasonal tendency is
most likely going to occur
well the first step is you want to start
looking to qualify the swings
in relationship to the dollar Index
and that's seen by looking at these
lower lows here
so our delineation begins at the
beginning of June 2015 and subsequent
lower lows
it transpired after June 2015 began
we start seeing a slide in price
and took out the low from May but
individually there was
five to six different candles
deck progressively kept making lower
lows in the first half of June that's
being delineated here but this short
little trend line
now in the dollar Index this is going to
be ideally seen
with a series of higher highs that's how
Market symmetry should
be posted and delivered in price
but let's take a look at what actually
happens in the dollar Index
at that same moment
we can see that the dollar Index
for June 2015
immediately to the right or after June
1st trading day
we were making lower highs
so this is a crack and correlation
and we have confirmation now there is a
trade idea unfolding in
to 10-year treasury note against the
dollar Index
it's further confirmed by
seeing the interest rate Market
declining at that time as the yield
declines the Futures price on a 10-year
note was actually rallying
note also
did the consolidation that the yield
stayed in
which also led to a consolidation in
dollar Index 10-year Treasury and
foreign currencies at the same time in
2015.
okay we're looking at the
June
of 2016.
again we're looking at that seasonal
tenancy
as seen here the market was making equal
lows so they should be seen in respect
to the dollar Index with equal highs
here's the dollar Index
going into June 2016.
did you see here the market made higher
highs this is a cracking correlation
the Market's shown a willingness to go
higher in the dollar Index but it was
not seen in the form of going lower
on the 10-year notes
that's a correct correlation there
therefore it is a qualifying condition
there is an underlying trade underway
this is further confirmed by visually
seeing the the interest rate Market
seeing it decline in the 10-year yields
again notice the consolidation
while it looks like if you zoomed in
really tight it would look like an
uptrend but we're still in a rather
large consolidation
and that is attributing factors to why
the currency markets had a consolidation
this period of time
lastly we have
the 10-year treasury note March contract
2017.
we have a lower high now I know you're
looking at that big wick on the
elections but just dispel that for a
moment
focus on the market structure alone
without that Wick we have lower high
formed in the first couple days of
November relative to the mid
October highs
so that should be seen
supported in the dollar Index as well
just contrary
in fact we see a lower low
so for the dollar Index to have a lower
low here
we should have seen
a higher high form in the 10-year note
that didn't happen
we see the opposite with a lower low
in dollar Index
we don't see the higher high in 10-year
treasury nodes as you would expect to
see with the lower low in dollar Index
again it's going to be a mirror image of
everything you see for perfect symmetry
when that symmetry is broken
it indicates there is a underlying Trend
or
manipulation otherwise
you can also see the open interest
decline in November supporting the idea
that there was short covering
by the smart money and the dollar Index
moved up as a result
again because
the 10-year note was in a move that was
trending it had more range to go lower
that supports the trending move on a
dollar Index where I was allowed to
trade for two complete months and you
can see it's supported with
the increase in the interest rate yield
on the 10-year note
during that time when the dollar rallied
markets seek yield and if the interest
rate's increasing therefore the dollar
has a strong tendency to own a rally as
well now as a side note
when we see these things occurring in
the price
you want to be blending these ideas with
the quarterly shift Concepts that's been
taught in this month's content
so if we're looking for the next three
to four months potential next swing not
that we're holding for that period of
time or our time Horizon is
three months out
generally it's going to be half that
time frame for the trade setups to come
to fruition
and complete
sometimes the trades will last longer
and go a full duration of three months
and sometimes a little bit longer but as
I mentioned in this mentorship my time
Horizon is about three months it's I I
think it's pretty much it's realistic as
you're gonna get because long-term
trends while they all generally stay in
the long-term trending environment
they can reverse and if it's in a
long-term uptrend you don't want to be
trying to pick the top so it's important
that
I remind you every time we talk about
this that my focus primarily is looking
at a time Horizon of three months with
the expectation I'm going to trade with
a position that may go up to three
months but rarely admittedly I don't
hold that long uh usually half that time
frame
but you can go in and look at these
times when the season will align
and there are qualifying smt divergences
between
the dollar Index and the 10-year note
when they have that pattern there you
can also qualify it with an interest
rate Triad
or you can go into a Forex currency pair
and look for the smt Divergence against
the dollar index that way those ideas
Blended together not that you need both
of them but one of them will give you a
qualification for a trade idea that may
be unfolding for a quarterly shift
by getting in sync with the marketplace
like this and viewing a higher time
frame charts with these tools in
alignment it gives your trades a high
probability
and it filters out a lot of the noise
and even if you don't trade in a
long-term position
capacity you can use these ideas to get
in sync with
higher time frame Trend or higher time
frame order flow and by doing that it
puts all your swing trade short-term
trade day trade and Scouts in line with
institutional workflow and with that
it's very hard to go wrong not perfect
it doesn't negate the opportunity for
you to lose money but it certainly does
put the odds in your favor
until next time wish you good luck and
good Trading