hey folks welcome back to lesson eight
the final of April 2017's content for
ICT day trading model
this lesson is going to be teaching
integrating day trades with higher time
frame trade entries
okay folks we're gonna be revisiting
Power3
and we'll be talking specifically with
day trade entries and hard time frame
setups
now we can use day trading entries to
position ourselves in our longer term
HTF trades
and a method that employs very little
time and Analysis
we do not need to use the London Kill
Zone if you're not able to trade it some
of you aren't able to get up aren't able
to stay awake can't do it because a
business family work I get it trust me
I've been there
we don't need that to London killZone
to be a day trader you don't need to
learn the Killzone to be entering with
your hard time frame setups as a day
trader either there's a way of using day
trading Concepts to facilitate an entry
on a longer term HTF sets
there are two essential times of the day
IPDA refers to reset
the daily candle can point the ideal
entries for all styles of trade
and when we look at a daily candle
obviously I've taught this in the past
Power3 refers to the open
the rally or decline and then close
obviously for an up close day or bullish
day we would see the open near the low
of the day a small little Wick below the
opening price an expansion move or range
expansion
up then a close that typically closes
just a little bit off the high today
for a down close or a bearish day we see
the open near the HOD with a
very small little Wick above the opening
price then an expansion move lower
with the clothes coming off the low with
a small little Wick making the low of
the day in respect to the close
that's Power3 it's the open rally
up close or open decline down close
the open is near one extreme of the
DailyRange and the close is near one
end of the DailyRange
so they're going to be opposite extremes
now obviously it goes without saying
typically you know we've mentioned this
in many times before in the free stuff
but there is
a vacuum of concern when we look at
Price action like this as a retail
Trader we're not even aware these
phenomenons have any significance
so when we look at price on a daily
chart
okay I just think from a say for
instance that you are not
able to  have any difficulty getting
up in London okay just imagine for a
moment if you did how could you enter as
a day trader or how could you day trade
and you have to avoid the London session
that was one of the
things I had to come up with to fill in
the  the void where there was a short
period in time where I could not do
anything in London I had to help take
care of the kids my wife was just unable
to do anything she was  nursing and
healing up from having a child
I wanted to trade but I couldn't do it
because I had to take care of three kids
and one of them being a newborn so I had
to really figure out a way to overcome
that and this was my answer or my
solution to it now obviously there's
this isn't the last and be all end-all
but for me it worked
okay the open or openings
now there's two session openings that I
monitored daily it's the zero GMT this
is your Standard platform on Forex LTD
demo you see me teaching with in my
tutorials you can use that time for
calibration wherever you are globally
and then obviously everyone knows about
the midnight NewYork time that opening
price as it relates to NewYork time
whatever that time is on your platform
that opening price on an hourly chart
that's what we're looking for
well this teaching
okay we're gonna go a little bit beyond
that
and there are very refined entry points
that can be had in London open obviously
that goes without saying
but here's the here's the Rub With It
you don't need it
if you understand the DailyRange and
you understand what IPDA is going to do
or most likely to do let's say it that
way and you understand where you're at
in the PD array Matrix where are we
moving from
are we moving from a discount up into a
premium are we moving from a premium
down into a discount
knowing that gives us DirectionalBias
it gives us an understanding of what we
should be looking for being a buyer or
seller
and
it's not required to position day
trading Concepts on
HTF setups by using the
London open you're not limited to that
there's other ways of doing it
so I want you to think for a second
imagine being able to trade to daily
range for a single day or hold for a
much longer duration of trade harvesting
a larger number of Pips how could you do
that
well we're gonna be looking at IPDA true
day open and this is reset
the daily candle
um at zero GMT
that's our beginning reference point for
IPDA that's treaty opening but then
there's true day as I refer to it when
I'm trading London using the midnight
candle in NewYork that's my opening
price there
because I'm able to be awake and I'm
able to trade London and I'm wanting to
be there because I want to be able to
capture that really small tiny little
move of protraction up on down days or
down moves right before the up close I
want to be able to capture that little
movement or at least get in there and
fade that move so that way I can have a
very tight Ultra small stop in
relationship to what I may be doing on a
HTF setup
but when we look at the Power3 what
we're really doing is we're looking at
the opening price and we're waiting for
the opposite to occur in the DailyRange
when we're bullish we're going to be
buying near the LOD or near
the opening
the main question is
how much lower from the opening will it
go
if it's going to be an up close
and if it's going to be a down close how
much higher than the opening will it go
before it makes a lower close
I get this question so many times and
I'm just going to tell you this
it's been staring at you all this time
it's been in your charts every day and
you don't pay any attention to it
I have also LED everybody away from this
because it's just one of those things I
wasn't willing to share but because
you're in the mentorship you get to
learn it
this little hyphenated little Dash that
appears on all the daily candles
or not candles but open high low close
bar if you set that for your platform
that little opening hashtag tick to the
left of your  daily candles or bars
that opening
is all you need to know
that occurs
very very early in the evening in New
York time so I'm on the East Coast I'm
basically the same time as in NewYork
residing in Maryland I have East Coast
time
wherever that is in terms of zero GMT
using the Forex LTD platform the demo
you need to calibrate your local time
and know what that time is where you
live
all you need to know is that opening
price
that's it
what we're going to do with that
information is frame it in such a way
where we can use it knowing when we're
going to be buying or selling
I'm going to up close we're trying to
capture that big lines portion move up
and when it's down close we're trying to
capture that big
range going lower for a day trade but
this is the same concept we'll use this
in the same vein by trading with higher
time frame setups the key is you have to
know where you're at on the hard time
frame pdra Matrix
obviously if we're looking for up close
we need to be seeing the daily moving
away from a discount array
it has to have already respected a
discount array so that way the next
trading day we should see no movement at
all if very little below the opening
price at zero GMT
if we are looking at a bear scenario
on the daily chart we have to have
recently traded at a premium array and
price has to have shown a respect of
that in other words it's repelled or
failed to go higher the next trading day
at zero GMT
we're gonna be using that opening price
to facilitate trade
so let's assume for a moment we have
watched our daily chart trade down into
a discount PD array
and we're expecting bullish prices now
institutional order flow has been
bullish we've come down into a level
that would be expected to be bullish on
a daily time frame we've hit a bullish
order block and price has shown a
willingness to Rally away from that the
very next day at zero GMT we're going to
look at that opening price now I've
trained and conditioned all of you to
look for that opening price and then
expect that down move
that's your classic London setup
but what if you can't be up during that
time
the London protraction you may not be
able to be able to see it you can't be
there to watch it you can't participate
if you will
well is that entirely true
not necessarily just because you're not
awake doesn't mean you can't take
advantage of it
what we look for is yes the opening
price but we have already arrived at
what if we were awake at London we would
expect that move down anyway
that's what we're looking for that Judas
swing that protractionary state in the
market where price goes lower to seek
liquidity to make a move higher with an
up close
all we need to know is Are we more
likely to go higher or more more likely
to go lower so if we set our daily bias
based on the daily
PD arrays and if the data ranges and the
quarterly shift is still bullish
everything that's significantly pointed
higher if we're in a seasonal tendency
for bullish prices if it's a Monday
Tuesday or Wednesday it's a loaded deal
the main thing is we have to see price
having already respected a daily
discount PD array
you have to see it do that and then the
very next trading day you're looking at
zero GMT
opening price
so that means that in local time in
America that's pretty easy regardless of
where you're at in the North American
continent real real easy to get that
price
where you're at in the world where it
makes it difficult for you I can't
answer for that so you'll have to work
in the London session
but
for those individuals that want to trade
Asia but have the effects of London open
this is how you do it
we don't know how much of a
projectionary state there's going to be
not always but we can have a reasonable
expectation
so why zero Jam T well you already have
CentralBankDealersRange closing right
now
at zerojmt you know what the Central
Bank dealers range is most likely going
to provide you in terms of Standard
Deviation
but what if you don't want to use
CentralBankDealersRange why you would
think that I don't know but does it say
you don't even want to consider it
I think it's Advantage  to knowing it
so you can expect how much of a
projectionary phase and  price will go
higher or lower in this case going lower
below the opening price for a bullish up
close during London
but what we're going to be doing is
focusing primarily on being a buyer at
zero GMT
wait a minute I'm just going to buy it
at zero GMT yeah you're just gonna buy
it at zero GMT
you're going to use a five day average
DailyRange
as you stop
whoa Michael wait a minute what you're
saying is
this could potentially be a
90 pip stop
what if it's a hundred pip stop
then that's what it is
remember we're not day trading with
minute risk trying to capture 20R okay
we're not trying to do that here this
topic and teaching is how to integrate
day trading and Concepts to get into
your hard time frame trade entries
since you're looking for higher time
frame setups
but 90 to 100 pip stop is relatively
insignificant because you're looking for
moves that are going to be paying
several hundred Pips or you should be
that's what you should be looking for
those types of moves so if you want to
frame those ideas and use day trading
Concepts you would be buying at zero GMT
using a five day average DailyRange as
your stop loss you would take whatever
the average DailyRange is subtract it
from the opening price at zero GMT
there's your stop loss and you just let
it rip you just trade it accordingly
based on your HTFs until
it trades to a premium PD array
now what if you want to use this concept
as a day trade you just want to do it as
a single one day event you think it's
going to be a big range everything's
pointing to a larger update close and
it's been small ranges recently and we
respected a discount PD array on the
daily chart it's institutional overflow
has been bullish anyway it's quarterly
effect is underway and it's still
bullish
everything is expected to go higher it's
a Monday or Tuesday or Wednesday
what can we do with that in regards to
intraday
well you're going to take the same thing
and reverse it for cells
we don't know how much of a
projectionary state we will have without
being awake so
we don't need to know exactly how much
that is we can have Central Bank dealers
range hint at that but again we don't
know how much of that London
protractionary phase in price is going
to move up above that zero GMT
the key is we have already seen price
move away from a premium PD array on a
daily chart it has to have to happen the
day before the trade day so the previous
session we want to see price having
respected a premium PD array and it's
not wanting to Rally or obviously hit it
and start to sell off so we're near
the high end of the range
it's at a premium it's already shown a
willingness to respect some measure of a
premium PD array some bear shoulder
block or it's rejected an old high
Turtle suit the very next trading day
well zero GMT
on Forex ltd's demo platform you're
going to be looking to sell short
rate zero GMT
or you can sell it 0 GMT
plus 20 Pips
and again using the five day average
DailyRange I just stopped
what are we accomplishing here
well we can anticipate obviously a
little bit of movement or projectionary
phase in the marketplace where the Judas
swing occurs right before that down
close
adding 20 Pips to the zero GMT opening
price
that would be your sell limit order and
then adding the average five-day range
ADR to your limit entry so let's give an
example say it was  you were getting
it and at 1.50
and the average DailyRange is at
50. you would get in at
105.00 and your stock would be at 105.50
now that's a relatively small stop but
that would be an example so what you're
doing is you're protecting yourself
and
building in enough of a filter or or a
barrier if you will that the likelihood
of price rallying from the open at zero
GMT 70 Pips before going down with a
down close highly unlikely especially if
we've seen a previous day or yesterday
it trading from a premium PD array from
a daily chart
so long and short is
we already know there's going to be very
little upside about the opening price
because we are in a bearish cycle
so if that's the case we can just look
at the opening price at 20 Pips To it
there's your limit order your stop is
the five-day average DailyRange added
to that entry and then you use your
hard time frame
objectives for your time of your profit
and you need to go to sleep just let it
go
now there's for me sometimes you might
have a 20 pip limit and it doesn't go up
20 Pips and just runs away
how can you accomplish  the same thing
and not be afraid of missing the move
well if you take your total position
okay and you divide it in half what was
your total lot size that you were going
to trade and or percentage risk that you
were going to trade at plus 20 Pips
above zero gmt's opening
take half of that risk and just simply
add it
at the zero GMT
there's your first portion put it in
there right away at zero GMT and then
you can do a second portion
at 20 Pips above the opening price it
may not fill you there but at least you
have something in so that way with a
five-day average DailyRange does it
should stop there you go you're
positioned
I'm going you could just sell at zero
GMT opening
and use the last five days average daily
range as your protective stop you can
take the Sell
at zero GMT
or add 10 to 20 Pips above the opening
price
for your Sell
so that way you're going to anticipate
some measure protractionary phase in
price in London
when price rallies up it might rally up
30 points it might rally up 40. it might
even rally 50.
but you already have several Pips above
the zero GMT opening price
to get you in as a limit to sell
then by having a five-day average daily
range above your entry you're building
in as much as 60 to 70 Pips
and again that's highly unlikely if
you're trading on the heels of the
previous day having respect of a daily
premium pdra
you can buy days simply buy at zero GMT
or
buy it with 10 to 20 Pips below the
opening price at zero GMT
there's your limit order of the buy so
that way you're going to catch some
Judas swing if it occurs
if it goes down a few Pips and fills you
and say it goes down 30 more the
likelihood of the five-day average daily
range
being subtracted from the opening price
is your GMT
and your 10 or 20 Pips below that
opening price as your entry again the
likelihood is 70 Pips 60 70 Pips going
down from the opening price just to have
it up close it doesn't usually happen if
price is already respected a daily
discount pdra now
you have homework
I want you to find three examples and
yes you have to do this go through your
charts and find in recent weeks where
you'll have three examples of this
concept in price action using only the
opening price at zero GMT when you're
bullish
or where price rallied up or using it as
the opening price and then a limit order
above or below relative to what you
think in terms of the the close if it's
going to be bullish or expected to see
bullish prices based on the analysis
that you would see around that time
obviously you have the benefit of the
hindsight but this is how you learn it
you look for it in price and you show
you show yourself many examples I can
give you 20 of them in this but it's not
as good as if you go through the price
action yourself I'm forcing you to go
through
the cycle of looking for PD arrays
the HTF looking at
institutional order flow and framing
that on clear cut discount or premium
arrays
when price is wanting to go higher
you'll see it obviously in hindsight but
I want you to focus on the Zero GMT
opening price
and how much that goes down relative to
the five-day average DailyRange
the
a five-day average DailyRange if you
don't have my ICT indicator
just about everybody has that but if you
don't have it
um you can use the simple indicators on
most of the platforms the ATR average
true range do it on a five day and
that'll give you your your your number
okay for each day it's going to get real
close to what the ICT average daily
range indicator is the only thing that
makes that one good is it gives you a
line when it hits it it turns blue it
gives the impression that you're you're
a lot more fancier than you really are
you don't need it but it's just  a way
of
building our stop loss we'll know what
our stop is based on whatever the
average DailyRange in the last five
days
doesn't mean you won't get stopped out
sometimes it doesn't mean that  the
market won't stop you out and still go
where you thought that still can happen
but this was what my solution was to not
being awake during London but still
looking for the setups based on what I
understood in price
so I look forward to seeing your example
shared on the Forum it'll be shared
hopefully by majority of you if not all
of you but three examples do it in one
post
what pair it was where it was how much
of a movement down or up from your
opening price relative to
um being a buyer seller
and I want you in these three examples I
want to see one that worked as a buy
one worked as a Sell and then one where
it did not work and I don't care if it
failed as a buy or so but find one of
each share that in your post on the
Forum in the April content thread
until next time I wish you good luck and
good Trading