foreign
[Music]
folks
sorry for my tardiness
OBS was acting up so hopefully they
won't
cause any more issues
while we're
[Music]
studying live
I'm sorry I have to put these types of
things in here because a lot of people
out there don't take my
video and upload it to their social
media and pretend it's them and
you know in the business
all right so we're
gotta check Twitter and make sure you
guys can hear me if you are a follower
of my Twitter account
uh just give me a five by five if you
can hear me and if the chart is on
NASDAQ
September contract 15 minute
I just saw my tweet saying it's a
60-second uh lag
not sure why
I have set to the lowest one so
not that it really matters because you
should be treating this today
I just saw my tweet
yeah there's a bit of a like isn't it
I'm gonna send you a picture that way
you can see I do in fact have it set to
the lowest latency
I know there's a lot of folks out there
that like to
make excuses for this that new thing
with here's your here's your proof that
it's set to the lowest ultra low latency
but for whatever reason it's
getting there
slowly today so
it's not for a lack of trying I promise
you so anyway
let's get over here to the chart
make sure my phone's set to do not
disturb
ERS like that
try to call me
all right so here is the NASDAQ 15
minute time frame
and I'm going to go up to a daily just
for a second
[Music]
and then it meanders around 2 30 it
starts at the real move okay so it's not
always like that there's some times
where it'll move and then move even more
in the same direction
in other instances but very much more
rare is where there'll be an initial
move at two o'clock and then it just
consolidates after a bunch of little
whipsaw movement at 2 30. so that's why
it's very important that you understand
that anything that I comment today
please don't use it as a like a secret
handshake that I'm trying to tell you to
buy or sell because if that's not what
we're doing here today but I want you to
observe how the market reaches for
liquidity how it behaves afterwards and
if this is the first time you ever
watched something like this live it'll
be
probably very obvious why you shouldn't
try to trade ahead of it
I will toggle back and forth between
es and NASDAQ
I know some of you don't have access to
those markets you have to trade the cfds
um
for my focus and for brevity's sake I'm
gonna Focus here
everything that you would see in the
hindsight later on
compare and contrast the charts that way
you can see how both
delivered on the
the basis of this
event at two o'clock and then 2 30.
all right so we have liquidity here
we've already hit the liquidity this one
you watch me do an execution on that
there are relative equal highs here
that is a lot to get back up to but you
know stranger things have happened on
days like this so I want to go right
into the 15 minute time frame
[Music]
and I mentioned this morning that the
640 level was too clean
right in here and that's that's what I
would like to see happen
doesn't mean that's what I think is
going to happen and it's going to
therefore be a trade idea for you to
take no
I might get it wrong
um just like a CPI you've watched me do
I think two times
where I've talked about CPI number ahead
of time what I thought was going to
happen and it was completely
diametrically opposed after the news hit
the marketplace and it just rolled
aggressively the other direction which
is again that's a that's a freight train
you don't want to stay in front of it
this is like a gambling
uh it's a gambling session you don't
know where it's going to go I don't know
where it's going to go
and the fact that you're not going to be
able to get in and get out because
broker's pool of liquidity so it's not
an absence of wanting to be a buyer or
seller it just means that they are doing
their best to try to protect themselves
because
a lot of you out there
you get heavy-handed with your bets and
sometimes you can get real lucky
and they don't they don't want to expose
themselves to that type of risk
all right so just 30 seconds to go and
then we'll see the first stage of
the FED event today
so the two reactive points is 15 640 and
fifteen thousand four eighty three those
are the two price points I'm monitoring
and what I want to see
is how they react after trading to
either one and I don't care really which
one it goes to because I'm not pushing
the button but I want you to see how
fast it moves
instead of
the two o'clock which is here so that
means this this here
and then I would look for it to run to
that level and then best case scenario
would be run for that 640 which was my
interest this morning on Twitter
if it would have ran
and it still could but it runs for the
15640 level then I would look for at 2
30 does it show a willingness to reject
that entire move and run for the lows
here and maybe gravitate towards this
not that it wants to go here or would
likely go there we just are looking for
a range to trade
and an opinion
okay we're trying to ascertain the most
likely draw on liquidity and right now
it's indecisive it's not really giving
us a whole lot to work with at least
it's not for me
I like the fact that we went up
into this self-center balance by side
and efficiency we overlapped this volume
and balance of two separated bodies here
if it rejects all this and runs lower
than that scenario that I'm looking for
at 230 might still be in contention but
right now there's simply not enough
the girl one
I can imagine some of you that are
relatively new maybe you're used to
watching Instagram guys talk about stuff
that didn't happen
um and you're wondering why well why
don't you trade in this why you know why
wouldn't you want to be a part of this
it's going to be a big mover
um the likelihood of you getting a good
feel number one is unlikely two the
risks far outweigh the potential reward
you can easily hurt yourself
and I've done that to myself on days
like this trying to be
a cowboy over leveraging and trying to
do things that thick feeling you know
you think okay well it should have
stopped me out and it just keeps rolling
way past your stop loss that's the risks
and that's that's all part of that cfdc
required disclaimer that people that
talk about the marketplace people that
uh yeah cell services or give signals or
just even comment about the market if
you read those disclaimers it talks
about these very scenarios where there
may not be an opportunity for you to get
a fill
and it's not good when you're in a trade
and it's going against you there's
nothing that you can do to fix it or
remedy it
okay so I like the idea that we've taken
these relative equal lows out here
you sweat the rejection block here if
you look at the closing price on that
candle
that's this up here upper left hand
corner
that closing price comes in at fifteen
thousand five thirty five and three
quarters
and the low
one handle less
so we went below that
it's staged off any lower prices
initially here
I'm gonna see do we treat this here
as a breaker so I'm going to be watching
this
right in here this is so sensitivity and
want to trade Above This high right
there if it does that then we want to
measure how much animation how much
energy how much
interest
does price want to show towards going
into that 640 level
now the worst case scenario if we don't
break this High here and we don't break
this low and it's like 215.
eight more minutes or so then the real
move is going to be 230 and it's going
to be a freight train and who knows
where it's going to go so that's why
it's important that you understand that
this event is two stages and it's
imperative that you can at least try to
figure out what the initial run was and
right here it's
it's either or it's 50 50. so 50 50 is
not a scenario that I want to go out
there and push a button on I don't even
want to give you a bias on that because
it's not clear so one of the things that
my students that have been with me a
long time
they know that I know what I'm looking
for when it's there I'm going to try
them all over like white on rice but if
it's not I'm sitting still
and you have to be comfortable with that
and it's a skill set that you should be
trying to acquire knowing when to sit
still knowing that okay the price might
move around it might move a lot but if
you are not in it that's not a losing
trade
but to a neophyte so when it's new
someone has just got into this industry
or watched other people that may not be
actually doing anything
their advice or their opinion about
something or showing maybe fraudulent
results
you might subscribe to their views on
you should be trading on a day like this
or she you should already be in a
position already and I I'm not
a proponent that I don't I don't like
that I think that it's
irresponsible
and it Fosters the
the wrong mindset about managing risk
which is what this whole industry is
about it's not about making money it's
about making sure it's that high
want to see speed Above This high right
here
usually when I'm doing an execution this
is when I'll type in I want to see large
up close candles or large green candles
incoming something to that effect once
we get into this area here
the reason why is because I suspect that
this area here is going to be used as a
kind of like Rocket Fuel that's that's
what I would kind of reach for in terms
of an analogy they're going to use this
area here to really speed up and run to
15 640. that would be my understanding
and my expectation but
if it fails to do that very thing there
that means we're going to probably hang
around inside the range between the
height forms here and the low here until
we get to 230 which is not helpful
now you might say well you know
what's the point of all this
and a new student or a new Trader would
think that you know what's the point of
all this if you're going to watch this
and not do anything well I'm teaching
students that have never done this
before or they don't have a skill set
where they can trust how to read price
action what is it you're looking for ICT
what what Garners your interest in a
specific price run to a high or low or
buy side or sell side what would negate
a specific idea that you made like
initially but what cancels it what what
makes it uh null and void that's what
I'm teaching you and that stuff is not
transferable knowledge in a book
okay so the things that I'm not going to
be able to include in my books I'm
teaching you in live market settings
whether it be through tweets calling the
market or doing live sessions
or doing things over recorded execution
and explaining to why I'm doing what I'm
doing and not other things
now what I'm looking at here
my interest is let me let me get this
Shameless advertising you like that
um
this range right there that that sibi
I'm cutting through all of this and my
eyes going right into here I don't want
to see any respect
of this Range High
so this should be a balanced price range
not in an event where we're reaching for
liquidity and it's also an unsettling
which is
the whole premise behind read
announcements the same reason that they
would use CPI number same reason why
they would do non-farm payroll
okay it's a disrupter it's a
it's very
point of existence is to disrupt
the existing order flow
that means that everybody that's been
going lower this morning that's been
profiting
their stop losses are above relative
equal highs or short-term highs so
that's a buy side level quality pool
I'm not interested
in seeing this as a balanced price range
because my my
interest is up here
I think that these individuals think
that they're safe
and I always look at the marketplace
with that mindset you know who who has
been making money
where would they be scared what would
make them scared and what would take
them out of the marketplace and why
would their stop loss be taken be
helpful to someone else
and that's narrative okay that's that's
things that help them the trader form
and develop an idea about why the market
should even go where you think it may go
you can't just look at Price action on
the basis of a pattern
or a Fibonacci Ratio or something
harmonic or anything and you can't look
at a depth of Market just because
there's a number of orders around a
specific you know high or low level
relative to the current market price
that's not enough to just you know I
mean like it is enough for somebody to
form an opinion based on that but that's
to me it's too myopic it's limited in
its
underlying basis so there has to be more
to why the market should go higher not
just simply even for my stuff you know
just because there's a down closed
candle and the market has you know
shifted above a short-term high and it
came back down to that down close candle
unless the narrative is suggesting
that the Market's going to go to some
buy side liquidity pool or some premium
inefficiency above the market price
that's not going to work
and that's what I see a lot of by
individuals out there trying to teach
over block Theory because
they think it's supply and demand so
they're taking the
the facts that just because there may be
a rectangle on my chart or I'm drawing a
special attention to a specific candle
um they will add in that they'll go
through candles because that's what
supply and demand says that you're not
supposed to do that you're supposed to
look at a fresh Zone
um
there has to be some underlying reason
for the market to go to either reprice
to inefficiency above or below the
marketplace
or trade to stops above or below the
they're the only two things that can
happen or it consolidates that's it
anything outside of that is manipulation
it's manual intervention these days like
non-farm payroll today the FED
announcement you know whether you're
going to raise interest rates or lower
them or leave them unchanged you don't
know what they're going to do
there's people out there that already
know what they're going to make public
but even
but I'm not going to stick my neck out
there on the Block
in front of these types of events
because I know what their Tendencies are
which is they're traps
they can entice you to do something that
if you came into the market like I have
I have no bias except for the scenarios
I've painted for you here
so it's limited to two ranges of
liquidity the 640
and the 43.
and I'm not convinced one way or the
other because we haven't overrun
this here I'm not subscribing that this
is a balanced price range either because
the reasons why is because we have a
looming
conference
where the jaw boning by the FED will
need to be behind us
and then the market will be permitted to
move around
but right now what's actually occurring
at this very moment is everyone that's
in in an interesting party in trying to
trade this asset
they're trying to determine whether it's
going to go higher or lower and they're
they're placing bets right now they're
entering they're buying and selling
and they're going to have a great deal
of regret here
you come three o'clock
they're gonna wish they didn't push the
button in they're going to wish they
just turned off the charts didn't do
anything today
because it's going to do probably very
much
opposite to what they were expecting
and the unfortunate thing is if you're
inexperienced and you get into a move
and it starts to run in your favor on a
day like this you marry the vein
meaning you fall in love when you marry
that position
and you will ignore every warning sign
that it's either run its course it's
done or it's about the reverse on you
because greed you'll see it move really
really fast and if you're on side
in the initial stages of a price run
it makes you feel like wow it's going to
really go it's gonna really really run
and you won't and it didn't happen
and they'll tell you that you should be
in here trying to trade on these days
and that to me is the sure sign that
they are absolutely not risking real
money and they are absolutely not in
position to give anybody advice with
trading or financial advice
so I try to be very responsible as a as
a mentor as an influencer
and I want my influence to end come
November so I know things are going to
get wild here globally and I I don't
want to have any reason to feel like
I've either inspired or
um
let someone down
you know an incorrect perception of
where price would go when it starts
getting nuts
I will be Trading but I won't be doing
things like this come November
the YouTube channel
content will remain out there my Twitter
account will remain up I have never
deleted deleted any tweets
everything will remain I just I won't be
active
my attention we've diverted to my
personal life and my family and I'm
Trading
so we are about
um six and a half minutes
away from the real move
and that's really what we're here for I
just like to have the opportunity to sit
down with you you calm me down because
I'm not a lot of people hopped up on
goofball you're like man he's doing a
live stream I'm going to take his advice
and whatever he talks about I'm going to
trade on that you shouldn't be doing
that today
so I've outlined what
interests I have in the marketplace
the buy side which I made noon and I
still right now with the market
structure that's in place at the very
moment we're looking at it right now
I still favor
a run for 640 if I was to have like a
gun to my head and say okay ICT right
now you call it what do you think is
going to happen
I believe that they're going to run for
6 40.
if I'm wrong
the only thing I lose is you know I
called a move that I would have never
taken with live money anyway
but based on the where I had to pay more
money for a better perspective
so I don't look at you know losing
trades like you know I lost my models
inferior now or it's obsolete too many
people to understand what the algorithm
is doing so now it's changing that
that's not going to happen more people
learning how to do this isn't going to
do anything except for create more
liquidity that's all it's going to do
there's gonna be a lot of people out
there that don't know what they're doing
like I was mentioning earlier down close
clinicals doesn't make it a bullish
order block
now where we're at here
I'm watching the Clinton encroachment
which is the midpoint of this Wick
right in here so
that right there I'm watching Dewey show
alone to expand a lot of momentum
running past that or is it just
fluttering around there and start
drawing back up into that candle
we're getting close to that 230 so
there's gonna be a lot of
whip song
I'm going to take this line off here
okay I don't want you to be confused and
it's also pissing me off because in my
way when I'm looking at everything so
I'm going to take this line off because
it's already been used this morning
[Music]
and you can watch the live execution in
the
Twitter
feed posted this morning
okay you see how it just reacted off
that right there
that in itself on a 15 or 5 Second chart
that would be a trade I would have taken
on another day
not today on another day where there
isn't this looming big injection of
volatility but look how much it's pulled
off of that that's bigger than most of
the guys you've watched live stream
you know they're big moves it's not even
one quarter of that
and you just watched it happen just you
know one candle in one five minute
candle
so we're about a minute and a half
about
fundamental drivers controlling price on
the day of the event
I think it's a matter of who who can get
her easiest and here we're about to see
it begin in three seconds
[Music]
so this is the window time
that your focus should be
at the highest
not being distracted with your spouse
your children
mind your children by the way but uh you
know don't let your attention be diluted
because this is this is where the real
move will form
so we've had an initial run now if we
were looking at it like this so here's
two o'clock
right there okay so what is the much
more obvious run did it go down a lot or
did it go up and reach further for by
side than it did sell side
it looks to me like they set this run up
for the stops here
if everything is true based on what I've
seen in the past for a number of years
this should
a road below here and reach for this
down here that's what I would expect now
if everything goes
against what I just outlined it would
need to completely run entirely over top
of this
range here
if it does I would expect it to come
back down in and find that as support
and then it's going to go much higher
than this
that's what I would expect but right now
based on the fact that we waited till 2
30 it's 2 31 now
the Run was here so this is a much
larger run than just little drop down
here below here
so if it's a two-stage development and
delivery in price they ran for the
trailed buy stops
and I want to see does it show we're
willingness to get down below here and
if it does I'd be looking for the 483
level
what changes it what negates that idea
is it has to run over top of this all
this shaded area here and then come back
down and find some support if it does
then like I said it would be a much much
bullish much more bullish idea than I
would have expected you know at the
beginning of the day
and what you do he's uh he likes to talk
a lot
I don't know what he's saying I could
care less what he's saying
I don't have that attitude
you know follow along and make any
sense out of whatever that he's saying
because I think it's all
basically
it's not moving because he's talking
they're just using the fact that he's
talking it because he's a puppet and
he's the he's the focus Point okay he's
like the thing
he's the right hand of the magician and
you're watching him where the sleight of
hands being done on the left hand and
you never see it coming
I guess you shouldn't say never see it
come
foreign
payroll Fridays when I'm studying price
and or events like this
I like to put myself in a position where
if I was in a trade long or short you
know at what point
would I feel that
discomfort
and whether you're trading with a demo
in in the learning early stages of your
development or if you get to the point
where you're trading with real money
um
this is those days where guys will tweet
to me
let's say here's a trade I took
but they're not to tell me right now on
Twitter that they're doing it so if
you're going to do that if you have it
in mind
tell me right now
otherwise I'm not gonna pay any
attention to your tweets
[Music]
foreign
that looks good
let me see the down
okay so we have reached that sibby
now we're going to drop down until one
minute chart and study everything in
here okay
[Music]
now one of the setups that I like and it
may not form because it's a little bit
oh I might do it now when it trades to
here to top of that range and it opens
up the next candle it could trade down
and touch the high of that candle there
and then I would expect it to run really
fast up into the 640 buy side and expand
through
if it trades it at 640
or higher I would not be interested in
seeing this as support not that it can't
do it later on I just would not want and
it looks like we're going to rip through
it
now if it were to not do that I was
going to go up here and then come back
down I think that this is just a Target
and we're going to keep going into the
close
oh
and check is the
335 London session
by side just attacked I'd want to see a
little bit more run through than that
I'm seeing some tweets guys are saying
that it's buffering
and the audio's breaking up I can't do
anything about that folks
you know I I have high speed internet
I'm not having any issues with my
delivery of
a signal
I'm talking to you on a expensive
microphone like it's it's all YouTube so
I can't do anything about it
okay go back into this candle here I
mentioned when we were trading down I
want to see do we have
a willingness to hit that and reject it
it's consequent encouragement I'll show
you the actual measurements on that
[Music]
so the 50 level or consequent
encouragement of this tail on that
Candlestick comes in at 15
545 and three quarters
the low and you're going to look up here
upper left hand corner
the low on that candle
comes in at fifteen thousand five forty
five and a quarter so it went one half
of a point or two ticks
beyond that and then sharply rejected
root over top of this the only thing it
didn't really do that I would have
expected and would have enjoyed seeing
was on a one minute basis come back down
and touch
let me go down them on that chart
I would have liked to see it have
a touch of that right that level there
and then deliver like it's doing here
that would have been
a nice
60 points
so I'm looking at
the likelihood this will want to go
higher
into
not yet
traded Above This High here then I would
look at overnight London going into New
York and tomorrow's trading is this
would be the draw on trading tomorrow so
I would have a bullish bias going into
that and the only thing that would
change that is going below
this balanced price range that's on the
five minute chart
so that's what I do with this
information even though I'm not willing
to take the trade on a day like this
because
it's a big gamble and I'm more
interested in the information that it
provides me after it's already in price
because my interest is really on the
Thursday and Fridays action to trade
that
I use this information here to try to
like help me frame a bias
give me context as to what I would like
to show as a parameter in my analysis
where where would I be
Incorrect and assuming that it's going
to go higher or lower
that's why I study it even if I'm not
talking about it live on Twitter
I'm always watching these big events and
I'm looking at it with the same
perspective I'm showing you here today
where I'm measuring things I'm looking
at does it have a wellness that want to
go to a specific level does it do
certain things that I would like to see
or if it doesn't do that you know what
does that help me
you know conclude in terms of
useful information for tomorrow's
trading indoor Friday's Trading
and to a myopic new Trader or someone
that just starts or a inexperienced
Mentor they'll they'll be out here
trying to promote the idea that you
should have been a part of that move and
you might get lucky
you know you might you might be able to
do something with that
but if I'm in a position like I'm in and
if I say I'm gonna do something or I'm
interested in doing something I know
there's a at least 15 percent of you are
going to go out there and try to do
something with real money or your funded
account
and you're not going to know how to
navigate it you're going to not really
enter at the right time
and you're going to open up yourself to
a adverse result
and that's going to really get used but
I'm finding the right ones because it's
my stuff that's authorship but the
things that I'm teaching you to focus on
helps you frame narrative
why you should trust
these cons these Concepts at specific
times and not lean on them at others
when everybody else will look at it and
think it's a down close candle it's a
fair value Gap it's a trade it's
something to get into and it's not
so it's it's it's hidden in plain sight
that's the beauty of it and that's like
the easiest straightforward answer I can
give to people that are afraid that more
people will learn it
look
you know everybody that's ever rode a
motorcycle
it doesn't mean they're going to go out
there and keep up and run with those
individuals that can run around that
track you know like professionals speed
demons
and just because you drive your car
doesn't mean you could be a good NASCAR
driver
and it means that you're familiar with a
motorcycle if you if you're driven one
you're familiar with your car that
familiarity isn't going to be trans
verbal useful information to a Nascar or
a sport bike
you know
there's a big Chasm between someone
looking at a video or watching me talk
about something
and then actually going out and doing it
it's a great deal of learning that has
to take place and they will be a barrier
to themselves so I've
I've never been a
afraid of teaching it because more
people are going to learn how to do it
and it's going to change now I've been
afraid to teach what I know because I'm
not supposed to teach that
so I created this language to talk in
this language and this is where I'm safe
so I'm gonna hang around till about 3 15
then I want to close it
foreign
folks I get it I don't need 30 people to
tell me that the video audio and such is
breaking up if you look at other people
tweeting to me
[Music]
thank you
doesn't quite have what I would want to
see going into three o'clock
[Music]
thank you
let's see if there's any interest in the
top of that
shaded area here
all right we're three o'clock now final
hour New York p.m session Trading
take note where the bodies of the
candles are
foreign
looks heavy
[Music]
foreign
didn't quite get to it
here
do we get any kind of
Insight from that
because I want to show some support
doesn't want to take out this swing High
here or does it just erode into that
going through this again to the downside
is very very very bearish
as long as we find support here
and it doesn't go through it
you take out this swing High here then
we would most likely try to gravity back
up in here
and we're on anybody that's trying to
sell short
he would need to do that though by 3 45
for me to like it
foreign
anything bullish we would not want to
see that at all
foreign
[Music]
now 483 is
the draw for today
I'm going to close
foreign
up here you're interested in 640 this
morning a bit too smooth
foreign
money used that liquidity in the form of
buy side and they
are short where's their best exits
below
I'd like to see this area up here
stay open
I want to see if it's sensitive in here
and touching this
over here so this
if it wants this
I'm sorry 15 000 483 and three quarters
it wants that level going into close I
would want to see this shaded area here
treated as a balanced price range
yeah I measured this range here in the
event that we had to retrace up into it
anything at the 50 would have been good
or less for a short
it didn't even get up there so that to
me is indicative that it's
probably gonna be really neat going into
the clothes
foreign
into this
at least he got the short-term High
there and then reject and go lower and
aim for that fifteen thousand four
eighty three
if it doesn't even go back up into here
that's really weak
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
so I wouldn't want to see anything
on a closing basis
above the midpoint of that blue shaded
area
it's already spent too much time in this
area for my liking
we ran for one size of the liquidity I
mentioned but I was
interested in seeing that
483 level give up the ghost
that would have been both our fools of
liquidity swept
35 minutes or so after three
so now I'm determining
what we'll run for on Market on closed
macro
I don't think we're gonna make a higher
high
and I don't want to see it trade above
halfway of this shaded area here so
either we consolidate
which is yeah
uneventful
or we eventually come out of this
aggressively and run for this sell side
here
[Music]
thank you
foreign
remember what I was asking
price to show over here
look and see if it'll offer it here
at the top of that range
it's an old bissy
I'm sorry Old City
balanced by certain efficiency
[Music]
foreign
hence the reason why
I tell you don't trade these days
I measured the high
to this range here
it's not the your song
it's hard to keep the Rhythm and
just a really crummy uh
fed day I thought I would get a lot more
momentum and movement around here today
but it's not doing so
hanging around
so I'm gonna have to see what we do
tomorrow morning
I will be trading tomorrow
but I don't have what I was hoping for
which will be a real nice heavy bias
where I could see it wants to do this or
that I want to close the video with this
is what I'm going to be doing tomorrow
so that way we can watch and see you
know how I framed it on this
and then use the executions and such
tomorrow but
I don't have anything here to hang my
hat on yet
must be the UFO discussion today took
all the steam out
everybody's watching the UFO disclosure
I realize there's some audio stuff on it
you guys are still Tweeting to me tell
me there's something wrong with the
audio keeps buffering and it's bad I
can't do anything about that
all right high-end equipment I'm using
YouTube YouTubes doing whatever they got
to do with it that comes to you
in a
substandard manner that's not my doing
them
dealing with that kind of lion
now let me close it with this
what keeps me from trading on a date
like this
the things I pointed to here
these are all things that I would expect
to see
in a market that's not being manipulated
it's not being pushed around
artificially
so all this is intervention it's going
Way Beyond what would be reasonable
higher and lower
so when I point out things okay the
cynics will say see it doesn't work when
the point is
that days like this I've already arrived
at and taught you that this is where
you're going to see a
of absence of precision otherwise it
wouldn't I be out here trading it yes
but I'm not this morning I did because
there was something obvious right at the
opening range
but that's it
the rest of the day I mean I would have
I would have taken that
and to run to here and then get up
hopefully up in here my best case
scenario exit would have been up here in
a partial would have been at me that uh
640 level even not 41 I would have been
out 40 at partial and then my best case
scenario here neither of which would
have been filled and I would have had a
stop out
so
it's not a matter of trying to save face
here I'm not trying to you know paint
something that would have wouldn't
happened you know and to make myself
look good the point is is I'm showing
you where the problems lie on days like
this so if you can identify it as a
problem area where you're going to have
friction you don't want to have a
slippery slope it's already bad enough
when you're first trying to learn how to
do this you don't want to compound the
difficulty with a day where even the guy
that comes the things that I highlighted
that I would like to see
did materialize
so if I'm telling you as the educator to
Mentor the person that authored these
Concepts if I tell you I don't trade on
these days because my Concepts don't
hold up well in this particular
environment
why should you go out there and gamble
on
the whole point is for you to understand
that these days make it more complicated
so when I point out things I want you to
observe does it respect those levels
does it do this does it do that no
only a few things happened majority of
it didn't
so when we get to another rate
announcement day in the future when I'm
not doing this with you without showing
you anything and you feel the impulse
they want to go out here and try to
gamble remember this because I'm not
trying to do it
so you shouldn't try to do it it doesn't
matter who comes later on today and
tells you what they did and how much
they did this and this and that nothing
it doesn't matter you can't spend their
money
you can't spend their money and they're
not going to give it to you because they
made it so there's no point even talking
about just know that this is a very very
tricky day just like another on payroll
day
and the odds of you being successful in
it are low
so you don't want to be trading in those
environments
I would have liked to see this
if you look at yesterday's afternoon
price action I trade I was with my
son Karen I was literally all over there
I beat it up pretty bad
and then later part of the day it did
something very similar like it was doing
here and what I was wanting was when I
mentioned I said I want to see it trade
up into this
Gap here and I want to see it sell off
and then reach for the sell side
it did very much that very thing
yesterday and I was waiting for a repeat
scenario the very thing that we saw
yesterday and what I was anticipating
here came all the way up almost at the
very high of it and it started to break
down and what I was watching was does it
have a willingness to get through
this mean threshold the half point of
this down close candle and it wasn't
even able to do that so that was
problematic and you watched me take away
all the things here because I want to
see does it gravitate back up to the
midpoint of this because if it does I
don't want to see it close above it this
here looked good initially went down but
then it this range started acting much
better
you're trading on probabilities
many times you're you're hanging it all
on a myth
some kind of animal pattern some kind of
indicator
and if I can't make Rhyme or Reason out
of where they're going to draw too for
inefficiency
or liquidity
whether it be premium or discount
I'll be just like anybody else on a day
like this
struggling trying to find out where it's
going to go because it's being
controlled it's being
outside the scope of normal Scripts
and it just does these types of things
here
and you can sit here and wrestle like
I've done for years when I was younger
try to figure it out
and I realized I don't need to do that I
don't need to figure that day out I
don't need to know what nylon payroll is
going to do I don't care
because I know I can find my models
plural
on all the other days
of every single month
and I also know there's certain times of
the year where seasonal Tendencies are
going to be more prone to
deliver price in a much more magnificent
manner a lot of speed a lot of distance
the magnitude of the moves will be much
more pronounced
and I try to focus on those because I
know that's where my Edge is that's
where my advantages are that's where my
models shine and the least amount of
manipulation takes place so you don't
want to have
the biggest defensive team go up against
your trades and you're asking
to play in the
the Super Bowl
with the with the team that has the best
defense
on a day that your quarterback has an
injury that's what it's like trading on
these days no matter what you have as a
model whatever whatever you use you're
up against the individuals that roll
this place
and there's no better way of me
communicating to
than to sit out here live and explain to
you what I personally would expect
on a day that I would not expect my
tools to to shine
if this is your first live stream here
you're gonna hear that and say well this
is someone trying to say face no you
don't know what I've said before and my
students will vouch for this I've always
said don't try to trade on these days
don't try to do it because Precision
will evade you
look at that move
look at that one
right after four o'clock earnings
[Music]
sweet sweet look at that that's a nice
rip
so there you go
I stated that I didn't think
back here that we'd see a higher high we
got one
to now
does that type of thing invite you to
want to go out here and crack the code
of this day does it make you want to go
out there and try to
figure out
something that I admit to use there's
better trading opportunities
away from these days
and all you need is one good week
out of a month and it'll fix a lot of
bad smaller little errors
you only need one profitable day per
week
to do well and stop you don't need the
everyday trade
but when you come into this business and
you're brand new and you listen to
Instagram mindsets
and people that
don't really have I understand what
they're supposed to be doing and they're
influencing more than they're educating
you get wrapped up in that kind of stuff
and you think that trading is every day
always
trying to do something you know hyper
active
and that's not what you should be
thinking it is
it's like a sniper they're now out there
Tommy gunning you know spraying all
their bullets into the direction of
their target they're waiting for that
one Mark to walk into their crosshairs
and then they gently squeeze the trigger
with the expectation that when they
shoot they know that that shot has to
make an impact on the Target because
when they shoot
the adversaries can triangulate and get
a vector on where they're at
so they're exposing themselves they're
that's their risk
they're stopwise their stop loss is
their life their soul leaving their body
get so many chances to get stopped out
in that environment if you treat your
trading like that not that you should be
making everything hinge on your trade
being successful
but you should be thinking about the
measure of risk like that
not to be para paralyzing you
or create Traders paralysis but you need
to think about like would a sniper
where
rainbow sweatpants and headband out
there in the jungle
getting ready to take down somebody no
they're gonna be camouflaged they're
going to be in amongst the natural
setting
but they're not going to walk out there
and
no foliage
and when you're out here on days like
this
you get
like a spotlight Channel and you you
can't
You Can't Hide and wait for your good
shot
because the more you hurt yourself just
know that that's a Learning lesson
growth pains
growing pains are never fun
the mistake I made and some of you might
make as well is that you think you're
gonna figure it out and know what to do
every time these days come
but you don't appreciate the magnitude
of how much they're manipulated
like you have no idea
you will
over time watching it you'll say oh man
it wasn't obvious at the time but now I
can see it
right now this looks like you'll find 20
different retail things in here that you
should have bought and sold from that's
because hindsight's 2020.
you're going to see all kinds of things
in here even maybe I have taught
oh yeah I see a concept here I see a an
overblock there
unless you know the narrative none of
that stuff's gonna work
none of it will work
and that's the that's the we're at the
roulette table this is my last analogy
I'm going to close it because I need to
get something
raw at the casino
and we're standing around the roulette
table
and you had the Bulls
they're betting on black you have the
Bears they're bet known red
you think it's 50 50 you got a 50 50
chance
it's black or red
but you don't realize that the market
makers are green
MS favorable for them to take both sides
out
Green's coming up
and they'll play Green
all day long on non-trial payroll
they'll play Green on
a rate announcement like this
it did move a lot
I mean think about the total range here
not in terms of where we have been in
terms of volatility
now years ago when I first started this
would have been ridiculous in terms of
volatility but this is nothing in the
grand scheme of things where we are now
and that was the first clue that we're
not seeing a whole lot of movement here
remember I was telling you at two
o'clock I was like yeah it's kind of
lame actually
and at 2 30 we saw a run
it took the 640 buy side out
and then
Consolidated and go into four o'clock we
have one more pump and creates a higher
harm
and we're sitting around that 640 level
now
so
anyway
learn not to be interested in doing this
as a live trading day
that's the main takeaway okay
if you haven't at least took that
and put that into your toolbox to say
don't tread here
do that here do that today
I promise you unless you heard this
unless you watched me try to do it today
you would have believed that I'm sitting
around here running up and down all day
long on a day like this and it's not
like that on these types of days for me
which is exactly why I tell you don't
touch them
I have other things I'm never going to
teach you and even those things are not
helping me
there's no advantage on a day like this
for me none
I'm just like everyone else they weren't
being respected that should not happen
if they fail that means it's giving you
a warning sign that you're offside or
it's not it's not performing like you
want to
now
as a younger man when I was 20 I took
that as
um yeah I'm just gonna get in your head
I'm gonna I'm gonna get ahead of my
signal I know my signal will happen
after I get in
the market will bend in my will
and that's many times what led to me
blowing on an account
when you're new you don't know that and
you try to ignore it like it's not going
to happen to you like you're going to be
the exception to the rule
and I I promise you every single person
that's ever hurt themselves trying to do
something like that it's the same way
you're not any different I wasn't any
different when it happened to me
you think that it's going to work for
you and you ignore even the smallest
little inclination inside you know that
if I should be doing this but
well we went to the casino we might as
well bet at all
and you can't do that kind of stuff on
days like this
you can't not and survive not do well
you'll have severe drawdown
you'll lose your funded accounts you'll
blow your combine you'll go on severe
drawdown with your Live accounts or even
Bloom them
because you get emotional you want to be
right you want to fix something you did
it wrong earlier now it seems obvious no
just don't touch it
use the information after the fact
it's okay I feel confident that we're
going to go higher or lower
which
let me take a quick look at this
15 minute chart
look at that
internet that is really nuts you know if
I were making the market for Nasdaq okay
this is my last point on closing it I
know I keep saying that but I'm always
over delivering the idea of it trading
order did here we went up into this area
here
I personally I would absolutely murder
everything and go lower
Thursday into Friday
I'm not saying that's what it's going to
happen but I wouldn't be surprised if
that's what they do
how am I going to trade Thursday
I'm going to sleep
through London I'm going to get up
tomorrow around 6 30 New York local time
and I'm going to identify where are my
15-minute pools overcoated just like I
have this chart here
right now it's 7 15
739.25 level
or
fifteen thousand five hundred and
fifteen even and therefore if it goes
lower than the
483.75 level
I am not confident right now to know
which one I've wanted to know
the way we closed today
I wanted to know what I could tell you
what side I won
like when I'm doing the analysis
commentary because that and this is
where I think it's going to draw to I
don't know I'm I'm torn between both of
them so whenever that happens and it
does happen in my analysis sometimes
students get frustrated because they
want me to be able to know what it is
all the time and sometimes I don't
and you're not going to always either
and you have to grow comfortable with
not knowing sometimes and just waiting
for more information more Intel that's
all
and it cost me nothing today to sit out
here and do this
it cost me no money it cost me no
emotion whatsoever
the only thing is is I was hoping at the
end of it I would know what I wanted to
do beforehand because I would tell you
okay this is where we're going to draw
to tomorrow and then we would all watch
it I don't have that here nothing
nothing really shows me one side or the
other better than the other because
they're just back and forth and this is
a whole lot of nothing going on
and
I'm not confident co-signing on One
Direction or the other so
the best I have to do is explain to you
how I'm going to treat it tomorrow I'm
not going to look at London I'm not
going to get up and see what London's
doing
I'm gonna wait until around 6 30. and
I'll either get woke up from my mom from
my children's mother or I will wake up
by a circadian circadian alarm clock I
don't have an alarm per se I just I know
what I want to wake up and then usually
get up at that time
I sleep in like four hour Cycles so if I
lay down I'm gonna get up between three
hours and a half to four hours
and that's usually how I sleep like that
I do
two of them and maybe a cat Napier there
whenever I can fit it and I have
cleaning rest
but based on these specific levels what
we're gravitating towards I know that
I'll probably get a 20 or 30 handle
range of opportunity
if I'm waking up at ahead of seven
o'clock between seven o'clock and 8 30
I'll look to see if there's something I
can use to frame it if not then I'll
wait at 8 30 to 10 o'clock
in that range between when the news
embargo lifts and the opening range is
complete 9 30 till uh 10 o'clock
and then I'll do something with the
Silver Bullet but I I already know I
already know
I'm making money tomorrow
I already know that that's going to
happen
but I know there is a chance that is
much more significant of me losing on a
day like this
so I have to respect that I have to also
identify my own limitations
you don't see that in the trading
Community you don't see that on Twitter
you don't see that in Instagram in
Discord and
Facebook
you see go go baby
and I I think that is foolish like you
have to every but everybody has a
weakness and there's no shame in
admitting what your weakness is that's
actually wisdom
that's wisdom
if you're a weight trainer and you know
you can't bench press 500 pounds why the
hell are you going to try to crawl under
those plates and try to do it
so you have to be responsible you have
to know where you're going to excel
where's your Edge where's your best
trading conditions
but on it other side of that
by journaling you learn by real data
real Journal experiences or you were
there it happened
what keeps repeating on what type of
scenario what type of day
what are you trying to trade
what model are you trying to force but
maybe not
be supportive with your
or compatible with your personality
these are very important things that no
one really touches on
but they're the very defining moments
that make you or break you
there's a way to do this
and be profitable and it'll feel easy it
ain't easy because you have to go
through a lot of stuff to figure
yourself out and then what model fits
you
but when you get to that point it's easy
to make money doing this
you always have risk
that's always there but it's easier
to take the initiative and trade with
that underlying risk because you know
you're in a condition or an environment
using a model that you trust that it's
conducive for you to find success in it
but in the beginning when you're brand
new or you're listening to someone
that's too new to even know better
you're going to have a whole lot of fear
and anxiety and regret doing things like
trading in these days
I mean seriously folks let me look at
this chart I mean look at that
does that look like
something that you can't live without
like you got to be in that I have to be
in that ICT you understand I love her
I get it
but you'll grow up and you'll understand
that she's not the only one for you
or he deference to the ladies
so
anyway
I'm not certain and we'll have another
one of these before we close in November
but uh I will do the non-farm payrolls
going forward so that way we can get
another