good morning folks all right so I'm
going to try to get through this rather
quickly some things have occurred while
I was asleep last night I want to look
into concerning the Middle East and
Israel and
whatnot the dollar
Index here on the weekly chart uh we hit
our objective the first objective which
was this candle's high on the weekly
chart so that high comes in at 107
274 and the week that we just closed its
high is 107.3 48 so just above it
reaching into this
inbalance now having the retracement
like we
saw and the lower close uh that to me is
perfectly acceptable I we've had 1 2 3 4
five 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 weeks of buy side
delivery that's like 3 months of steady
oneway direction to a premium level and
it's reasonable to anticipate you know
something of a
retracement I'm not trying to pick the
top in the dollar as I mentioned many
times
before
incidentally uh you might want to take a
look at the economic calendar I'm not
going to show it here it's something
that you should be looking to do on your
own anyway day by day and for the week
to come always on the weekend uh try to
get a feel for what it's potentially
offering in terms of underlying risk
with the high impact news drivers or
medium impact news drivers or Fed chair
speakers something to that effect and
there's a lot of that next week so next
week week's trading will be laced with a
lot of
volatility Monday's a holiday so we're
going to have a pretty wild week to come
and with all the things that's just
popped off with the violence over in
Gaza and Israel um that's going to
increase tensions as well so I know it
sounds silly that you know those two
sides always have an issue with one
another um I do believe we're going to
see something
significant uh arise from all this so
for the folks that have been watching or
listening to the Twitter space I did
over a year ago um I told you about in
18 months from then we'd start seeing
some stuff going
on we're at it now okay so you just need
to be paying attention to it's going to
have its reverberations in the
marketplace it's going to have
reverberations where you live even
though it might be on the other side the
world that stuff's going to start
happening and impacting your everyday
life so daily chart you see we went
right up into that inefficiency right
above the high that we were looking for
or not the high but the low of the
inefficiency that's what's being
highlighted here and there was buy side
still that I have an interest
in we rallied
up Friday we went right up into this
small little Gap in here
to this candle's low this candle's High
non payroll sent it up and then rejected
it consequent encroachment of this
Wick we'll highlight
that
so
105 90 and four pit
bets that's a that's a level of watch
see if there's any kind of reaction off
of that otherwise we could return back
down
[Music]
into this daily Gap okay so I'm going to
leave these levels here as they are
we're going to drop down into an hourly
chart you can see the effects of non
front payroll I did a quiet not
intentionally live stream uh the other
day and I talked for like an hour
thinking that the audio was good and
took the chance of assuming that it was
and like Murphy's La whatever can go
wrong did and I've done that in the past
with the recordings you pre-recorded
videos and some of them were rather long
and discovered after the fact that the
microphone was on mute or wasn't
connected or had an issue and didn't
pick up any of the audio so a little bit
of a annoyance but um I drew out key
levels for liquidity I mentioned this
one in here and I mentioned this one
here graph you buy
graphically depicting it on the chart
even though I wasn't saying audibly if
you're a student of mine you know
exactly what I'm drawing your attention
to the liquidity above and below and we
went right for it
again here on nonfarm payroll
numbers then rejected it so they pumped
it
up during the 8:30 even though it's
showing 8:00 it's an hourly candle so
it's including the post NFP number
release at 8:30 a.m. and then quickly
sent it lower attacking the cell side
here so here's
that consequent cor of that daily Wick
10594 and the daily Fair Gap
there and I mentioned how when we were
up in here just be mindful of this order
Block in here in that
Gap so
ahead of the nonr
payroll we working it trade down
into the OR BL a little bit more and
then sent it up into buy side and then
rejected and sent it to the cell side
here going into next week you want to
have this level here
this
shaded area I'm going to look at that as
a potential inversion everybody out
going
forward so it could come back up trade
into the breaker which is high low
higher high it took liquidity this down
closed candle that is your breaker and
is inside of the lower end and lower
quadrant of this old inefficiency now
because we went through it it's
reasonable to anticipate lower price is
initially going into next week so if we
see a trade up into that that might be a
catalyst that send this lower if we
don't take out this low
first I like the idea of coming back up
in hitting the breaker touching this an
inversion fair value Gap and then
trading lower for the cell side worst
case scenario we open with a gap lower
and never return back into this area
here which is you know potential you you
never know where we're going to open up
on Sunday now because of all
the militaristic things that are going
on over in the Middle East uh those
types of things cause a lot of concern
and and they like to use those things to
to stimulate the marketplace so we might
see an extreme gap opening on Sunday as
a result to what's taking place last
night and what obviously we'll be going
on for the remainder of the weekend
going into next week
um let's go into the daily chart once
more and breeze on through to Euro I
don't want to spend too much time this
morning
so we had the relative equal lows we
mentioned that we traed down into it uh
my targets as I mentioned earlier in the
week uh I was done like everything was
met everything I outlined was was
delivered in price for the dollar Index
the Euro for the pound
dollar uh Aussie dollar
um es and NASDAQ so everything I
mentioned with the exception of gold
gold didn't quite get down to that uh
180 for level yet so that was the only
thing that didn't really deliver thus
far but um pound dollar we saw I'm sorry
euro dollar we saw it delivered below
the cell side and came back up watch
this Gap in here once more and then the
order block right there so these These
are the PD arrays I'm
watching it's perfectly acceptable for
it to retrace back up to here and still
not really
have
anything in terms of a a confirmed
reversal it's really important that you
understand that I try to avoid what I'm
highlighting here is the order block
opening in the low these two consecutive
up closed candles that's your par sh
block which is above this Gap and this
shortterm high right there on that
candle is by side so those are the three
PD arrays in logic we've already traded
back to consequent encouragement of this
Wick
here so this is kind of like the line
the saying if we get above that and
um start to expand or you know
accelerate in terms of speed then it
might be much more uh deeper retracement
required and in that case we may have to
revisit
this okay so um if I were to be held to
tell me right now what makes you
confident that we probably made a an
important low for the rest of the year
and it goes higher from where we're at
it needs to take out this high and then
once it goes above this inefficiency
should it ever do it this year or the
remainder of this year in 2023 we hit it
in active support once it starts doing
that then and only then would I'd
qualify that as a a low of any real
significance I I try to teach the
avoidance of trying to pick tops and
bottoms um because it's a skill set that
you're not going to be consistent with
no one's going to be that consistent
with it
and I'll just leave it at that okay so
it's not important that you try to get
that type of uh Turning Point you want
to trade in a direction of order flow
which removes a lot of the concern for
being
perfect all right so here is the
business on the houry chart on
Euro you can see we traded down took out
the cell side here and went right down
to that old
low nailing it here and here the old low
on the daily chart that's what we were
looking to see it sweep below that's
what that level is and it hits it
beautifully then runs back above so
there's buy side here so just be mindful
of
that that might be what we probably Gap
above you I wouldn't be surprised if we
end up gapping above or gapping close to
this and then running a little bit
higher on
Sunday daily charts go back up
to that Ty frame and look at the pound
dollar all right so pounded again what
we were looking for we were looking for
lower prices um it's acted much like the
NASDAQ in relationship to the es whereas
pound dollar was a little reluctant to
go lower in sympathy with the euro
dollar with the um run to our premium
Target on the dollar index that daily
inefficiency where we trade to it this
week and then we've been selling off
since
then the wick and consequent
encouragement of that you know we have
to watch this this is going to be going
into or we open next week and we could
revisit back
into shorter time frame premium arras
again avoiding the entire idea of
picking the bottom okay I'm not I'm not
trying to support the idea of anyone
doing that and I don't try to do that
myself so longer term I'm still focusing
here
and you know for three months straight
dollar Index going up having one weekly
down close doesn't change the trend for
me so if it's going to have a
retracement then it's going to be seen
you conversely with other Forex paays so
they're going to have a little bit of a
you know retrace as well but avoid the
whole idea of trying to pick a top and
and bottom respectively to those markets
longer term I'm still focused down here
for sell
side and let's take a quick look at
Aussie
dollar I was looking for the sell side
to be upset on that market and we showed
it the other day and we we got it here
so as long as we stay below these uh
these highs here I think we're lower you
know across the board for Aussie I liked
how we went back up in this
inefficiency so have this on your chart
if we resume higher on dollar next
week and we don't really move outside of
this and efficiency on the
upside we'll be looking for lower prices
on Australian dollar down to get into
this sell side right there okay that
kind of gives you an idea if we break
above these
highs I would not be interested in
Aussie dollar at all all so I'd like to
see it remain heavy and bearish and
eventually you know reach below here
otherwise I would not want to be buying
going long on doy dollar just not
interested I'm not trading Forex at all
anymore but I know you all like to hear
my opinion about it so that's that gold
we'll do that one real
quick all right and as I mentioned in
the live streams um
in the recent weeks I said that gold
would be looking to trade down into this
inefficiency between this candle's low
this candle's High that's why this is
being shaded here um once we broke
through it it would act as an inversion
fair value Gap we opened on this day
trade up into it broke
lower the order
blocks and the sell side was the
relative equal lows that was where I was
taking your attention to um this was the
very shortterm Target
we didn't get that on Friday non front
payroll came in and did its thing and
ultimately I still think that this is a
viable
Target and let's see where we at
um let's do
[Music]
es
right
okay so es we traded
into our old inefficiency
[Music]
here body stayed inside that we had
Candlestick Tails or or Wix however you
want to refer to it it's it's the bodies
are telling you the narrative so if we
have a deeper retracement it's perfectly
acceptable for it to come back up into
this area
here so my eye is on this
inefficiency right
there
so it can trade up in the that
inefficiency and it still by my
definition hasn't reversed and it would
be complet completely acceptable so I
could trade up here and then end up
trading lower uh these lows here just a
little too clean for my liking and over
here so sell side in here and this low
is my focus longer term um I'm
completely willing to be proven wrong
because you know on a daily
chart these ideas tend
to pan out over a longer period of time
it's a lot more forgiving as well in
terms of a missed move or if you do
something wrong with the
analysis you can get yourself back in
sync and then trade once you get better
visibility of what the Market's likely
to do uh right now I'm I'm still holding
and subscribing to the idea that nothing
has changed to bullish there's
absolutely zero reasons for anyone to be
bullish on stocks I mean there's nothing
there's literally nothing for anyone to
be at these multiples you if you're
going to talk about things fundamentally
it's absurd
where these stocks are still trading it
it's ridiculous and at some point you
know the the chickens are going to come
home to roost and that means you know
things are going to have to hit the
reality and lower prices are in
order so try to avoid all this business
in here I don't think we're done and
lower prices is where I'm focusing but
this short-term likelihood of a
retracement it's completely within the
realm of possibility uh 60-minute
[Music]
chart all right and here is saleside non
foray roll drop down into
that hit the order block
here rallied
up obvious buy side waiting right here
with an inefficiency over
[Music]
here so you want to have this on your
chart going forward into next
week and again with everything that's
going
on geopolitically speaking um you we
could really see an extreme gap opening
on Sunday so um and it could be either
direction so I'm expecting a lot of
difference between where we settled on
Friday and where we open because it
could it could do either one I tend to
think that this was all pumped up ahead
of all the economic news
drivers that are due out and all the the
speeches that's going to be had
on the trading week that's coming
so just be mindful that this is
classically what's seen with non-ir
payroll in my opinion um they take the
market in a Direction which many times
is like a a fake
out okay just like I teach that the nonr
payroll and the rate announcements for
fomc um they are two stage de U
deliveries whereas initially we see the
market
drop at nonr payroll so that's the first
stage and then the second stage is the
reversal of that move and then you see
it happening here every single time we
sit down and do fomc analysis or if I've
done them live streaming you watching it
happen with you over shoulder um it it's
always the case where it's two-stage
delivery and it was just like this again
over Friday the only thing it was a
little bit surprising is they took a
whole lot of distance in like 2 minutes
you know a very very short time they
they covered
175 handles and that's you know a
wonderful illustration of why you need
to be respecting the measure of risk
with this particular because it can harm
you and your stop- loss won't work like
it won't work in the first minute it GED
down ad
handles on
NASDAQ so you know that's that's pretty
significant drop and no one can really
you know tolerate that if they're doing
contracts that's a that's a that's a big
smack in the
face keep my wife's name out of your
mouth
so
the buy side here they went they ran on
it aggressively and I talked about
how the market would likely close in its
upper 50% upper 60% of its range and U
we we got that so it's all in the live
stream and I'm not trying to try to say
face here
because everything I said in the live
stream you're welcome to go and listen
to it for the nonr peoll live stream
where I was watching it live with you
the things that would be concerning
things that would be utilized for
reading price you know all that stuff is
in that live stream so you can listen to
and revisit whatever you want to take
away from
it the drop again at
8:30 that was the first stage delivery
it means it's the fake drop it's the
fake move it's the thing that's most
likely going to be faded in the rest of
the day we see that happening here 8:30
look at the
high up here upper left hand
corner that comes in at 4294 even and
the low comes in at 4248 and a
quarter that's a that's a significant
amount of handles for
S&P at $50 per point or handle you know
it doesn't take long to to go into a
significant draw
down swing High Here let take that off
here
swing High taken here so there's a shift
in Market structure that low to that
high as it's retracing what's it
reaching
for inefficiency right here and Order
block the last down closed
candle
note the
bodies where they reside inside that
fair Val you
got see
that zo me a little bit so you can see
it
[Music]
better so even though we went outside
that's a mohawk it's just a little tiny
coloring Outside the Lines it's t it's
typical and then we rally up order block
touched body both on these candles
signifying that okay we're probably
going to run higher so where's it going
to
run rebalance all this and go back to
the previous day settlement so
using what I teach in terms of the riv
of trading
hours where we settled the previous day
here on
Thursday it trades right back up into it
there okay and you need not see it trade
above here or here to be profitable
all right let's go into a one minute
chart and we'll take a look at
the Silver
[Music]
Bullet
okay the fair value Gap we drop down
into it we don't get a shift in Market
structure until I mean this is
technically it's a a shift to Market
structure Above This High rate there and
they used the higher time frame 5 minute
Fair got which really could have been
refined to inside here so dropping down
lower time
frames on a moment chart you would have
that that would be a little bit bit
concerning for me there so again it
would have to show willingness to want
to go higher and it does that with this
swing High being broken
there and the
underlying premise would be this was the
first stage delivery and the second
stage would be moving back up and I
mentioned on the live stream that you
know it might not go above and go higher
it could just go up here rebalance and
then consolidate because it's Friday it
is
um on the heels of nonfarm
payroll we've covered a lot of distance
and we had already had a intra week
retracement from Dollar targets es
targets so one of those things were
likely to be a catalyst to cause us to
be content with consolidating but
they've taken it a great deal higher
which you to me looking at it now it
feels like it's all you know fluff
they're you they're fluffing it up going
into next week and next week you know
major damage is going to be done and I
could be wrong it could be sending it
even higher aggressively higher you know
and it's okay you know as long as it's
moving around I don't care I'll find
something I'll get in there and do
something but we want to try to have a a
good read on it using the daily charts
and it makes things a lot better when it
is in concert with what we have expected
or expect with the weekly chart so
that's why I'm saying ahead of
the new week where I don't know where
we're going to open but I think we're
going to have a big gap opening one
extreme or the other above or below on
all the markets
um but I think we'll have a very
volatile week and I'd like to
see initially I'd like to see it retrace
a little bit further lower on dollar to
kind of like sell the idea that it
topped to retail Traders and everybody
else go long still at these elevated
levels on ES NASDAQ Forex paays and then
and
gold and then they send it lower
aggressively next week you know by next
Friday's close you know I would like to
see lower levels on all the uh Forex
Pairs and on ES and NASDAQ and gold and
higher prices on dollar Index that's
what I'd like to see uh but I have to
have the alignment with the technicals
and what price is doing when it's time
to expect it to be delivering so this is
a matter of waiting and seeing so going
into next week that's what I'm
expecting but we see a trade back down
into that inefficiency here and then it
starts to really ramp up and that occurs
at
1021 okay so um what you what you don't
understand is this is a silver bullet
because it's using a fair value Gap even
though the fair value Gap is outside and
before 10:00 and this is part of the
rules go back and listen to the
recording the fair value Gap does not
need to be inside of 10 to 11 the setup
is a retracement into a fair Val got
between 10 and 11
so seeing that is the case and we're
seeing it rally up if you didn't take
this one in
here you could use this
one
and it found its opportunity to drop
down into consequent encouragement which
is midpoint of that Gap here with the
expectation that we would see it at
least run back
to the previous day settlement by using
regular trading hours which right now
we're toggled at electronic trading
hours so from here to where regular
trading hours previous settlement price
all offered room to Rally which would be
going above this high and maybe maybe
reaching above here if you're so
inclined to hold
that but silver bolet we're only looking
for five handles and as a as a minimum
and it offered it here so it end up
keeping you you held on to it it's
that's a pretty good
[Music]
run and settling on the
close and here's your Silver Bullet at
the 2:00 hour here that fair value got
all right so let's go up to the daily
chart and do next I can be done with
this all right there's a whole lot of
business going on in this one isn't
[Music]
it all right so I wanted to see it trade
down into this inefficiency um we have
returned back into this area right up in
here so I'm going to add
this for the sake of this
analysis okay so we traded up into that
inefficiency
there we
are avoiding trying to pick the bottoms
okay um again I feel like this was all
part of this consolidation Trail stop
losses were brought down to here and
also getting up into this inefficiency
perfect excuse for them to have run
liquidity for anyone that's been
trailing it because I believe that we
might be seeing a larger selloff coming
okay and and this would be classic
scenario for that very thing so we've
Consolidated everyone wanted to see it
drop lower I wanted to see it drop lower
but it just wouldn't drop doesn't mean
we couldn't find setups obviously we've
outlined it you saw me executing you saw
me doing things with it and long story
short where we're at by taking the buy
side of above these highs here and back
into this inefficiency this upsets
anyone that has been short so now if we
are going to see a lower deliveri and
price on the indices specifically NASDAQ
I'd like to see it be trading down
here um that would be perfect
engineering of sending it higher getting
everybody thinking that we're you know
we're bullish when we're not I'm not
bullish on NASDAQ I'm bearish it doesn't
mean that I won't take
Longs okay um it just means that they
have to be intraday scalps because it's
going against my higher time frame order
flow and bias and the narrative I think
is that we went higher to upset the
shorts knock them out and if they buy
stops that are being trailed while
they're bearish if they buy stops being
triggered Above This
High those buy stops are being
accumulated as smart money for shorts
like that's how I'm that's the internal
dialogue that I'm holding when I see
this chart as it is so I know there's a
whole lot of this stuff here cuz I don't
have it set to only show on specific
time frames and I just wanted to go out
here and do this because I want to spend
a lot of time studying what's going on
over in the Middle East because I want
to talk about it on Sunday on a Twitter
space maybe but the
uh the idea I'm holding here is we went
up just to go down that that's kind of
like what I'm suggesting here until I'm
proven wrong you what would make that
you know a
truth this inefficiency if he trade
above it and it touches it and starts to
show uh some support starts to Rally
then I'll concede and say I'm wrong and
you maybe something underlying did occur
down here that I
missed and then we're going to go higher
there's a whole lot of things in motion
right now and geopolitically um with
Russia and China
there's so many things so many things
that makes it very complex to have a
macro read from a weekly and daily that
has a longterm time Horizon that won't
be met with
shortterm disruptions that May
challenge the opinion or sentiment idea
of someone that's been doing a lot less
so I'm leaning on the fact that I know
that this is the climate for that to
occur
meaning I see in the chart that it's not
enough for me to trust that it's made a
low like in other words I don't see it
from where we are right now I don't see
it trading to make a new high up here
okay um I don't see
it as bullish I just see it as going up
to get ready to have
another a sharper drop lower
okay and if I'm wrong it's fine it's
okay I mean it's good for you to see me
get it
wrong doesn't happen all that
[Music]
often it sounds irant I know but it's
the truth so anyway the hourly chart we
had the buy side in here we finally got
that level tagged but not before seeing
the drop below here taking out cells
side and rally up uh this opening range
Gap that level I I taught how to
determine what that is and it's again
using the regular trading
hours here so that was Thursday where we
settled and then on
Friday where we opened at 9:30 we had an
opening Gap so it makes it the opening
Gap High why because we open down below
it remember we start this annotation
with opening range Gap
settlement so as soon as we get to
around 9:15 or so right before several
minutes before the opening bell at 9:30
eastern time uh that'll tell you what
it's likely to do and since we had a gap
opening lower we went down took out the
previous day's
low Wicked through it and then came back
that that trade here that was the
premise I was working with okay so for
um
I'll get to it in a second relative
equal highs there's b side there and
then there's this actual gap which is a
real liquidity void okay um when you see
these single candles like that okay
technically that is not a liquidity void
a liquidity void is where there's
absolutely zero trading going on between
two candlesticks or two time frames so
this duration of time measurement on
that candle on an hourly basis and then
the next candle here there is no trading
at all
between these two price points this
candle's this candle's low and that
candle's high so this is a real
liquidity void and the price gets itself
worked into buy side delivery here so my
question to you is
this if this was a real Gap and it is
obviously if it trades up into it here
with buy side what would make it a
balance price range sell side so I'm
expecting price to want to pass that it
back down into this range because every
Gap should be or every
inefficiency and or Gap should be
delivered with both up and down price
action so a a buy side delivery as
Market goes up through
one range defined as we have here the
difference between this candle's high
and that candle's low low there's no
there's no trading there no one had a
trade there no one had a fill no one was
selling short or buying long no one was
closing trades there there was literally
nothing being booked between these two
candles that's what makes this a
liquidity void it's void of
liquidity so what will happen is the
market algorithm will deliver price to
and through that range and what has it
done so far on the hourly chart it's
only delivered with buy side
delivery not liquidity by side delivery
that means price has booked delivering
price as it goes up so it's reasonable
to expect it to drop back down for the
sake of offering both buy side and sell
side and then once that occurs then the
real narrative will be in play do we go
higher or do we go lower and when we
leave that range that's shaded here it
will act as a balanc price range and
whatever Direction it works from after
the balance price range is established
that's probably going to be the the
price run that has a lot more
sustainability versus right now I'm
speculating and not really having a clue
what it wants to do exactly going into
the opening on Sunday like we don't know
what it's going to do no one knows what
it's going to do but I do expect an
extreme gap opening because of all the
things that's going on right
now all right 15 minute time
frame okay so here is our Gap here and
again showing rular trading hours this
was Thursday
settlement and then when we open down
here so that opening range Gap is from
here and the opening of that
candle then we had this inefficiency
here and then the new week opening Gap
and its consequent encroachment in that
buy side that we were talking about all
this week finally got its rear end
smoked and then powered through it so
again here's that inefficiency I
mentioned that is a real liquidity void
that by side was delivered to look at
the the reaction
here that trading right there reaction
there is that low of the liquidity void
on the hourly
chart so you have to have these
understood visually it's probably going
to be helpful to you if you have them
drawn on your
chart if I was awake and I was sleeping
during this
time I I was trying to take a nap but I
ended up sleeping over 5 hours so I was
apparently in need of rest but I wasn't
able to see any of this stuff here in
the afternoon so it would have been
something I would have liked to take a
trade on um I would have done this here
like as this candle opened and dropped
down into the order block there I would
have used that to go long trusting that
these lows here wouldn't be touched
again because it's the low of the
liquidity void on the hourly chart which
is a a range that's defined where there
absolutely zero trading just like there
is no trading
here see
that
so a good example of what I'm talking
about where there's a liquidity void
there's one right here okay look at it
here from that candle's low I'm sorry
that candle's high and that candle's low
we'll extend it out in
time
so what's missing in here buy side and
sell side delivery so there's no up or
close candlesticks or
Wicks until we get down here so we see
it trade down into it
here we see a trade down into it here
look where the bodies are stopping you
see that that's not
random move down again the bodies are
staying
where inside of that real liquidity void
Chris Lor is not going to teach it like
that okay and I know that sounds
disrespectful but I'm so tired
of hearing people say that I regurgitate
or teach what he's taught because I had
the man himself come out on Twitter and
tell you all publicly it ain't
it this when we leave it okay we've
taken out the cell side here we Trad it
back down into an inefficiency that's a
larger time
frame then we leave
it this energetic
runaway makes this a balanced price
range this Gap here what is it missing
buy side not any longer it's been
offered there so in this area here
between this candle's low and this
candle's
high it's missing what sell-side
delivery it means down delivery price
moving lower so in my mind here's how
I'm visually thinking about this as I'm
talking about it live with you well live
in this recording right um it's 8:00 in
the morning on Saturday
so that's as live as going to
get so the market is uh being pumped up
ahead of next week's economic calendar
and I believe because we have a short
week because Monday's a holiday I
believe that we will see
acceleration in terms of volatility and
I believe that all this is
fluff in this area down here
will be needed to be
Revisited so I'll highlight that now so
it's on my
chart and everything else I'll remove
that's not Salient like for instance
this opening range Gap High I don't need
that anymore um actually I'm going to
keep it on here for a moment um
the five minute
[Music]
chart in
here you can see how we we we trade down
into that inefficiency after taking sell
side on the Thursday low in the morning
session we rout it
up 11:00 we have a fair value Gap with a
breaker so we have this high low high
lower
low and I apologize it's it's a lot
of lipstick on this I apolog
but I want to get through it and usually
I would have all these things removed so
that way I can take your focus right to
the only thing I want you to be looking
at as I'm talking and that's why I do it
with PowerPoint makes it a lot easier it
makes it like very streamline for me to
teach but whenever I'm going over charts
live like this um and I'm pulling out
what I see is as it's happening it's a
little bit more organic you know some of
you like it like that um but for the
folks that tend to complain that I go on
and on and on uh because I I love
teaching and I want you to know
everything about what it is I'm talking
about not just be familiar with it and
give you a false sense of security like
you understand how to do it because you
watch me discuss something in an
abbreviated tense um that that's not
really learning and that's not someone
that's willing to put in what's required
as at work but the breaker here and I
know some of you're like well why you
highlighting the down Clos candle I say
t why aren't you doing the up Clos
candle because we're looking at a f-
minute chart so inside that highest up
closed candle I'm sorry that up that the
highest candle in a FIV minute chart
there's going to be an up close candle
in that on one minute chart just give me
a moment okay I already know what you're
thinking I already know the questions
you got popping up in your head you can
see how we worked in that fair B got
right there there so institutional order
entry drill here and here and then we
send price higher it's also occurring at
what price
level what's going on in
here we have the new week opening Gap
low consequent encroach of the new week
opening Gap and then the new week
opening Gap high so between the new week
opening Gap low and its consequent
encouragement or midpoint level what
level is that between these two halfway
it's the lower quadrant and that's what
you're seeing
there so when you have a bias when you
have a narrative in play that you think
that the market will deliver either on a
buy side run or sell Side
Run and you're inside of an
inefficiency you need to be cognizant of
that the grading of that range or
inefficiency is not quarter Theory we're
using logic based on inefficiencies and
or a range that is implied it may not be
there technically yet and that's what I
talk about in my core content lessons
grading a price r that is not quarters
Theory even though I'm talking about a
quadrant of a specific range
go and look at go study quarters Theory
and you'll be just like I've told you
with everything else it's not white offl
it's not supply and demand it's not
Elliot wave it's not none of that stuff
this is absolutely the market this is
what the algorithm is doing everything
else is going to explain things
perfectly in
hindsight I'm telling you what to do and
look for before it happens I'm doing on
all time frames in live streams in
pre-recorded analysis and you watch it
pan out that's bending time and space
so anyway I'm going ready to go into
Twitter mode and start going off but let
me just reel myself in here Lord help me
so the market rallies up we have an
inefficiency here and we trade to that
as
well and just a real nice run price
higher up
into the inefficiency that it has tagged
as I mentioned we on on a higher time
frame so here is the business for the
quote unquote ICT student on Twitter
that said I got it wrong um I want to
pay attention now okay pay
[Music]
attention because I said in the live
stream for the uh nonr payroll it's a
two-stage delivery okay so it's a
two-stage delivery meaning that it will
likely do what feed the first move just
like fomc teach you when the rate
announcement comes out the 2:00 run to
2:30 that's the fake move so you have to
determine what what did they do between
2:00 and 2:30 during the rate
announcements nonfarm payroll is the
same macro it's the same thing that
they're doing the first run not all the
time predominantly yes but most
cases the first run at 8:30 when the
news is hitting the wires whatever that
direction is in price that is the fake
move that's the first stage delivery the
second stage is the opposite of whatever
that is meaning we saw price do what it
drops
down gets everybody thinking okay it's
going to go lower it crushes everyone
that's already
long and it did so in stunning fashion
very quickly which scares everyone in
the marketplace it terrifies them then
the market does the second stage which
is opposing what the 830
news sentiment shift caused everyone to
think that it would keep going lower
keep going lower keep going
lower they trapped them short and then
they run against the move that took
place in the morning so um pay attention
you see that right
there here see let me show it to you
again here look at that you see that
right there that's not Market replay
that's not Market Replay that is not
Market replay folks okay so what that is
is me trading using the logic of the
first stage delivery down
here let me go into electronic trading
hours okay and I'm looking at Price
anticipating that it's going to use
these wicks in here okay um I want to I
want know that I'm on side before I do
this because non payroll can trick
me sometimes it just will behave in a
manner where I will get smoked if I
allow them to do it to me you know it's
it's me to blame right so because I
outlined you
know the the second stage is opposite to
what you see in the morning at
8:30 on these big news
drivers I felt that it was something
that would be reasonable for it to trade
up to the opening range Gap High that's
that level right here okay and again let
me take you back to electron um sorry
regular trading hours and see where it's
anchored here is the Thursday settlement
price so that's the Gap from where we
opened on Friday down here at 9:30 so
that Gap I was looking for that Gap
closure I'll have to put this back in a
second I was looking for the price to
run
here and obviously as I mentioned I was
tired so I put the order on put the
limit order on to stop and if it would
have been stopped out I would have
showed you here you go here's what
happened but here is what happened the
price ran up to closing that Gap but
more specifically I wanted to see it
trade and give me a limit exit just
below that opening range Gap high so
that's why you see my exit is
14, 856 and A4 whereas that price level
let me put everything back like it was
CU I want that level to stay there CU
this void is significant to me and it's
also has the added benefit of having an
old PIR Gap in it
here so what is it still lacking here
big big big big paradigm shift for you
folks before I finish this so buy side
and balance sell side efficiency here
and we have it here again what's it
missing cide delivery we didn't get it
here because it's a void and only pass
through one way here so what is it
missing downside delivery so my
attention is in this shaded area in this
fair value Gap I'm aiming for that next
week for some trade setup I'll be
looking for that okay I'm going to be
looking for that very thing next week
unless I'm proven wrong and I'm okay
with being wrong it's okay doesn't mean
anything this means I I don't get what I
want that's okay it's not burgering when
you're trading just like mentorships you
can't have it your way all the time
so inside of here inside these
Wicks if you
measure like that you see you have 14
770 and 3/4 so you have that right there
and then you have this order block
forming with that down movement right
there as it's happening I'm also looking
at this
Wick
[Music]
right
here 83 and 3/4 so in my mind as long as
I'm buying below that price of that Wick
why this one because it's slightly
higher than that one but there's two of
them so I want to get a range between
both the consequent encouragement of
both of them and that in itself is a PD
array
too
oh no it's going to end up on Amazon in
a book somewhere else somebody else is
going to write about it you're going to
talk about it wrong that's all the
details I'm going to give you
here you love that twist the knife ICT
twist it oh so slow ever so
slow I'm being mean I know but you guys
are trying to be ahead of me and every
time I teach something you want to put
it out in a book so you can claim you
had it imprint first technically it's
not in print first when you do there
you're you're copying me because I've
already put it in production
here okay I've already I'm already had
all you but anyway a lot of these things
that I'm talking about here will be
Amplified in book format but you have to
see examples of it and that's what I'm
showing you here so the entry here was
14,775
even which is between both of those two
consequent encroachments of those Wicks
right in here the damage is done down
here and as long as I'm buying inside
this order block as it's forming what's
the high of that candle 91 A2 what's the
low 63 even what's my fill 75 even it's
less than the 83 of that Wick
here and above the consequent correction
of that
Wick this is too complicated okay it's
not for you listen not everybody needs
to be a PhD rocket scientist using
technical science I understand that
okay it's going to for some of you this
is going to be above your pay grade
that's okay but you won't get the level
of entries that I have in my repertoire
if you choose not to do it you don't
need them you don't need all this stuff
okay I am sick with it okay it's it's
it's an illness because I need to know
everything everyone else doesn't know I
need to know every little intricate
piece of what makes these markets move
around and where I've placed my
fingerprint I'm telling you this is
what's codified and you're hearing the
man that did it so the run up into that
opening range Gap
high that price is
14,857 and
34s I want to get out as it's going
there and because I'm not going to be
there awake and conscious I want to make
sure it's very very likely that it's
going to fill me so the liit order is
just below where I think it's going to
reach to because what could have
happened was it could have went right up
to that previous settlement price here
and just hit it with the spread not
offering my
exit I showed you this year with a live
account where I had a limit
order and it didn't fill me I had a
large portion of the trade already
booked in profit and the stop was rolled
into a position when it turned back
against me it stopped me in
profit
but it did not let me out at the Target
I wanted because of the spread which was
one
tick so because I was tired I was
fatigued I wanted to sleep the limit
order on this trade was placed
significantly lower than and you might
not think that's significant you seeing
it at 57 and a
quarter here and I'm trying to get out
at 56 and a quarter so it's to me you
know it's one and have handles that's
that's fair you know I'm okay with that
I don't have to have the exact opening
range Gap high price I don't need that
or higher now looking at it it would
have been nice to wake up and still have
it you know without that limit order
there and just have my stop loss at a
level where if if it stopped me out I
made 500 bucks or 10 you $1,000
something like
that it's a reasonable position size it
wasn't a largest portion of what I'm
looking for generally um I wasn't trying
to build any kind of pyramiding because
you know either I'm going to be right or
I'm going to be wrong and using the
logic I've been teaching using the logic
I talked about in that live stream okay
this is a real execution and you can't
hide it you can't explain it the way
because it's really there it's not in
Market
replay I'll let you see over here there
was no other
executions it's just that
[Music]
one
see
so this weekend I want you to rest I
want you to keep your eye on what's
going on over in the Middle East because
that will have shock waves that go
around the world and the markets will
show you that in price next week in
addition to what we already have as news
drivers and volatility injections with
all the red folder events that's part of
and leased through next week's trading
so until I talk to you next time be safe