[Music]
thank you
hello welcome to the Monster Lab here
Dexter
this is the first video for the correct
content the Monster Lab standard
deviations Theory Blues Market maker by
or cell model
I remember you my native language is
Spanish
so please patience
some things
I will tell you in Spanish because
I need more words to explain some things
I don't think it is a problem to
understand you can add automatic
subtitles or captions to English at the
bottom right
okay
everything starts with an opening
it is important to know that power of 3
or candle you are working too
identify your accumulation manipulation
and distribution phase with high
precision
if you do not know what you are
measuring you will hit lows in the price
fluctuations
time it's now limited to kill zones or
macros the openings timings are supports
Naturals and provide context by knowing
if we are below or above the opening
power of three in development
the three phase of price delivery are
the ones we can measure looking for the
right sample for each of them
okay
um in the description you can see the
last video for the standard deviation
correct content plus power of three
you need more
context for this presentation so here is
the last previous video standard
deviation Theory number one
price being algorithmic moves according
to the previous range
if the manipulation range
was to the expansion we will follow the
double or a little more
be taking a sample the manipulation
range and reaching two or two and half
deviations we will anticipate that price
will have a one retracement or one
reversal
this is because price is not
unidirectional and will seek to
rebalance the inefficiencies henerate
the previous range okay
rebalance inefficiencies below the
equilibrium range
the priority of our retracement it's the
inefficiencies or salsa liquidity or by
side liquidity below or above the
equilibrium Branch for the current range
to know if it will be a retracement or
one reversal it's it's necessary to have
a big picture of a high time frame
the easiest way to identify a
manipulation range it's to observe the
week of the current candle and in lower
time frame find the most discernible
range
Market maker Dex model
pronunciation
Market maker models they will be format
from a pdra high time frame and will end
in a opposite PD array of the same time
frame
among these two high time frame Speedy
arrays we will identify the
openings and accumulation manipulation
distribution phase
that are format on the way from the pdra
a
for the pdra B
so in one market maker
buy or sell model you need two high time
frames PDR rates from the same time
frame in this case have this pdra a pdra
b and bdra
C
in the words of standard division
theories we could say that one and one
Uncle deviations it's the
re-accumulation or redistributions
levels
in other words Silver Bullet Zone in the
words of a standard deviation theories
two two and hard deviations and four
deviations it's the smart money reversal
for the market maker models
so in this point you can combine the
high time frame pdra a
and two or two deviations for the
previous range on the left
um you can anticipate the smart money
reversal
one retracement or
reversal today pdra oppose pdra High
time frame B
so in this point
you will expect one
Market maker cell model do the high time
frame pdra B and
you will expect one market maker by
model to the high time frame pdra C in
this case your order flow is bullish so
you can anticipate retracement and one
continuation
simplicize this low and this high
deviations for the previous Range pdra
High time frame
and you
anticipate one retracement so I take
this high and this low for the sample
size
in one deviations for this range
Silver Bullet Zone you anticipate one
retracement
for the redistributions
levels
you anticipate or identify the
displacements in this area
look for
value gaps or
any internal liquidity
distribution zones it's the same
Silver Bullet Zone
price continuations little retracement
this this point is other level for
redistribution
and you anticipate that this move
reaction to the evasions level for the
sample size this high and this low you
will expect the double
to standard deviations and look little
retracement and continuations to the
high time frame pdra B
in this point to the deviations
how to truth in this move it's one
retracement and no reversal
you can choose in this move or continue
ages if price have unfinished business
in this case is one high time frame pdra
oppose it for the main range in the high
time frame PD array
a
so you can choose in this move it's only
one retracement for the continuations do
the two and hard deviations and when
price reacted to 100 deviations and PD
array B you anticipate the smart money
reversal for the next moves the market
maker by Model start in this point this
point is your action point smart money
reversal you need two things two and
hard deviations and pdra high time frame
opposite
Market maker by Model start I take this
high and this low for the sample size
for the next moves
price
one deviations
for the sample size
you will expect one retracement
any internal liquidity in this area you
look for displacements
will anticipate one retracement and
continuations to the to the deviations
to the aviation's reaction and price
retracement but it's different this
retracement in two deviations it's
different for this retracement in the
market maker cell model in two
deviations you see one little
retracement for the continuations to the
Chua Hull deviations in this point in
two deviations you see one more deeper
retracement to the cell side liquidity
you can take this low on this high in
two deviations you
anticipate one retracement in one case
is in one little retracement and in
other case it's more deeper
if you look one market
with high correlation
in this point you can find one crash
correlation lows this is one
confirmations for the continuations Okay
so
if
how you choose in this move it's no
reversal and it's one retracement
you can choose in this move
only if you have unfinished business
in this point pdra High time frame C
it's the unfinished business so you can
choose in this move it's only for
re-accumulation phase
price
continuations
Market Chief in this high
displacements
fair value Gap other accumulation Zone
and in this point you can confirm the
prices continuations the upside price to
unhull deviations reacted smart money
reversal Zone
but
the same Dynamics how truth
price don't have one reversal in this
point
the only way you can choose in there
continuations it's if you have
unfinished business if price Hub
unfinished business to the upside you
can choose this move it's only one the
accumulation level and when price
have this retracement you anticipate one
move to the pdra high time frame C and
moves to the four deviations for the
sample size in this case this high and
this low
in every phase of redistribution or
re-accumulations you can find crash
correlations highs or crash correlation
laws for the confirmations for the next
moves in this point you can find crash
correlation highs in this high and this
high
and in this low this low or this low in
other short-term low
this is one way to confirm the
continuations
how to apply the standard deviations
Theory number one
you need understanding of high time
frame
be aware of
developing power of trees of the present
moment
High time frames PD arrays
time window data the you looked three
previous candle look back
if you look the weekly power of three
your data is for the three previous
scandals in other words three weeks data
if you look the monthly you anticipate
monthly hour of three
your data time data time window it's for
the three previous scandals in other
words three months data
your targets if you worked with the two
or two and half deviations your targets
its internal liquidity below
or above the equilibrium by stops or
cell stops above or below the
equilibrium or the youth
trade or you anticipate one
continuations your target it's for
external liquidity for the current range
or the current market maker model
your confirmation tool
it's the smart money tool SMD
this will help use identify when smart
money is ready to make a change in the
state of delivery the expansions to
retracement or reversals or the
accumulation to manipulations or the
manipulations to distribution
use the apy example for
this week
this is the weekly chart
I take the
the XY chart and compare with
USD JPY and you see the last moves it's
bullish the order flow for this Market
it's bullish okay you can't see the
crash correlation lows in this point
write the last previous candles it's
totality bullish
I take the three previous candles for
data for the work in the next
power of three
this this is the one
the first candle second candle and three
candle data
you can identify the PDR rates in this
portion of price
in the three previous scandals brights
the previous weekly low taken this fair
value Gap continuations to this weekly
volume a balance
and right now price is in this point
this weekly volume imbalance and I
identify the
PD arrays opposite for the same time
frame in the three previous scandals in
this point I have this
preview Scandal this reaction block
previous weekly low
and the mid of this week the large week
this week taking the previous weekly low
um
reversal continuation to the weekly
volume imbalance so this High time frame
Speedy arrays
it's transport or overlapping in lower
time frames told us to speed the arrays
customers
a lower time frame in lower time
framesa identificarlos Market maker by
models or Market maker cell models
foreign
one old Shard you can see the three
weeks data this is the one week two week
and three weeks Okay so
you
can identify in this time frame in lower
time frame with high time frame speeder
rate
you look for the most these are nibbly
range for projections your standard
deviations okay you have the three weeks
data for the standard deviations and the
previous range
is this week in the
two weeks look back I take this high and
this low for the sample size the
manipulation range taking this previous
weekly low this is the high time frame
pdra
and look for the moves to the weekly
volume imbalance so I take this sample
size
um projection today
one one and a half two and one whole
deviations so when you start new week
you need
three questions the few questions
where does price come from
in this case
price come from here
is the low I Stay High
is the primary information
the second question is where is price
right now
price right now is in two and you are
all deviations for the previous range
the D is high and this low
so the next question is where is it
likely to go
In This Moment
in the standard deviation Theory you can
anticipate one retracement or reversal
smart money reversal in this point two
and two on Hull deviations
standard deviations Theory
be taken a sample the manipulation range
this high and this low this is the
manipulation range or the sample size
deviations
[Music]
price
will seek to rebalance the
inefficiencies and rate below
the equilibrium range in the previous
expansions this is the equilibrium
previous expansion where is the most
discernible internal liquidity or
displacement is in this area look these
are a price action you don't find
um
internal liquidity of use
but in this point below the equilibrium
you can find these areas for internal
liquidity so in this point you will
anticipate one retracement or reversal
to discount for the current range
[Music]
thank you foreign
Market maker modeling the weekly power
of three
the more important question it's where
it's the opening
for the present candle
in function for the previous range
is
seminal
standard deviations
foreign
okay entonces surprise
apertura in one or one and half
deviations two percent
this is
a
in this point some precise this high and
this low price
retracement
to the high time frame pdre B in this
case previous weekly low and to a whole
deviations this is the
action point is more money reversal
price
Market shift this high and you have new
sample size or the New Market maker by
Model start in this point
sample size this high and this low and
price low risk buy the first
accumulation level disorder block is
changing the state of delivery
and in this point the previous weekly
low you can
find one crash correlation laws with dxy
in this point so this is one
confirmations for this Market maker by
model and the next phase of
re-accumulations is in
internal liquidity
on the right of or on the left in this
point is one inversion for Value up
reaccumulation
other accumulation so this fair value
Gap look what is the candle it's above
this level this is the real accumulation
level in one deviation one deviation
Silver Bullet Zone retracement to the
One internal liquidity
retracement 4 continuations to the two
deviations or two and a half deviations
in this case price one deviation
retracement this fair value Gap
re-accumulation
other level for a accumulation this
internal liquidity BC and price continue
above the weekly open weekly open it's
the level for the candle in development
development
okay so this is all for this
presentation
a
qualcare commentario is bye