welcome back folks
all right just a quick little review and
an introduction to a new PD array I'll
make public
so we're looking at the dollar indexes
our daily chart
and we have basically just been
Meandering around
the Gap I told you about between these
two weekly reference points so without
going into the weekly chart save some
time that's what we're watching I would
prefer to see it trade down into a
little bit but uh it didn't do so
all right here we are folks
I'll take your attention back to the
video I did on my YouTube channel
July 9th 2023 it's a market review
and prior to
this day running
off the weekly version fair value Gap I
mentioned that we would open on a new
week trade down use this
inversion fair value Gap from the weekly
chart and I'll count you to go back and
look at the old videos
now all this is not added to the Chart
after the fact
that we opened traded down rallied up
and then we had finally today Mark trade
up complete the weekly volume and
balance when you're a dollar
so that is an absolute
slam dunk
all net
swish
my side
that was the initial draw then we would
get into the weekly volume and bounce
just a beautiful delivery these are the
types of moves that you want to capture
and really sitting your hands and wait
for it makes trading very fun
but unfortunately you know
when these big powerful moves take place
they don't give you a whole lot of
opportunities you have to know what
you're looking for and then get in and
try to avoid
um thinking that it has to retrace
because it'll just keep running higher
and higher the reason why it's done this
is because the dollar was exceedingly
bearish like we were expecting
on July 9th
so even the s p here is our weekly chart
so I'm taking your attention into and
Beyond this was the original weekly
volume advance that we were talking
about back down here we finally got into
that closure
today uh well this week rather
um we traded to it and through it now
we're looking at this
volume and balance so there was two
volume imbalances on the weekly chart
for Nasdaq and it had already completed
both of them
es has been lagging so the es has been
the sixth sister between the two
averages and I mentioned that NASDAQ is
the leadership issue so you're all
asking me why am I trading NASDAQ I'm
actually in the NASDAQ as the leadership
issue so it's going to be an
outperformance at the upside
but here we have a fair value Gap in
here with a breaker
and then we have Bubble shoulder block
and a propulsion block and the market
sends price higher
completing this weekly volume amounts
and the pink and then we have this one
here so you want to have these two
levels here the
the high and the low the weekly volume
balance
have that in your chart and
use them as potential support resistance
I
see a lot of questions about this
button down here for settlement I like
to use the settlement price
toggled on when I'm looking for things
like
where we closed in reference to like the
uh
TGIF trade okay I I toggle back and
forth between both of them so I'm
looking for volume and balances I'm
looking for
inefficiencies that may materialize so
things that might go on the radar of
other Traders I'm looking at both
perspectives so it's not a matter of it
only works for this it only works for
that I'm flexible in terms of what I'm
looking for in terms of imbalances and
or where we actually close at silent
because of
the TGIF ideas
all right so we are looking at a daily
chart here e-mini s p
um You probably hear my puppy Bailey I
apologize if you do here but uh she's
morning like I am we lost our
other boxer Bella but uh she wants to be
close to me and I can't send her away
while I'm doing this because you know
they still have the heart to do it so
anyway that's her whimpering
she's fine she's just sad
so
we have today's trading here
Monday's Trading
and then here's where we were working
off of this fair value Gap right there I
mentioned and I'll show you the Tweet
um
as it was today but I've mentioned it
many times
over the years that we do not try to
pick tops
in buy programs
okay and we don't try to pick bottoms
and sell programs that means we are
always
giving the market the opportunity to
color outside the lines that most other
Traders would think that okay we're
we're so overbought now it has to come
back now it has to retrace it has to
have a retracement no it's awesome it
doesn't have to do that and when the
market is wanting to go higher you have
to submit to that or
don't trade because if you arm wrestling
you'll hurt yourself
so these are the levels we have on our
chart now so let me drop in a lower time
frame so it'd be much more meaningful to
you
so here we are on the 18th of July 2023
and
we had a small consolidation and then we
dropped down took out sell side and then
a rapid acceleration into and above
Monday's high trading up into that
higher
weekly volume of valence
all right let's take a look at the
five minute chart now I'm skipping over
the 15-minute charts just for the sake
of
gravity but these are 15 minute fair
value gaps
so that way you can take a look at on
your content time frame
and Order block as well we trade down
and hit that this is all 15 minute chart
basis I'm heading here so that way for
your homework you can go into a 50
minute time frame and find out what
these are
on the Bellwether chart which is in a
time frame but the five minute lots of
opportunities lots of entries today
quarter block on a 15 minute time frame
order block on 15 minute Tony frame you
can see the reactions off of it here and
then trading up into that Weekly volume
and balance
[Music]
okay moving on into NASDAQ this is where
the
the brass tags are for this presentation
so I mentioned how we had
these relative equal highs
and we were likely to go through that
last week we did that and now we are
continuing through
last week's High
and again that's you're only going to
catch this type of continuation if you
avoid make it part of your repertoire
and routine as a mindset as a Trader you
do not try to pick tops while the
Market's going up you don't do it you
simply do not do it it's far easier for
you just to Simply submit to the idea
that it wants to go higher so trade in
that order flow
don't look at patterns trying to capture
Market reversals because they're going
to run right over top of you
all right here's the daily chart here
and
you have an order block there we talked
about that repulsion block we don't want
to see a closing price below the middle
or mean threshold of a compulsion block
we never saw that the market rallied
last week and then now we had here
Tuesdays Trading
Tuesdays though for me and Monday's
trading here so we had a really nice
little drop down in small little
institutional Oracle entry job not by
much but you don't need much right so
we'll take a look at that when we get
lower time frames but continuation on
the upside just a wonderful amount of
opportunity to see that trade notice
that we opened
traded down today and cut through the
candles because we're not supplying to
me
they're high down Revisited that is a
discount array
so if you look at my month four content
uh
St mentorship it's my premium mentorship
there's core content lessons are on my
YouTube channel go to playlist for month
four
and you'll see the pdra Matrix lectures
in that
segment of videos
and in the discount we have
old highs and old looks so let me trade
back down in to it like that
one more bullish we would expect to see
prices trade higher
all right on an hourly chart
we can see that we have
the market dropped down
small consolidation this is where retail
is going to see a bull flag
okay rallying consolidation and they
want to see it go higher
I was asked today on my Twitter account
you know what my bias was so I went over
that and actually show you the Tweet so
that way it's not me just saying
something and there's no record of it
but it had a really nice explosive price
move higher
and
cleared the 16 000 level
five minute chart here you can see the
low forming here just shortly after the
9 30 opening
creates a fair value Gap here trades
down into that beautiful run
right from there takes off
a small little fair value Gap here hits
it with an overblock very very high
probability
rallies
order block
rallies and then Finds Its High the day
in the last hour trading
and then trading off the highs
back into
an order block
[Music]
at 7 43
New York local time
I tweeted today
and I said that
we're not trying to pick tops and buy
programs okay basically a buy program is
when the market is under an algorithmic
price delivery or Price run that's
repricing higher
it's not a classic bull market it's not
a
Trend because I don't like talking about
things in those
terms because
I don't have any affinity for those
types of things I did when I first
started but once my eyes were open to
how markets are highly manipulated and
then I codified a lot of things you now
are learning from me I've completely
dismissed everything else
so when I'm looking for higher prices
when my algorithm is looking for higher
prices and it's spooling and running
higher I'm going to refrain from and I
teach my students to refrain from trying
to pick tops no matter what pattern you
think exists in price action no matter
who you love
in worship online
whatever they say avoid it I promise you
if you do that you'll you'll spare
yourself a lot of losses
but yesterday was evidence that it's
never a good idea or strategy
and I mentioned this morning I mean
July 18 2023 this morning I am waiting
to see if they use the retail sales data
which was released at 8 30 in New York
local time
to drop in then rally higher if it drops
and doesn't rally it matters not to me
movement is desired so what do I mean by
that
well
here is the 9 30 delivery
okay and this is the time of the Tweet
right there
so I was not counseling you as my
students to look at that consolidation
as a bullfight and go higher
I didn't want to see that I wanted to
see it go against retail mindset which
would be continuation or classic retail
continuation patterns and they would see
and would have saw a bull flag
I'm not a fan of that so the market
drops down at 9 30 which creates a Judah
swing this market for Traction in the
opposite direction to what retail would
expect it goes down creates a short term
little low rallies up and then Dives one
more time that is absolutely
beautiful because that sets the trap for
every Trader out there that thinks that
that bull flag was going to pan out and
then now they want to catch this low
down here then they get stopped out that
immediately scares ninety percent of any
retail Traders won't get along
they don't want to go along now they're
scared they're going to get stopped out
and they don't know what to expect what
I'm looking for is I want to see does
the market respect my PD arrays my
discount arrays things that I would look
to go along on in any bullish scenario
so now it's time for a new gift to the
trading community
okay so I want you to take a look at how
the market
created a run higher last week
we had a run up
and then a break lower
when we see that
you understand that this pattern here is
if we trade above it
come back down in that should be what
she does a bullish breaker right not
when we're in Trend continuation
we're in train continuation I want to
see the low
High lower low and then the next day if
we rally through it
like we do here so here's Monday's
Trading
now we have
one two three isn't that three drives
pattern and that's a topping pattern
right no
no no no no no no what did I say this
morning we're not trying to call Tops
so anyone that would have saw this as a
three drives pattern
here or three Indians padding if you're
a reader of Street smarts books which
is in my opinion one of the better books
out there
but that's not a three Jaws pattern
that's not a three Indians pattern okay
it is a setup for those individuals that
want to use that idea
so one of the things that I codified in
my algorithm is if there is a
opportunity for the market to continue
higher or lower everything I'm going to
show you here just reverse it
but since I'm bullish and I told
everybody I was bullish I was looking
for a drop in drop in the what
we'll get to it
that price level up there sixteen
thousand twenty eight point seven five
absolutely random
no
if you look at the price range from the
low
to the high this is a breaker
but there's something specific about
this breaker that we have to know and
then use it slightly different
low high lower low
this stops out longs
so lungs are now no longer allowed to be
participants of the next energetic price
leg higher
I'm not requiring price
to trade in a normal sense with the
breaker I want to look for something
different
this low up to this high that is the
standard
measurement for projection on targets so
if this was a classic breaker you would
use the low to the high
and the lower low
that goes below this low here that sets
the tone for the pattern as a breaker
but for
swing projections for targeting purposes
all we're doing is taking the low to the
high one standard deviation
that's what we're looking for sixteen
thousand zero two eight
point seven five
I think it went one handle above it is
that is that precise enough for you
we're going to go a little bit beyond
that now
[Music]
this is
my ICT Reaper inversion for your value
go
yes I know it's a badass name I know
a Reaper
in version bear I got is when you're
inside of a breaker
you're going to cut through candles
because we are not supplying demand
folks I can't stress this enough
this is this is one of those lessons
where you can look at folks on the
internet they try to say I rebranded
stuff or I call supply and demand
something different or I complicate it
folks there is nothing like this
anywhere else okay I wanted to create
and codify a method to go in and
capitalize on number one Precision two
take advantage of shifted sentiment and
go under the radar of everybody else out
there
that's what my Reaper does
it's devastating it's absolutely
devastating because you don't see it
coming
but it's right there
price run
leaves
a fair value Gap in the lower portion of
this price run okay so it's the first
leg of the bullish breaker
the fair value Gap must be in a discount
relative to that low to that high you
see it here
between here and here
that's a discount the discount is being
measured on this basis the low to high
once we have that extend that forward if
we're bullish in this case we were
enough I've proven it to you I told you
we were looking for higher prices
the market
trades down through it doesn't respect
that as we would
expect
everybody that would see my stuff online
or think they understand it or think
this is a liquidity void it's not
it's going to trade down through it run
the stops why because I want to knock
those individuals out that have a
trailed stop loss there
in the market rallies
one Sunday into Monday
takes out the high
now everyone that wants to use my
breaker they get punished here too
they're not going to be able to go in
here and go long
and also the traders that are using this
as a bull flag they're going to get
punished
now I know if I was just to say all
these things right here this would have
been like oh this is Cherry Picked
your form fitting you're doing this
you're doing that
I said it this morning before the market
even got to 8 o'clock
it's 7 43 this morning New York local
time I want to see it drop down into
what
Monday's range
here's midnight on Monday New York local
time to Monday's high
measure that the best
the best fills for getting long
is going to be at equilibrium
or higher
except
when my Reaper exists in price action
cut through all these candles
and go right there
we see it drop down
and then bang that's that right there
that signature there that's what I was
looking for this morning
because it was respecting all through
here all through here and go right back
there folks this is proof that my
algorithm refers back to candlesticks
highs and lows that you would never
otherwise know
where is the support and resistance idea
with all this you're gonna go right here
right you're going to take that high and
draw it out in time wonderful but I've
already told you
classic support resistance is only
confirmed
if it has one of my fair value gaps
and look what it has right there
consequent encroachment of that Reaper
right there but if you want to know
and you want to have all the details
that I'm making available to the trading
community at Large
these are the things that I've codified
a Reaper is a fair value Gap
in a discount of the impulsive price leg
of a bullish breaker reverse it a
bearish ICT Reaper inversion fair value
Gap would be a bearish breaker that
would have a fair value Gap in the
premium side of the impulsive Priceline
so all of these things are completely
reversible
but the context is you have to have a
bias
there has to be some kind of retail idea
that would lure traders in well we have
here bullfly
it drops down in to what
the previous day's range
now look at the bodies respecting
50 of the previous day's range see that
remember the Wicks do the damage
that's the Reaper's job
and then that little signature right
there tells me it's done it's going to
go higher
I'm entering on that candle
[Music]
taking all that aside
free pressure a little above your pay
grade and
a little confusing for you that's okay
I'll talk more about in my book
we have our standard and version fair
value Gap there within a breaker classic
bullish breaker and then here's the
price like
between the lower that handle and high
that candle those are the specific price
points and my fill going long six
contracts was 15781 even below and
inside the inversion Fair bag Gap there
at the candle that qualified and
confirmed that my Reaper was in fact
good to go send price higher
and I took a market exit it wasn't a
stop I just simply closed it because my
intentions were going to be somewhere
else and I wasn't going to be able to do
anything I wanted to do managing it on
my cell phone so there's where my
clothes was and a little bit higher one
above the 16 000 but that's still good
enough over 120 handles
on NASDAQ so about 14 Grand Plus
so not bad for a
couple hours of
leisurely fishing
and here is the one minute chart on
NASDAQ but I was entering also was we
had this runoff and as the candle was
dropping down
I'm going to enter that right there and
then this would be your classic return
in for a
Fairway Gap
bullish breaker and then secondary entry
would have been here
Gifts of that one and around on up and
this is where I closed it manually
so
that my friends is what took place today
and it was a wonderful explosive price
move today higher after me counts on you
this morning we would look for a drop
down in previous days range
and just was beautifully beautifully
offered it was one of those days where
when you know what you're looking for
and if you're struggling with trying to
capture big runs
okay if you're on these little time
frames
and you're just simply just looking for
things like okay well here's relative
equal highs and and say you did buy this
sofa bullet okay because that's what
that was by the way this entry is a
silver bullet with all the other things
I gave in context so which is like a a
silver bullet with on steroids
this here is a lunchtime macro
it starts running higher there and you
might think okay well it gets about here
I'm done
but if you're ignoring the higher time
frame that we're going to go higher
anyway we're going to keep going higher
we're not trying to pick tops and buy
programs
and the daily range is likely to create
that extreme high if we're bullish in
the PM session
going into
that last hour
well look at the time of the day
you know
highly was formed
around three o'clock it didn't go beyond
uh 16 000 much
but I gave up about a hundred handles
but that's okay 120 is enough
you don't sit here and try to
convince yourself that five handles is
enough or 20 handles is enough if you
really want to capture big runs you'll
scare yourself entirely from holding on
to them and one of the best ways of
doing it is when you get a entry
you place your stop don't worry about
trailing it don't worry about trying to
take Parcels just let it go
turn off the charts go out like I did I
was away from the house
I wasn't looking at it
because I'm not worrying about all the
things I'm trusting my algorithm I'm
trusting what's codified I'm trusting
that the delivery of price is going to
be exactly what it has been coded to do
price the high in the afternoon session
the last hour then you'll get your
retracement
that's power three
this is not the entire daily range here
I'm just showing you where my trade
entry was in my exit remember it goes
higher than this it goes to sixteen
thousand something
and I didn't get all that and I don't
need to
so if you're looking for ways to hold on
to a trade and capture these big runs
not just get 10 handles or 20 handles
and you know yes it's great you know I'm
killing it
you may very well be killing it but
you're missing these monster Halls
by not knowing the higher time frame
bias not understanding what the
likelihood of a large range would do
for your trading and your equity
and you don't need to have a full
positional like this is my initial entry
usually it's six contracts
I was tempted to go in and do four more
here I said you know I'm just going to
leave it there I'm gonna leave it there
and I'm not going to worry about it
and while I was out doing what I wanted
to do today the market just kept on
plowing higher smashing everybody that
was wanting to go short
on the heels of
they're going to use the retail sales
number and then going into 9 30. drop it
down create relatively close rally it
sharply
fair value
sales off
now retail doesn't want to be long so as
long as they're afraid to buy it that's
a welcoming feeling for me with a smart
money mindset with trading I want to go
in when they're fearful
what time do we trade for a silver
bullet 10 o'clock to 11. displacement
down closed candle as it's trading down
I'm buying it
this right here could have been another
four contracts
and then I'd have my full 10 positions
this is my standard model for trading
index futures
and then rallied up I'm not from the
charts my stop loss is below
this candle is low right there
that's where the stop was
and you've seen me use tighter stop
losses than that
but it went down into the Fairbank Gap
there
if I would have saw that I would have
did another entry just to prove to you I
was trusting the pattern but I wasn't
there I wasn't watching the chart at the
time
and just keep on moving up and because I
wasn't in front of the charts and
because you wouldn't be in from the
charts when you're training yourself to
do this you put a position on and you
just let it go if it stops you it stops
you out it's not gonna be the last trick
you ever take
but you have to condition yourself like
this to hold on to it for a long period
of time by not looking at the chart
because it's real easy to see this thing
okay okay I made a lot of money now let
me just get out of it no
trust time of day
trust it
and the market just explodes higher
[Music]
hopefully found this one insightful and
it was beneficial to you obviously it's
just an introduction to my ICT Rebrand
version favorite you got I'll have more
talk about that in the book I won't be
releasing anymore because I already know
somebody's going to come out here maybe
many of you you're going to come out
there and try to create little tutorials
on YouTube and misinform everyone
because you don't know what you're doing
please don't try to do that okay I
understand you want clicks and all that
stuff but uh you don't know what you're
doing and you don't know what I'm going
to teach about that very specific PDA
rate but I want to introduce it today
and I hope you found it inspiring and
interesting until talk to you next time
be safe