foreign
price is reaching down to offer
the price into this
eyeshadow balance outside efficiency
[Music]
oh
my God
thank you
okay
well
I guess we'll see it delivered to prompt
wax it on this one too
yes has the same thing here
without losing to her muscles turned
into better either one
small little balancers in there
[Music]
foreign
can go down to
here which is also inside of this
inefficiency or not it's not entire book
but it also can go to this depth
take things off
this is the other one efficiency right
there
so we're gonna actually put it right on
the high of that whatever you got right
there
in the cell side residing rate full of
that
[Music]
you probably hear my dryer I'm in my
kitchen area
and we have a laundry
room that's on the first floor
and my wife left the door open while
she's running the jars
you're hearing that in the background I
apologize it's annoying but
I'm not gonna get up close it
so it's an accelerate lower here
you can go up to the sell side
right below here
okay this is the original consolidation
runs up for accumulation
accumulation smart money reversal low
risk sell
redistribution
second stage distribution
acceleration attack then
Regional consolidation with South Side
resigned at
low rate Bears several factors between
this low and that efficiency rate there
it could go a little bit more than that
too depending on how overzealous it gets
going into close
but it's not
it's not enough for me to want to do
anything with that I was actually trying
to take a losing trade
I was asked on Twitter I get this asked
a lot in conditional losing trade
I guess I'll
have to create some kind of drawdown
to teach how to resolve drawdown
later this year so
I genuinely did try to uh
take a losing trade up here
I put the stopwatch real close thinking
it might bump it and didn't do it it
started working out my favor
and I said it would go down here instead
so I closed the trade and we've gone
down there I sold short in here
and add it to it here because I already
knew I thought it wasn't trade so I
might as well just make the best of it
right
don't waste
a good opportunity
so we'll take uh
we'll take three
off here
I'll take one off
[Music]
right under here
you want just underneath there and that
final will be
the
the target here
and that will close out this week
foreign
all right
Freedom Memphis low
in this low and then that small little
Gap right there
[Music]
all right
come somewhere look
does not exist
is like a real phenomenon
is another
partial
[Music]
and we'll keep it around 500 on the
balance
just in case good o ICT gets it wrong
these next two might fail pretty quick
my stop is rolled
if you're wondering
that's how you were just thinking it why
they're almost out there is just above
mean threshold of that last up close
candle so if it does roll back on me and
stops me I'm okay with it
but it
I want to keep going lower then
obviously that's a
favorite location for a trail stop
it's a logic will be even if it has a
little retracement up into this
inefficiency here and bumps the bottom
of this old Bison balance cell Sun
efficiency
that's completely permissible
just to prove the theory
I'm going to add
one contract it bumps the bottom end of
that bicycle side efficiency
it could run lower from here it's
already done it's
high and deck
whatever you got right there
thank you
[Music]
watch those wicks
right here
Council encouragement of those wicks
I'd like to see that via barrier if
anything on the upside starts to
materialize
foreign
[Music]
take that entry
as a reminder when I was teaching the
concept of five handles or five points
which is 20 ticks in the e-mini SMP on
the equivalent for Nasdaq would be 20
handles
or 80 ticks
just reading some comments
figure out toss them in here
in case the
person that made that inquiry was
listening they had their answer
does that look random to you
or is it like it's engineered
coded
scripted
authored
so fun
so you can see that fifteen thousand two
eighty nine and a quarter level
that's a actual low right there so right
before all this run up
stop loss orders are sitting right below
that one kind of stop loss
cell stops
why would that be advantageous for price
to deliver there
from up here here on here
here
that would be counterparty to buy at a
lower price from sellers that want to
sell at a low price right below that low
and then one Fell Swoop they could take
that liquidity and reach into this
inefficiency and Order block and
complete the numbers for today
I don't trust those
doji's this is promoting the idea that
this is going to turn and go higher
that's not the case
for marks on heat right over top of this
run right over top of it and go right
into this area here foreign
not doing that again but it's okay
we're leading into the last hour of
New York PM session
begins
at three o'clock
and so we're about uh five minutes or so
one less than five minutes for that to
begin
all of this drop from here to here is
nicely delivered efficient
inefficiency here was repriced too
all this back and forth price action
then down we had an inefficiency here
we've been in here multiple times
we've hit the bottom of the Bison
efficiency
so it's all green light for it to go
lower
and pair up that
sells out liquidity deliver inefficiency
over here to efficient
right in here
I'm not saying it's the lowest of the
day but that's all I'm looking for
so inside of all this fractal
that's what I'm looking for for
the completion of that run
being Friday not for on Friday I'm sorry
nine from April Friday
um
I pretty much I hammered this today I
got I beat it up pretty bad
to see
confusions
and then I'll change the chart so you
can see it's not
Market replay or anything like that
and I apologize I know it probably get
something nervous moving the trial
around because I don't like it when
people do it it gets on my nerves
but I want to add that uh
extra detail in here
thank you
[Music]
foreign
the question I like to always ask is
internal dialogue
like if I was long
and I have my stop loss below that low
what I feel safe right now
and I wouldn't
and they should be trembling right now
too
they're not going to get a chance to get
off of it now
quickly search for it
notice the time
three o'clock
or is it liquidity
below 15 289 a quarter
and what's below that
in inefficiency
so no I don't want to see it come back
up to the bottom
on that old vitamin balance or certain
efficiency right here I don't want to
see that bump it again
so it either goes to my limit order
or limit orders
or it's dossing out there and I'm
content with that
foreign
[Music]
thank you
I stopped sitting right above this
really smooth highs
like those out and then come down
go to my target it's okay
I've already smashed it today pretty
good
it's really nice being in a position
where
being right is not the
end result
of choice it's just you're in a position
now where if it goes to your Target's
wonderful and if it doesn't you've
already taken something off multiple
times
and I was all over this thing like white
on rice today so
hammered pretty good
you know if all things being equal it
should deliver on this candle or the
very next candle
foreign
for those that are asking why would I
say something like that you can see a
small little separation between this
candle's low
this candle is high we went up in there
once twice and we started the price run
that went below this candle's opening
right there
so these two up close candles together
I want to see price move away from that
when it does that if it doesn't then I
have to accept the fact that I may get
stopped out
foreign
no emotion no reason for concern no
excitement when you're right
it's a continuous Balancing Act
that Trader must uh maintain
foreign
in a lot here in the last hour
so you're getting a feel for why I speed
these things up it's like watching paint
dry sometimes
[Music]
thank you
so I'm looking at I'm wondering does it
want to really accelerate down to
this order block here these two
consecutive down close candles the high
to the opening
that would be a very sensitive
price point for me
because they have a fair value Gap in
the same area
but I'm leaving what I have here
in terms of the orders if it can book
those orders that completes my week
lots of manipulation here
it's one
[Music]
see if we get that final one here
inside that varying that
take this stop and roll it down to the
rejection block right there on this
a closed candle
so if it stops me there I'm comfortable
with that I don't care
it's traded to the market maker cell
model South Side liquidity which is the
reason why I had that limit order there
and the two remaining contracts I have
Are Being Framed on the basis of that
small Little Ferry you got there
so if it can deliver that wonderful if
it doesn't it stops me out and it's just
as well
[Music]
here we are
just like it's coated
just like it was explained
in source code
so my friends that is a 26 240 day
all over this thing
right out of my
collection notes and mentorship
you can see that all the fills
I'll take them all for you as you can
see it's not Market replay
and I'll toggle to
yes so it's not like I can go back and
pull them up again once you change the
screen if you reset your account all
that stuff
it wouldn't be there okay so again
that's 26 240 dollars
all on the es I'm sorry on the uh NQ
up
and down
the macro I'll teach you that this
weekend on Sunday at 2PM enjoy your
weekend
until talk to you next time
be safe