this podcast is brought to you by Blue
Guardian the fastest growing prop film
in 2023. I became obsessed instead of
being at the job doing what I was
supposed to do at the job I was looking
at charts all day yeah eventually that
got me fired but it was one video that
actually clicked for me from his YouTube
I've seen it at least 30 times the
videos title is this is brilliant it's
absolutely real I've never heard
anything like this in like 300 odd
episodes I've done episode 239 right
folks we've got Alex Lira here in the
house today now this is an ICT style
Trader she simplified things down so
dramatically in fact we see a
step-by-step breakdown of their full
strategy in the next video dropping on
the channel so make sure you hit
subscribe so you don't miss that she's
also got a crazy heck and you're going
to hear it in the show where it's gonna
stop you from any fomo that you may have
with your trading so such a simple
little trick first time I've ever heard
on the show so you've got to stay tuned
for that as well and the crazy story
that got her into trading in the first
place so that's all coming up other
things going on here at trading like
we've got the live streams hitting the
channel on a daily basis Asia London and
New York covered so if you're looking to
get some support or just have a
community to join whilst you're trading
those sessions then jump in there and
check out these great Traders and you
can see how they performed if you are
wondering how everyone is performing
we've got a lot of them doing the blue
Guardian challenge so you can see the
recap videos at the end of the week
including myself and see some of my
trades as well across the course of the
week so jump in there and make sure you
grab that content and last but not least
if you do want to automate anything that
you're doing I've got a 10K blue
Guardian evaluation that I'm giving away
with my robot Builders club for new
members that join this month of August
2023 so go and check that out alright
folks enough from me let's jump into the
show our sponsor blue Guardian is the
only problem that gives their Traders a
tool to protect them from hitting their
max daily loss and over trading it's
super simple to use just set the
guardian protector each day from your
dashboard did you also know that they've
just released an unlimited time
evaluation with as zero trading days
requirement giving you plenty of time to
hit their low eight and four percent
targets making it super fast to get
funded plus it's cheaper than the 40-day
time limit evaluation check out the link
and coupon in the description to get
tempting off your next Blue Guardian
evaluation all right folks here we are
on trading up we've got Alex rbv Forex
Made Easy in the house that's where she
that's how she goes by on what she goes
by on Instagram welcome to the show all
the way from Romania and I don't even
think I've had a Romanian guest on
before so you might be the first I'm
pretty sure you are the first
I hope that's good that's good
breaking the ice yeah yeah yeah exactly
so um now you you sort of came to the
attention of of me because it's been
knowing that you are you you've I
suppose the way you explain uh ICT is
among the sort of simplest ways that
people are explaining it I.E you've
simplified the whole thing down so we're
going to get into your journey today and
find out man how you managed to do it
why you managed to do it how you even
found this ICT dude uh and all this sort
of stuff so do you want to start off
with uh how you found trading and I
believe it so that some kind of
interesting story at the beach
yeah yeah so I found training 10 years
ago uh when I met my partner and
um I didn't feel any attraction towards
trading because I've always felt like it
was a male dominated uh industry and uh
but about four maybe five years later we
were at the beach uh vacation and
something really strange happened where
a guy out of the nowhere came at me and
he told me
um that he knows me from trading in
South Africa and I said no you you're
confusing me with someone else uh then
you know we just didn't consider that
something important and then when I got
back home in uh in Bucharest after the
vacation was over I actually uh was
approached by a trading group from South
Africa uh I left that group yeah it was
really really weird it was really weird
yeah I was I was approached on WhatsApp
which is unusual because usually in this
industry people approach usually on
telegram I didn't even have telegram at
that time so these guys approached me on
Whatsapp I don't know how they got my
number so I started looking into their
strategy they were trading something
like beat the market maker from Steve
Morrow
um so that's how I started with trading
and uh then from from that point till
today it was a long trip and can you
even do you even know why why I know
somebody came up to you saying oh you're
yeah I have no idea no absolutely no
idea very wonderful at that time yeah at
that time in Romania I remember that
there were some protests
um you know Romanian people were
protesting because uh the government
wanted to uh you know do something silly
and uh this guy uh because he's um
girlfriend came then afterwards uh you
know to take him away from there because
he was really acting weird and then she
told us she apologized for the incident
and then she told us you know
um he was acting weird because he's
really stressed with his job he was
working uh
um law enforcement and because of the
protests and all of that he was really
so yeah she just said he's acting weird
we don't know why and the weird thing is
that we were at the beach in Romania
they were Romanians but he approached me
in English
which was super weird ah that is kind of
odd you even wonder if like
it's some sort of scam it was some kind
of scam yeah but then it's like how when
I said would they get your phone number
if they were going to watch it exactly
everything exactly you know Steve Morrow
beat the market maker ain't exactly
exactly that's weird there's very weird
but anyway very weird obviously a sign
because you're here and this you know
yes if the guy's watching then hey you
know reach out in the comments and let
us know why and if you did that and who
was the sort of doppelganger Trader from
South Africa I don't think he even
remembers yeah
um okay so so um so you you you sort of
it's delved into things but didn't I
mean what what happened next
what happened next is that I studied for
about three months with the people in
that group
um uh btmm strategy it was very much um
indicator based uh that's what caught my
attention uh because it was indicator
based and I really like geometry
um so indicators all of that stuff it
looked very mathematical to me but then
when my boyfriend found ICT
um we started looking at uh you know
consuming his content on YouTube and
then I felt like trading with indicators
is uh not the best way to do it so then
I was very interested in looking at
naked charts I felt like uh that's what
the next stage would be in my developing
Journey so that's where I decided to
leave the group because I also came in
in that group with my own ideas you know
maybe we should use this indicator or
maybe we shouldn't rely on indicators
that much maybe we should look more at
naked charts and that wasn't really seen
with good eyes so then I decided that
it's time to you know part ways and uh
from that moment we studied ICT
uh on YouTube went into his mentorship
didn't finish it because of uh financial
difficulties
and then we just continued to study uh
from his YouTube from the free
um stuff that he had on YouTube and in
about six months I think
um we started applying it and when I
opened the charts uh I was like really
really eager to apply everything that I
believed that I understood took notes I
still have two big notebooks that are
that are filled with um uh with
indications and all the stuff that I
understood at that time but when I
started to apply it in uh in the markets
even in back testing
um the results were not as I expected
I'm not talking about results as in the
trade results but more like I didn't
feel like I was uh 100
sure of what I was doing I still felt
that I had doubts I still felt that I'm
not looking at the right things I still
felt like I'm uh not understanding
concepts correctly and I always always
had uh conflicting signals something
told me to buy something else told me to
sell at the same time
because I was trying to eat all the
candies yeah at one time
do you think it was part of like not
finishing the the paid mentorship no no
absolutely not I think that ict's
content regardless if we're talking
about paid mentorship or free YouTube
stuff I think that it's like an
encyclopedia it encompasses everything
that someone can know not that they need
to know but any everything that someone
can actually get to know uh retail you
know Wise about the markets but it may
be even more than retail but um
I always felt like a kid in the candy
store I wanted to eat you know basically
apply everything at the same time
because charts are like books full of
words and sentences and they will have a
certain meaning if you use them in a
certain context and I didn't see the
importance of context at that time so
that's why I wanted to use everything at
the same time and when you do that you
just
it's going to be a total mush in your
head yeah yeah and the results are going
to speak you know and so you did even
get past the back testing phase at that
point where you know you said before
that you couldn't even make it work in
back testing and how did that yes I did
I did practicing at some point when I
started to exclude stuff I decided to
use less of the concepts that I learned
uh from his content I decided to use
less and
um started to focus more on back testing
I said okay I'm just going to leave
um you know live trading uh set it aside
for uh for a few weeks maybe a few
months uh back testing started going out
pretty well but then when I uh felt
confident or that's what I thought at
that moment that I felt confident uh and
again
um increased My Equity uh through
depositing and I started trading live uh
it went good for about a month and then
it was not that good anymore because I
came back to my old habits of trying to
use everything at the same time thinking
that you know overconfidence right I
became overconfident and that really
hurt me because you said you you lost
your job and that was the sort of uh
Genesis for you you know yeah full-time
right I'm just going to do this so so
that at that point I'm guessing it was
before prop firms and uh you know oh
yeah
forever but I mean like before the
prevalence of them uh so you had to
deposit your own money and try and make
it work what I mean what kind of can you
sort of given us a typical week back
then like how many hours at the charts
how many trades are you taking
six hours a day at least six eight hours
a day I would literally be glued
to my computer yeah and when I say six
hours a day I say six hours a day
because my boyfriend was literally
ripping me away from the computer I
became obsessed especially because after
I got fired from my old job and it
happened because of trading because I
was uh not drinking the results that I
was anymore because I started to look
into trading it felt more interesting to
me and instead of being at the job doing
what I was supposed to do at the job I
was looking at charts all day
and um yeah eventually that got me fired
but it was you know
it was a good a good thing that happened
now looking back it's a good thing it's
the best one that happened yeah exactly
well I mean yeah so six hours a day and
how many trades would you place in that
six hour period when you were doing
things you know when that month that it
worked well versus the month that things
started to go pear-shaped
I started to have bad results again when
I started to look at many pairs the
number of Trades increased because I
would look at more pairs previously I
would only look at Euro USD and GBP USD
which is what all ICT students have
started with because that's what he was
trading at the time uh and I did good
while I was focusing only on one two
pairs
um but then when I said yeah you know
what why not apply this because it works
why not just you know scale and apply it
on many pairs and that's where the focus
starts to
shatter because now I was without
actually realizing I was uh chasing
quantity instead of quality
and uh the number of Trades started to
increase of course because I was not
focused anymore on doing a proper
analysis anything was everything was
happening quite fast okay well I think
this is going to do this so let's buy
okay and this is going to do that let's
sell sometimes I would even put like
let's say I would take a Buy on GBP USD
and then on GBP JPY on GBP AUD also
because I thought well you know what
they are just correlated so let's just
over trade over risk not make a proper
analysis and uh I started having
good results with about maybe two three
setups a day on two pairs Euro USD and
GBP USD when one had something and the
other one didn't I would trade the one
that had didn't trade both at the same
time but then when I started to you know
in my head scale up
for the good but actually not uh I
reached about
10 20 30 trades a day it was awful
[Music]
right folks I'm here at the Blackpool
markets headquarters up in Auckland New
Zealand and I'm standing in front of the
whiskey bar now if you like that kind of
selection you're going to love the 26
000 tradable assets from Forex cryptos
indices stocks you name it they've got
it so folks go and check them out at
blackballmarkets.com or click the link
under the video or in the card above
and so so with with these like I mean
when you had this strategy that was
working and I suppose even where you
evolved to and what you're doing now
what was sort of like maybe two or three
of the key components that factor into
that from the ICT arsenal of you know
12-month mentorship kind of kind of
thing what were the the three things you
found that like the most powerful
to put into a strategy from the from the
mentorship I don't think that I got to
consume
um as much as I needed from the paid
mentorship uh to be able to extract
something from it because like I said
I've only been in it not personally but
I've only watched it like the first four
months uh order blocks have always
attracted me but I then realized
afterwards that uh when I started you
know filtering the information out I
realized that I was I thought that I was
attracted to order blocks simply because
everywhere you would look for how to
trade you would find order blocks so it
was like something fashionable yeah
let's get into it because everyone jumps
into this bandwagon
um but um I actually found and my entire
trading strategy is based on
his free content
and that was the frequency before the
before the premium yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah
it was it was yeah
I find that people do have have managed
to get a lot out of those free videos
that uh that he put out like you know
not that many but enough to do some
damage yes it yeah it's a it's a hard
path to follow when you want to you know
just study his uh YouTube content
because it's you don't know what to
start with uh there there's not a an
actual structure this is phase one phase
two phase three you need to start with
this and first learn the basics and then
uh you know learn more about those
things and then start to apply them make
yourselves uh a trading plan uh YouTube
doesn't have that and you're uh let's
say enticed into using or consuming
everything randomly yeah so that
delays the a proper understanding but it
was one video that actually clicked for
me from his YouTube only one do you
remember do you remember which one that
was what was it about I've seen it at
least 30 times the videos title is uh
liquidity purging revert right okay okay
yeah and is that when things started to
to click for you after that sort of down
period yes
exactly after that video I said oh
okay this is what I need to do
this is and from that moment
I don't know it just it's different did
you then bet did you then back test that
and sort of changes okay I didn't I
started back testing but I've actually
started to
um uh
more like go back in the charts not do
actual back testing but to go back in
the chart and see my understanding from
the video would apply yeah and I just
couldn't believe my eyes when I saw that
so then I said I spent about I think two
months till uh trying to figure out uh a
rule-based strategy because I I needed
rules I needed step-by-step plan and my
mind is
um constructed in such a way that I
always need a step-by-step plan anything
I do I need to know this is the first
thing that I need to do this is the fact
the second this is the third and if I
don't have the second then I'm still at
stage one I don't I cannot go directly
to step three that's what I've actually
spent time in figuring out how to do it
at first I was using some indicators
um
uh and then I ditched them as I started
to understand more price action and
focusing more on price action the
indicators you know disappeared from my
charts and now I just trade with uh
rectangles
lines
not trend lines
uh and the bear chart and that's it I
only focus on what happens right now in
front of me
and how many steps in your step-by-step
plan
uh
if I were to count the parts that takes
less than 30 seconds to identify what is
the actual the overall Market bias
whether we're bullish or bearish if I
were to include that one also so I'd
have the bias I'd have the point of
interest on the word time frame uh and
then for the actual entry setup
candidate
imbalance
uh three steps only three okay three
steps three steps is like a two
Candlestick uh model let's say yeah but
yes just that okay cool word so yeah
three is easy to remember I think it was
I was picturing 30. so no
um yeah it was five previously but then
you know understanding the markets has
levels
so when you understand another level you
just simplify it even more okay and what
when you say it has levels what do you
mean by that
I mean that
um my strategy was not perfect
three months ago but now I feel like it
is
uh and um
even though I've used my strategy for
like the past two years two years and a
half in the form in which it was two
three months ago
um it was not perfect and I've felt like
it needed some improvement
in regards to the risk reward ratio
because sometimes my stop loss was a bit
bigger uh than my actual first DP but
then
I've found a way to improve it after
I've
you know leveled up another layer of
understanding so it's it's levels to
understanding the markets you think you
understand something but then you
understand it even more and you have
another aha moment to your previously
aha moment
and uh and so how did that turn around
feel for you and what was sort of like
the The Experience can you explain that
uh that that made me go from the um
imperfect sort of yeah so basically we
transition from you know like losing
Trader to profitable Trader how did that
transition happen was it like a
instantaneous thing where you just you
know all of a suddenly you started you
know winning trades after trade and and
they're growing the account consistently
or was it you mean you mean back then
back then yeah back then
um no it was just a I I didn't notice
that I started to make actual profit I
was focusing not on making profits
anymore when I started focusing on the
process itself of me being disciplined
of me following a set of rules even
though the set of rules was was still
being built
um even though
um I I still didn't control my emotions
I didn't master myself I still don't
master myself the way that I would want
to master myself but
you know it's a continuous learning
process
um but it was actually a
a process oriented thing I was focusing
on what happens in the chart didn't care
about the Pips didn't care about the
money if I made money
um because then we you know
we were a little better financially
speaking so I didn't felt that pressure
anymore oh we need to make money I need
to make money because I'm at a job and I
need to bring money somehow into the
household uh things started to go a bit
better for us and uh that pressure
disappeared and uh
I I was again able to focus on the
process on me waiting for something
specific to happen
and then I
I just didn't care about the profit that
I made at the end of the week when I
looked at how much profit I made I said
oh I mean two percent that's good it's
good and two percent was nothing at that
time because my account balance was
small
and so if you had to like sort of break
down and you know you said you're doing
six hours at the charts and you know
you're trading multiple Pairs and that
sort of fell down uh what were you doing
when you were like two percent for the
week great what was it what was it what
was the change in time of the charts and
or markets trading a number of Trades
uh focusing only on Euro USD uh only
your USD because my my major losses
happened always on GBP USD even when I
was trading only those two pairs uh then
when I started to trade everything it
was a total catastrophe and then I
restarted focusing again only on Euro
USD so when I did that
um you know my focus became very sharp
only at one thing and um a normal
trading day would look like I would wake
up uh wait for about two hours after I
wake up for the London fuel Zone to
start uh I'm sure that the listeners
know what a Killzone is I think they
will nail because I think that the one
I'm releasing in a couple of hours is
all about the Cool Zone yeah the kill
zones yeah okay so um uh wait for the
Killzone to start and then just focus
two three hours from the London Kill
Zone and then if I have time
two three hours again on the New York
Kill Zone but not necessarily placing
trades because previously this is this
was what I was doing I felt like if the
market moved 12 Pips
to the downside I I I I I needed to be
in that
a move you know uh and then if there's a
pullback of eight eight Pips I need to
benefit from that so that's
how my mentality was previous to that
but now I wanted to focus only on having
one setup if I can have one good trade
in a session I don't need more and
that's actually the thing that changed
so focusing on only one pair back to one
pair and
two three hours per session but wait for
one single setup don't feel like if
markets it's dropping you need to be in
that trade no okay it's dropping I'll
wait for a pullback and then you know or
I'll wait for a reversal yeah and so so
uh if you look at your stats now
um say for example the past month I mean
what would you
how's your win rate look and if you see
it risk to reward per trade how does
that look what are those two for the
best month my win rate someone was
asking me yesterday on Instagram for the
past month my win rate has been 93 I
didn't have that much traits
um only trading one single pair now I've
transitioned to trading all the gold and
I've been doing this for one year one
year and a half
been trading mode for quite some time
yeah
um and
not too many trades usually one maybe
two trades a day if I trade both
sessions London and New York usually I
don't trade both sessions because if I
if I take a setup on London I feel like
I've
I don't need to be in front of charts
anymore I want to enjoy more the other
things that become available to us you
know yeah
um when you start to know what you're
doing in the charts and
risk reward previously when my strategy
was imperfect it was
um I would risk more than I would
actually aim to take profit so my risk
reward was negative but my win rate was
also good however right now I don't aim
for something less than one to one if I
have one to one doesn't matter if it's
going to be 10 tips doesn't matter if
it's going to be 15 or 20 or 30 if it's
30 Pips for example
um dirty bib stop loss I would aim for a
30 bips TP but I've made like a golden
rule for myself and this has been the
best decision that I've ever taken I
think is to take most of my position off
at 20 Pips so I still do that yeah yeah
so even though my stop loss is 30 my TP
is going to be 30 at least 30. I don't
use TP usually I just might manually
close partial but I would still take
most of my um trade off at 20 Pips okay
so it's like something that I've been
doing yeah any you like moving a stop at
that point or I believe the stop loss at
break-even yeah I move the stop loss to
break even after that and then if it
takes me out I don't care because I made
money if it doesn't take me out and it
continues to go higher I'm not going to
feel mad previously I would feel mad oh
my God so stupid why did I close the
trade because I could have made so much
more money but now I just realized that
I don't have to do that because when you
find consistency you're going to make
money from
um you know trading more uh you know
more of your trades are going to be
quality trades so it doesn't matter
because now I don't feel like oh
um I took three losing trades so I need
to catch one big trade to recover
everything and being a profit and I
don't feel like that anymore
so now I don't care if the runner goes
200 Pips and in Gold it can happen right
because I've already made my my share
tired of missing trades or spinning out
of the charts introducing my robot
Builders club with our platform you can
build bots in minutes not weeks without
any coding required get lifetime access
to my video course VIP community and
over 40 ready-made robots works with mt4
or mt5 and as a bonus you'll get three
months access to my robot lab where
we're building test bots on live calls
every week join the hundreds of traders
who are trading smarter not harder click
the link in the description to learn
more get the free training and download
a free robot and and how do you work out
like you're where you're going to get
out of your Runner
uh I look at money I look at money as in
usually I leave a 10 Runner so if that
10 is going to make I don't know 200
let's say or a hundred dollars I would
take something off at Double to a 40
bips so TP
um one in case my risk reward ratio it's
bigger than 20 Pips
um I'm gonna take something at 20 Pips
then I'm gonna take something at tp1
let's say uh uh the normal the the equal
size of the stop loss I'm going to take
half of the runner off and then 40 Pips
60 Pips and
um this I have this approach when um
higher above price if I'm in a bullish
position or in a bearish one lower below
price if I don't have like important
Market structures like uh Killzone highs
and lows I like session highs and lows
um daily highs and lows weekly highs and
lows if I have something like this and
price already reached there I'm going to
close most of the runner and I usually
leave a zero zero one
which just needs to feed my ego yeah
that's it it's just like leave it alone
it's like a symbolic yeah
yeah it's a symbolic thing that's a good
idea actually yeah that's a good idea
zero zero one how do you I suppose are
you using metatrader for you I'm using
that a Trader yeah so I suppose you can
just close everything bar 0.001 so
whatever yeah
um oh that's interesting yeah and it's
probably a little good tip there I think
people should take away from this is I
think it's something that I always
recommend how did you come up with that
every time I so so this Golden Rule of
um taking uh uh of closing my position
at 20 Pips most of it I've actually got
it from ICT because uh back in the days
when he was trading Euro USD he wouldn't
leave his entire trade to go for more
than 10 11 Pips and he would always say
you don't need more than 10 bips per
trade to make a living out of trading
and then when I started uh looking into
gold gold is a lot more volatile so I
felt like it's natural to have like a
double uh you know golden number 10 Pips
for Euro USD or four experience 20 Pips
for gold felt like natural for me but
then when I closed my entire position at
20 Pips
um I felt like and it would continue to
go in my favor
um I I always felt like
and little by little when you start to
pay attention at this these things that
you feel you want to look for uh you
know a way to resolve them uh it's it's
not a good way to uh you know make
yourself not feel those things anymore
it's a good way to feel them but it's a
good way to address them in a way that
you can satisfy that need that you have
for you know I want to be in the trade
for more Pips yeah uh so I then um
realized that in every Trader's head
there are two personalities that leave
and one of them is the trader who is
actually interested in paying his bills
making money and all of that stuff and
becoming consistent with trading so it's
all about the money for this guy and for
the other personality that's technical
analyst who doesn't really care about
the money uh it's the I.T guy if you
want you know the geek that spends a lot
of time in front of the computer and he
makes an analysis and he wants to ride
the entire move or at least as much as
possible from it so I couldn't get rid
of that personality from my own hand so
I said okay I need to make peace with
this girl girl you know inside my head
and that's how I came up with the with
this thing you know take money so the
trader in me is the one that I will
always prioritize because she helps me
to pay my bills she helps me to fund my
lifestyle and all that and I also need
to
um the other girl you know the technical
analyst in me I need to keep her
satisfied because otherwise she's going
to start sabotaging me she will not
allow me to take my money put it in my
pocket and she'll just say you know just
put a break even and if price goes 20
Pips in my favor and I don't take profit
and it takes me out a break even I'm
gonna feel
um more pain you know mentally than I
would if I just take most of the
position off at 20 Pips at least I paid
myself and then just leave something to
satisfy the technical analyst yeah this
is brilliant it's absolutely real I've
never heard anything like this and like
300 odd episodes have done yes so this
is fantastic it's interesting because I
I challenge you out there to anyone
who's listening uh how many of you
thought that she was gonna say that the
second person the technical analyst was
the one that you wanted to be I I
thought that for a second there I was
like are you gonna say that that's the
one that sounds like the right one
doesn't it not the one that's going to
just take the money and run but yeah
that's that's a that's a complete and
utter
um mindset shift that I think you know
it's great for people to hear that uh
fantastic stuff now um
what about like prop firms they sort of
came on the scene whilst you were you
know doing well by the sounds of it I
mean have you ever considered it did you
ever sort of think this was something I
need to look into or you know trade in a
on a firm no not at all okay no I never
and and what was the reason for that was
there something in that you sort of
decided like nah I'm not going to do it
because of XYZ or was it
[Music]
uh it's something that I decided I'm not
gonna do because
um back in my job when I used to work
um we had a lot of trainings about time
management and about how to make the
people be more productive and all of
that state all of that stuff and uh
something from one of those trainings uh
actually uh helped me a lot in my
trading uh and that was whenever you
have a time limit set by someone else to
accomplish a Target you will always
stumble uh you will always not be there
in time uh
and the main thing that prop firms do
they give you a time limit by which you
need to make a certain amount so it's
basically you are being imposed some
rules the purpose of trading the purpose
of me becoming successful is to not have
anyone else impose me their own rules
and I know that for a lot of people uh
prop firms have been a blessing uh it it
just I couldn't find a good reason for
me to start looking into a proverb you
know starting with a big Capital because
I thought well I deposited 500 and I
blew the account what on Earth makes me
think that I can pay a prop firm a
thousand dollars to give me a hundred
thousand dollar account what makes me
think that I'm gonna do better with them
okay if it's my own money and I can
afford to lose it and it's the less it's
500 and I can't do good with it what
makes me think that I can actually you
know take care of someone else's money
and even though at the beginning with
prop forms you start with a demo account
you still pay the challenge yeah you
know so I thought instead of paying for
the challenge let me start my own
account
start being consistent and then I'll see
if I need a a bigger fund you know more
money and then I will see but at least
let me get consistent with my own
trading method yeah and uh little by
little I just didn't need it yeah
because I started doing good yeah it
makes sense yeah but the rule-based or
the imposed rules and I know now there
are preference because that's a very bad
rule that they have it's very
um traumatizing I would say for a Trader
yeah the these guys here I'll tell you
what though they've just released an uh
an unlimited so this is blue Guardian I
know unlimited time yeah so they've yeah
I think I know yeah I know they have
this because now you know when they're
the first prop first that started to pop
up you know uh like ftmo or mff maybe I
don't know if mff now has like an
unlimited time period to pass the
challenge but whatever but at first all
the platforms that appeared
um they'd have this 30 days to pass the
challenge now when they're like other uh
prop fronts that are emerging they know
how to do better because it's pretty
obvious that that imposed 30 days to
make 10 or 8 or 12 12
people will rush things they will not
see that okay I have one month I have 30
days to pass the challenge if they take
one or two losses or maybe even three
losses in a row there they will feel the
urge to recover that fast because they
will feel like they are running out of
time so now prop firms that start to
emerge now or that appeared after ftmo
because you know fdmo and everyone's
head is like the first proper you know
um now they start to do better with uh
less rules less strict rules and all of
that so this is good but now I don't
have any reason to go for a profit but
it's good that they they start to uh you
know have
more uh to be more Trader oriented
because if you're oriented towards the
trader that's going to trade your funds
um then you're also oriented towards
yourself you know yeah yeah and like I
mean you invest in the trader make him
feel safe make him feel not rushed and
uh she's gonna do a lot better yeah than
if you rush him yeah you need to do this
in 30 days otherwise you're out yeah
yeah which and I I suppose it does like
really you know get rid of the traders
that can trade because they are going to
you know blow the account at 30 days and
the ones that are very exceptional like
you know for yourself for example I
don't even you know they're not you're
not enticed by the the proper model
because you don't need it
um so it's it's a it's a fine line uh
right let's move on it is yeah so so uh
what do you think made you different
from other you know folks following like
you on Instagram or or people you've
like either I don't know if you Mentor
people but like if you're mentored
people what do you think made you
different at the start yeah
I think it's the same thing that makes
me different at the moment which is
my availability to help everyone
regardless if they are part of my paid
mentorship or not I've always
spent a lot of time in answering all the
questions that I've received and not
just give like a blunt answer yes or no
or yeah you need to go check that or you
need to go look at that uh no I've
always spent a lot of time every day to
answer questions
in the same way in which I would have
wanted someone to answer me so I think
that the fact that I've always been
helpful friendly
um you know answering questions even
when they were about my paid mentorship
like if someone asked me a question that
would be something that I would only
teach in the paid mentorship or
something like that I wouldn't say oh
you know well I covered that only in the
paid mentorship no I just give him what
he asked for me from me and I think that
this little by little started to add up
more people were coming to me asking me
stuff I kept replying I kept being
friendly and I still do that I have I do
not have a single comment
in my entire YouTube channel that has
remained unanswered not till this date
and it's a thing that I do three times a
day I go to YouTube studio and I go to
my Instagram and I go to my Telegram and
every day three times a day I make sure
okay what new comments do I have when
your questions that I receive I need to
answer them all I cannot leave people
like that without answering them without
making them feel like I pay attention to
them so I think that this is what
um you know made me be different and it
still is something that
um makes me be a bit different from the
others yeah you're making me feel like a
bad YouTuber I I was really struggling
to talk it to the comments no because
I'm sure the comments that you receive
are not necessarily questions about
technical analysis and all that stuff
that's me yeah so what I was really
after was like from from a trading point
of view versus a mentorship and I think
I probably screwed up the question there
um yeah what do you think made you
different as a Trader like you know why
did why were you able to sort of come
through it and become a profitable
Trader whereas so many come through and
fail or give up or or just spend years
and can never really make it happen
okay it's um
my
my needs to simplify things I don't like
complicated things I don't like uh
complicated designs complicated clothes
complicated jewelry complicated makeup I
don't like any of that stuff uh and this
also transposed into trading when I
first started to learn ICT everything
was complex I at that time I would say
it's complicated now I know it's only
complex not complicated anymore
um but um
trying to do good in a very complex
environment with very complex methods
it's going to make you
be successful a lot harder and a lot
later so I think that when I realized
that I need to simplify things I need to
exclude more than 90 of the things that
I've understood that I've learned about
and I need to understand that if I'm in
a candy store and I will want to eat all
the candies I'll get cavities very soon
so it's not in my benefit so I then
spent some time realizing only just
staring at charts and trying to
understand myself what is that thing in
the charts that makes me look at it
right at the first moment when I open
the charts and for me those were highs
and lows and big candles and balances so
then I said okay if this is these are
the two things that I feel like my eyes
and my bracer instantly attracted to I
have two brains my eyes and my brains my
eyes and my brain are instantly
attracted to
um I said okay maybe it's time to
learn more about these things focus more
on these and then if I feel like I need
to add something I will look into a
third concept or something like that but
I think my need to simplify things and
to have everything simple around me is
what made me simplify ICP Concepts
explain them in a simple way not you
know put a lot of lipstick on the charts
like ICT says himself and uh just keep
it simple this this is yeah so
simplistic so keep simplifying things
down which is which in a way is kind of
hard for like it's hard it's hard for
everything right I mean Apple do it very
well in terms of they simplified all
their products down and but it I don't
even remember a speech from an Apple
employee who was saying it is actually
one of the hardest things of the world
to do is to simplify something that's
quite complex yes exactly so it's a
special talent there
um in terms of I mean the other thing
you did I suppose with the regard to the
stop loss and take profit and and exits
is that's kind of simple right it's like
it's almost old school I've even heard
people talk about a 30 pip stop loss and
a 20 pip take profit and Donkey tears
nobody talks about it now so the fact
that you know with that you get a 93 win
rate last month then there's something
to be said about that because you're
always making money right and exactly
that's the game
um I'm loving this interview by the way
it's really really good uh right what
about a mindset sort of technique or
something you do like on the day to try
and get you on the in the right right
frame of mind
do you have anything oh I see I do I
think uh it's not necessarily something
that I do but it's something that that I
pay attention to I think that starting
your day
um in front of charts if you open a
chart but you know that you didn't get a
proper rest during the night or you had
a fight with your partner or there's
something else you know working in the
back of your head that you're thinking
about and you can't really focus if
there's something that needs to be
solved right now and it's not trading
related I try not to engage that much in
trading I first try to fix that thing
and then
um you know
refocus on trading another thing that I
started doing is
um I bought a whiteboard and I write on
it uh thanks
for all the good trades that I take and
for all the batteries that I take and
for the bad ones when I don't follow my
rules when I jump ahead of myself and
all of that stuff I write there thank
you for the lesson that cost me this
much and I don't erase those from the
Whiteboard uh because I want them to be
like a a statement of what happens when
I
don't do what I'm supposed to do but I
don't do what I teach other to do other
people to do and that really helps me
keep myself accountable
and how many how many though sorry
what's the oldest one of those that
you've written on the how long ago was
it
uh oldest one is like an entire account
not a trade I haven't had a like a trade
that I lost because I didn't follow the
rules so those are the kind of things I
saw you I mean um I mean on the
Whiteboard if you're writing these
things on the Whiteboard yeah how long
ago was the last the the first one you
put on
first one oh it was uh I think five
months ago because I didn't
how many of you go on there now
yeah
let me check
14 but one of them 14 but one of them is
an entire account right I'll tell you
the story if you want yeah go for it
because it's already public you know
yeah yeah okay so uh four months ago I
said that you know there are a lot of
people who want to learn more but they
don't necessarily
um have the money to pay for a
mentorship and for some whatever reason
even though I'm always available to
answer questions they don't ask
so I said okay maybe my YouTube content
doesn't help I don't even have that much
time to produce YouTube content so I
said there has to be a way in which I
could um make other people benefit from
my trading and I opened a copy effect
service and that happens about four
months ago I think maybe three months
ago uh it was uh in uh at the beginning
of
March or middle of March so I'm going to
copy FX service I deposited three
thousand dollars people started to
um you know copy my trades it went good
for the first two weeks and then
I I don't know everything like all my
mindset was doubt absolutely I started
to do everything that I did in my
beginning stages of trading everything
that I was not supposed to do Buy sell
Buy sell if I see a good girl a big
candle just buy at an Impulse sell out
an Impulse oh my god
um don't post don't don't put stop bus
remove the stop loss all of that thing
and eventually I just blew the account
it was such
[Music]
that was because that was the pressure
the pressure of like having other people
yes taking those trades a lot of people
because like I said in the first two
weeks everything was really good in the
first two weeks I did
20 I think or 17 I even had a day in
which I did seven percent which I was
wow that's good and then
um people started writing me
thanking me uh thank you for the
opportunity I put my rent money and you
uh made more of it and all of that stuff
a guy wrote me
um because I had like a minimum deposit
of a hundred dollars you know it was you
know the requirement from the broker
um and
a guy wrote to me and he told me could
you please lower the minimum deposit
requirement and make it 50 because I
only have 50 it's my only money and I
wanna you know put it there so I copy
your trades and make it more uh and make
more of it but I started receiving all
these messages and I realized that most
of the people that have
signed for The Copy Service were people
that didn't even afford to lose that
money that they put in and I said I've
opened
a Pandora box something that I was not
supposed to do because people who
sign up for a copy service they don't
trade or at least they don't have the
results that they want so their mindset
is like well she'll make money for me
and I'm sure that she will so I'll put
all the money that I have so they are
not aware of the fact that they can lose
that money and when I realized that that
you know I cannot control the kind of
people that are going to copy my service
and when I say the kind of people I say
aware people people that have the
awareness that stuff bad stuff can
happen and the money can be lost
and I couldn't control that so then I
started feeling really responsible oh my
God what if I'm going to lose someone's
rent money what if I'm going to lose
someone's entire life savings what am I
going to do then because I'll feel
responsive and I will be responsible for
ruining the lives of people how can I go
about that so I felt at the time you
know I was already losing it I felt that
the best thing to do was to trade more
you know to make more money faster which
is a rookie mistake
I just completely
you know rug to pull myself yeah yeah
that's what I did what what kind of risk
were you what kind of risk were you
putting on that account versus what are
you what are you put on your like normal
account what counts on that account I
was putting like five maybe ten percent
risk per trade on my normal account I
use a fixed slot size on my own
personal account yeah I put a fixed lot
size
doesn't matter how big my stop loss is
going to be but the thing is that with
when I was doing The Copy Service I was
still trading the let's say old rbv
strategy
um and that incident
with the copy effects account made me
realize that there is something that I
need to fix with my strategy so that was
because remember I I told you earlier
that my strategy was not perfect but now
I feel that I don't need to modify
anything related to it but back then I
always felt like for the past three
years I felt like there's something
missing but yeah it works it makes money
so you know what and it was a big stop
loss that I had and it was
um some entry confirmations that I had
and the copy effects incident
gave me no other choice no other
alternative but to face
the problem that I felt the strategy had
and find a way to fix it
and then I started taking all my
um
uh Instagram reels because I would post
my trades on Instagram reels I took them
all one by one and all the pictures that
I documented I ever documented my trades
with because I keep for every year for
every month I keep a like a uh you know
I uh screenshot my screen when I take a
trade uh and I keep those as a journal
of my trade and I started looking at all
of those trades all of them taken within
the past two years
and I realized how to improve my
strategy because I've just filtered out
the traits that didn't do good but that
I you know I said oh it's just part of
the game losing smart again it is part
of the game but it's only part of the
game when you when you when you don't
feel like there is something else that
needs to be improved if you feel like
there's something else being to be
improved but you don't work to improve
it then the loss is not part of the game
it's the kind of loss that it it it it
you left the room for an error there and
you're not doing anything to address it
if you find the error and you do
something to address it and you address
it and you still get a loss and you just
literally feel like there's nothing else
that you need to improve or that okay I
don't know what other things to improve
honestly if that's the case then yes
that's a loss that is part of the game
it is what it is accept it because you
know no system is 100 bulletproof but if
you take a loss
and you treat it as if it's a part of
the game but deep down you have a doubt
what if there could have been something
that I could have done
to you know improve my entry to improve
my stop-loss placement to have like a
better uh price level at which I need to
wait for price to be informed of my
specific setup when you feel that but
you just ignore it
eventually is gonna
come against you yeah yeah I'll sort of
I'll sort of get what you say in there
I'll sort of get what you're saying
um yeah now what about uh uh we're gonna
jump into the quick far round in a
second but before we do I just want to
see if there's any one thing you would
recommend a retail Trader spend the next
month mastering
themselves
themselves your
um
pay attention to what you feel when you
open the chart pay attention to the urge
that you feel of being in a move that is
happening right now pay attention to
[Music]
um
you know
if I were to to relate only at a
technical analyst from a technical
analyst standpoint I would say focus on
understanding Market structures if you
understand Market structures and if you
can find a way in which to blend price
structures with time structures and
understand that there has to be a price
level that it is
a Time structure and a market structure
like price structure at the same time
and that's the one that you should focus
on then yes spend time on that so
understanding Market structures and
understanding
um
you know time and price not just price
from a technical analysis standpoint
this is what I would focus on
understanding Market structures from a
time and price perspective
psychologically speaking Master yourself
try to pay attention at all those urges
that push you you know push the button
when you know you're not supposed to pay
attention to how your heart is racing
when you push the button
because the heart is racing I mean your
heart wouldn't be racing when you open a
trade if you if you have a rule-based
strategy that you know you followed
you're gonna feel like okay well I have
a plan I'm following it so why is my
heart racing but if the heart races it
means that you're not taking the
decision to open a trade based on a rule
or a set of rules that you've you know
decided to follow and if that's the case
you know whoever doesn't have rules
they're not gonna
evolve and it's also yeah having the
rules that you that you've tested so
you've got confidence in it so that
absolutely absolutely otherwise you can
have rules but you've still got you
don't you still don't know whether or
not it's going to work or
right we're going to jump into the quick
fire around here so
um a few quick questions so how long did
it take you to go from newbie to
consistently profitable
uh about two years
what's your favorite favorite entry
setup
entry setup is price has to be below 12
minute open for me to buy and it has to
create an imbalance to the upside and
then like a ICT sphere value Gap
um and this uh pattern has to form
between uh let's say nine not not my
hour
um 2 a.m till 5 a.m New York time zone
for the London session and then I want
to sell only prices above the 12
midnight open uh price and it gives me
that imbalance to the downside and then
it comes back rebalances and then starts
to move down so that's my favorite entry
pattern sell above 12 minute open
buy below 12 minute open
what's your preferred broker and trading
platform look folks I know you want the
answer to this question which broker is
this Trader using now the answer has
been sponsored by black bull markets so
to find the answer out you're going to
need to go over to tradynet.com find the
show notes page for this guest and then
all will be revealed do you have a
recommended trading book or resource
never read a trading book I started
reading treading in the zone I think uh
uh very good at the beginning but then I
just left it I don't know why
but trading resource definitely uh ICT
yeah let's see what we'll put that link
up to the uh the video you mentioned at
the start of the show yes
yeah okay right brilliant um before we
wrap up what's the best way for Traders
to get hold of you
uh they can get hold of me on Instagram
my handle is true underline Lara uh they
can also get hold of me on telegram the
handle is the same true underline Lara
t-r-u-e underline l-e-r-a brilliant well
look a big thank you also yeah I'll tell
you what we'll make it easy for everyone
because um what we're going to do is
we're going to hook all those links up
in the show notes and to find them
simply search for Alex in the search box
on tradynet.com until next time I wish
all my listeners trading happiness and
success all right folks there you have
an interview done in dusted now we've
got Alex's full strategy broken down
step by step and it is a simplified way
to trade the ICT method so if you do
want to check that out go over to the
channel hit subscribe on the YouTube
channel and you'll see that video pop up
very soon so other things remember we've
got the live streamers we've got the
blue Gaddy and they're taking the blue
Guardian challenge we've got the robot
Builders Club Tim uh K evaluation if you
join this month of August folks have a
great trading week and we'll see you in
the next episode