welcome back folks this is lesson 6.1
of the january 2017 ict mentorship
defining high time frame pd arrays
okay when we look at a chart
regardless of what time frame we're
looking at it uh there's two elements
that come to mind as a trader obviously
we think in terms of support or
resistance or we think in terms of audit
we're sold we think in terms of price
patterns uh secondary but
generally we think of
a price being valued too low or too
cheap or expensive or too high
and
the algorithm
has similar thought processes built into
it
and we look at it in the form of a
premium and a discount market for the
sake of
discussion just think of this red line
at the top as a resistance and a blue
level in the bottom being support
as price starts to move away from a
level that would be viewed as too cheap
or support
naturally our expectations as traders we
expect to see price move higher
when it does this we're confirmed to see
a
response moving up to a resistance point
of some kind now the problem is with
retail trading and with technical
analysis as a whole
by itself it doesn't help you because
every one of us could come to the
conclusion that a specific level above
current price action would be a
resistance level
some of us will see it as a an old load
they would be trading to some of us
would see an old high some of us would
see something else that would equate to
a resistance level
now
to remove all the ambiguity
you have to have a mindset going into it
and
this teaching is to teach you the
hierarchy on the tools that i use for
framing the trades
now these same arrays are the same
things that we've talked about since the
beginning of the mentorship but we're
going to prevent you from having them
in a disorganized fashion in other words
there's an iraqi in how they are used
and how you look for them in price
as price makes a retracement lower from
a support level
how far does it usually retrace back
all of us again based on different walks
of technical analysis and different
disciplines we'll all have a different
conclusion some of us would use a
fibonacci some of us would use some
fashion of support and resistance some
of us would use elliott weave and
ratios and harmonic patterns all kinds
of things would come
by way of discussion if we were in a
round table meeting we're all sitting in
the same room together we all have
different opinions about how far it
would retrace some of us wouldn't have
even expected a retracement
okay some of us would not see this as a
retracement but a
beginning of an all-out reversal to
trade below the old low
that's the problem every trader is
plagued with when they come into this
business
who's right
who has the the means of knowing with
great deal of prognostication what is a
support level and what is the resistance
level and therefore what will propel
price
away from the current market action
higher or lower because the common adage
is if i knew where price was going next
i wouldn't need to know anything else i
would make money that's not true because
you would find some other way to lose
money over leveraging or or
you
doing something different you shouldn't
be doing and you'll break a rule and
you'll get the emotional psychological
impact because of that and you'll end up
blowing the account
so
when we look at
charts we want to be viewing price in
the terms of are we in a premium or are
we in a discount market earlier in the
mentorship i taught how you could do
that but we're going to talk a little
bit more
in terms of how to frame that on higher
time frame charts
in the form of an hierarchy with the
arrays
as price starts to retrace and then
moves higher it hits a level of
resistance now for the sake of
discussion we're going to say we
collectively understand what would deem
a
resistance level to remove all the uh
secondary discussions that we could have
if we were
a front in front of one another in the
same setting in a you know live setting
where we could literally shake hands and
talk all of us would have an opinion
about what would constitute a resistance
level but we're going to say that this
level that's noted as red that is the
commonly agreed upon resistance level
the reasonable expectation would be to
see price move away when price does that
some of us would expect one more try to
get to that level maybe to go through it
or to fail
that's how i trade that's how i expect
to see price react
some of us would not even expect that
they would expect this one time punch up
there and then all together all you know
reversal
this is the type of setup i like to see
here another pass towards that old high
either it's going to give me a run
through
or a false break or it's going to give
me a failure swing
we talked about classifying
institutional price swings that's what
we've done
for that teaching
here i want you to start thinking in
terms of premium and discount on higher
time frame charts because the hierarchy
on how you view this
is going to help you whether you're a
day trader scalper position trader
short-term trader which expectation of
lower prices how far would we expect to
see price go down
well the first impulse leg
and then retracement then as a second
leg higher hitting that resistance level
that secondary impulse leg that's
probably going to be a good reasonable
expectation for support level
now it could be a bullish order block it
could be a an old short-term high in
there on a lower time frame if this was
a monthly chart
at that low there may be a
daily short-term high that would create
a
a support level that can't be seen on a
monthly chart
so
when we're looking at these higher time
frame charts just understand that
there's going to be levels that exist
inside of larger price swings
that
you may not see unless you go down to
the lower time frame now when i say
lower time frame i'm only referring to
the daily
because the higher time frame analysis
is all we're focusing on here nothing
below a daily chart
so if we're assuming that this is a
monthly chart and we're looking at price
the expectation is okay well at that low
we would expect to see some lower time
frame
support level again it could be the
monthly bullish order block it could be
a weekly bullish order block or it could
be a
daily short term high
you may not be able to see it inside
that that little low there
but nonetheless when we look at price
swings back and forth on a chart whether
it be monthly we clear daily and even
lower time frames
you have to understand that there's
swings that exist and support levels and
resistance levels that exist in the
lower time frames that may not be so
apparent using these higher time frame
charts
that is not
what you base the majority of your
trades on what you're going to be doing
is you're gonna be using the monthly
chart
and the weekly chart
to frame the context of what that market
should be doing
using these pda arrays
so
if we watch price and it continues to
trade higher here
where would you reasonably expect to see
price trade to that short term little
swing low at the failure swing
that's going to be what
a potential mitigation block
that means any orders that were used to
go long but failed to make another pass
at that old high
they're underwater now so they're going
to look to mitigate those losses
and
cover
their long positions and go short
potentially or just get out of the trade
but smart money just doesn't cut losses
they know what they're doing they scale
in scaling out and they hedge so this
would be another selling opportunity
the market seeks liquidity below the low
and below
the second impulse swing
prior to the run into resistance
so it seeks liquidity below the
marketplace once it takes that liquidity
out it can drive all the way down to
that old support level
but generally it doesn't
it will retrace again and pick up more
orders back at an old low
where we'd see another opportunity to
sell off and take out the liquidity
below a short term load that was just
created and back down to a logical area
of support
the expectation would be what the sea
price bounce price does this
when price starts to retrace again some
of us if we were all in the same room we
would expect to see that price low to be
violated and a new low created sometimes
that will happen sometimes it won't
this failure swing in here could be used
to set up another long opportunity
where price rallies and here's the
million dollar question
the understanding is how price moves
from one level to the next but
predominantly it's moving from a level
of discount to a level of premium from a
level of premium to a level discount
between the red line and the blue line
they are extremes in the middle
that's classified as equilibrium
or balance
buying imbalance
is seen when price gets above
equilibrium or up into that red level
which would be resistance selling
imbalance would be when price gets below
equilibrium and down into the blue line
or what would be just derived as
discount
so where would you expect to see price
go next
that's what you're always faced with
when you sit down in front of the charts
this discussion we're going to use
the common ict
tools as far as
setup parameters
in the form of the way they form on
charts in other words the order in which
they form and how to use them based on
wherever you're at in terms of the
marketplace
we're using this teaching
as a foundation that's going to lead us
into a better understanding of this
example we've shown we're discussing
money management for the january content
so lesson five that example for the
dollar yen pair
for a long term position trade
this idea will be used as an example on
framing pd arrays on higher time frame
charts but
before we get into that teaching for 6.2
we have to do the foundation to
understand what we look for and why we
expect it to unfold
like we would
okay again using our thought process of
premium which would be the red line and
discount which would be the blue line
when you look at charts you want to see
where price has moved away from an old
high
and it's dropping down from an area of
premium in other words it's two it's too
high so the valuation is going to be
reduced and dropped lower so repricing
takes place and the market goes down and
the price goes lower as a result of it
until it gets to a point where it's too
much of a discount then there has to be
a premium built into it
the algorithm will do this moving price
back and forth back and forth back and
forth until again something of
significant impact comes in the
marketplace and drives the market
one-sided and it creates a strong
imbalance otherwise the market's just
going to generate back and forth looking
for liquidity based on premium and
discount
conditions
we'll assume for a moment right now the
market price is here
okay and we can clearly see that the
market in recent times had a clear
discernible level of resistance and a
clear discernible level of support
now that can come in the form of bullish
and bearish order blocks or it could be
just old highs and old lows and we'll
just use old highs and lows as an
example for this discussion
your expectation is is right now price
is at a level where it should
by all standards move lower because it's
at a classic viewed resistance level we
don't know how long that time is going
to be required
before the market does in fact submit to
our expectation
and see
a lower price
so that
time frame okay
that part is what you're always gonna
have to submit to time is a murderer
it's a killer for for traders unless you
know
that some of these ideas are gonna pan
out for a long long time you're gonna do
a lot of things psychologically and
emotionally that you wish you wouldn't
have done because you haven't submitted
the time aspect of trading there's two
two elements in trading you have to
submit to time and price when they both
agree with one another and you have
waited for that agreement to come to
fruition
that's where profitability and
opportunities are
so we're looking at price and we have no
idea how long time is going to be
required of us to wait before the
displacement takes place
but eventually our expectation is we'll
see lower prices down to a level of
discount
and that's what we're expecting or
forecasting as a future price
in between these two pre reference
points again
time and price is what's
essential you have to submit to the
level of time which no one knows how
much time is going to be required before
your setup pans out or goes to
profitability
price is what you're studying you're
submitting to time throughout the
process but while you are in the trade
or expecting this to unfold studying it
you're submitting to the price you know
what you're not trying to force your
will in price you're analyzing price to
see what it is that's telling you in
terms of institutional order flow is it
justifying your expectation that it
wants to go down to that discount level
or some bullish order block
to buy back off of and cover a short
position or could be a old low that it
wants to run below
that future price could be a number of
things but for now we're just going to
aim for an old low between the market
price today and the future price which
you anticipate or forecast lower in the
future
there's going to be
zero opportunity for it to be a straight
line in other words you're not seeing
that diagonal line in the way the market
trades it just doesn't do that there's
always some give and take that takes
place so
understanding where certain arrays occur
in that process will help you number one
stay with the trade idea
not be shaken out of it and have the
confidence to hold until the objective
is met or
your stop gets taken and it's simply
moving to a next opportunity the
opposite scene
when you're looking for a bullish
scenario
everything's just reversed
you expect market price to be in the
future at a premium in other words it's
going to be higher than it is today
again you have no idea how long time is
going to be required
to get to your future price or
forecasted price and you have to submit
to that a measure of time that is
unknown you can't know for certainty how
many days or how many hours or or how
many months it will be before that price
is actually arrived at or if at all
but you also have to be studying price
and again monitoring and studying the
the pd arrays that occur in price action
that leads to supporting your
expectation on institutional order flow
that would drive price up into that
premium level
the understanding is that price will
move from a discount to a premium
because the discount can't stay discount
very long price is going to be
established by whoever is selling it who
who stands to make a profit off of it
well the central bank is going to be in
in the business of adjusting price so if
we know that they are in control of
price ultimately
by way of steering sentiment in
economies through the delivery of an
interest rate long term to stimulate or
to suppress an economy for our country
we have to view the market in terms of
technicals to align ourselves with these
ideas so
if we see a level of support
our expectation is okay where is the
evidence that this thing will go to a
premium market
where is the premium market where's the
resistance at where's the higher level
that i would want to see it trade to
between the market price you're at right
now in that future price again it never
happens in a straight line there's time
that you have no understanding of
exactly how long it's going to be
but there's also an element of price
that you have to study in other words
just because you think it's going there
doesn't mean it's going there it could
go halfway there and fail and go lower
nonetheless
what we're going to do is we're going to
outline now the arrays and keep them in
a specific order so that way you know
wherever you're at in terms of market
price what you would expect to see or
what you're looking for
okay you know you know what should i be
looking for an order block or should i
be looking for
a gap you know what should i look for
right now that's what this teaching's
going to do
okay for a monthly chart okay what
you're going to do is you're going to
look at
the current trading range that it's in
okay and
so we're going to assume that you uh
outline the marketplace in terms of old
highs and all lows on the monthly and
that's the easiest way of doing it
there's other ways you can do it but for
now we're just going to outline in the
context that the most recent trading
range that the market has moved from an
old high
to an old low that would be our
premium and discount
definition
in between these two reference points
the halfway point this is always going
to be referred to as equilibrium
now equilibrium between where you think
price will go because it's been there
before
and where it's at right now
relative to an old high and old low
that's the current trading range and
i'll give you an example what that looks
like when we go into lesson 6.2 but for
now i want to lay the foundations for
what it is you look for
the first thing above equilibrium in the
form of an array is an old high and old
low
you want to be looking for that above
equilibrium
the next
thing that you'll be looking for and
this is in the order of importance okay
hold high or low then the next thing
you'll be looking for is a rejection
block a rejection block will be just
above the candle's body
not the wicks
so the actual high and low is the wick
but then the next area of importance is
the rejection block that would be just
above the candle's body
then the bearish order block
a fair value gap
liquidity void
bearish breaker
and the mitigation block
put another way
if we were at equilibrium and we were
moving away from
a premium level or resistance in other
words prices already dropped down
and we anticipate price going lower down
to a level of support or monthly
discount we would be looking for above
current market action again assuming
that we're at equilibrium right now we
would start looking above current market
action in the past on the left side of
our chart
where is the nearest mitigation block
there may not be one
okay check that off
where's the nearest bearish breaker
there may not be one of those either
okay check that off but if there is one
then you would reasonably expect to see
price trade up to that price point to
breaker
then expect some selling to go lower and
once it moves below equilibrium then you
would be all set to go to the monthly
discount or support but let's assume for
a moment the mitigation block isn't
there and the breaker isn't there what
would you look for next okay well the
next order of hierarchy is liquidity
void
is there a range that needs to be closed
in
again that may not be so clear
check that off no problem the next thing
is their fair value gap
again that might not exist either go to
the next thing bearish order block
that's probably going to be there
chances are it's very strong that's
going to be there so what did this give
you i gave you the air archie and which
you look for
a mitigation block
is going to be first considered before
you get to the bearish order block
because the various order blocks will be
really high up in the premium
mitigation block is going to be the
lowest
mitigation and breakers are basically
mitigation blocks but
generally mitigation blocks can occur
lower than breakers
small little bounces and bear markets
would be a mitigation block basically a
bearish breaker will keep your ability
to get to a bearish order block which
will be resting higher up in the premium
when an old high is taken out
that down candle right before the second
high is made taking an old high
or turtle soup in other words
that down candle
if it's
retreated too that's going to be a
bearish breaker that's going to keep you
from seeing most likely high probability
that it won't allow you to get to a
bearish order block so whenever you see
bearish breakers
just
don't expect the bearish order block to
be hit okay because it's going to most
likely keep
price lower because that's going to be
the most dominant
array of all these in here
there is a liquidity void that would be
viewed
if there's no breaker you can close in
that range and that may take you often
to a fair value gap or a bearish order
block
but breakers by themselves even though
they're low end on this list
it's the first thing you're going to
encounter because if you're at
equilibrium and price has already been
moving away from the resistance level
you're looking up now for any potential
areas to resell at
first when you look at is the mitigation
block
or bearish breaker and if there's
neither of those you look for liquidity
void to trade up into the close in that
range warfare value gap to close in it
may not be any of that then you would
expect to see the bear shorter block to
be traded to then that would be your
selling opportunity because you're at a
premium and you go to a logical area
where institutional overflow would kick
in new orders would capitalize and then
selling would
ensue
if there isn't an obvious bearish order
block okay um and there's very little
times that's like that
but we will talk about that when we get
into entry techniques and concepts but
if there is a lack of bearish order
block
understanding and what you're looking at
currently in the market action because
there may be a lot of wicks something
like that may occur
again you would look for a rejection
block which would be just above the body
of the candles you would expect that to
be ran out and then you'd be really high
on the premium there and ultimately a
whole whole entire run on the old high
that would be uh an expectation now i
have here old high and old low
why would the low be there well if
you're on a
very low end of a downtrend on a higher
time frame monthly chart you may be
rallying up to a old low if it gets to
that old low even though
it's an old low in in terms of price
it's really high up in the premium if
it's been rallying a considerable amount
of time and price to get to that level
so retreating to an old low
that's resistance classic understanding
but it may need to run out of old high
as well so basically all you're doing is
you're you're scaling the grade of how
much importance you're going to have on
each one of these
so again in summary i want you to
understand what i'm talking about here
we're not just listing the things we've
talked about in in previous teachings
okay i'm putting them in an order of
significance when you're at equilibrium
or
if you're moving up from discount
okay
your
expectations are to look for very first
thing you look for in the list as price
is going up the first thing you're
looking to see to encounter is there any
mitigation block that i got to consider
because that's the first objective
it could be a selling point
then it's a bearish breaker
that could set the tone for another leg
lower or stop any rallies on a bullish
idea
then the next idea if you're bullish
from a discount or if you're expecting a
new selling opportunity say you're at
the equilibrium price point anything
below
the premium
the expectation is when you're looking
up in price for areas where price may go
up to
it's in this order from the lowest up
in other words from mitigation block all
the way up to old high or low
that's the order you would expect to see
them now
the order of importance
you know it's the highest of the premium
array is the old high and old low
that's that's as high as you can get
then you have rejection block
then you have bearish order block fair
fair value gap and liquidity void
bearish breaker and mitigation block
you're going to be looking up and the
first thing you're going to encounter is
the first thing on the bottom of this
list and then you start working your way
up that list the farther you go up in
this list the more deeper you go into a
premium market
certain arrays in here will keep you
from seeing the next higher array in
other words the next
institutional order reference point
that's listed in here if you get to a
breaker chances are you're probably not
going to go higher than that you won't
generally get up in to close that void
if there's a breaker below a liquidity
void the liquidity void may stay open
basically that range may stay open so
they kind of like it's in the order of
importance as a trader when you're below
premium and looking higher up for prices
or expecting prices to move higher
that mitigation block you know that's
the lowest or the most
likely one you're going to expect to run
into first it doesn't mean that there's
one in price action but you start from
that expectation first and you look for
it it's not there okay what's the next
thing you've been looking for the
bearish breaker if it's not there okay
then i'm okay to expect that void to
close in there but there may not be a
void it may have been a really
systematic and efficient way that it
traded lower
and that won't be any void there so
next thing is is there a gap that would
draw price up into it if there's no gap
then you go right to the order block
okay but the main thing is if there's a
breaker forget about closing in the void
and forget about getting up to that gap
because the breaker is going to take
precedence over everything on this list
when you're below it in terms of market
price if we were anticipating move lower
into price
into a discount or into a support level
we would expect the very next
pd array to be a
mitigation block
now again that may not appear in price
if there is no mitigation block you
would expect to see the next pd array in
the form of
a bullish breaker
again this may not occur or be seen in
price action but this is the order in
which you would expect to see as prices
going lower looking in the past to the
left side of your chart you'll be
focusing on whether or not these arrays
appear in price action
their importance is again is listed from
equilibrium
the expected order of how they're going
to
be in the price action
in the form of a discount the first one
you would anticipate seeing is a
mitigation block bullishly then a
bullish breaker
then a liquidity void now
if there is a bullish breaker now again
a bullish breaker is a
up candle between two swing lows and the
most recent swing low
would be lower normally you're seeing a
stop run in the past
and
the high the swing height it forms
between the two lows
that up candle is going to be your
bullish breaker so when price comes down
to that bullish of candle it'll find
some support
if you see that in price action
chances are that if there's a liquidity
void in price it won't go down to fill
that in it can if it overtakes the
breaker but if it has a breaker
anticipate price not going below the
breaker and leaving the void intact
again assuming there is no breaker
and there is no void but there is a gap
and it may be a liquidity void any gap
sometimes that can occur too but you
would anticipate price reaching down
into a fair value gap which is just a
common little gap where price has only
been delivered on one side of the
marketplace
and then the next
array would be the bullish order block
and again without the breaker
you would expect the void to be filled a
gap to be filled straight down into the
bullish order block then below the order
block would be a rejection block which
is just below the most lowest candle and
its body in other words if it has wicks
long wicks below it
uh we're only gonna be looking for a
move just below the bodies of the candle
and that would be rejection block
and then ultimately the deepest form of
discount would be in the form of an old
low or trading down to in the historic
high and like we said when we were
talking about the premium market
when prices trade up to an old high it
can also trade up to a very old
long-term low and that would both be in
the form of a resistance level
when we look at markets like this
what it does is it gives us a framework
you see here
the monthly premium
arrays these are going to be focused for
primarily bearish premium array trading
in other words you're going to be using
these areas at which to frame a trade or
look for bullish targets at these levels
for monthly discount
your bullish discount arrays
these are your bullish discount arrays
and you would be looking for these
for
bearish targets or looking to get long
at any one of these based on the current
conditions in the market now the same
thing is seen also for the weekly chart
the weekly chart you're going to be
looking at the same thing from
equilibrium up
the first thing you would expect to see
when you're expecting higher prices are
we going to run into a mitigation block
bearish breaker if there's a bearish
breaker you're probably not going to go
higher than that
but if there is no breaker you look for
a void to close in
or if your value gap
if there is no fair value gap or avoid
price could just simply trade right up
into the bearish order block
and if there is
an idea that suggests that there's
possibly not a strong bearish order
block there we would look for a
rejection block which is a movement
above the candles bodies if there's long
wicks that top that market
and then ultimately a run above the old
high or return to a historical low the
same things we just outlined for the
monthly is seen for the weekly both
premium and discount the same hierarchy
and how you would expect to see these
arrays occur in price action
this is the way they are seen
and obviously the same thing is said for
a daily chart nothing's changed the same
hierarchy exists
if we're at equilibrium
and that's the current market action
price and we're expecting lower prices
the first thing we want to look for in
the left side of our chart is there any
mitigation blocks or a bullish breaker
if there is anything less than that
breaker probably won't be considered or
retreated to
the breaker has precedence over
everything both bullish breaker and
bearish breakers
so we're going to take a look at an
example of all this information with our
dollar yen example that we mentioned
briefly in lesson number five money
management was higher time from analysis
using these ideas
in 6.2
that lesson will actually give a real
practical example