welcome back folks this is lesson 6.2 of
January 2017 ICT mentorship
we're dealing with trade conditions and
set up progression
okay we're going to be outlining the
1200 pip move we mentioned in the money
management lesson number five
and obviously it's just a brief recap as
a refresher just in case you came back
to this lesson solo without going into
6.1
when we're looking at a premium market
and markets are trading near a premium
and we have reasons to suspect that at
lower future prices in order we don't
know how much time it's going to be
needed to get to that lower future price
but we're looking for a displacement in
price
and vice versa in this example we'll be
focusing on a buying opportunity when a
market went to a deep discount
on a monthly weekly and daily time frame
and how we would use that insight to get
to a higher Premium Future price
and briefly just as a click overview
again since this
teaching's going to be specifically
dealing with the discount
opportunity buying at a discount and
aiming for a premium
objectives
are focuses down here
where mitigation blocks bullish Breakers
liquidity voids fair value gaps bullish
order blocks rejection blocks and old
lows or old Highs are our focal point
for entries on Long positions
the idea is we're looking for something
down in this list of arrays
to Target
one of the premium arrays
now obviously the first one we'll be
reaching for is a mitigation block that
would be a first objective
then if there's a breaker of any kind we
would aim for that and we'd have to
weigh out whether or not there's a
significant force that would drive it
through a breaker
and we'll talk about that
should we come to it in our example
and then obviously looking for any range
to be filled in for a liquidity void
and aiming for fair value gaps in the
premium range of the market and then we
look at Value gaps bearish order blocks
and then looking for a rejection block
and or old high and old historic low
so we're looking for bullish
PD arrays to buy into with the
expectation of
selling it at one of the monthly premium
arrays
if we were looking at a bearish example
which is what we're not going to be
doing here but just for the sake of
completeness
we would be looking to sell short at a
bearish PD array
aiming to cover that short position with
one of the bullish PD arrays mitigation
block bullish breaker liquidity void
fair value Gap bullish order block
rejection block and or old low or
historic High
so selling at a premium and buying back
at a discount
before we get into our actual example I
want to give you some uh study points so
we keep it in mind when you are looking
at price
it's important to keep this as one of
the focal points when you're studying
when markets are at a premium or at a
discount they're always going to
initially look to rebalance that means
the equilibrium price point between the
last recent range so even if it doesn't
go all the way up to a deep premium or
down to a deep discount
you can always reasonably expect it to
go back to equilibrium and if that's all
you aim for if you if you buy it a real
deep discount and just get back to
equilibrium you'll find a lot of Trades
like that if you're a big premium in the
marketplace you're at historic highs or
a annual high or three month High
you got a real good chance of seeing the
market sell off back to some equilibrium
price point of the most recent trading
range
when markets are in premium
again and if you're in equilibrium
you're gonna be focusing on the market
potentially moving up into one of these
monthly PD arrays that possibly may be a
shorting opportunity
when the market's at equilibrium can
anticipate a market move down into a
monthly discount
aiming for one of the PD arrays
as an objective
so basically at equilibrium you can look
for either expansion on the outside or
downside now you're going to be
Consulting
the market structure on the monthly
chart to determine what side of the
marketplace you're going to be looking
for so it's not indiscriminately going
in there rolling the dice and seeing
well I'm going to sell it short because
it's at the middle of the range or I'm
going to buy it at the middle range we
have to look at some of the uh the
criteria around that price action at the
time
you know weekly ranges just as a
complete approach or overview all of the
same PD arrays for premium and discount
are the same and the same is said for
the daily chart so we're gonna move
through the charts now and look at the
Japanese Yen cash price
okay we're looking at the daily of a
cash price for Japanese Yen
this is seen at barchart.com and
historically uh last year in 2016 we
made a high in August
and the market showed willingness to
want to start breaking down Market
structure at this low here
this low
became broken at this moment here so
Market structure on a long term basis on
a daily chart had been broken bearishly
and we see this Trump
election
rally up into bearish order block and
then it sells off so we're gonna be
looking at this move in here
okay and we're going to go over to
the Forex chart now just so you
understand clearly because a lot of you
may be knew and maybe you're used to
trading the Futures Market or following
the Japanese Yen cash price but when we
pair it with a
currency like the dollar Index the
dollar Index is the front currency and
then the Japanese ends the second so
that means if we're bearish or expecting
lower prices on Japanese Yen cash prices
the dollar Yen pair is actually going to
be inverted it's going to go up because
if Japanese Yen cash price is dropping
that means dollar prices are rallying
and if the dollar is the first in the
name of the pair dollar Yen that means
when you're watching dollar Yen price
action you're watching the advancement
of dollar versus decline of the Japanese
Yen
okay here's a monthly chart of the
dollar yen
okay you can see how we've seen the
market have a really nice rally up in
here this is going to be again
diametrically opposed to what we
expected or just saw rather on the cash
price on the Japanese Yen
now as a reminder for some of you
um we talked about the Japanese yen in
the beginning months of our mentorship
and I gave you some study points and
gave some examples about this move
higher and some of the levels that we
saw a trade to the 118 for instance was
one that was mentioned so
if we look at what has happened and
what's transpired we're gonna map out
this this monthly chart
and we're gonna get some
some levels on here we have a high back
here
okay and I want you to take a look at
these equal lows
okay
the equal lows in here we're going to be
expecting what to be there cell stops so
while the market was dropping last year
we would be expecting it to trade down
into these levels now what's this over
here
these two Down Candles
that is a bullish order block when you
blend both of the bodies together
because it's two consecutive Down
Candles
okay and that gives you your equilibrium
price point in here
okay we'll take that off and round it to
the full 99 level so we have a range
here we have a high end or premium and a
low end or discount
what makes this a discount level the
fact that we saw a price move away from
it here now this could be a discount
level as well we want to go back to
where the move originated here we saw a
big move away here that left the Gap
open so we saw the the dollar Yen leave
the Gap open here where price is only
delivered on the upside there was no
down movement to counteract that up move
that was seen here okay came down
closing that little range in here okay
so price comes down hits the full big
figure 99 okay so we have a defined
range up here
this is premium on the monthly level
this is discount on the monthly level so
on this level down here
we would look to see a move below
these wicks in here
the bodies of these candles we saw it
right in here
this candle comes in at November
2016 it went below the bodies of the
candles in here
that is going to be a rejection block it
cleared out the bodies of the candle on
a monthly chart rejected
sent it higher okay
we have a range up here
we also have this down candle which is a
breaker why is this a breaker because we
have an old high here
old highs
anyone that gets short they're going to
put a buy stopper is resting right above
that the market rallies above clears out
those buy stops here and then trades
down through it once this down candle is
violated rate
here it becomes a valid breaker
if it trades down below it comes back to
it here we have it middle of the body of
the candle extend out in time
it would give you a level of watch this
is actually a weekly level we're going
to see very clearly when we drop down
into weekly range
but we also have notice we have a gap in
here which I'm not going to add all this
on this chart to make it way too busy
but we have a gap in here price has only
been delivered on the downside between
this candle's low and this candle's high
it's been delivered down here as a gap
so that would be one reasonable
objective to look for when price was
rallying
but what makes the buy down here we're
going to discount
on a monthly let's change it over to a
weekly okay here's the same dollar Yen
just in a weekly format okay you can see
here we have an up candle right before
the down move okay that's a bearish
order block so we're mapping that
opening out
over to here okay and the reason why I'm
using the open on this candle not the
wick is because there's an absence of a
gap the reason why is because we have a
wick here and the market traded down
through here so this is two times
this little area has been traded to and
it was blocked in with this candle's
high so this whole little area in here
wouldn't be viewed as a gap
or fair value Gap it's it's been closed
in because the the very bearish
water block itself had a movement lower
initially so it's been passed through
twice there
price comes up and closes it right to
the opening so they also have a we have
a gap in here fair value Gap here
between this candle's low and this
candle is high that would be an
objective to reach for also but I want
you to look at the weekly chart we're
deep in a discount on the Range
and the price shares of willingness to
want to rally and comes back down into
the down candle right before that move
this is a bullish order block you could
be a buyer here but we're focusing on
that November
loan that's this move right here it's
trading right back into and
recapitalizing an old weekly bullish
order block
let's see what's done it's hit that
right there perfectly and rally away now
on a weekly time frame this bearish
order block which is the last up candle
right before the down move this is what
you could have on your charts as well
this is how you
map out the conditions
okay so that would be a reasonable
objective once the price
comes down hits it this by here
it shows it hit that but then we had
this set up here so which is this is
later on you don't really see this as an
objective once it's already been hit
this wouldn't be no resistance
whatsoever
so you can take that level move it over
to here
that would be a reasonable objective on
the upside closing in that range but now
look at the bodies here see that equal
Body candles above that we would expect
to see a rejection block
price reaches through that as well
another rejection block candidate here
equal Body candles
we can expect to see that
as an upside objective as price
continues to trade higher
here
and then we have that fair value Gap up
in here where prices only delivered on
the downside
that would be an objective over here you
can see that I'm not going to move this
line all around and then finally all the
way up here to the bearish order block
which is the last stop camera before the
down move
so we have a
discount to Premium
using the monthly and weekly charts but
now let's go down into a daily time
frame
after I add one more little thing to
this
we also have this last down candle right
before this buy occurred
so right in here
we're going to map that out with a
different color
so that way we can see
the hierarchy between the weekly and the
daily
let's use a different color that a
little bit darker maybe a little a
little too dark for some of your
personal tastes but we're just going to
deal with that won't we
I'm going to go over to a daily chart
okay and you can see here the darker
area is a weekly bullish order block
this is the lower weekly order block and
this is the higher weekly order block
price comes down it hits that and
actually touches both it gives you the
return back to lower weekly order block
that's bullish so it trades two times
into a higher order block on the weekly
chart and the lower of the two bullish
order blocks
and price rallies away and through
right here on this November bye
same thing we start seeing here on the
daily we see an old high here we see an
old high here we have equal highs in
here
we have relatively equal highs here as
well we have a fair value Gap
in here
this high and this low which is what
that would have been on the weekly chart
by the way
and then we have
the last up candle right in here that
low comes in at 118.55
so 118.55 so you can see how prices
reached up into premium level
over here
now important thing is is if we don't
see any
retracement to come back into for a
daily bullish order block or or if we
saw for instance
um let's say it like this
let's zoom in
we have this down candle right here okay
price rallies away from it every time
you look in an uptrend you want to focus
on the Down Candles because that's where
institutions are going to buy either
they're buying at the time of the Down
Candles creation which is usually always
the case
and then if it comes back to that same
down candle at a later time they will
they will buy more at that time
we have three consecutive Down Candles
in here
right in here
okay the order block really begins at
this candle's opening not this last one
you can use that one but if you want to
be ultra Ultra tight on your stops but
you're really going to be using
the opening on this candle because it's
the highest open of the three
consecutive candles
so that's this candle right here open
comes in at 113.28
and this candle
it's open was 113.26 so it's only two
Pips below it and you see look at the
the movement off of that level one two
three times you're gonna bought and
caught that last piece now that's not a
long-term position trade mind you but it
is what you'd be focusing on to see more
upside pressure on this move once you
have already been in it every down
candle here
okay price trades through here and it
comes back down to a hit rate there in
that moment right there adding the
spread you could probably get another
position on there
but more more likely this is one as well
uh you have a down candle price trades
through it come back down into this
candle what is the high on that candle
High concept 1 11 39 the low on this
candle comes in at 1 11 36 so that's
definitely an opportunity for you to get
in and get new Longs on
so having these levels
from the monthly and the weekly on it
gives you context to what to reach for
on a lower time frame daily when you're
executing long-term trades but more
importantly not that I could show it
here but if we would have lost say for
instance this candle here in order to
trade it down below it we could look for
another return to this order block here
as the high end
not down this V but we could expect for
it to trade back down here and give
another Buy
and what I mean by that any bullish
order block or any supportive role from
a PD array on a daily chart if it is
bullish but it fails to give you a Buy
Signal or a support price the next level
you drop back to is a weekly PD array so
you're going to be looking for something
bullish to support price on the weekly
chart if the weekly chart PD array has
no support and it breaks then you'd get
back to the monthly support so
because you're trading off a long-term
perspectives and higher time frame
charts the retracements can go through
what you see on the daily the daily
isn't going to support a monthly
retracement it just isn't going to do it
sometimes this is going to give way it's
going to break through it's going to
pull all the way back to what you would
otherwise not see unless you're looking
at a monthly chart
so by having the monthly
PD arrays on your on your charts and
looking for them also on the weekly
chart and having those levels on both
monthly and weekly on your daily now
it's not going to be on your executable
time frame chart okay it's not going to
be there
but you should always have in your
platform the asset that your or the
market you're Trading
you should have these monthly weekly
levels on regardless even if you're a
day trader because it's going to
surprise you how many times it has great
impact or significant impact even in day
trading or short-term Trading swing
trading you're gonna definitely need it
but position trading it's absolutely
crucial you definitely need it here
because it's going to frame what trades
you're taking and it's going to provide
you support structure in the form of
support of resistance or natural support
for price to find new buying and or new
resistance to find new selling at
the takeaway from this is
if you're following the market on a
daily chart just because there's a
bullish order block or a void that gets
closed in or fills in a gap and that
supposedly is bullish doesn't mean that
it's going to keep price up from that
point price could come back on the daily
chart and retrace rather deeply see this
is a one-sided Market delivery here the
Market's been priced in on one side they
completely keep running it higher higher
up to a logical level which was that
Weekly bearish order block
the market moved from a discount all the
way up to a long-term premium notice on
the daily chart
understanding order block Theory you
could see that as a viable upside
objective
but for those that simply look at
the higher time frame weekly for levels
to key off of
this is a logical area because it's very
clear and distinct it's last up candle
right for the down sharp move
so this is going to be your bearish
order block the opening on that candle
comes in at 1 1861.
the high it comes in on this candle at
118.66.
that's Precision I mean that's really
really tight for a weekly chart it's
hard to deny Precision in that case
there because this is simply it's
irrefutable
so when we look at Price every one of
these new uh these ranges in here
they're all tradable so even if you
don't have the wherewithal to hold all
the way through to get to the Deep
premium
Market
you can get a premium here
on this range
this is a premium from this high down to
the low
these highs in here down to that low is
a premium but as you go through and
deeper this is where the last
last opportunity for the highest premium
and unloading along from that down here
in these discount area
so moving from higher time frame charts
to the Daily monthly and weekly levels
moving them on to your daily chart
that's obvious it's just transposing
hard time frame support resistance ideas
okay but we're using the PD arrays in
terms of understanding institutional
order flow but the main takeaway is if
we lose a level that's arrived at only
on a daily chart
you could drop back into the levels
that's seen on a weekly chart
and I'm going to show you what that
looks like now
if you look at just a horizontal line
all right we have
this old high back here equal highs
when you use that
and let's see what that looks like on
the daily
we have another one
here
right there
and we have another one
and all this consolidation is down the
move here the candle
making a swing low in here we're going
to look at that as some early scaling in
long they were buying here they're
buying in here they're buying in here
they're buying in here they're buying in
here they're buying in here it bought in
here and then boom you see that big move
long-term hedging that's what you're
seeing in here every time it's a down
candle and then it's a subsequent up
move
you know that they bought and that's the
footprint they moved the market by doing
that and every time they do that it
allows new scaling in for them and their
positions are large and they can't get
them all in one time
so if we go out to the Daily again
you can see there's that order block
right here
and here's that order block here that
level trading right down here now it's
not going to be right to the point okay
or right to the PIP if you will but you
can see how these levels draw your
attention to where a future order block
on a daily time frame may occur so it
gives you an opportunity kind of like to
anticipate when the next down candle
should occur in terms of price not time
but around the time of this price
hitting this you want to be focusing on
when there's air down close on a daily
chart because that's going to be new
buying opportunities especially if you
have a higher time frame premium level
that's still unmet
so hopefully this is giving you some
insights about how you can use the PD
arrays in a context for moving to
monthly to a daily if I want to be
specific and make sure that you've drawn
something of value out of it is not
because we can take higher time frame
levels and transpose them onto a daily
chart that's not the point it goes
beyond that if we lose a level
if we lose a order block for instance
like we see
here
okay we saw price trade down and it
moved up
so this could have been a bullish order
block
price came down here Why didn't it go up
why did it come all the way down here it
went through this down candle to go
right back into which is a higher weekly
order block it wasn't until we saw the
the election of Donald Trump that's what
this big whipsaw move was where they
took out the stops here and it had to
trade all the way back down to the lower
weekly bullish order block which is what
this is now I'm showing on the daily
chart but this level is all on that
lowest weekly bullish order block
so again you can see how this low here
it was violated but it went down to the
most logical area on the weekly chart so
the daily chart was pushed
aside and the values that's attributed
to using daily time frame
that wasn't sufficient enough
the banks went back to recapitalizing a
level on the weekly chart and that's
what this whole move is here usually
when you see these big surges higher or
lower in price and you're watching it on
a daily chart or if you see it on a
lower time frame you just can't
understand what's going on quickly go
out to a weekly chart and you'll see
what they've done or what they're
reaching for and then many times what
everybody else gets afraid of to go back
into if they got knocked down take a
loss like for instance say you bought
down here maybe you bought this low here
as a old well and you bought it as cell
stops being ran out okay great
about it you start to see some money and
all of a sudden this boom you get
knocked out
if you go and look at the weekly chart
you can see that all that was in the
return back to that Weekly order block
and if it was starting to trade back up
to this level here it could be a buyer
again
because you know that they went down to
the weekly order block and there's
nothing to worry about dude all they did
was recapitalize a longer term
pdra and that's all it was this is a
return back to a Polish or block on a
weekly time frame so if you lose a level
on a daily don't be concerned just go
out to a weekly chart and you'll see
what they're reaching for if you can't
find it on the weekly chart which is
probably unlikely but if you can't go
out to a monthly chart and you'll
probably see much clearer where they're
trying to push price
the algorithm is going to work
predominantly on a daily time frame but
if the levels are already worked enough
and already absorbed all of the
potential liquidity because it's already
been trading to them it will go out to
that larger open float and that usually
will dip you into
the weekly ranges so when you see the
market movement to the weekly objectives
or the levels that we identify with
these PD arrays
then you'll know that you're probably
going to have a really significant price
move because of the weekly level those
large funds Banks and institutions
they're all going to Dogpile on those
levels because they're significant and
they're long term and they're poised to
make moves like this
so until next time wish you good luck
and good Trading