okay folks welcome back to lesson six
of the April 2017 ICT mentorship
this month is ICT day trading model this
lesson is when to avoid the London
session
okay this lesson is going to be
completely void of any charts any kind
of examples any kind of distractions
because I want you to think about
the characteristics that I'm outlining
here it's not a long lesson but it's
very very important I want to make it
separate apart from everything else
because many of you look at the charts
and you try to question why I'm drawing
a line here or I'm highlighting this or
why is this time feeling either there
and why is it not this I want you to
think about the things I'm outlining in
this lesson
from a conceptual or characteristic
Viewpoint because they're not ambiguous
they're very specific things I look for
and these are the types of things I want
you to think about when you're going
into trading the London session for day
trades
so when is the London session not ideal
well typically after a large range day
which is greater than two times the
average five day range in other words if
you look at
the average DailyRange of a particular
pair
if you ever have a day prior to the day
you're wanting to day trade or trade it
on the session If the previous day or
previous trading day had a huge or large
range day that went greater than two
times its five day average DailyRange
on the day that it had the large range
day okay that is a day that you do not
want to trade immediately the day after
typically there'll be a consolidation or
it could go choppy
after a series of three consecutive up
closes on a daily chart you want to
avoid trading longs
at least in the London session because
typically you can get a retracement that
could be rather deep
creating a down close day on a candle on
the daily chart or a really long Wick
intraday and then maybe continuing in
the direction of the three consecutive
closes but generally after three up
closes
you're going to either get a pause or a
retracement lower
after a series of three consecutive down
closes on a daily chart
you want to be avoiding London shorts
and again just the same thing we just
mentioned with three consecutive up
closes as a daily chart would indicate
many times when you see three
consecutive down closes on a daily
trading short in London the next day or
the fourth trading day in a row many
times you can get caught up in a deep
retracement or it can go sideways
and it makes it not ideal for London
session
now with both of these conditions
outlined here three consecutive up
closes and three consecutive down closes
again that's relative to a daily time
frame
so if we see that criteria what that
will do is help filter out
when we have that situation generally
you won't see a big range day now it
doesn't mean it can't happen but it's
highly unlikely to occur on the fourth
trading day
after a FOMC event that produces extreme
whipsaw
now this could be
linked to the very first one I said as
well after a large range day greater
than two times its average DailyRange
on the five day basis
that can be
the factor that puts you on the
sidelines not trading London or if
there's an FOMC event that produces
extreme whipsaw it means that if there's
an interest rate announcement that comes
out
if they don't change his trades or if
they do change interest rates or it
wasn't just what they as high as they
thought it was going to go or low as it
thought whatever that
um
release is I don't care I don't care so
much about that what I want to say is
what was the action in The Marketplace
so if the FOMC event creates and
produces an extreme whipsaw up and down
generally FOMC comes out two o'clock in
the afternoon in NewYork time
so if we see that big whipsaw price
action that's going to mess up London
okay it's going to screw up the Central
Bank dealers range and possibly roll
right on into
the Asian session so just
avoid trading London open after FOMC
events that create whipsaw
ahead of non-farm payroll numbers
typically  the first Friday not always
but generally the first Friday of every
trading month we expect to see non-farm
payroll
if
we are looking for non-farm apparel to
occur we are not trading London session
at all on that Friday
now the same trading day
that's heading into a long weekend or a
holiday that day we avoid trading London
as well because it could be an early
leave a lot of Trades are going to go on
an early Escape From The Marketplace
and a lot of money is going to be
sitting on the sidelines now this is
going to be a hit and miss type thing
invariably you're going to be able to go
back and find instances where ICT look
at this it went 300 Pips okay going into
the holiday and it was a short day is it
going to happen possibly yeah sure it
was I mean anything can happen but we
trade in a world of probabilities and
statistical Edge so if we know that
historically the normal event is if
there's a day leading into a holiday
usually it's a Friday it could be a
Thursday generally you want to avoid
trading your London session because it's
going to probably be a quiet session
it's not worth taking on the risk
multiple High to medium impact news
drivers for that particular market so if
we look on the economic calendar you can
use Forex Factor you can use any other
reputable
economic calendar that tracks what news
releases or Market drivers that are
going to be released throughout the week
in each particular trading session for
every major pair
if we're looking at that for the London
session and we see multiple
high impact or medium impact events for
a particular currency that can spell a
pretty tricky London session not all the
time again there's always a caveat there
where it can happen but generally if we
see multiple drivers like for instance
maybe it's a two o'clock event that's
coming out and then at three o'clock
there's another one or maybe there's a
three o'clock event coming out and then
there's a five o'clock in that at five
o'clock in the morning event as well one
may be medium impact or one maybe a high
impact or they most they both may be
one or the other in terms of medium or
high impact news if we see multiple
events due out on the economic calendar
for that particular pair it could be
problematic for your London session
trade okay so what we ideally look for
like we learned in the first portion of
this mentorship is we want to see
generally one high impact or medium
impact news event and that way we know
there's going to be probably one stage
of manipulation for that particular day
and then the profit release portion of
the day or the expansion of the daily
range will unfold going into NewYork
an absence of any news during London can
be a wild card day that means it could
go either way it could be a real easy
technical day where your profiles unfold
exactly as you expect or as we just
recently seen in the time of this
mentorship the UK prime minister came
out with a snap election decision right
on the heels of the holiday break and it
took the cable by storm so we had a 400
pip move in one trading day
for  the British pound USD
so and there was an absence completely
of any London time-based news events so
it was sprung on the market last minute
and then that was the result so there's
always some kind of a Black Swan
unexpected
didn't see it coming curveball and that
was when we just seen while we were
doing the mentorship
now what characteristics do I look for
to look for an avoidance of London
session the first one is the Central
Bank dealers range if it's greater than
50 Pips I'm already knowing first hand
i'm possibly going to pass on a London
session it doesn't mean it's a
guaranteed set in stone but if I have
plans the next day
if I have  you know plans with my
family and I want to be rested I'll just
not Pat I'll just pass on a London
session and even if it moves well I
won't even get up at midnight to see how
it sets up I'll just avoid the London
session altogether get a good night's
rest if I can and be rested and spend my
time with my family
if I don't have any plans the next day
going into the NewYork hours then I
will still wake up around midnight time
to see what the Asian range did and
that'll set up my decision factors like
we just learned in lesson five
if the agent range is greater than 40
Pips I'm going to consider the delayed
protraction profile
but it has to meet every one of those
criteria for it to unfold otherwise I'll
move to the sidelines and avoid trading
London
if the market starts to sustain Rally or
decline from 8 PM NewYork
that's usually a poor indication of a
London session that means that the real
event is started at zero DMT and they're
probably going to keep a sustained move
going through and very little
retracement usually the retracement will
occur if at all during a NewYork
session
if CentralBankDealersRange and or
Asian range is not visually and it means
obviously consolidating I'm going to
look to avoid the London session
so that means there has to be a
completely different Market profile from
that what we saw of the intraday price
action between the London open and
London close of the previous day so it
after 2 PM the previous day going into
8 PM if it isn't a quiet small little
consolidation range
that's not an ideal scenario it means
it's going to be a poor setup going into
London same thing with Asian range if
the Asian range gets really wild or
widens up
that again lessens the statistical Edge
that IPDA will give us by moving into a
protractionary state
right after midnight so
bottom line CentralBankDealersRange
and or Asian range must trade down into
small tight consolidation range if we
don't see that if it's trending in both
or either or it makes the London session
highly suspect and you'll know clearly
by looking at the time window that
creates the CentralBankDealersRange
and the Asian range if it's not in
consolidation or if it is in
consolidation
very clear obvious you'll see what I
mean by going through your charts and
going back over a 15 minute time frame
you'll see it clearly when it creates a
consolidation it looks very very
distinct small little narrow range in
contrast to all the previous days into
the action
if it's wide or erratic or trending in
either one of those ranges Central Bank
deals range are Asian it makes London
highly suspect and I don't want to trade
in those conditions
now we as Traders as a day trader we're
going to be aiming for days when the
banks will hold the market to build open
float and again that builds on the the
idea of the previous point
when we anticipate the banks holding the
market in a small tight consolidation
what they're doing is they're allowing
orders to build above and below to
intraday height is being formed between
the Asian range open and the Asian Range
close at midnight so we're looking for
that building up of orders we don't need
to know what the orders are how much
they are because we're never going to
know what that is but we can see it
indicated in how they maintain a very
narrow price range through Central Bank
dealers range time window and the Asian
range again if it's not clear if it's
not obvious in a small tight range
it's probably going to be an ugly London
session and you're not going to see a
clear manipulation cycle or
protractionary state
if the market is trending from 8 PM New
York
generally this is going to create London
sloppiness that means the move is most
likely occurred at the beginning of zero
GMT
8 PM NewYork time and it's going to
keep on rolling through until we see the
NewYork session
so again we don't want to see an Asian
session trending environment for an
ideal London entry
when the market is conditioned for
London slop as we just described in the
previous point
sleep in trade NewYork
that means if any of these things that
we've mentioned so far are there that
means that the London session is going
to be sloppy
if it's going to be sloppy does that
mean it's a high probability condition
absolutely not we want it to be so
slanted in our favor and that means not
trading every day
every single trading day will not have
the recipe for a clear profile as we
described in lesson five
but when we see these characteristics
here it lends very well for us to weigh
whether or not we're going to be
participating in London or if we do
participate in London and we just second
guess it and we have to see it for
ourselves by experience
trade with very very very little risk
because you're probably going to regret
knowing it
accumulation manipulation and
distribution is the business of intraday
trading that's all it is intraday is the
short-term Horizon where Banks can
manipulate and knock people out push in
orders
you know facilitate  false sentiment
ideas
so what we're looking for is these
orders to accumulate in the marketplace
we don't necessarily know how many
orders are above and below these
consolidations that we look for in the
CentralBankDealersRange in agent
range but we know based on our
DirectionalBias from the daily chart in
four hour with using the pdra Matrix and
if the data ranges where price will most
likely draw to on the HTFs
so if we know that and we're bullish we
can anticipate the next stage which is
manipulation
taking the price lower down into an area
where Traders will be induced to sell or
get knocked out of premature entries
that are already long they're going to
unseat those positions then they
distribute those positions they've
accumulated going long near the low of
the day near the high today at London
close or late NewYork
that's the model we're trading off of
that's we're looking for so if we don't
have clues or fingerprints if you will
to lend to these ideas being in price
it's not ambiguous it's not a guessing
game it's not well I wonder if it's
going to do this or what if it's going
to do that no we know exactly what we're
looking for there's Hallmark trademark
characteristics that make these London
session entries perfect and ideal and
it's based on the criteria we've given
you from the CentralBankDealersRange
and the Asian range
there are specific things that you look
for if they're not present you do not
have high probability conditions to
trade in
if they are as we were describing here
and you take the trade and you take a
supposed bullish order block or a
supposed turtle soup or something okay
and you lose money
now you know why because you don't have
IPDA in your favor where they're clearly
going to draw a price One Direction or
the other based on the criteria we've
given you in lesson five
if the conditions were selling you here
in lesson six are there
you have a great deal of odds in your
favor of losing money
so pay attention to these points because
it will keep you
at least in my opinion it's kept me from
doing a lot of trading where I was
that are off sitting
on the sidelines than there of getting
in their Marketplace if you look at
some of the conditions that we've
outlined over the course of this
mentorship some of the days are ideal
for these events right here
then other days there are
instances where they're not so prevalent
and the conditions were probably in our
favor to trade but you still can be
wrong
so again this helps you avoid the ugly
periods but you're still going to get
these once in a while moves where it
would have been better had you taken a
trade
and all this is doing is help you know
when the odds are less in your favor and
believe me if you avoid this lesson if
you discount it if you think well you
know I'm just going to look for the
signals you're going to look for the
signals in this kind of mess and you're
not going to see the results you're
hoping for and you're going to attribute
to the stuff doesn't work ICT doesn't
have an edge there's no benefit to
knowing these types of things and it's
all fluff wrong you've seen enough
instances where Precision is there the
Precision won't come into the
marketplace or be evident in price
action when these elements are present
so I know what you're probably saying
what's going on in the marketplace when
these events are happening what are the
central banks doing
ready for this
I don't know
and if I don't know or have a belief in
what they're doing
then that's certainly not a time where I
want to put money at risk and neither
should it be for you
we know what they're doing or most
likely doing
when we have these narrow consolidation
ranges between central bank dealers
range and Asian range when we have a
daily bias when we know where the draw
is on a daily chart where is the price
going to be drawn to what is it going to
be moving up to a premium or is it going
to be moving down to a discount
we knew that for a DirectionalBias
having that
applying it to our London session if we
can find the Standard normal protraction
profile or the delayed profile
in that direction of the day
we got it linked but you still can have
losses
if we see these conditions here
regardless of what we have as a daily
bias whatever we think it is doing it
doesn't matter all those things fall
second
to this criteria here because we're
specifically dealing with intraday
action
we have to have rule-based ideas we have
to have filters these are our filters
you do not trade every single trading
day
these
conditions will prevent you from taking
positions in London
and you have to accept it you got to
submit to it you have to be subordinate
to some level rules if you don't have
them you're going to over trade you're
going to trade every single day and yes
you might catch some amazing moves that
may appear when these conditions are
there and you'll be able to show me an
email I didn't do that and I still I
made 120 Pips here Michael look at this
and I'm gonna say you didn't follow the
rules you're gonna get mad you're gonna
be offended but I'm telling you up front
if it looks like this and you traded in
London you make money
I don't want to know about it because
all you're doing is just saying you did
not follow the rules
okay when is London open Killzone ideal
and we obviously we've talked about what
makes the avoidance of London session
most apt to be the best choice but what
do we do
to help formulate an ideal scenario
going to London
well the daily chart is going to be
clearly respecting PD arrays so are we
in an environment where the Market's
clearly respecting a
obvious clear
um non-ambiguous PD arrays where the
market just clearly is going to a an
order block or it's closing in a gap and
it's responding as you would
realistically expect it to when we have
those in here and find a high odds
probability trade in my favor as a day
trade I'm just going to get in here and
you know get lucky and learn that's
gambling we don't do that
so we have to have a discernible
Direction in the marketplace on the
daily chart and it has to be respecting
a PD array Matrix in that way we know
what our daily bias is is it going to be
reaching higher it's going to be
reaching lower it's just that simple
now when the market is poised to trade
higher on the daily to a premium array
we're going to be looking for London
Longs because they're going to be ideal
entry points because we know that on the
HTF daily it's respecting
The pdra Matrix and the most likely
outcome is it's going to be reaching for
a premium PD array
the range at which it is trading at
right now at market price to the next
premium PD array
that is going to be indicative of how
much we can anticipate for the next
price move higher it may not fulfill
that entirely in the day trade day that
you're trading that in other words it
won't fulfill that entire range in one
day it can take several days and that's
going to also facilitate the
um continuation of the next trading day
are you going to be trading in London as
well because he may have that ring still
to fulfill and if it's still there on
the daily chart to reach up into that
premium
you have still reins to work with and
you may end up getting another set up in
the following consecutive trading day in
London and do the very same thing he did
in the day before buying
when the market is poised to trade lower
on The Daily to a discount array London
shorts are ideal
same scenario just reversed in the
previous point if we have just recently
traded off of a
premium array
and we're going to be reaching down into
a discount array that means a bullish
order block closing a fair value got the
below market price closing a liquidity
void below market price  trade down
below an old low Market deploys to make
a low resistance liquidity run to a
discount
if we see that scenario in the daily
London shorts are ideal it doesn't mean
circumvent all the previous slides that
I just mentioned those conditions have
to be eliminated in other words they
can't be present even in this condition
here in the previous Point as well
as it relates to premium arrays
either one of these conditions can be
canceled out if we've seen the
conditions that we just shown in the
previous two slides
when the DailyRange has not recently
exceeded its five-day average daily
range
an expansion day is due to form
so in other words if you study average
DailyRange you can do several
studies like this you can look at every
single day what's the expected average
DailyRange from a five-day basis
and what is the actual five-day average
DailyRange at the close of the day
and keep a running log of that of the
pairs that you trade this is the reason
why you don't want to be trading 20
pairs because you can get really tuned
in to your payer or pairs if it's just
two by doing these types of things
because when the average DailyRange of
the last five days is factored not every
single day will the average DailyRange
be met many times it'll be
just below it or not even much more than
half the average DailyRange if we're in
a quiet period but if we have traded
several days and the previous day has
not seen or exceeded it doesn't mean it
has to go two times the average daily
range of a five-day basis but it has yet
to trade above the average DailyRange
on a five-day basis the previous day and
you're bullish you have a really good
chance of having a large range day the
day of your trade and we don't have the
commissions in the previous two slides
that will cancel out woman
if we have all those things present and
we can see the profile unfolding that we
learned in lesson five
you have the highest probability of a
big expansion day because the five-day
average DailyRange has not been traded
to or exceeded
in the previous day so we have a
condition of volatility it's low
and the average DailyRange many times
will be either one and a half or maybe
even two times the five day average
DailyRange in instances where we can
get a big range day you don't need very
many of those over the course of a month
to erase a lot of the screw-ups that
you'll make if you try to trade every
single day
you don't want to take your big winning
day and use that to remove all the
stupid trading days in order avoiding
the previous two slides conditions and
still trying to force a trade and trying
to show you know the community and
mentorship or show the internet that
you're you know you're smart or you
outdone what was necessarily  the ICT
rules you were able to find a setup
don't do that okay you're not going to
impress anyone you're not going to
impress me and it may not be important
to you but I can tell you if you stick
with these rules you're going to do
better than if you don't
but know that when we have these big
range days
we that's that's the cream
that's the that's the bonus for the
month okay when we catch these big range
days
you don't want to be trading every
single day because you're going to get
small little singles
draw down days draw down days draw down
days and then when you get a good win it
doesn't really show as a win because you
have all these small little singles
small little singles that erased by a
loss a loss a loss so you're treading
water and then all of a sudden you have
a normal trading win and it won't
register that much in terms of your
Equity growth
it will require you to use the big rain
stays to show all your profit and if you
look at a 20-day
study of every train every trading month
if you trade it every single day you're
going to see that your results are
skewed in such a way that if you're
profitable if you take out your largest
profitable day you probably aren't
making money
you don't want conditions like that in
your Equity growth okay you want to show
a smooth Equity growth line by ferreting
out the times when you don't want to be
trading because if you can take the
periods of drawdown probability out of
the equation or at least do your best to
remove it
then you stand a better chance of
trading when it's in ideal scenarios so
you really slant yourself to high
probability conditions so while you
still may suffer losses and you still
absolutely will
the larger losses will hopefully be
avoided because you're forcing yourself
in a role-based idea that way you'll
have singles singles doubles
three to one wins and then when you get
these really big huge Runners and you're
able to position yourself in London and
you let them go that will push your
Equity return for the month way over
your average you know if your average is
like eight to ten percent for the month
you catch a big average DailyRange big
move and you hold on to it for the whole
day many times that'll push you 10 15
more for the month than your normal
return
and
there's a way of standardizing your
monthly return
but you have to start with these
rule-based ideas so
as we learn more things we are we start
applying them to our live sessions we
start applying them to our
exercises and drills and
when we practice so when we have these
things we go through a specific criteria
a list of rules and eliminate certain
trading days and you'll know why we're
not trading those days versus if I say
I'm not trading today and you're you're
less scratching your head saying why is
he not trading today what makes this day
any different from the other now you're
going to know so if I say I'm not
trading today you'll know why I'm not
trading it and you won't get upset you
won't be offended you won't think I'm
trying to go to the beach the next
morning and I'm just trying to get some
sleep you'll know why there's a real
reason why and it's consistent
it's not something that takes a great
deal of you know mental acrobatics to
understand these are very simple things
to understand when you look at the price
study it go back and look at several
months of data
I don't care what pair you look at if
you see these things in the marketplace
it's highly unlikely they're going to
get a clean London session and that's
what we want we want to trade when the
market has a clear squeeze on volatility
they're holding in the consolidation and
they're letting the order stack up we
know where the Market's going to want to
go on a daily chart how many times have
you seen over the course of the last six
seven months where I'm calling the
market on the daily chart it's almost 98
accurate it's ridiculous okay so when we
apply these ideas and we fare it out all
the times when the conditions we showed
in the two previous slides are there
we're going to miss some moves and
that's fine we don't care about that but
we're leaning ourselves heavily in the
basically the salad days the easy
trading days okay and we're moving now
into a framework where I actually trade
with these types of things so I don't
trade every single day and there's gonna
be times now going forward in our
mentorship when we have these conditions
there I'll let you know in the Forum
this is not a high probability day we
will be sitting on the sidelines waiting
for new events or waiting for the New
York session
so now you have a clear reason why
I won't be taking certain participation
in in trading days and you'll know what
you're going to be learning from not
doing it and we'll see many instances
where it will protect us from taking
what would otherwise be a losing trade
in London
so hopefully you found this lesson
insightful I know it's not exciting it's
not sexy it doesn't have all kinds of
charts but it's one of those ones that
require you to think it's one of those
why
it's one of those lessons that helps you
build a Winner's mindset you have to
have
rules you have to and the best rules are
the ones that help you stay out of the
marketplace because everybody can get in
the marketplace there's no there's no
shortage on reasons to get into a trade
because everybody can come up with one
they make books about it all day long
every bookshelf in the bookstores have
some reason why you need to be a buyer
or seller based on something
but very little is written about how do
you know when to stay out of the
marketplace
that's what this lesson has given you
so here's one of the beautiful elements
to it
I don't care if you're a position Trader
at heart
a swing Trader at heart
I don't care if you're a One-Shot one
kill Trader
I don't care if you're just gonna be a
day trader or if you're going to be a
scalper like we're going to learn next
month
the criteria I just gave you here will
save your backside regardless of what
trading discipline you have
because if you're going to be executing
and trying to trade with the London
session
as your means of Entry if it looks like
these two previous slides you want to
wait just wait until a better technical
picture and when you get it you'll have
no problem taking your entry and you'll
be much more
fortified in knowing that you have the
all the odds that you could possibly
have reasonably you know in your favor
and that's where you want to live as a
Trader you want to be in the market when
it's highly favored on your side of the
marketplace you want to be on side not
offside
and the way I've learned over a long
period and these are lessons that I had
to learn painfully very painfully
because I'm stubborn I want to do things
the way I want to do things and if
someone tells me I shouldn't do this I'm
going in doing that very thing you know
what it's like the sign says on the lawn
don't step on the grass I'm doing The
Jig on it I'm dancing all over it
moonwalking on it not because I'm
ignorant I'm trying to be rude it's just
that's my nature it's human nature to do
the very things you know you're not
supposed to do so you have to have these
rule-based ideas so that's why there's
no charts in this there's no let me show
you examples of this okay it's rules
it's 100 rules and I'm going to leave it
up to you to have this created as a
checklist
I'm not going to give you a checklist
that has this stuff because I want you
to write it in your own handwriting once
you write it out subconsciously you're
going to retain that and then every day
you're going to refer to it when you
look at the marketplace and in the
previous two slides if those conditions
are there you already know probability
has fallen off the table and it's not
likely to be a easy trading session for
London
now think about that
very very empowering
it also gives you context
yet you might still be bullish on that
pair
you might be bearish on that pair
but when you don't have the conditions
in favor for technical symmetry
where you can expect and clearly
anticipate the manipulation on the
central banks when they reprice higher
and go in a perfectionary state we're
entering in that
if we don't have the framework to
clearly see when they're going to do
that
what are we doing in the marketplace
then
what everybody else does Gamble and
gamblers sometimes make money
but gamblers rarely make a living
with that wish you good luck and good
Trading