welcome back folks
just a quick little review here
the left hand chart is the s p Futures
Contract the daily chart and the right
hand is the NASDAQ daily chart
you can see here we did in fact
run outside of the imbalance we did in
fact trade up into a due to swing and
trade lower look at last night's review
and you'll hear that that's what we're
looking for we wanted to see a measure
of movement to the upside which sets up
a due to swing okay so the context is
when we're looking for daily bias
is we're looking for a weekly drawn
liquidity
the frame a buy or sell program
then individually each day we're waiting
for a power 3D
materialize in this case we've been
bearish on s p and NASDAQ that means the
open is going to be near the high and
anything above the opening price would
be viewed as a judo swing
a fake rally to entice traders to chase
that going long and then aggressively
trading lower we have sell side resting
in here
for the s p and over here on the NASDAQ
we had
similar
delivery and price we have the open the
due to swing moving higher above the
opening price and then moving lower sell
side liquidity resting below here
all right hourly chart here and Lefty
inside s p
we mentioned this uh in passing last
night we had
to buy some balance outside of
efficiency worked up into the top of
that range and broke lower I told you
exactly where this shaded area is here
we ended up revisiting that again today
so it kind of like framed the daily High
so the market teared up into that
inefficiency
broke lower
shift in Market structure
rallies back up
we have a fair value Gap in here and
then look at all the
movement beyond that but the bodies are
very close to that shaded area now this
is one of the signatures I was referring
to last night about August August tends
to be a little bit more
money in in the sense that it's not as
clean as you would expect to see
in other months of the year
there's a small little inefficiency rate
in here in the form of a fair value Gap
and or
civi so you can mark that on your chart
says I'm going to try to keep this area
clean as we work through the time frames
and then at the time of the recording
here we're looking at the next cell
cycle which is enclosed proximity to
where we are at the time of this
recording
my right hand side NASDAQ okay we traded
up into consequent encroachment on the
15th
broke lower
consequent encouragement of this city
here
order block
consequent encroachment of the bicep
balance on efficiency around the hourly
chart then we have a fair value Gap here
look at the bodies
okay this is today's price action extend
that forward
okay this is not your classic support
and resistance to the fellows that like
to show up in my comment sections and
talk about how this is nothing but
support and resistance well if it is
just support and resistance and it's
this this easy I would love for you to
do these things in advance and call it
before it happens too but something
tells me it's just it's not going to
happen but the inefficiency here plus
the Wix doing the damage trading up into
the inefficiency the bearish order block
here but the bodies telling the
narrative meaning that this imbalance
now we have a balanced price range we go
up
down up down half consequent
encroachment
we leave it
hits it like a brick wall
sells off we have a fair value Gap
consequent encroachment of this Wick and
tilt closed candles lots of indications
at that two o'clock fomc minutes
expecting that to be a wonderful
sell-off and then gravitating towards
that 14 853 and a half
that's our expectations going forward
15 minute time frame left hand side s p
you can see we did in fact straight up
into that shaded area as I mentioned
last night took you into exactly where
that occurs
and then price broke lower we have a
shift in Market structure so this
movement right here this is model 2022
okay so the mentorship model that I
taught in the year 2022 on my YouTube
channel here this is the exact model
being delivered here
in the afternoon during fomc minutes
in the market accelerates the downside
taking out the 4424 level that I
mentioned on YouTube NASDAQ on the right
hand side here's our imbalance or fair
value guide and the Monday 10 A.M
60 Minute bicep and balance outside
efficiency high and respective low
that's what these levels are here we
trade it up into that lots of Confluence
in here okay lots of Confluence and
again the market shares displacement to
the downside
shift in Market structure here
two fair value gaps just like over here
here and here you make allowance for
price to trade up into the second one
here we see it I see a curve so we have
the inefficiency here and then this one
here so during fomc minutes we trade up
into it here for a 15 minute cell sign
balance by side efficiency
consequent encroachment here for the gap
then aggressive sell-off institutional
overflow entry drill which is a move
just above this candle High there and
sells off and then again looking for
fourteen thousand eight fifty three and
a half
finally moving into a five minute chart
you can see here this is our afternoon
PM session which I was sleeping through
the Silver Bullet so we can see it trade
up into here
and aggressively move lower attacking
that 4424
and and similar vein here and you don't
see the the inefficiency so much on the
five minute once we drop down from 15 to
5 but having this higher time frame PD
arrays on your charts are very important
otherwise you'll lose yourself in the
candlesticks and it's important not to
get lost in price delivery
so we see it straight up into here
breaks lower look at the bodies forming
inside of the Monday 9 30 a.m low
and the Sunday 11 50 p.m low those two
cell cycle according poles I mentioned
this morning at the start of the trading
day
and
all of this movement here at 9 30. all
of this was a Juda swing okay so for the
guys that like to comment when I post on
Twitter when I'll say princess when an
objective is reached okay I'll put like
something to the effect like a boom or
there it is or something that affected
me to draw some kind of emotional
stimuli around it so that way it's
meaningful to you that way you'll go
into your journal or your charts and
you'll refer to that as a milestone in
your observation because you watch
something outline in advance then
deliver
so
obviously people that say those things
that say oh well it only went up you
know
so many handles before going down there
well it didn't really go up
you know a hundred handles
and higher it went up to go to levels
that I had outlined last night listen to
the outline and Analysis I gave you last
night we were looking for a move higher
first okay so if you're a student of
mine you know this is the case when
we're looking for daily bias and we're
bearish we wait for initial delivery
that's opposing
that means it's against it's not in the
same direction of where we want to see
the market go to so initially we want to
see some kind of false movement in the
opposite direction that does not scare
us that doesn't make us second guess our
analysis this means that that's exactly
what we're looking for
and there's a lot of retail traders that
thought that these markets and these
levels up here were going to go higher
and it just simply was not going to do
so because everything I shared with you
last night before the fact and then
without stealing the Thunder from the
tweets because I actually called out all
the key turning points and where we're
going to draw to throughout the morning
and then we actually get it here so
it's important for you to follow me on
Twitter if you don't follow me at least
go and check it out look at tweets and
go and pull them up and plot them on
your trading view chart okay you can
just do a copy of the individual tweets
that I send
when I'm referring to specific levels
and that way you can right click your
mouse button over top of a chart and
then click paste in the actual tweet
that I make a comment about
will be attached
to the very Candlestick at the time that
I made the tweet and then you can judge
whether or not there was any visibility
there or not but you have to take the
entire
understanding and observation and
Analysis that was given to you last
night we were looking for lower prices
we were looking for where the NASDAQ
traded to today we are looking for where
the s p traded to today
it's undeniable folks these things are
transferable you can learn how to do it
but you have to do these types of things
every single day to condition your
understanding and activate your
particular activating system where it
allows you to see these things that
you've been hunting for and you build in
importance you build an affinity towards
these things that we're annotating the
chart by journaling them and as a result
the default function of you seeing these
things in hindsight and then
anticipating them studying them with a
tape reading environment that means not
trading it in a demo that means not
trading it with a funded account
challenge not trying to trade it with
live funds just simply relaxing and
letting the understanding build over
time not be in a rush to try to make
money you can't speed that part up but
the way that becomes easier is for you
to go through this part of your growth
which is the longest part
and it's going to be longer than you
want it to be
but if you submit to it you'll get these
things you'll understand what it is that
you're expected to see in price and
everything that I'm teaching you is
linked to time
every price run is linked to a Time
delivery mechanism
nothing's random nothing's just oh look
at this unless
unless something happens on a
geopolitical or a warfront where you
know
it's something that would be completely
unexpected
and then they would not waste that
opportunity either
so if we found this one insightful and
so I'll talk to you tomorrow
be safe