okay folks welcome to lesson eight uh
one shot one kill trading model
for the short term Trading
module for ICT mentorship this is the
last of March's content
okay one shot one kill setups
what does it require to do these
efficiently and successfully
well first you have to know all the
macro conditions and all the January
content lessons
you have to be proficient with
understanding the if the data ranges
looking back at the last 20 40 and 60
trading days
looking for PD array Matrix Concepts
applied to both time and price
you need the understanding of position
trading logical Concepts
you need to understand the swing trading
module Concepts
the short-term trading tutorials on the
ICT website
the power 3 concept applied to weekly
candles or ranges
and I'll talk about that in a few
moments
the intraday Concepts from ICT day
trading modules
day of week concept
looking for the high or low to form on
Monday through Wednesday with a 76 odds
of it happening
using fibs for targeting and
understanding the correct price points
time of day or ICT kill zones for
entries on one shot one kill setups
and you need to know the seasonal change
that may impact or frame directional
setups
and lastly you need to understand the
CRT or commitment of Traders analysis
and Commercial hedging programs
now
I said when we started this mentorship
that this was intended to fill in the
gaps that I purposely left
in all my free tutorials
now if you've gone through the
mentorship so far and you've not really
studied all of my free tutorials that
are on my website
now's where you're going to feel that
sting of having never done it
it was intended and I've told you before
the prerequisite is to know those free
tutorials
everything that I'm going to show you in
this module is really just a quick fill
in the gaps and then you'll understand
how it is I do one shot one kill the
gaps that remain for this month are
filled in with the intraday Concepts
for day trading
and it just basically helps you get more
precise do you need it not necessarily
well you want it most likely
so if you've gone this far and you
really want to know all the intricate
details about how I finally narrowed
down very tight small risk high yield
setups like you've seen now lined and
mapped out this week with the euro
dollar
yeah you need the intraday Concepts to
get that precise but you don't need it
to do one shot one kill because you
don't need here's other things that uh
help you get close to but not that
precise
that's already been showed in the
content for this month and the previous
months
now as it relates to the cot analysis
and Commercial hedging programs
obviously everyone's aware of the
commitment trades report where they plot
the net Trader's position of each
commercial and small Speculator and
large Trader and Larry Williams was the
first one to do real good work on that
back in the 70s
with his book uh how I made a million
dollars during Commodities last year
but in my own study I believe I've taken
it to another level no one else does
what I do with the CO2 data
and I'm going to show you again this
module and it's teaching how it is that
I uh incorporate that information now
when we get to the commodity section
later on this year when I'm teaching the
Commodities I'll actually show you how
to go in and construct the
commercial hedgers program and how to
look for a high probability setups using
the information but I'm going to give
you one set up in here for the euro
dollar that was just like a no-brainer
so you'll see why this week was just
pretty much
no problem at all knowing that it was
going to come down like it did
all right so the one shot one killed
trade procedure okay this is kind of
like a
back of a matchbook idea just real quick
short and what I mean by that is you
should already know a majority of what
I'm going to refer to here procedurally
so this is the reason why you need to
have a mentorship this is the reason why
you have to have a modular approach to
learning because there's such a vast
amount of information that you need to
be aware of you just simply can't make a
video and here it is here's how you
trade
for those that have gone through all of
my free tutorials and this far in the
mentorship you can now think about how
much information you now have
now you probably flounder for a little
while wondering you know do I have too
much information do I have analysis
paralysis and it's simply because you
haven't had a procedural way of using
all the information
so we've gone through a lot of content
between the free tutorials since 2010
all the way to now now through
2016-2017 Circa you are now learning all
of the procedural things that fills in
the gaps and by the time you end this
mentorship you'll know everything there
is to know about ICT Concepts and how to
apply it
but the first thing we do
when we look at our market and we're
going to use euro dollar as our example
we're going to determine the current or
potential next quarterly shift remember
that we talked about that in January
we're going to identify the higher time
frame PD arrays in the ipta data ranges
again that's content from January
we're going to refer to the interest
rate differentials and Market profile of
the rates in other words our interest
rates or treasuries or the the Bund
are those markets trending
or are they stuck in a consolidation
if they're trending then you're going to
get movement permitted in the euro
dollar
if they're Consolidated and tight it's
going to be very hard for the market to
move around
we're going to be scouting seasonals
throughout the calendar year that offer
High odds of a move going higher or
lower based on the seasonal tenancy
respectively
we're going to use swing analysis on
price action on higher time frames down
to the 60 Minute chart
so in other words what we're doing is
we're classifying all the price swings
we're looking at all the fractals and we
went over how larger Trends have smaller
swings that break into smaller swings
that break into smaller swings first an
Impulse swing then an expansion swing
after the retracement so by looking at
the market in a euro dollar and breaking
that down we can come to the conclusion
of what price swings we're going to use
for projections measurements and
retracements
we're going to anticipate specific
weekly profiles that may unfold based on
our analysis if we're looking for lower
prices as we're going to justify in this
teaching we're going to be looking for
specific Market
templates if you will that allow bearish
ideas so the first thing you would look
for is the Monday high of the week
Tuesday high of the week Wednesday
reversal those types of scenarios
then by identifying those respective
templates for the week we're going to be
looking at the market maker manipulation
templates to have the respective profile
characteristics
then you determine where the premium and
discount ranges are in price action
and you're going to wait for volatility
to Signal a high odds of a large range
being created
in other words when range expansion
should ensue
small ranges we got large ranges if the
Market's in big ranges we know there's
going to be a high probability for the
market to go quiet we want to be getting
in the market as quiet so that we can
expand and get larger ranges and big
volatility
we're going to refer to cot which is
commitment of Traders in the commercials
versus the large Traders
and open interest to confirm smart money
action
we look to frame a low resistance
liquidity run with opposing PD arrays or
for bearish we're looking to sell short
at a premium PDA
and then we're going to be looking at
a discount PDA to pair it up with
we're going to use fibs converging with
opposing PD arrays and blending it with
time and price
in other words what I'm looking for is
the Fibonacci level that overlaps with
a logical discount PD array
and we'll be confirming our trade setups
with inter-market analysis
all right so we're looking at our one
shot one kill set up on a euro dollar
now this was
provided to you this week the time of
this recording the last week of March
2017. I outlined through Twitter and
tweets the
basis of expecting a high the form in
the euro dollar around the 109
08 level
that was the level I called and the
actual high was 109.09 on the Forex
ltd's platform
I projected a low of the week at 106.50
that could have rolled over into Monday
but throughout the week I gave a
1-0
6.95
low objective
and then ultimately at the very last
minute of the day on Friday's close uh
they pushed the euro dollar down
to
106.55 now our objective is 106.50 if
that's what we're looking for we add
five Pips To That
that would have been uh your objective
used in your own platform some Trump
traders in my own live feeds I got down
to
106.497 I'll leave it up to you to
determine what you know what your data
provider allowed for the low of the week
for euro dollar but uh for the Forex LTD
it didn't make it down to 106.50 but I'm
suspecting it's probably going to open
up lower on Sunday
that's coming this weekend and then
obviously uh you know that would fulfill
the whole
projected uh swing but we're gonna go
into great detail about all this amount
apart from what's already been shared in
this chart here I'm not going to rehash
what was already talked about in this
week's teachings in the videos and and
commentary because that is in my opinion
a gold mine and you need to go through
those notes as well but what framed this
whole move and how I knew that the high
could most likely be formed on Monday
and we would look for a low 106.50
we're going to go into details about
that now
okay so the first thing we're looking
for is we're expecting either uh up move
or a down move so how do we start doing
that well we go to our seasonal tenancy
okay if you're a sports fan you'd like
to go and watch a specific sports team
like the baseball season or football
season you can actually track when those
teams play and what days and the
calendar days and all that and you know
when they're going to play they have a
they have a schedule they have to keep
well the markets almost have like a
built-in generic schedule as well and
and is followed or tracked by way of
using a seasonal tendency now I shared
these seasonal Tendencies with you so
far in the mentorship and what we do is
we look for times where the market has a
real clear indication in both the long
term and short-term
basically the blue and the red lines
they have to agree with a directional
bias and when they move in the same
direction
red and blue
if they move in concert with one another
we have a really strong tendency to see
that market generally move in that same
direction
what we're going to focus on here is the
month of March as you can see it
initially starts off with a rally up
into the middle of March and then it
declines to the last week of March going
into the first week of April
so our tendency is to see the euro
dollar going lower
so we have a strong seasonal tendency
for bearish prices for euro dollar
now we're going to go over to the
commitment of Traders hedging program
now you're not going to find this on the
internet there's nothing talked about
it's not in books I swear to the Lord
Almighty there's nothing out there like
what I'm showing you here okay what I do
is I use the information from the
community Traders report and I make a
new
way of uh creating a zero-sum line so
what I do is I look at the last year
okay and I get the highest high and the
lowest low of their commercial
activity in other words I'm only
tracking commercials and I'll show you
how to create all this and make it for
yourself it's
um a complete bull in our group have
emailed me asking for this specific
indicator there is no indicator okay
what I actually do is I actually create
this with paint okay I grab the
information and then I actually by hand
create it and I know what you're
thinking well I track 39 markets Michael
there's no way I'm going to keep up with
that well that's your fault you should
be tracking 39 markets but when I focus
on the two pairs that I like which is
Euro and cable it takes literally
seconds for me to do this and it's not a
big deal but if you're going to be that
hard up about it I'm sure some of you
that are in our group
um are capable of programming something
I'm certain of it but uh once you learn
how to do that when we do go into our
commodity teaching I'll leave it up to
you uh you smart whippersnappers to
throw something together maybe for mt4
platforms it can uh you know provide us
a real quick easy way of doing it and
then you can go back to trading you know
um team number of pairs with the
information
but what I do is I look at the hedging
program that is
illustrated by looking at the last
calendar year so I rollback data for 12
months and I look at the highest high
and the lowest low in their net
positions of the commercials only I'm
not looking at the large Traders or the
small spec I don't really care what the
small specs are doing but when we track
commitment to Traders report data or cot
data
every week this uh cftc commodity
Futures Trading commission requires
traders that trade at a reportable level
to report whether they're buying or
selling and the net positions that are
held because commercial Traders are like
Banks and large institutions and
manufacturers of goods or commodities
there are groups that produce
their commercial level and there are
groups that are consuming or
um
resellers okay so there are users and
creators of the commodity on a
commercial level and based on that
there's always going to be buying and
selling on a commercial basis the net
positions
okay are the collective whole of all
their total buys and all their total
sales and what are they more net long or
net short as a basis
and what I do is I take that information
that comes by way of the cftc
and I plot this graph here by simply
using a website and the information and
just basically throwing in some lipstick
and it helps me visually see what the
commercials are doing in terms of
hedging
as you can see at the time of this week
the commercials which is tracked by this
line as it's below the zero line okay
it's going to be marked red that's going
to be bearish when it's above the zero
line
they're net long that would be bullish
okay and back below the zero line
which would be represented between 100
and K and 50k okay that that line I have
drawn in there that blue line that
represents the new zero line that would
otherwise be viewed like a regular
commitment shares report
you don't need to see that as
I'm going to teach later on but I've
shown this in uh real quick
short sessions throughout my time
teaching but I'm going to give you the
details about how to use it in great
detail about how I break it down there's
actual seasonal Tendencies to their
hedging programs that you'll actually
look at too and there's seasonal
tendencies that go along with open
interest declines as well and that's
really neat information you need to know
that to do Mega trades Mega trades are
like huge big moves that take place
every year there's like two or three of
them that really explode you want to be
focusing on markets that give you those
types of conditions but I'm digressing
so let me get back to a discussion with
the euro dollar
at the time of this week the euro dollar
was making a higher high than that of in
January
but look at the commercials they were
hedging against those rallies and they
really went that short selling
aggressively in the rally above the
January High and the December high of
2016.
so as we made a higher high in the euro
the commercials are actually selling
aggressively in that rally so what are
we seeing here a seasonal tendency
that's highly probable for lower Euro
prices
at the same time commercials are looking
to sell short or they want to exceed
prices going lower why because they're
hedging against that rally
they're selling into that rally why
would they want to do that I don't know
they're Banks they do it all the time
but logically over a period of time
looking at it you'll see that they kind
of put the brakes on a market rally by
selling aggressively into it
and that caps the market as you've seen
here this week so we had a blending of
two things commercial Short Selling
now if you look at a regular commitment
Traders report
you're not going to see that you're
going to see them net long
that's what screws everybody up even
Larry Williams because they're looking
at information because they're looking
at Price through cot data from an
archaic caveman approach now I'm not
saying it can't be used efficiently and
effectively in certain conditions like
it's traditionally taught through Larry
Williams and everybody else is used now
but if it was just that easy everybody
was making money right so why is it that
commercials aren't on the first of
everyone's list because nobody knows how
to use it
but you're learning how to do it now
because you're in the click you're in
the mentorship that teaches you
everything about smart money
so what we do is we use this graph okay
that you're going to learn about in the
commodity section of this teachings
that's later on in the months I think
it's in June
but I'll teach you how to use the
hedging program and actually look for
seasonal Tendencies for when they would
really be buying or selling
certain times of the year and also their
seasonal Tendencies of open interest but
open interest is not that important here
because we have two things Blended
together and you really only need two
things to couple for smart money you
have the seasonal tendency just in other
words there's a seasonal influence that
usually see zero dollar and I don't know
what it is I don't need to know
seasonally historically euro dollar
drops down in the second half of March
going into April okay so we're looking
for that seasonal tendency to take place
not by itself but we're looking for
technicals to support that idea well we
can see here the commercials were
heavily net selling into that rally
we've seen last week leading into
Monday's rally initially for this week
and the euro dollar and then it topped
and tanked going lower
you can see right here that new high or
high
has been met with heavy net selling by
the commercial Traders
this is smart money shorting
so now how do we go in and justify these
ideas just because we have a chart that
looks like it indicates that commercials
are selling and we look at a seasonal
tenants just because season Tendencies
are suggesting higher or lower price it
does not mean that it's going to happen
there has to be something lining up
technically to get in sync with the
markets and seasonal tendency so it's
not a seasonal tendency be all end-all
it has to happen no seasonal tendency
illustrates a probable condition or a
probable outcome for the market
Direction but without technicals
aligning with that in a market
environment that supports that idea the
seasonal tendency will get you in
trouble
so we're looking at the dollar Index
here
we're going to frame out the market
conditions from a macro standpoint and
we're going to look at the next
quarterly shift and we're going to look
at how the markets should be moving and
we're seeing here on a weekly chart for
the dollar Index we have an old
high and now this is whereas price is
trading down to it
for this uh this week we've traded down
into an old weekly High which makes this
a discount PD array
and we move down into a daily time frame
and we can actually see another
level that is a old mitigation block
and it comes in at 98.92
now if you look at that level you would
obviously suspect that it's going to go
to what we round up so it'd be 98.95 you
can go to 98.90 if you want to because
it's only like two Pips but generally
the rules are we round up to the nearest
five or zero level
and then breaking it down into a hourly
chart dollar Index we can see that this
is again
illustrating the
potential weekly range
and we're looking for price to reach up
from this discount level we saw on the
weekly chart
we're looking for premium PDF PD arrays
so we go through our Market looking at
where liquidity pools are bearish order
blocks fair value gaps mitigation blocks
Breakers old highs and old lows that act
as resistance
as you can see here we have a few noted
each one of these were draws on price
and you can see they are all traded to
with no problem with the exception of
the fair value Gap I suspect next week
maybe even on Sunday we'll probably see
a gap up on Sunday's trading that
remains to be seen but it certainly
looks like it wants to do that and if it
doesn't Gap up we'll look for it to
expand through Sunday into Monday into
that fair value Gap
okay and getting a better look at the
dollar Index this is an hourly chart
what I have here is I have the
equilibrium price point
identified so anything above the
equilibrium price point is going to be a
premium and anything below it is going
to be a discount so now what we're doing
is we added the PD array Matrix
in the form of our premium and discount
ranges so now we can see graphically
thinking like an algorithmic Trader so
we're getting in sync with the algorithm
ifta is going to pull and draw a price
up to these levels logically to allow
the bank traders to to put on trades or
manage their in-house book so looking at
what's going on in this chart we can see
clearly that the market has been drawn
back up to equilibrium so you're always
going to look for discounts at least try
to pull to equilibrium then it has to
determine if it wants to go into premium
or it could go back down deeper into a
discount
you never know that for sure but you
need to blend time and price with the
ifta data ranges looking back over the
last 20 40 and 60 days
also adding the PD array Matrix as we
have here and we have all of the PD
arrays noted that would be needed for
this idea
now we're going to look at the Euro
pound because we have to have
inter-market analysis supported as well
so we've seen the dollar Index
poised to go higher it's trading off of
weekly discount PD array and we have all
the premium
PD arrays above us noted in the previous
chart
that would be drawing price higher so if
we're looking for weak euro dollar
prices we need to see if the Euro pound
would support that idea as well and you
can see obviously the European has
tanked it went down to a very clear
logical bullish order block
on a four hour basis a series of downed
candles sets the tone for that bullish
order block so that is a discount PD
array it trades right down to it at
Friday's close but all throughout
the week we saw the Euro pound
be aggressively sold off so that's going
to be week for euro dollar and strong
for pound dollar
okay so we're looking at the euro dollar
now
and we can see here the Monday we opened
up with a gap
well actually it's Sunday we opened up
the Gap and traded higher throughout
Monday
and we traded up into the weekly bearish
order block for the euro dollar and I'll
leave you to look at your weekly bearish
order block on your own platform
but this is the only level that was
missing from this week's discussion
because I want to be able to have some
meat for this teaching but uh weekly
bearish order block was traded into on
Monday
and the question is how far into the
weekly order block would you expect it
to trade into Michael
well we're going to that in in the last
slide for this teaching but
we're going to assume that you have
studied the weekly templates that expect
specific
trading characteristics you know what
days make a specific higher low of the
week you know how the markets trade you
know relative to the respective
templates and then what manipulation do
we expect by the market makers with that
specific template well since I elected
to use the bearish idea that euro dollar
is going to go lower because the dollar
Index was bullish okay or should have
been bullish trading off of its weekly
discount PD array
couple that with we have seasonal
tendency for euro dollar to decline
we had commercials supporting lower
prices with heavy selling into the rally
we have
the condition
for lower expectation
in pricing on your dollar
that means we're going to be expecting
either Monday Tuesday or Wednesday to be
the high of the week so you always
obviously start with the first day of
the week which is going to be the Monday
okay so price opens up on Sunday gaps up
and it starts trading immediately right
up on Monday
so right away we have to assume that
Monday is going to be the high of the
week
so what we do is we go through the
procedures of potentially
picking the high of the week now we
don't try to go in here and and time
that Weekly High we don't try to do that
now you can over time do that yourself
but initially you don't you want to
teach yourself to trust these Concepts
okay because it can go up on Tuesday and
make a higher high that's why you have
to give it a little bit of leeway now
you can sell us a very small portion on
Monday
and then if Tuesday fails to make a
higher high at least you have a small
piece on the higher level
but if it does go higher on Tuesday
for Wednesday at least you're not going
to be at a full position underwater as
it makes a higher high on those later
days in the week
what we do is on the Monday
we look for price to trade up and then
have a retracement intraday so you can
see the London session
had a retracement and then an expansion
all through New York
what I did was I measured the swing
using the Fib from the high formed in
London down to the retracement low
prior to the New York session rally and
what I did was I measured That Swing
intraday and it gave me
the
109.09 level
so I do is I used one pit below that and
called it 109.08 because generally I'm
usually one pip off and in this case I
was one pip off still one pip short
because I thought I was making a
compensation for it but it actually went
right to the level of 109.09 at least on
Forex ltd's platform
so by doing that what we end up doing is
we can see
a way of projecting the weekly High
using the intraday stuff that we'll
actually teach in April and you'll be
able to combine a lot of other things
with time of day and specific uh
measurements that I use to to more or
less nail down the power three or dare I
say it weekly Judas swing so the initial
rally here we saw on Monday was a false
rally all that was was Heavy selling the
engineered price higher built in a
premium so they can sell it to the smart
or lower
intelligent crowd obviously the lower
intelligent crowd smart money sells it
to lesser informed money and that's what
we saw on Monday
so it takes us to the euro dollar we're
in the four hour chart you can see the
PD array in the discount Zone you can
see that liquidity void that we
identified here and at 106.50 level
so using the 10650 level as our Baseline
drawing up from that point and our
projected high of the week at 109.08
which is what I called that's our range
and then we can divide that in half get
an equilibrium price point and having
that we can now have a premium and
discount PD array Matrix then you start
breaking down your markets
PD array for premium and discount
we know that we have a liquidity void in
the lower end of the discount range so
that's what we're aiming for that's what
we are aiming for
we came out of a premium Market at
109.08
and as the market traded lower each one
of the respective
PD arrays gaps
liquidity pools
old highs to sell into bearish order
blocks all those things as the market
slid lower they were all contributing
factors as we mentioned throughout the
analysis this week through tweets and in
video production and on the daily chart
indexes
blending all these things together all
these things that I taught conceptually
the way you get to the results that you
saw this week is you have to use them
you have to practice with them there's
not going to be a clear cut this is how
you do it every single time there's
going to be
potential decisions that you're gonna
have to make you might think that it's
going to be the high of the week on
Monday
and you sell short and then Tuesday in
London or New York it runs up here and
blows that high out are you going to
stick with the idea and expect lower
prices still or are you going to be
whipsauled and thinking okay I was wrong
and they go long
that's going to be a demon for you to
wrestle with so you have to come to a
conclusion of what you want to do for
the week and come hell or high water
stick to that until it no longer makes
sense and that happens mid week and you
learned in the previous lesson that
there's many times a weekly reversal so
you always have a potential to mess it
up
this is what makes it difficult but it's
so easy to do how's that for an oxymoron
the point is is in this teaching we have
a way of looking at Price blending
Concepts together using experience
obviously okay but over time seeing it
studying in hindsight you can look at 10
15 20 years worth of data and get to
these outcomes okay through study and
build yourself a a library mentally with
past experiences using the information
you don't need to have every little
thing down to an hourly chart you don't
need that you can see the outcome based
on a daily chart you can see it
so
I'm going to counsel you to use this as
an example of how we can take the
information
blend it together
and then come up with the
nearest thing to Perfection you're going
to ever see in market analysis
being one pip off from the high of the
week and only five Pips off the low of
the week but in most platforms 106.50
was hit with real-time data not demo and
the high of the week was uh you know it
was called and the lower leak was called
so I'll leave it up to you to determine
whether or not this is something that
leads you to more proficiency as a
Trader or does it create new barriers
for your learning I think that if you go
through the concepts and especially when
you finish the mentorship you want to go
back through all the lessons again
listen to all that boring stuff I talked
about in January go back through all the
lessons in September October November
and December and use all that
information I helped pull all the free
tutorials together back then some of you
were complaining about that now you're
seeing the fruits of having done that
and
if you haven't watched the free
tutorials more than one time at the end
of this mentorship you want to do that
all over again okay so that way it kind
of completes your whole learning and by
then you have everything you ever need
to know you'll know procedurally what
you need to do and yes it requires a lot
of work it's going to require you to
think it's going to require you to come
to the decision and it's not going to be
black and white it's not going to be
this or that initially but when we get
to August
there's a specific procedure that you go
through from the top down okay and it
leads you to specific decision points
that tells you okay right now I think
this is what I should be doing
regardless of what discipline or Trader
you're going to be it starts from the
higher time frame position Traders
mindset as you would do with one shot
one kill and you reduce it down
and you reduce it down to swing trading
and you reduce it down to short-term
trading you need to reduce it down to
day trading so you can get that real low
risk real tight precision and if you
really want to get insane about it you
can use the scalping ideas and get
insane with 10 pip stops but it's not
necessary you don't need that but the
point is it's there it's made available
to you
so the police has been insightful to you
and it helps fill in the gaps with the
short-term trading that I taught in my
free tutorials and it gives you all the
elements to how I trade ICT one shot one
kill