okay folks welcome back this is lesson
7.2
of the january 2017 content
using limit entry techniques for
long-term traders
okay we're looking at buying with a
limit order
and much likely used for the
buy stops
the monthly end or
weekly should suggest institutional
order flow will be seeking a pd array
above daily market price
the daily should post a bearish candle
the daily chart must close the candle
with a down close and it is not valid
while the daily chart candle is treating
and or forming
and the buy limit is going to be placed
at the bearish candles close this is a
daily candle
so we're looking at the daily high
the daily low
the daily open
and the daily close we're gonna be
looking to enter a buy limit order at
the close of the daily candle that's
down close while the market is bullish
and we're expecting a higher price
move in the asset class we're trading
what you're going to be seeing is the
markets are going to be undervalued in
already primarily bullish market
condition
preferably this is going to be useful to
you when the market's already shown the
willingness to have a market structure
break it's already started to move
higher
it's already started to move higher so
therefore
prices are really underway
there's going to be opportunities when
we start talking about swing trading we
can utilize the information in that
module to help get better fills on the
long-term entries
closer to the turning points but for
this module really we're focusing on how
you don't necessarily need
the big
turning points at the top or the bottoms
you just need to meet in between
and be a long-term trader still and it
capitalizes on a lot of pips a lot of
points if you uh if you do these types
of trades it takes a long time for them
to come to fruition and long time for
them to set up but nonetheless
when we use a buy limit entry
at the close what we're doing is the
very next day or the next candle when it
opens up we're expecting price movement
to move below that down candles close
what we're actually doing is we're
buying at a deeply undervalued price
it's already going to be oversold
without requiring any indicators
but we're going to be buying at a deep
deep discount
when the market's predisposed to move
higher you're going to see in our
examples how it nails down extremely
extremely awesome entry points i mean
they're so deep in discount and you get
quick immediate feedback even on a daily
basis that you're on the right side of
the marketplace and you start seeing
profitability almost immediately
okay selling with limit orders
just like we had with the
cell stops the monthly and or weekly
should suggest institutional order flow
will be seeking pd arrays below daily
market price
the daily should post a bullish candle
and the daily chart must close the
candle with a up close
it is not valid while the daily chart
candle is trading and or forming
and the sell limit is going to be placed
at the bullish candles close
so this candle again representing our
daily candle up close this is the daily
high
the daily low
the close
and the open for that particular day
and we're gonna be looking to
have a sell limit order right there
at the candles close
and what we're doing is essentially
we're selling short in an overvalued or
overbought condition in a market that's
predisposed to go lower based on monthly
and or weekly
pd arrays that will draw price lower so
institutional flow should draw prices
lower on the daily but we're getting
this
up movement against what longer term
institutional order flows suggesting
again on monthly and or weekly chart
so while prices moving higher for this
particular day
what we're doing is we're going to be
looking to sell short
at the next day but it has to be above
this particular candles close now again
we're not just selling on a limit on any
up candle if we have an opinion about
being bearish
these conditions are best suited when we
align them with
a daily pd array in other words if
there's a bearish order block if there's
a gap that it's traded into if it's
filled in a void if it's traded above a
recent high
okay or it's retreat back into an old
historical low
support broken analysis resistance
there's like those types of ideas we're
not just indiscriminately going out and
finding up candles and dam candles i
should have mentioned this as well when
we talked about the stop orders but
you're not just simply going in based on
the candle itself by itself it's not a
be all end-all and
you know
a system
in and of itself you have to blend the
pd arrays on the daily chart as well so
by blending these things together with
the higher time frame monthly and weekly
pulling price one side or the other
bullish or bearish respective on those
higher time frame charts
when we have those conditions also
in opposite terms so basically what i'm
saying is on monthly and weekly if
you're expecting lower prices or
bearish pd arrays that should draw price
down to a discount
what you're expecting to see on the
daily is up movement to go to a short
term
premium when that occurs then you have
really really low risk high probability
entry patterns at your disposal and this
is one of the most amazing ones you're
going to see
by selling short on a limit above that
candles close what you're doing is
essentially getting that last little
piece of market movement above
getting that last little surge many
times when we look at day trades you're
going to see that that's many times what
you'll see is the judah swing it'll open
make the high in london and then sell
off and it'll be the beginning of a long
long term move
in that particular pair or asset
okay we're going to go back to that
japanese yen example and we're going to
use
this idea as well
and you can see we have
the down candle
and using the close
as our limit order to be a buyer
you see how that transpires here each
down candles close the next day it
trades down below it you would be filled
only limit going long
and look at the responsiveness of price
immediately after that there's one two
three four five examples here on this
daily time frame and while it probably
doesn't look exciting here probably
doesn't feel like you know it's that big
of a deal i can assure you when we get
into
two slides from now you'll see just how
much of an importance this is
but again what we're looking at is
the
weekly chart here you can see how price
was moving away from that 100 level
and there was a bearish order block up
around that 118 119 level
and that was the
weekly premium pd array that would draw
price up to that level long long term
and we saw a bullish order block down in
the discount level at 100 so you saw the
willingness to want to bounce off that
level we go back down into a daily chart
here you can see
in november during the post election
rally of
donald trump's election in the u.s
price stabbed one more time down into
that weekly bullish order block uh prior
to that
november
dip we saw a september
rally away from a previous order block
that was formed in august 2016
september we saw it retrade back down
into it and using the down candle the
very next day it did trade down below
the close giving an amazing fill
now what you're seeing here is these
lines that are drawn right up from the
down candle up into that red shaded area
that's that weekly pd array or bearish
order block what that means is this
price should be drawn up to that level
in weekly
and from the low that was formed in
september buying on a limit below the
daily candles close
from that point all the way up to the
weekly pd array or bearish order block
it's 1800 pips for that particular low
the next one comes in around november
17th or thereabouts
and you can see that that
limit order below the daily close would
have been filled as well and from that
point up to the weekly weekly pd array
up at
the weekly bearish order block was 980
pips
and then the next down close
on this daily chart here again using the
close of that down candle as a buy limit
order
entry point
that next candle puts you in a position
where it would have been 785 pip move
the next down candle again
comes in with a 600 pit rally and
another one comes in at 500 pips and the
last one right before it gets to the
weekly pd array
given a 360 pip
price move and again buying below the
candles close on a limit
you're buying that real deep suppressed
um undervalued market
and it's in a deep discount and it will
look to seek to move to a premium
and it's an amazing thing when you go
through your charts and you look at this
and start studying it and again
what we're looking at is daily time
frames it's not that we're looking at
you know hourly charts or 15 minute
charts
and a lot of folks assume just because
we're on these higher time frame charts
there's not a lot of opportunities
there isn't as many as you would see in
terms of day trades or scalps no i would
quickly agree with that but there are
plenty of opportunities when you're in
these long-term trends and they have a
real clear indication it wants to move
higher to a monthly or weekly level
there's many opportunities you can get
in there and get positioned and not have
to get the high and you can see here
that move from the 980 pip move it's
essentially the equilibrium price bar
just below it and even above the
equilibrium price point there was many
opportunities where you could have got
several hundred pips and whether you are
a day trader scalper or whatever i mean
those types of numbers are just simply
not something to scoff at they're very
respectable numbers
so my question to you in closing is do
you still think you need intraday
trading to make pips
hopefully after this teaching you'll
quickly come to the conclusion that you
do not need that so folks that felt that
i'm only teaching day trading and
short-term trading things
this is the type of trading that you can
find
opportunities with still maintain risk
relatively low and still find a payable
framework for your trading ideas to pan
out and this is just one pair
in one focus on a pd array on a weekly
and monthly basis and until next time i
wish you good luck and good trading