welcome back folks this is lesson 7.1
stop entry techniques for long term
traders
okay buying with stop orders
preferably you're going to be looking
for setups to have the monthly and or
weekly
suggesting institutional order flow
would be seeking a pd array above daily
market price
the daily should post a bearish candle
the daily chart must close the candle
with a down close it is not valid while
the daily chart candle is trading or
forming
and you're going to be placing a buy
stop
at the bearish candles opening
okay here's the high the candle
the low of the candle
this is the opening on the candle
and here's the close
you're going to be placing a buy stop
for an entry on long
positions
at that price right here this is where
you place your buy stop entry
the concept is you're going to be using
strength to get you long in the
marketplace now you're not going to be
just buying any old down candle you're
going to be looking at the pd arrays
that would be in a discount market
or
while you're in a long-term uptrend
every down candle
promotes new buying opportunity for
smart money
so you'll be using this entry technique
here to get in sync with those long-term
trends
again you have to have a monthly and or
weekly
institutional order flow
reference point in the form of a pd
array that means that has to be a weekly
order block that's bearish above daily
price it has to be a fair value gap
above
daily price
in the form of a weekly or monthly chart
something on the monthly and weekly
preferably both
is leading you to believe that price
will be drawn up there on that time
frame
the daily
you're gonna be actually waiting for the
move to go against that intended
direction that's why we're buying
off of a down candle
we're using the opening price on the
down candle now think about this for a
second
order block theory
this would be a bullish order block
a down candle is a bullish order block
if price trades away from a down candle
and we trade back down into that opening
of the down candle that's also what
a future entry long position so see what
we're doing here we're using this
buying of strength idea
the mechanics behind it is is that
it should price trade back up to that
opening price and through it
we should be turning the corner and
should be training higher
but
if it doesn't trade back above the
opening price you don't get a fill
you just got to wait for another new
down candle and you keep moving forward
every time you get a new successive down
candle you keep adding that new entry
at the opening price
so you you would be consistently moving
forward one new trading day every time a
new candle paints and if you don't get a
fill
on the daily these go to the next daily
candle once as long as there's another
down candle you keep doing it
you may miss moves you may not get a
fill you may get filled and eventually
get stopped out
we'll talk about stops when we talk
about trade management but for now we're
just focusing on the entry pattern an
entry concept using a daily time frame
and now think about this we're actually
dovetailing really nicely with order
block theory so
if we're buying at the opening price on
a down candle long term
expecting monthly and or weekly
pd arrays to be the draw on price in
other words something on the higher time
frame charts are going to bring price
higher the daily charts going to submit
to those higher time frame weekly
monthly ideas and they're going to trade
up into those levels okay but they won't
just go straight up they'll go up then
come back down to that same opening
price many times giving another
opportunity to buy so what you can do is
when price moves away from the opening
price and comes right back down
you are looking for confirmation you're
going to see new buying
and that may be another opportunity for
you to add new positions
but that's only in
instances where if you've taken profits
off in other words once this
by entry
has been executed in your long if you
get several hundred pips in your favor
you can take some of that position off
with the expectation that you may end up
seeing a retracement back to that same
opening price if it does you can put
that same position that you took off in
partial profits right back on at that
same opening price
and it gives you an opportunity to get
basically the average then same cost for
that long price
then you hold it for the remaining
portion of your trade and you can do
this every single time there's a new
down candle that you enter on a buy stop
at the opening price it's the same
concept as going forward every single
time until you reach that monthly end or
weekly pd array in the form of a premium
market so once it gets overbought if you
will when there's a monthly and weekly
charts then as long as that's not there
we continuously follow along with the
marketplace on a daily chart every down
candle promotes new buying opportunities
for smart money the higher we get on the
monthly and weekly range and get closer
to those premium ranges the less likely
these candles are going to promote
strong buying
so just be careful about that you will
be buying preferably at equilibrium or
less than the range that you would
identify on the monthly and weekly
charts
okay selling with stop orders
okay the monthly indoor weekly should
suggest institutional order flow will be
seeking a pd array below
daily market price
the daily should post a bullish candle
the daily chart must close the candle
with a up close and it is not valid
while the daily chart candle is trading
indoor forming
the cell stop is placed at the bullish
candles open here's your high
here's the high the candle
the low of the candle
the close of the candle
the open of the candle
and right here is we're going to place
your
cell stop for a short entry and the
premise behind this is we're gonna be
expecting weakness to take us into the
marketplace
now again think about what we just
showed you in terms of
the buy stop on a down candle at the
opening price
it's just like a return to a bullish
order block because we buy at that
opening price
this same premise here is the entry
price technique that we use to go short
at a bearish
order block which is the last up candle
rate for the down price move we're going
to sell on a stop right at that opening
price
and if we get profitability in our trade
and we looks like we can see a
retracement back to that same order
block
or same up candle in this case we could
get short again with the partial profit
we've taken off so for instance they say
we
go short on daily chart and we get short
on the stop at the opening price of this
this bullish candle
we could look for
several hundred pips in our favor in
terms of profitability take a portion of
it off bank some profits
then if we do get a retracement back to
that same opening price we can sell
short again with that same portion we
just took partial profits and
re-established that same initial
position back on again at that same
average price again the premises we're
expecting the market to be drawn
lower from a monthly and weekly
standpoint so there's a pda rate that's
going to be drawing that weekly and
monthly chart lower
okay so we're trading on the higher time
frame monthly and weekly but we're
executing on the daily so while the
monthly and weekly are poised to go
lower
institutionally speaking
we're waiting for a move that's
opposite the direction by having an up
candle or a bullish candle we're seeing
the market have a short-term retracement
or creating a short-term overbought
scenario when we see the opening price
on that up candle
traded to many times you're going to see
that it never turns back from that that
low
it just keeps on going and that opening
price becomes a very good trigger for
short selling or
a sell program
okay let's take a look at this
few examples here we have a
nice move up here we have a small little
down candle
and you'd be placing a buy stop at the
opening price
so buy stop at that opening price on
that daily candle
and we're going to say that we didn't
get a fill here so it'd be a missed
opportunity
we have a new down candle
place a buy stop
on the opening price of the down candle
you see the next candle we open lower
than that
down candles
open
so in other words the very next green
candle or bullish candle it opened lower
than our down candle or bearish candles
opening price so our buy stop would have
been triggered as that
bullish candle trades up so we would be
triggered long in that position
but now we have another down candle so
we could take a look at that opening
price
and should we see price trade back up to
that level we could be entered long
again
on a buy stop
same thing happens here
market trades up through it and gives us
a nice little pop
and here we have
that successive
one two three candles lower all being
down candles each time
we have the opportunity to be net long
the one in the middle
the
other three down candles
you may have been tripped in long on
that
particular entry point
but your stop-loss as you'll learn will
be below the swing low that's most
recently been created on the daily chart
and below a specific reference point
which will outline
in lesson eight
but you could be long here
and you can also then use
this opening price as well to add to it
so you have a buy stop on the opening
price of this down candle
you see price does fill that and you
would be net long from that price and we
have another down candle
we could watch this buy stop and trigger
in a long entry at this opening price
price does eventually make a lower
candle and then that lower candles
opening price does get tripped two
candles to the right of it
and eventually sees another little move
higher
and we're going to take a look at now
using this idea for selling on a
stop
and here's the section of
the japanese yen looking at old high
from 2007 you can see how price made a
piercing of that 123.50 level
and price rejected had a break in market
structure and had a sell-off we're going
to break that whole area down in the
shaded area
you see there's a market structure break
here
that's the initial one but there's a
secondary one but we're going to
focus on this one primarily
we're going to assume that you can see
that this market on a daily time frame
was getting in sync with the lower
objectives for
the monthly and weekly
dollar yen
and in pd arrays they would be looking
for lower prices
would draw price on the daily chart
lower and i mapped out every one of the
up candles that went back to the premium
of the ranges that price was trading in
for the daily chart and every opening
price once it's triggered
you would be net short
so there's one two three four five
examples in here where each one of the
up candles just a short time after its
formation of the up candle
it trips you
short
for the japanese yen
and you can see another example here
where the price trades back up to a
mitigation block
and the up candle you would look to sell
short at the opening price
and you see that down arrow indicating
that was the candle that you'd be using
the very next candle you would be short
and that's that same level right there
just shown in a more higher time frame
view of it several hundred pips again
and this last one here over a thousand
pips available in terms of downside
potential and again this is using
the monthly weekly pd arrays as your
directional bias and then using the
up candles and down candles
in relationship to using the stop entry
in this case we're using uh the selling
on the stop
at the opening of a up candle
and the opportunity is and many times if
you look at these candles here you can
see how they return back to the same
candles you shorted from on a stop
they become bearish order blocks at a
later time too so you can actually
put more position in
and you can build in larger positions if
you start with a small amount allocated
to the initial position you can build in
another position in other words if you
go with a half position or half
of your traditional size you can go and
add more back in but have already
profited on portions that otherwise may
not have been viewed as an opportunity
so until we talk next time i wish you
good luck and good trading