welcome back folks this is lesson three
short-term Trading
just lessons going to be teaching Market
maker manipulation templates
okay in lesson two we went over the
weekly profiles
how the market generally unfolds not
every single subtle Nuance of price
action is covered obviously
but the majority of the time you're
going to find that one of these market
profiles will
basically classify the price action
you've seen it'll classically Define the
weekly profile if you go through each
one of these templates
it'll give you basically the idea of how
the market manipulation has taken place
along with the market profile for that
week so we're going to be blending the
two ideas on why the market does what it
does in these individual weekly profiles
and applying it to a template idea so
you can almost forecast what the market
makers are going to be doing in advance
based on the conditions currently in the
market that you're Trading
before we get in to the details of it
all
every example here much like in lesson
two
all of the charts or diagrams are
represented in and depicted as a 60
Minute chart
so the perspective I'm trying to show
you is if you were to go through your
charts and open them up in a 60 Minute
or one hour chart basis
Monday through Friday this is generally
the theme of which you see the market
trade in
okay the first one we're going to cover
is classic Tuesday low of the week now
there's going to be a few
instances where we go through a few
scenarios each template and there's a
few that only have one or two ideas
around it but for the classic Tuesday
low of the week
what you've been looking for is a market
that is primarily bullish
and the market trades down on Tuesday
into a discount now this is going to be
in the form of either old monthly weekly
or daily low
to run a liquidity pool in other words
it's running out cell stops
Thursday end or going into Friday but
generally you want to look for the high
the form for the week by Thursday's New
York session
I can carry over into Friday a little
bit but in the general rule of thumb
just look for Thursday as the lines
portion of the weekly range and you're
looking for it to trade up into a
premium Market PD array now the key is
you're looking for a time frame lesser
than the discount liquidity pool that
you used to buy off of
for an example if you bought a monthly
liquidity pool
you're gonna be looking for a weekly or
daily premium PD array to trade up into
another scenario for the market maker
template for a classic Tuesday low of
the week again the market condition is
you're bullish
the discount Market you see the market
trade down to an old monthly weekly or
daily high that means the market has
already broken out above a historical
high or an old high and the market has
now come back and retested that area as
support
you'll be looking for this Market to
trade up into a premium PD array and or
a fib extension combination of 127 or
168 extensions for or a 100 percent
symmetrical price link or what I
classify as a perfect Market structure
swing
you're gonna be looking for it to trade
up to this premium Market PD array
and overlapping FIB in a time frame
lesser than the discount old High
so in other words if you're treating
at a weekly high as support
in the form of a discount Market you're
buying down there
as a support idea
if it's the weekly high that you bought
you're going to be looking for a daily
or four hour PD array and an extension
of either 127 or 168. or preferably a
perfect symmetrical price swing of 100
percent
another scenario for the classic Tuesday
low of the week
we'd be looking for the market to trade
down into a discount Market
and trading into a bullish order block
this could be either a monthly a weekly
and or daily
or any combination of an overlap of
those three time frames
it can also be a four hour
just for the sake of space I didn't have
that in here but you could be trading
that to a four hour bullish order block
and or this can occur as a market has
already been trading higher and you've
determined the overall price move may be
much significantly and higher than what
you see graphically depicted here in
this diagram in other words it could be
a multi-week scenario where the market
could trade higher for more than one
week so if that's the case you could be
seeing the trade trade down into support
or below shoulder block on Tuesday where
you'll see the first swing grade or it
could be happening in at the equilibrium
price point
where price could be expanding up and
seeing equal measured move higher or it
could be a third swing grade now
generally third swing grades are the
halfway point between the equilibrium
and the ultimate objective in your price
objective or the for the trade
generally you don't see a stop run
in the third swing grade right before
the determinants of the price move
you're looking to trade entirely as a
profit
go back to the lessons where we talked
about grading the swings and you'll see
what I'm referring to that third area
or midpoint between equilibrium and your
target generally you don't see a stop
run there but you do get a little
shorter box sometimes that you can trade
off of them this is that type of
scenario we can use this template
regardless of what time frame you use
you'll be looking for it to trade up
into your premium Market PD array and or
if extension overlapping of 127 or 168
or a perfect symmetrical price swing
or basically a 100 duplication or
measured move of the price swing and
traded down into the Tuesday low
and you'll be looking forward to trade
up into a time frame lesser than that of
what you use for the bullish order block
so again if we used a weekly
quarter block we're gonna be looking for
a daily or four hour premium PD array to
take our profits at something lining up
with price above us in the premium
Market but in a time frame lesser than
that which we traded our entry on
fair value or a liquidity void also
could be an instance where this trade
could materialize
okay the classic Tuesday high of the
week okay the first scenario you're
going to look at is a market trading up
into a premium Market
could be trading up to an old monthly
weekly or daily high in the form of
running a liquidity pool in other words
buy stops above and on high
and we'll be looking to frame the trade
with a time frame lesser than that which
we used for the premium liquidity pool
and we're gonna be trading down into a
discount Market PD array what you'll be
framing is
for instance an example would be if you
sold short at a daily High being ran out
for a liquidity run on buy stops you
could see a four hour
discount PD array
to trade down into as your objective so
that would be your weekly range Being
Framed another example would be if
you're looking for a weekly High to run
out buy stops you'd be looking for a
daily or four hour discount Market PD
array again you're looking for a time
frame lesser than that which you use to
trade with since we're using monthly
weekly and daily as a framework it gives
us a great deal of probability that the
moves are going to take place secondly
we're using a lesser time frame to take
our targets because if we don't want to
hold for what would many times take
greater than a week to unfold for a move
moving off of a monthly or weekly level
okay our second scenario for the classic
Tuesday high of the week would be the
market trading up into a premium market
and trading up to an old monthly weekly
or daily low that means the Market's
already broken down
out of a measure of Market structure or
maybe took an old low now it's retesting
that as support broken down resistance
and we'd be looking for a discount
Market PD array and or FIB extension of
127 and 168.
and or a perfect symmetrical price swing
and a time frame lesser than that which
we used for the premium old low so
they'll write it for an example we would
be looking for the market in a bearish
context we're looking for lower prices
overall The Market opens on Monday
trades up into Tuesday creating the high
of the week but it's retesting a old
monthly weekly or daily low to that
daily low whatever it is we're going to
be using that as our means of framing
our entry with the expectation that
we're going to be selling short looking
for a discount Market PD array any time
frame lesser than that which we used to
get short off of so if we're trading a
weekly low
as resistance we could also employ a
lower time frame bearish order block or
something that effect to get in sync
with it but for instance if we're using
the weekly low
we would be looking to trade down to a
discount daily or discount four hour
Market PD array and an overlapping FIB
extension
converging at the 127 or 168 or a
perfect symmetrical price swing now I'm
going to show you examples of what I
mean how you anchor the FIB in here in
several examples but just remember the
move up initially in the beginning of
the week that's your price Suite is
going to be using your fibon you're
going to run your projections off of
that and I'll show you what the fulcrum
points are for each one of these
foreign
value or
void that fills in is all that's
necessary before the Tuesday highs form
back up to that old monthly weekly or
daily low
okay our next scenario would be again a
fair value or liquidity void
and the market moving up into a premium
bearish order block either a monthly
weekly or daily
and or it could be a first swing grade
or at equilibrium or it could be a third
swing grade entry in other words if
we're seeing a larger longer term price
move going lower if we graded our swings
we could be looking for this scenario to
take place at the first grade swing
equilibrium
or the third swing grade
discount Market PD array
or FIB extension 127 168 or perfect
symmetrical price swing measured move
in a time frame lesser than the bearish
order block we use to trade off of now
I'll give you an example on this one
the market makers will see the for
instance we could Gap open lower
on Sunday and then all through Monday we
could trade up through higher and then
up into Tuesday London open arm New York
open we could create the high of the
week we would be in a premium Market
relative to the weekly range that's just
started we would potentially fill in a
fair value Gap or a liquidity void
trading back up to for instance a
daily bear shoulder block so if it gets
to a daily bearish order block we could
be using a four hour discount Market PD
array that overlaps with a 127 or 168 or
perfect symmetrical price swing in our
fib
we're using a time frame lesser than our
bearish order block entry in other words
it was a daily in this example I gave
you we'd be looking for a four hour
discount PD rating to take our profits
but it has to overlap with a projection
on that fair value or liquidity void
swing that's going up into Tuesday
that's your swing so you would measure
your Fib from that low up to the high
that's one on Tuesday and your
projections down in the form of 127 or
168. if they overlap and converge with a
four hour discount PD array then you
have your target for the week and you
can Define what their weekly range would
be and you hold for the opportunity to
unfold until Thursday and maybe into
Friday
okay now we look at the Wednesday low of
the week okay this is a market profile
that's bullish
okay we'll generally see the market show
a short-term low on Monday and trading
up into Tuesday and then Tuesday we'll
see it trade lower
down into a discount market now it could
be trading down into an old monthly
weekly or daily low for a liquidity pool
in other words running out sell stops
and we're looking for the market to
trade up into a premium Market PD array
in a time frame lesser than the discount
liquidity pool that we use to train off
of for a long you'll see this if you're
familiar with my old teachings many
times this is the framework I use for a
reflection pattern and trust me I'll go
through all these patterns in August
when we fill in a lot of the gaps on
things that are just subtle nuances and
little extra tips I throw in that don't
really have a place always that I can
clearly Define it where this always does
this or does that there's going to be
some quirky things I teach you in August
so that's one of those things I'm also
going to apply but the uh
the reflection pattern is basically a
127 or 168 extension where it runs at an
old low but it's going to trade down to
a discount Market PD array
if it takes out the cell stops below the
lows we're going to be looking for the
market to trade up into Thursday or
Friday preferably Friday into a premium
Market PD array if we're going to see
this occur on a weekly we're going to be
looking for the long on the weekly
and exiting our position on a daily or
four hour premium Market PD array
okay our next example for the Wednesday
low of the week we can frame our Market
with a discount Market old monthly
weekly or daily high in other words
we've seen the market trade up broken
out now it's coming back down Monday we
started to trade up a little bit then
Tuesday it traded lower
down to the old High
so it could be a monthly high that
retains back down into on Wednesday
and we're going to be framing that with
an expectation of seeing the market
rally up into Friday
with a premium Market PD array and or
FIB extension 127 168 or perfect
symmetrical price swing in a time frame
lesser than that of which we use for the
old high long so for instance if we
bought a old monthly High retest after
it's broken out we can see the monthly
High acting as support so our electric
time frame PD array or premium Target
would be seen either in a weekly daily
or four hour
the key is finding where it overlaps
with the 127 and 168. we're not just
simply looking for 127 and 168
extensions we're doing that also and
coupling it with in all these examples
with a lesser time frame PD array that's
contrary to what we use to enter the
trade
okay our third example for the Wednesday
low of the week we can see the market
trade down into Wednesday into a
discount Market
when the markets generally primarily
bullish anyway and we're going to trade
into a bullish order block and it could
be in the form of a monthly or weekly or
daily or it could be a first swing grade
entry in other words if we see the
market moving higher much longer term
than just one week and we're seeing our
first retracement back where we can get
our lawn
take a swing trade or a position trade
on that
it could occur at that first swing grade
or it could occur at the equilibrium of
the overall price move or halfway point
of what you expect to see as an overall
price Target or could occur at the third
swing rate in other words one half
between where you're halfway point
equilibrium is for the trade
and the ultimate Target now when we look
at Price swings or targets And Trades we
graduated into four stages first stage
second stage takes us to equilibrium
third stage or third swing grade and
then the fourth is Terminus where the
end of the trade takes effect and that's
where your profits are taken that's the
maximum we expect to see the market move
this occurs sometimes at the first
equilibrium and third swing grade as a
potential opportunity so the market
could be just floating around between a
premium and discount Market on Sunday
and Monday and Tuesday but then
Wednesday it trades down into a discount
level where it clearly hits a order
block and now can be capitalized and
send price higher up in through Thursday
into Friday
whichever you use in other words the
time frame you use to go long on
whatever that order block is whatever
time frame it is that you use for
instance could be a daily we're going to
be looking for a premium Market PD array
with an overlapping FIB of 127 168 or
symmetrical price swing
in a lesser time frame in other words if
we've seen it on a daily that we bought
a bullish order block on on Wednesday
we're looking for the four hour
premium pdra that overlaps with a 127
168 or a perfect symmetrical price swing
the fair value or liquidity void
that run down that price swing is what
you use your fibs on to run your
extensions for 127 168 or perfect 100
percent
duplication of that price swing down
just projected from the high
okay Wednesday high of the week this is
when you're looking for a bearish market
environment
okay and you have a short-term High here
the market will trade up into a premium
Market
up into an old monthly weekly or daily
High liquidity pool in other words it's
running out an old High
and we're framing the idea with a move
down into a discount Market PD array in
a time frame lesser than that which we
used for a premium liquidity pool for
instance if we are expecting bearish
prices and this can occur in an
equilibrium area on a larger price move
that you expect maybe from a position
Trader's mindset or a swing Traders
mindset in other words if you're looking
for a move that's much longer than just
uh just one week
we could be the Midway point of that and
you'll see a short-term High being ran
out this is a classic stop run and this
is generally what you see on a Wednesday
and if you see it on since for instance
like a weekly
liquidity pool if he runs out a weekly
High
it takes out those buy stops we could
expect to see a daily or four hour
discount PD array be our objective
for the week
another example for Wednesday high of
the week okay we have a fair value or
liquidity void and then it runs through
that for the stops
if we see that and we're overall bearish
disc again we're gonna be looking for
this as a scenario where
it's a retest to an old load okay this
could be a return back to a premium
Market in front of an old monthly weekly
or daily low
and we're looking for a discount Market
PD array and or a fib extension of 127
to 168 and or a perfect symmetrical
price swing and the time frame lesser
than that which we use for a premium or
blow retest
so in other words if we're looking for a
retest back to a monthly low
if we get short on that monthly low
narrowing down our time frames down to a
smaller time frame which we'll learn in
April and in May
with a shorter time frames but when we
use the hourly chart
we can fine tune that to a smaller
degree of risk
but we're framing our trade-off of the
monthly load that's being retested
traded button to Wednesday we'll be
looking for that opportunity
to send us lower if it's monthly that
we're looking at that low on Wednesday
to sell short from we're gonna be
looking for a weekly daily or four hour
discount PD array that has an extension
overlap of 127 to 168 or perfect
symmetrical price swing from that low up
to Wednesday's high in other words
Tuesday's low to Wednesdays high that
price swing up that's what you're going
to be anchoring your FIB on and the
extensions below Tuesday's low would be
a projection of 127 168 or a perfect
symmetrical price swing or that of
Tuesday's low the Wednesday's High
that range subtracted from Tuesday's low
that would be a perfect symmetrical
price swing if you get that overlapping
with a in this case if we're looking at
a monthly low uh we could be looking
from a weekly daily or four hour
discount PD array that overlaps with
that so again we're blending time and
price
in the last example for Wednesday high
of the week we're looking for a fair
value or liquidity void
price going up into a premium into a
bearish order block on a monthly weekly
or daily basis or it could be returned
back into our first retracement of an
overall larger price swing and this will
be the first swing grade entry or it can
occur at equilibrium or it could be a
third swing grade entry
discount Market PD array or FIB
extension preferably both overlapping a
127 or 168 or perfect symmetrical price
swing in a time frame lesser than that
of the bearish order block that we used
to trade entry on
consolidation Thursday reversal okay
this is a market profile that's
generally bullish
you'll see this happen where the Market
opens up on a Sunday and Monday trades
sideways on Monday and Tuesday into
Wednesday and then all of a sudden
Market trades down on Thursday into a
discount Market
you've been looking for many times
Traders expecting the market to shoot
higher because of buy stocks being taken
out or will be deemed as a market
structure shift bullishly
but we're looking for sell stuff in a
bullish Market to be ran out
so when that happens generally it's
going to be like an fomc or an
employment release the fomc release
generally happens around the two o'clock
hour in Eastern Standard Time New York
time or it could be a New York session
employment data released that can send
the market higher based on this false
break below
an old low early in the week on Monday
or Tuesday
this false break becomes a turtle suit
long and you're looking for the market
to trade up into where the weekly buy
stops are this is your liquidity pool
and it's going to trade up into that
level as your weekly objective
so your one shot one kill setup would be
buying the break below
the weekly low on Monday or Tuesday
running out to sell stops on the heels
of either a high impact news event
with employment data on the New York
session around 8 30 in the morning
Eastern Standard time or if you're again
if you just want to play the fomc
announcement once the market drives down
takes those sell stops out if you can
take a very very very very low risk
entry and small position don't put a lot
of money on this type of trade because
if it's fomc you can get really crushed
if it's a lot of whips on it but if
you're going to be trading fomc very
very small position wait for the initial
knee-jerk reaction put your limit order
down below the low let's follow Monday
and Tuesday
absorb all those sell stops and look for
the buy stops to be ran out for the
intraday
high or running out the entry week high
in the form of the buy stops liquidity
pool
so your one shot one kill would be
framed only Thursday going into Friday
so it's really one day's worth of action
that you waited for all week but the
scenario looks like this generally
consolidation service a reversal this is
when you're looking for bearish markets
on Thursday the market trades up into a
premium Market earlier in the week it'll
look like it's taking out sell stuff or
Market structure shift has broken to the
downside and then Wednesday into
Thursday you'll see the buy stuff taken
they were formed intra week
usually fomc 2 pm Eastern stand time or
a 8 30 a.m Eastern Standard Time
employment release could be the driver
for this or the Market's driven up to
above the intra-week high to take out
the buy stops in an overall bearish
Market environment in the market
causes a false break this is a turtle
soup short
and you'll be looking for the targeting
of the cell stops below the intra-week
low for your liquidity pool
okay and consolidation midweek rally
this is a bullish Market profile and
what we generally look for is the market
to start off on a Monday right right
from the beginning
and on Tuesday you'll see retracement
down into Wednesday
and you're going to be moving back into
a discount fair value Gap or liquidity
void or bullish order block
so any one of those scenarios could be
your Catalyst but you're looking for a
discount PD array
and you're expecting on Wednesday a high
or medium impact news event either in
London or in New York session
your swing projection or fulcrum point
is the intra week high formed on Tuesday
now this could also be a Monday High
ticket in other words it can trade up to
creating a short-term high on Monday and
then trading down Tuesday and into
Wednesday but that's one simple caveat
to this this template and it's a reverse
for when you're looking for a
consolidation midweek decline
what you're aiming for a premium PD
array either in the form of a monthly
weekly or daily and converging FIB
extensions of 127 and or 168.
or could be a perfect measure
swing projection now what does that mean
the swing projection fulcrum is the
highest high at which the market starts
to retrace from that's the point which
you want to pull your FIB down from into
where it trades into the order block
that'll give your swing projections up
into the premium PD arrays let's take a
look at that what that looks like an
example
so we have our high here this is going
to be our swing point for outcome and
then we're going to take our FIB anchor
from the high down into the oral block
or whatever PDA rate that we're using
for a discount to enter that's our level
we expect price to move up from so
there's our range
what we get then is an extension of 127
and or
168 FIB extension which takes us up into
the premium Market what we look for not
just a fib of 127 or 168 we're looking
for a time frame lesser than that which
we used to get long on
either a bullish order block or bear
shorter block whatever that time frame
we see forming
our entry on on Wednesday
we use a lesser time frame to take our
profits at
but it has to be an overlapping of a
premium PD array and a lesser time frame
you use to buy at
that overlaps with 127 and 168.
now the FIB overlap levels are based on
the time frame we enter on
we look for a lower time frame
COPD array in a premium range to overlap
with that 127 and 168 when we get those
two things we have a high Confluence
level where we have both time and price
and a green where the algo may very
easily retrain for those levels and then
that'd be it for the Target
okay consolidation midweek decline this
is a bearish market environment
okay what we're seeing is on Wednesday
you'll see uh it could it could occur on
Tuesday too but we're looking for a
premium
fair value Gap or liquidity void to be
filled in or trading up into a bearish
order block
and high or medium impact news
in Wednesday London open or New York
open
and we have a swing projection fulcrum
point
and we expect to see the market trade
down to a discount PD array in the form
of a monthly weekly daily and converging
fit extensions in the form of 127 or 168
and again it could be a perfect
symmetrical price swing or 100 measured
move
so let's take a look at what that looks
like as well in Reverse terms of what we
just showed for the buy side
okay we have our premium fair value Gap
or liquidity void and or bearish order
block but normally we're looking to sell
short at a premium PD array in a bearish
market environment
we know our low the week is formed we've
measure that up
from our fulcrum point
and we get our 127 extension from that
low
to Wednesday's High
projected down that's 127 percent of the
range between Tuesdays low and
Wednesdays High
and then we get the 168 percent of the
range of Tuesday's load when it stays
high now you don't need a Fibonacci
overlay tool for this all you have to do
is get Wednesday's highest high and
Tuesday's lowest low
and or it could be Wednesday's low okay
but basically you're looking for the
lowest low between Mondays
opening and Wednesday when it trades up
it's got to be trading up so whatever
the highest high is that forms your
projected low is whatever the range low
is for the week up to Wednesday's High
that range in terms of Pips times that
by 1.27 and that will give you
your range that you subtract from
Wednesday's High
and you can do the same thing for the
range from below the week up to
Wednesday's High
whatever that is in terms of Pips each
times up by 1.68 and you subtract that
number of Pips from Wednesday's high and
that'll give you your Fibonacci
extension whoa
okay so you can destroy bullish Friday
okay this is a low probability or
neutral condition all we're really doing
is watching to see if it gives us any
favorable outcome and it's more or less
a market environment you want to be
either on the sidelines or just
demonstrating just for experience
okay the market will generally create a
small consolidation throughout the week
going into Thursday we have a liquidity
pool for cell stops it's forms in intra
week
higher medium impact news on Thursday
usually it's tight like I said it's
either fomc or employment
decision
and we're going to be anticipating the
sell stop raid below the lows of the
week
intra week buy stocks would be
determined
and a liquidity run to a daily or weekly
premium PD array would be the result in
other words we're not going to be
looking just for a intro week run on buy
stops we're going to be looking for a
run completely above all of the entry
week highs to a liquidity run on daily
or weekly
premium PD arrays
so in other words we're going to be
creating a new weekly Range High in a
level that hadn't been traded for so far
for that week and it's going to move it
aggressively and very speedily to that
level now this Market environment can
occur when the Market's bullish but it
also can occur when the Market's bearish
if the market trades Down Below in Old
low or breaks out on a higher time frame
but sales that have any movement lower
we can get a Thursday high impact on
medium impact news event or interest
rate environment that sends us
aggressively higher in this environment
or this Market profile
this is one of the hardest ones to trade
and if you see the market just
consolidating back and forth taken by
stops and sell stocks you know
throughout the week it's probably better
for you to sit on your hands and just
don't trade it anymore because the
chances are you getting this right are
not 50 50. you know and if you're wrong
it can really blow through whatever your
stop loss is if especially if it's fomc
or if it's you know um
well it would just have to be something
along with the monetary policy once it
gets up to a daily or weekly premium PD
array what we're looking for there is we
want to see possibly a potential
reversal
so what we're doing is why is this
template useful that's your answer
you're waiting for it to get up to a
daily or weekly premium PD array once it
does that we are expecting a reversal
okay so you can destroy bearish Friday
again this is a neutral low probability
profile and Market manipulation template
what we're looking for is the outcome of
this we're not looking to trade it
so we're looking for the market to
create a consolidation Monday through
Wednesday and then building a liquidity
pool of buy stops intra week and on
Thursday
we anticipate that market to be taken up
to that level taking out the buy stops
and a run on high end or medium impact
news usually is the Catalyst for that
we're anticipating the buy stop breed
and the market will run the intra-week
cell stops and ultimately Target a
liquidity run to a daily end or weekly
discount PD array
again we're not looking to trade this
we're looking for it to unfold usually
when the markets are in consolidation
Monday Tuesday and Wednesday and it's
usually like a employment number or it's
a fomc type event that type of Market
driver that's released later on in the
week the second half of the week uh post
Wednesday in New York open
we're looking for the market to run to a
higher time frame PD array okay and if
we see they run to buy stops intra week
and they sync it lower what we're going
to be watching for not that we're trying
to trade it we're looking for it to
trade down into a higher time frame
daily or weekly discount PD array when
that happens what we're looking for is a
potential reversal
okay uh Wednesday weekly reversal now
this is not the same as the Wednesday
low of the week uh templates that we're
given into towards the front of the um
this presentation this is a little bit
slight slightly different
we're looking for an old low or retail
support
and high or medium impact news drives
price down below that
and it is generally on a hard time frame
basis that we see these types of moves
taking place in other words we're
running a weekly monthly level or
support level out and it's on the heels
of higher medium impact news and then
once it dries down below that the Market
discounts that news and reverses what
we're looking for is a Fibonacci
extension of 127 or 168 or even a
perfect symmetrical price Wing but
generally it's usually a 127 or 168
extension from the old low
retail support rally up into Tuesday's
High project that down that'll give us
some measure of extension
the market usually will find its way
down into a monthly weekly or daily
discount array and we'll be using the
swing projection fulcrum point to
project up to a 127 or 168 extension and
overlapping of a weekly or daily premium
PD array
and lastly the Wednesday weekly reversal
when the market is bearish
okay we're looking for old high or
retail resistance higher medium impact
news runs it above it and then the
market rejects or discounts that news
event and it takes us up into a
Fibonacci one extent 127 or 168
extension and a monthly weekly or daily
premium array in order to looking for
something up there to align with that
127 168 extension
and then the market will look to move
below the swing projection fulcrum Point
down into a weekly or daily discount PD
array overlapping with a Fibonacci
extension of 127 or 168. now what I gave
you is basically the The Playbook that I
use when I go about trying to find my
one shot one kills
the weekly range you'll find it
generally will be one of these templates
okay and while it probably looks like a
whole lot okay it's a handful of them
but you're already going to know if
you're going to be bullish or bearish
based on a higher time frame information
that we talked in January
so if you're looking for information to
lead to bullish or bearish ideas if we
have that limited to okay we want to be
a bullish we go to our profiles that are
bullish and we start looking for
telltale signs of characteristics that
are given to you in these uh slides and
it was taught in the second least lesson
of this month by blending that and also
looking for the manipulation factor that
takes place how the market makers
manipulate price Within These market
profiles you're going to see that it's
pretty much almost like the script now
the key is is once you identify it the
moves that transpire on Tuesday and
Wednesday you may not get the actual
highest high to Short from or the lowest
low to buy from and that's not important
once we have the range defined and we
see the characteristics that outline a
potential Direction going into Friday's
close that in itself can be your
One-Shot one kill so you can look for
opportunities on the back end of the
week not necessarily having demanding
and treat on Tuesday or Wednesday
because I teach Tuesday and Wednesday
generally will give you the higher low
of the week if it's a bullish or bearish
prospective Market that's not necessary
one shot one kill is you're looking for
one setup to pay you your weekly
objective my objective is usually 50 to
75 Pips a week so if I'm looking for
something that's going to frame that
that type of move I'm generally going to
be using these manipulation templates to
frame the idea whether I'm bullish or
bearish and I'm looking for
characteristics to line up if they don't
line up with what's been described in
lesson two and in this lesson here in
lesson three if those characteristics
aren't obvious or in alignment then I'm
generally going to sit on my hands in
either day trade or scalp or do nothing
but for one shot one kill setups this is
kind of like my playbook and what I go
to so while it's going to take some
study on your part to go through and
convince yourself that these are the
templates of how the market actually
operates uh just pick a pair just pick
any individual pair go through a period
of I don't know three to four months
using an hourly chart and go back and
see what each weekly profile looked like
and how the manipulation took place that
made that Weekly range form as it did
and you'll see that many times you're
going to see that this is this is the
profile and template they use to
manipulate price and you also see how
it's easy to get to those profit
objectives that you don't otherwise
think of by using the Lesser time frame
that we used for our entry
so until next lesson I wish good luck
and good Trading