welcome to lesson five folks short-term
trading this teaching is going to be
specifically talking about low
resistance liquidity runs and
consolidations
okay we have to preface it by a reminder
of every setup that we look
to execute on
and to stalk into the track if you will
is based on time and price
and the time element is going to be
related to the upto data ranges
last 60 days
40 and 20.
and we're going to be focusing on
premium and discount PD arrays
so for short-term Trading
we will excel in the range of the last
three months so the up to data range of
60 days
is our look back period
and it's going to comprise every element
that we need to frame a short-term trade
or one shot one kill
now as a reminder
when we deal with time and price you
price moves from a premium to a discount
array or from a discount array to a
premium array
in between these two Realms of premium
and discount
price will key off of a time element
related to the if the data range so
we're blending both time and price
an element of the last 20 40 and 60 days
to a institutional reference point in
the realm of the PD array Matrix
okay for our study and case study
examples we're going to be looking at
the cable or British pound USD
and this is a daily chart
and what we do is we Define a market
whether that it's it's trending or it's
in consolidation and obviously anyone
with the average intelligence in terms
of market analysis they can tell looking
at the British pound we have been in a
consolidation Mark it's not been in a
trending Mark it's been in consolidation
so whenever we see a market that's range
bound or it's cannot move outside of the
current trading range that you're
looking at
at any given time on a daily chart
you're looking at a frame of about three
months again you'll come back three
months or 60 trading days which is the
relative if the data range that we use
for maximum
definition of look back
so when we have this framework in terms
of the last 60 days what we do is we
have to define the range in terms of a
high and a low
now what we do is we Define the range in
the form of its highest and lowest
Candlestick body
we're not concerned about the Wix so
much but we're primarily looking at the
bodies of the candles
so I have here the lowest and the
highest
in terms of the candlesticks bodies and
you can see those reference points here
but the arrows
and that's going to be our range that
we're going to be framing all of our
analysis Concepts as it relates to one
shot one kill
okay so what we'll have to do is we have
to look at the market
in this range and we can use a tool
that's on every platform it's the
Fibonacci
so we're going to use our FIB tool to
determine the 50 of the range and we're
going to note that range
midpoint
so I'm dragging the Fib from the highest
body candle
to the lowest body candle in other words
I'm not using the lowest Wick low in the
highest Wick High I'm looking for the
highest body on the candles either it's
an open or closed I don't care which one
it is but whatever highest form of high
open or close that's the one I'm looking
for in the last 60 trading days and I'm
looking for the lowest open or close in
the last 60 trading days
that gives me my defined range in terms
of consolidation
then I note the 50 level and I draw a
horizontal line on my daily chart
next we have to determine the 50 levels
of the upper and lower ranges
anything above the 50 level that's going
to be our
area which we look for cell scenarios
either by taking profit on Longs or
short positions and anything in the
lower portion we're looking for Longs or
covering short positions
now the upper portion of the range
from the highest body close or open to
the midpoint that we Define by the total
consolidation range
we measure that with the FIB as well and
I gave you two examples of where you
could draw the anchor points with your
FIB with the arrows
and you note the 50 level on your fib
and you drop a horizontal line there
by noting this we've now noted the upper
range
for the total consolidation range
next
we do the same thing by noting the 50
level of the lower range between the
midpoint of the total consolidation
range to the lowest body close or open
noting it's 50 level as well on the FIB
and I drop a horizontal line on that
now what we have here is by defining our
consolidation range in this manner it
gives us a form of
premium and discount identification
anything above the midpoint or mean 50
level or in this case the gray
that would be deemed as a premium range
and anything below it would be deemed as
a discount range
next we identify the PD arrays in each
new range now I'm going to save this a
lot of time and just apply everything
from a monthly
a weekly and daily
okay so now you can see all of the if
the data ranges and from a form of a
premium and discount have been applied
to the chart
now I want you to look at this for a
moment before we go to the next slide so
pause the video here and really study
what's been identified
so every premium and discount array
provides setups in the overall PD array
Matrix
so what we're looking for is a element
of time and price to blend
a setup for a buy or a cell
we understand that the highest
probability trades for shorts is by
looking for any PD array
in the premium range of this
consolidation so anything above the
midpoint of the 50 level
or the gray level here that's going to
be ideal cell scenarios if it is coupled
with a PD array
for a premium Market
we are blending both time and price
we would look for that move to be
correlated to a later discount PD array
when price moves that down to either the
50 level of the total consolidation
or any level below the midpoint or 50
level of the consolidation
an example would be the fair value Gap
and bearish Order block
in the premium level
around the
February time period of 2017.
and pairing that with a weekly bullish
order blocking threshold
in a discount
in March of 2017.
now when we look at their quadrants like
this where it's been broken up into a
premium and discount
we can also further Define those
quadrants
into their own respective or unique
premium and discount trading range
and what do I mean by that well let's
take a closer look
as you can see here the lower quadrant
can be divided into
equal halves as well and that in itself
can be viewed from a premium and
discount
format
when we see these elements here anything
that forms as a discount PD array in a
discount range from this view or
perspective this is going to be high
probability short covering objectives or
it's going to be high probability new
long positions and any first profit
would be best taken on a loan once it
enters the premium
range of this uh PD array Matrix
again moving up the same thing can be
applied to the new quadrants that's
shown here
ideal Longs are entered at the discount
level
or in that discount range
and taking first profit would have to be
best applied by taking your uh first
long exit in the premium
range of this PD array Matrix
now what you're looking at is a daily
chart so in the form of a four hour or
one hour you'll see that there's going
to be
premium PD arrays in those lower four
hour and one hour time frames that you
could pair up first objectives for
targets I'm giving you the elements to
look at through the scope of a daily
chart
and I'm finally we can apply it to this
area as well each
path is further divided into new halves
but we're looking at it in the form of
an algorithmic way of defining premium
and discount
so when markets are creating discounts
like this again this discount range it's
shown here they're high probability
Longs and again a four hour or one hour
premium PD array as defined here you
can't see them in the daily but you
would drop down into a lower time frame
four hour and one hour to take first
profit on your Longs that you used to
get entries on by buying in the discount
area
now we're above the midpoint of the
total consolidation range
so now even though we're above it and
technically in a overall premium Market
we can still take Longs but it has to be
defined in the scope as we're showing
here we have the overall consolidation
we divide it in half then we divide
those halves into halves as well so we
have quadrants then those quadrants are
divided in half as well as we're showing
here in incremental increases moving
further up the overall consolidation
range
by buying in the discount range and
again taking first profit in a lower
four hour one hour premium range coupled
with a PD array that's premium based in
other words if we were buying for
instance the bullish order block mean
threshold here and a discount now
overall we're in a
premium Market but this is still
a possible long entry because we're in a
lower portion of that total
larger premium range so we still have
room to reach for higher premium PD
arrays and obviously we have rings that
reach for much higher objectives so
looking at it like this framing it what
would otherwise be deemed as overbought
we don't view it like that this is why
indicators do not work from a
algorithmic perspective looking at price
ranges like this it gives us a greater
definition on how we can frame entries
and classify them as
oversold or undervalued entries for
Longs or overvalued or overbought
entries for shorts
in this case we could take a example of
the daily bullish order block mean
threshold
we could be buying there and then once
price trades up into the premium
range we could look for a four hour or
one hour
premium PDA rate the couple and exit
with
and moving further up the consolidation
range we have a new
discount and premium
PD array Matrix and we could Define this
as well and what we're doing is we're
coupling the range as defined by premium
and discount with actual PD array
in the form of fair value gaps
Bears order blocks weekly rejection
blocks all those things to the left of
our chart we're looking back that 20 40
and 60 trading days for the ipta data
range so we're blending both time and
price
in the in the form of premium and
discount so we're blending
the elements of time and price we're
looking at the market in the scope of
overbought oversold but not in the
context of an indicator
we're looking at it algorithmically in
the scope of quadrants
that are broken down into premium and
discount
and by itself it doesn't mean anything
but when price trades down to a PD array
whether it be a discount
or a premium
if we trade into that element whether it
be a bullish order block a breaker any
of those things from the pdra Matrix
that we've taught you
if you're looking for a long
the highest probable entries for Longs
again are entering in the discount range
and coupling it with a premium range PD
array
it doesn't matter that we're in a
premium range of the overall
consolidation because price can move
back and forth and oscillate from the
highest portion and many times make a
slightly higher high and return back
inside of the range
and it can go to the lowest low move
outside the range a little bit and come
right back in the middle range as well
so we're anticipating the isolation
effect of price while it's in
consolidation but in that consolidation
there's smaller consolidations so we're
able to look at price in the view of
overbought never sold without the
element of indicators or relying on
mathematically derived number crunching
lines
what we're looking for is range defined
in the overall context of the
consolidation as we've had here
we're in a the upper half of the portion
of the larger consolidation and by
itself that would many times filter out
buy signals from anyone else that would
look for over about a result but for us
we can frame this with the oversold
condition
even in the element of a premium Market
it's a discount Market in a overall
premium Market that still has room to go
up that's basically in other words a
Layman's way of approaching a definition
but whatever we do in terms of Entry or
exits we're looking for elements to
frame the discount PD arrays that means
bullish order blocks Breakers fair value
gaps below us in price trading below an
old low to take out cell stops we're
using those ideas to frame long
positions and then taking first profits
at a four hour one hour basis once it
enters the premium
PD array Matrix range
and finally at the top of the larger
consolidation we can see that there is
still an opportunity where one could be
a buyer but the opportunities fall off
precipitously in terms of probabilities
and you can see now that the premium
array
area in other words for PD array Matrix
bare shorter blocks old highs
bearish Breakers bearish mitigation
blocks all those ideas they're going to
be much more influential in terms of
price action and you'll see much more
Dynamic price action from that side of
the spectrum and you can see that in the
form of the weekly rejection block
prices traded from in March of 2017 we
saw also a move away from the fair value
Gap and bearish Order block again and
it's
largely hinged on the fact that we are
in an upper portion of the overall
consolidation and we made it up into
that last smallest portion of the
premium
Market or premium PD array Matrix
the Shaded area that says premium that's
the highest portion or last little
segment of price in this consolidation
so anytime price reaches up into that
it's going to have a much more
impactful response in price when it
trades to a bearish PD array or a
premium PD array so we see that
happening with the weekly rejection
block it also took out an old high
formed in February so there's many
instances there where you can see why
price had a strong rejection also King
off of that last midpoint that's
dividing the premium and discount levels
noted here we had a really significant
sell-off and it trades all the way back
down into a daily bullish order block
mean threshold
then we had a 100 pip move that we
called for in our day-to-day meetings
and charts and you see the response it
trades right back up to what the daily
bearish order block and it also overlaps
with the premium 50 level
so there's a lot of things that you need
to be able to look at conceptually and
you have to do it on your own time I
could give you a plethora of examples
over and over and over again but this is
one teaching that I've given you enough
that if you break your charts down and
do your own study yes this is the part
that requires your work this takes study
time it takes you uh wanting to be in
the charts looking for it because I'm
not going to be there when we separate
you're going to have to do these things
on your own you have to find these these
opportunities on your own but by having
this element what we're doing is we're
looking for low resistance liquidity
runs from one PD array to another from a
discount to a premium but we're coupling
it with looking back over the last three
months because one shot one kill uses
and excels inside the last three months
of trading
so when we look back at the last 20 the
last 40 in the last 60 trading days it
gives us framework to say okay where is
the premium PD array Matrix
leading me to in terms of what I can
sell to
and what I can reach for for Longs the
couple my exits with or where are my
discount pdra Matrix and where are those
levels I can cover my shorts at and I'm
going to look back over the last 20 40
and 60 days to pair those things up
I'm also now applying ranges in terms of
the
PD array Matrix whether it be a premium
or discount market so it allows me to
build context of what I'm looking for as
an entry and how I can look for my first
objective in targeting
now in an Ideal World the best buys are
going to be in the lower portion or
lower half of the overall consolidation
and in the lower quadrant in other words
the discount Matrix
and the highest probability trades for
selling short or taking long exits are
going to be in the premium range divided
by
the upper portion so in other words that
last quadrant that's going to be your
best cells the highest probability cells
or highest probability uh exits for
lungs
that's going to be your best scenario
that's where the algorithm is going to
reach for
for selling or exiting on longs
and any long position in here again you
have to take it with a grain of salt you
have to know the overall range you're in
because just because you see a train to
a down candle you have to have I
understand that it has a room to go up
and in this case you can see what the
daily bullish order block mean threshold
that 100 pip rally
was a response off of yes a PDA rate
discount
bull shoulder block but it trades up to
a daily bearish order block but it
trades up into that bearish order block
once it gets into the premium range that
also gives us a high probability Target
now yes it's one shot one kill scenario
and we're trying to trade the weekly
range but one shot one kill is not
defined by getting in on a Monday and
getting out on Friday one shot one kill
is a couple days of trading it's
short-term trading it can be as little
as one day and as long as a week
and finally when we look at the range in
the middle this can be
the areas of where you're going to get
chopped up the most because if you're
looking at a range incorrectly if you've
already defined the range and you're
looking at PDA rate
of premium and discount that have
already been traded to in order to look
at a down candle in a discount Market
normally
that may be a bullish order block but if
it's already been traded to the
likelihood of it being a bullish order
block with high probability falls off
because it's already been used we want
to use a
new PD array in a discount or premium
Market
that has not been traded to because the
algorithm knows price has been there
once before so it's going to seek new
liquidity and expand to allow the banks
to take participation in a move higher
or lower
so looking at the Rings like this as we
defined it if you're trading in the
middle of the range like this and you're
not strong in your directional bias or
where the market May reach for next in
other words understanding where open
float is where is the buy stops and the
sell stops if you're not really strong
with that if you're trading in this
range here you're going to get chopped
up a lot
over time you'll learn how to better
approach these specific premium discount
ranges but when you look at the outer
rim when we are just showing the
previous slide
the higher you can get up and the
overall consolidation in a premium
Market the better your short positions
are going to be and the easier it's
going to be to reach for a profitable
discount PD array
the lower you are in the total
consolidation
the better your discount long entries
are going to be and it's easier for you
to get to a profitable premium PD array
blending the two
time and price working in a Range
environment like this
gives you context and you can find very
easy low resistance liquidity runs
between one PD array to another
and understanding the element of time
and price