[Music]
hey Dexter huh some kid told me you have
a laboratory a laboratory Dexter your
lab it is the one thing he does not have
and it will still make you the smartest
one of all go ahead show him your lab
come and be amazed that the world of
Dexter's Laboratory hello welcome to the
Monster Lab here Dexter
today we are going to dipping into the
standard deviations lose power of three
language is Spanish I wish I called
sight a lot but I will be very direct
and clear if you don't understand most
things you are probably new this content
it's not for newbies or newcomers
everything was learning from ICT but
with my own research
all start with an opening a power of
three this can be any power of three
monthly power of three
weekly power of three daily power of
three four all power of 3 any power of
3.
the first element for power of 3 is the
accumulation or consolidation
the second phase the power of 3 is the
manipulation
and the third phase of power of 3 is
distribution or expansion
okay all
face
accumulation manipulation and
distribution in one single candle one
single candle it's
alt okay
must think
the that expansion is only measured with
manipulation but we can also measure
manipulation with accumulation
once the expansion is finished
we can also measure the retracement or
reversal
we are looking for synchronization
to know if price is in accumulation
phase or manipulation first phase or
distribution phase
identify
where
price delivery it's in the present
moment when it's finished and when it's
start the next phase of the power of 3.
we start with the opening
on
we identify the accumulation range
inside the accumulation range we will
look for the most discernible range
highest swing High and the most recent
swing low that was broken the dog will
or two and a half deviations will be the
projection for the manipulation
phase okay in right now the monthly or
the candle the power of three
it's
in bearish right but your anticipate
that this mob price is the manipulation
and look for one reversals in the two or
two and a half deviations for the next
phase of delivery yeah the distribution
or expansion
once the manipulation is finished in the
two or two and half deviations
we will look for the lower swing low and
the swing High most recent
is it will it is the last move in
direction of money manipulation phase
okay this high and this low
um project
upside for the distribution or expansion
phase for this power of three
that will be the range project
for distribution or expansion
the double or two and a half two or two
and a half deviations for the
projections for expansions
there are some rules to look for
a standard deviations if price close
above the two and a half deviations with
body candle
um but we'll have that for another video
once price
complete the expansion
in two or two and half deviations
we anticipate retracements or reversals
to the
equilibrium range
of the current dealing range that is low
and is high
anticipate retracements to equilibrium
range to know if it's a retracement or a
reversals depends on the high time frame
premise
if price has unfinished business he will
continue in the same direction
once have finished his retracement
if price no help unfinished business a
reversals is very likely
we look for the highest swing High and
the most recent broke swing low to
project the retracement or reversals
this low
and this high
same Dynamics we will look for two or
two and a half deviations for these
projections the retracements or
reversals let's look an example in every
Z
with the monthly power of three
here
we have the opening of the monthly power
of three we can visualize the
accumulation
manipulation expansion
retracements if we see it it's very
ambiguous to know where one's the genes
and another ends circumulations or
consolidation manipulation expansion
retracement or reversals very very
ambiguous
I show you how deep the rabbit hole goes
let's dig deeper
inside the accumulation phase
this is the opening the monthly power of
three
accumulation phase we look for the most
discernible range to project the
manipulation
and you look this high
on this low this will be below the
opening the projection for manipulation
it's below of the opening power of three
it is important to identify the
direction of the institutional order
flow and identify which standard
deviations match with high time frame PD
arrays of the same time frame of the
power of three under development
if you work with the monthly power of
three you can search or identify monthly
deviations for the accumulation range
projection
anticipate
then finish for the manipulation move we
can see the last movement of
manipulation
in downside
identify this single o and swing High
must discernible for projecting the
distribution or expansion phase look
this high and this low I will project
for the expansion or distribution phase
to the 2R or two and a half divisions
once the start of the distribution phase
we can't find specific areas where price
will have recumulation or
pre-distribution
to continue
towards its or two or two and half
divisions
these areas will be found in divisions
one and one and half one and one and
half this area also it's the Silver
Bullet Zone it's very very powerful
you have a power of three in development
and in this point price is an expansion
phase
you know you you already have the
accumulation
manipulation and when price is an
expansion phase is more easy look for
a specific areas there is distribution
or re-accumulation I look for internal
liquidity in this area it's
um any internal liquidity verbalog apps
by side
imbalance cell site imbalance
any internal liquidity inside this Zone
the Silver Bullet Zone and look for
moods there
and if if price had unfinished business
in utsai I will look for both deviations
or five deviations if price have one
pdra or imbalance in this area in this
case we Excel the power deviations even
five deviations this is because price
looking for monthly
pdra monthly order Block in this area
in this point you can see the
multi-cernibular range for retracements
or reversals
this high and three this swing low it's
four
the predictions for the retracement or
reversals
face between High swing low
the same Dynamics we will look for in
each phase of delivery you can look for
one and one and a half deviations for
the Silver Bullet Zone you can use two
and two and a half for
anticipate one when
the face of delivery is finished and
when the next phase of delivery is start
here we can see the three phase of the
power of three being measured with
Precision the piece if together like a
fossil the conclusion we don't not only
mature the manipulation phase as
everyone thinks we can measure the
accumulation range manipulation range
retracements range it all depends on
which phase of delivery its price in the
present moment
your your own back testing with
different power of three in different
time frames I only warned you and you
will not learn your City Market in the
same way
Alex