welcome back to lesson two of short-term
trading March 2017 ICT mentorship
content
this lesson is defining the weekly range
profiles
okay before we get into this let me
preface it by saying this is one of the
lessons that if you just look through it
quickly and not paying much attention to
it it's going to look rather uh
ambiguous it's going to seem unfruitful
but its impact is shown and solidified
really by you going through price data
and seeing these profiles unfold in
hindsight seeing how they operate how
they unfold and the conditions that I'm
giving you how they are always generally
precursors to them performing
so the classic Tuesday low of the week
okay this is a market profile that is
generally bullish so you're already
looking for bullish prices anyway
and what you're looking for is
manipulation in the form of price
hovering above a higher time frame
discount array on Monday then drops into
a higher time frame discount array on
Tuesday to form the low of the week
how to anticipate this you have to know
the higher time frame discount arrays
and when the market fails to drop into
that array odds are Tuesday we'll likely
see the drive lower Tuesday London open
and or
New York session
okay the next one is the classic Tuesday
high of the week
this Market profile for the week is
generally bearish you're already
expecting lower prices
and the manipulation You're Expecting is
when price is hovering below a higher
time frame premium array Monday then
Rises into a higher time frame premium
array on Tuesday to form the high of the
week
and you anticipate this forming by
knowing the higher time frame premium
arrays and when the market fails to rise
into that array odds are Tuesday we'll
likely see the drive higher Tuesday's
London open and or New York session
just like the classic Tuesday low of the
week well the classic high of the week
there can be another run higher to make
a higher high in the week for this
profile than the highest formed in the
London session Tuesday so in other words
they can come back and run the London
High out and still form this for the
classic Tuesday low of the week it can
come back and make a lower low in the
New York sessions there's one caveat
that has to be applied to both of them
so have that in your notes
okay the next one is the Wednesday low
of week
this is when you're generally bullish on
the marketplace already
and the manipulation you're looking for
is when price is hovering above a higher
time frame discount array Monday and
Tuesday then drops into the higher time
frame discount array on Wednesday to
form the low of the week
you anticipate this by knowing the
higher time frame discount arrays and
when the market fails to drop into that
array odds are Wednesday will likely see
the drive lower Wednesday's London open
and or New York session
Monday and Tuesday can also be down days
as well to form this profile Wednesday
London session low can be ran out on the
Wednesday New York session and then it
can create the low of the week so be be
aware that that can possibly happen as
well
okay the next one is the Wednesday high
of week
this profile is generally bearish you're
already looking for lower prices
and the manipulation You're Expecting is
when price is hovering below a higher
time frame premium array Monday and
Tuesday then Rises into that higher time
frame premium array on Wednesday to form
the high of the week
you anticipate this by knowing the
higher time frame premium arrays and
when the market fails to rise into that
array odds are Wednesday we'll likely
see the drive higher Wednesdays long and
open and or New York session Monday and
Tuesday can be up days as well to form
this profile
just like we mentioned for Wednesday low
of week the London open high on
Wednesday can be ran out on Wednesday's
New York session and still create the
high of the week so have that in your
notes
okay the next one we have is
consolidation Thursday reversal
this is a generally bullish Market
condition
so what you're looking for in
manipulation is we're going to be
looking for consolidation Monday through
Wednesday
then price runs the entry week low and
rejects it forming a market reversal
the key is it's consolidating it's not
only going higher or lower Monday
through Wednesday
okay to anticipate this as you have to
know the higher time frame discount to
raise and when the market fails to drop
into that array odds are Thursday we'll
likely see the drive lower Thursday on a
market driver news and or rate release
late New York session this is typically
around the two o'clock Eastern Standard
Time
or 2 p.m New York time
okay consolidation Thursday reversal for
a bearish market profile
the manipulation you're looking for is
consolidation Monday through Wednesday
then it runs to enter week high and
rejects it forming a market reversal
you anticipate this by knowing the
higher time frame premium arrays and
when the market fails to rise into that
array odds are Thursday we'll likely see
a drive higher Thursday on a market
driver news or rate release late New
York session around 2 p.m New York time
now just like we saw for the bullish
consolidation Thursday reversal
this is generally on rate announcements
fomc or interest rate uh adjustments
okay consolidation midweek rally
this is a bullish Market profile already
expecting higher prices when you're
looking for this
the manipulation You're Expecting is the
consolidation Monday through Wednesday
then runs the inch week high and then
expands higher into Friday
how to anticipate when the market is
bullish and has yet to run to the
premium array on the higher time frames
it has recently rallied from a discount
array and simply paused without any
bearish reversal price action
indicating price is about to expand
higher for the premium array
consolidation midweek decline
this is a bearish market profile
You're Expecting bearish prices and the
manipulation you're looking for is when
price is consolidating Monday through
Wednesday then runs to enter week low
and expands lower into Friday
you anticipate this profile forming when
the market is bearish and has yet to run
the discount array on the higher time
frames and it has recently declined from
a premium array and simply paused
without any bullish
reversal price action indicating price
is about to expand lower for the
discount array
Seek and Destroy bullish Friday
this is a neutral or low probability
Market profile
the telltale signs the manipulation is
taking part in this profile is where
price is consolidating Monday through
Thursday running shallow stops under and
above the entry week highs and lows then
runs the intra-week high and expands
higher into Friday
how to anticipate it
when the market is awaiting interest
rate announcements and or non-farm
payroll can create this profile in the
summer months of July and August it's
better to avoid trading these conditions
altogether
Seek and Destroy bearish Friday
the profile again is neutral low
probability
manipulation is seen by Price
consolidating Monday through Thursday
running shallow stops under and above
the entry week highs and lows then runs
the intra-week low expands lower into
Friday
how to anticipate it when the market is
awaiting interest rate announcements or
non-farm payroll can create this profile
in the summer months of July and August
it's better again to avoid these
conditions
Wednesday weekly reversal
this Market profile is bullish you're
already expecting higher prices
you're looking for is where prices
consolidating Monday through Tuesday and
drives lower into a higher time frame
discount array to induce sell stops than
strongly reverses
how to anticipate this when the market
is trading at a long-term or
intermediate term low price will pair
institutional buying with pending sell
site liquidity or traditionally known as
a sell stop rate
Wednesday weekly reversal
profile bearish
you aren't expecting lower prices
the manipulation You're Expecting is
when price is consolidating Monday
through Tuesday and it drives higher
into a higher time frame premium array
to induce buy stops then strongly
reverses
how to anticipate this when the market
is trading at a long term or enemy a
term high price will pay our
institutional selling with pending buy
side liquidity or as otherwise known a
buy stop read now it may seem rather
simplistic to go through this
squiggly line and a few comments but the
impact is going to be really appreciated
in your understanding when you go
through price action with a one hour
chart
go through any pair
any segment of time go back as far as
you want okay and I want you to break
down price and Define these
Moves In what you're seeing in price and
then look at the characteristics of what
is going on prior to these market
profiles forming
and you're going to see a recurring
theme that generally the characteristics
that we have outlined here are
precursors to these Market model
profiles
so hopefully this has been insightful to
you we will be giving you more insights
about this when we start looking at the
market maker templates and we'll be
referring back to these as well we use
PD arrays and
if the data ranges
until next lesson wish you good luck in
good Trading