okay folks welcome back this is lesson
three of the April 2017 ICT mentorship
content this month we're teaching ICT
day trading model
and this teaching is specifically
teaching CentralBankDealersRange
foreign
okay for CentralBankDealersRange I'm
going to assume
you've already went through my YouTube
tutorial dealing with the essential Bank
dealers range
but
if you haven't gone through it this
one's going to pretty much teach you
everything you should have gleaned from
that lesson anyway but
we're going to assume for a moment that
you have an understanding of
StandardDeviation
now first we have to have a
range or a
number or a level in terms of a central
focal point and then it has to deviate
above it or below it to give us our
Deviation
well essential Bank dealers range is a
specific time of the day we're going to
teach in this lesson but for now I want
you to think about ranges in terms of a
predefined higher low
foreign
box here represents the Central Bank
dealer's range and I'll get into the
specifics and show you what it looks
like in the chart but for now we have to
know
conceptually if there's a range that we
have deemed a specific important range
in price
once we determine that
that range height from high to low based
on two different types of parameters
which we'll go over
that measurement of price range in terms
of Pips can be reproduced or replicated
if you will in the form of a Standard
Deviation
one StandardDeviation above and below
would be the same range
added to
the high the Central Bank dealer's range
and one StandardDeviation is the same
range that makes the Central Bank
dealer's range and total range in terms
of Pips and we subtract that range
from the Central Bank dealer's range low
and that would give us one Standard
Deviation above it and one Standard
Deviation below it
that range would be added to the high of
the first StandardDeviation
and subtract it from the low of the
first StandardDeviation below
giving us the second StandardDeviation
and this would go one
replicating that Central Bank dealer's
range with StandardDeviation one two
three and four
typically most Sell days will create the
HOD
from the CentralBankDealersRange up
to
three StandardDeviation
most buy days will create the low of the
day from the CentralBankDealersRange
down to the third StandardDeviation
ideally sell dates create the high of a
day no more than two StandardDeviation
above the CentralBankDealersRange
many times just one StandardDeviation
ideal BuyDays
will create the LOD no less
than two StandardDeviation below the
central thing deals range and ideally
many times you'll see it just go one
StandardDeviation below the Central
Bank dealer's range creating the low of
the day
four StandardDeviation above for a
high today is going to be on the heels
of a very high impact news event for the
session in London
same thing is said on BuyDays if it
trades down to four StandardDeviation
usually it's going to be very high
impactful news or price can come down or
go up to the fourth StandardDeviation
to create a NewYork session Market
reversal profile
okay dealing specifics with the Central
Bank dealers range
the time period that frames the Central
Bank dealers range is
2 PM to 8 PM NewYork time
the ideal range is less than 40 Pips
preferably the range should be no more
than 20 to 30 Pips in total range highly
low
so what are we saying here
between 2 PM
and 8 PM NewYork time regardless of
where you live globally you need to find
where your price charts indicate what
would be seen as the candle that starts
the 2PM
and 8 PM times in NewYork time
so for completeness sake and the sake of
avoiding all confusion
like everything else I always teach find
out what NewYork time is
where you're at geographically
and then find out what that looks like
in your platform for your charts and
delineate that with a vertical line
with 2 PM NewYork
and 8 PM NewYork
between those two time windows
the highest high and the lowest low
ideally should be less than 40 Pips
preferably 20 to 30 Pips total
range is larger than 30 Pips
can tend to be unfruitful for
projections
foreign
the range in Pips
by calibration from high to low or using
the wicks
or alternatively we can use the range in
the highest body and the lowest body as
well whatever the highest closing or
open price is
and we have the lowest close or open is
in between 8 PM and 2 PM NewYork time
now obviously we need to know
DirectionalBias for this to be any of
any assistance to us so it has to be
used in conjunction
for our projections to work the Central
Bank dealer's range strength is aiding
in the LOD or HOD
selection
that's the most important thing as a day
trader we can focus on if we can look
for the highest probable high or low of
the data form
or in terms of when markets are bullish
we're looking for the low of the data
form predominantly in the London session
so where is that low most likely going
to occur and is it going to be on a day
that's highly favorable for that event
to unfold remember I said many times
over the last seven years teaching Forex
online that I don't trade every single
day and even in this mentorship you've
seen that it's not productive to try to
trade every single trading day
but there are times we're going to learn
that there are highest probabilities for
a condition to be met for that higher
load of form in London when we have
these conditions
we can go in with reasonable expectation
that we have a good chance more than
most days that the high or low
will form in London and we can get a
ballpark idea where that lower high
should form
using the CentralBankDealersRange so
the CentralBankDealersRange
main focus is to help you
find the high or LOD
in respective bullish repair stays in
other words if we're bullish on the
market
as a whole or if we're looking for one
shot one kill for the week that's
predominantly expected to go up for the
for a Friday close higher than where it
opened up on Sunday
for instance if we're looking for one
shot one kill in a bullish week we're
going to be looking primarily for low of
the day in London each day Tuesday
Wednesday and Thursday preferably those
days but it could occur on Monday as
well
but we're looking for the LOD
to form in London in that criteria but
just because we're looking for the low
of the form and be a bullish close every
single day doesn't mean this highest
probability setup and we can use the
CentralBankDealersRange to help frame
that context
as we'll teach in this lesson here
but we're using Wix in this example here
so every one of these blue boxes
represents the Central Bank dealers
range for that respective day
now this chart represents the Central
Bank dealer's range with using the
bodies now I will have to admit to you I
like to use the bodies predominantly
because the Wicks are always going to
show erroneous price because of your
dealing spread through your broker
everyone's going to have a disparity
between their high and their low on
every candle it's never going to agree
so what I use is the bulk of the trading
which is the body that in my opinion and
there's no real Tennessee of y'all
end-all answer for this but my
studies over the last two decades is
if we focus primarily on the bodies of
the candles we're going to get more
closer to what smart money is doing in
relative terms than if we use just the
Wix now we can get a lot of feedback in
terms of what retail is doing if we
study Wix but if we study the bodies of
the candles and we frame our ranges with
that we'll get more clear pictures about
what the institutional accumulation
distribution ranges are going to be when
we use the CentralBankDealersRange
so as you can see here each one of these
ranges has its respective ranges in
terms of Pips the first is 13 Pips the
next is 58 Pips
the Nexus 19 and the last in this
example is 16 Pips in range
so using the bodies we're going to focus
primarily on that now
before I go into greater detail I want
you to think about
just because I like using the bodies and
I think it's got the most Advantage we
still have to look at the ranges with
the Wicks included okay so let's take a
closer look at each example here
for this first one we have replicated
that
CentralBankDealersRange the little
blue shaded area and we duplicate that
range and projected up one Standard
Deviation that was that's what the one
SD stands for so one StandardDeviation
and
second StandardDeviation which is just
basically CentralBankDealersRange
total pip range or in that case 13 Pips
we added 13 Pips more and then added 13
Pips Morse for a total Standard
Deviation of two
notice how it takes your rate to
the HOD formed in London
that particular session immediately
after the CentralBankDealersRange
closes so in other words at 8 PM
starting the Asian range
project that
range that we created for Central Bank
dealers range two StandardDeviation up
that gives us the projected London high
now it does not mean it's going to call
it to the PIP it might go a little bit
above it it might fall a little short of
it but it gives us a range to look for
the next one in our example here the
range is 58 Pips
now this is too large our rules state
that we want to have 40 Pips or less
ideally 20 to 30 Pips so this particular
trading day we have to allow the market
to do whatever it wants to do if we're
going to scalp that's another thing but
for day trading we can't use this
criteria because it's too large of a
central bank dealer's range and this is
not what I taught in the free teaching
on my YouTube channel but when you're
using CentralBankDealersRange
projections highs and lows the criteria
is 2030 is ideal in terms of Pips it has
to be less than 40 generally but ideal
ranges are 20 to 30 Pips High and
the reason why is if the average daily
range of the candle for the daily chart
that you're trading is typically around
100 Pips a site now they're not always
100 Pips but I like to use as a ballpark
figure general rule of thumb if we have
a hundred Pips one third of that is
around 33 Pips so that's why I give
about 20 to 30 Pips ideal scenario  it
won't you want to be less than 40 Pips
for that reason so for Power3
concept to unfold if we're bullish we're
looking for the opening price and then
the market to trade down 20 to 30 Pips
ideally no more than 33 Pips
if it trades beyond that we don't want
to
see it trade more than 40 Pips it
doesn't mean it can't but ideal
scenarios the the drop down from the
opening price on accumulation days where
the low the day is formed and we have a
higher close bullish
we're looking for that 20 to 30 pip drop
down and we can use the Central Bank
dealers range to confirm that with other
things that we'll teach in the next
lesson
the next
example here we have one Standard
Deviation projected below it
and
you can see we just about hit that but
it was definitely inside the first
StandardDeviation creating the low of
the day and price trades up aggressively
next example we have one Standard
Deviation
projected below
and a second StandardDeviation
projected below so now we have two
StandardDeviation below the Central
Bank dealers range for this particular
day
and it takes us right down to the low of
the day it was only off by one pivot
went below one pip and then we saw the
low that they formed in London
looking at this
obviously you know it looks like cherry
picking hindsight and all that business
but I want you to take in consideration
when we look at price
we have to have a bias what do we think
price is going to do is price going to
go higher or lower
over the next two or three days
what's the price most likely going to do
over the course of this present week or
next week is going to go higher is it
going to go lower
where are we at seasonally
are we looking for bullish prices or
lower prices
where are we at quarterly are we in a
quarterly shift that is underway that's
still unfolding with bullish prices with
premium PD arrays that haven't been met
yet
if that's the case then we could be
looking for scenarios to look for
Buys so we're looking at discount PD
arrays we're looking at reasons to
suggest buying in a discount range so
our PDA array Matrix is going to help us
look for reasons to build ideas that are
bullish
if we look for those ideas with the
CentralBankDealersRange in
conjunction with those it'll help us
narrow down with time of day London and
open it'll help us frame ideal entry
point
so if we look at the daily chart and we
see price trading up at a premium PD
array and markets are bearish we're
looking for lower prices for one shot
one kill scenario looking for a lower
close week
we could be looking for one two or three
StandardDeviation moved higher
when the CentralBankDealersRange is
around 20 to 30 Pips ideally
and if we get that projection up into
London we have a great deal of advantage
on our side that we're probably going to
get the HOD in the London
session
now you add that also with your
expectation of
seasonal Tendencies all of those things
start coming together and draw a closer
picture to what institutional order flow
is and how IPDA moves price in the next
lesson we're going to go into greater
detail about how we can pick the high
and the LOD with this
information and with the Asian range