hello and welcome to this model
my name is Gene and today we are going
to go for
what model would I trade for life if I
was the only trade one model
now every successor Trader launches
their Journey
to consistency
usually with the model
I also started out trading one model
and then I started to Branch out to
different models and I'm at a point
where I have multiple models that I
utilize for execution in management
and the fitness models over time you
start to build experience with them and
the more insight and the more experience
the game with them the more you start to
develop other models and usually it
takes just one model for you to find
breakthrough in trading
understanding the in and out of that
model can give you all the success
everything you need in trading but now
the problem is a lot of you guys want to
Branch out and learn multiple models and
this one and that one and that one and
then you complicate it and the problem
for the most or the majority of you guys
watching this video right now is that
you are complicating your journey
because you're trying to do everything
at once so what I'm saying is
all the different things you're trying
to pick up at once and learn at once
drop all of them focus on one which one
resonates with you which one resonates
with your own personality choose that
one
get data get back data you can back test
it or you can forward test the model
with data and see the performance what's
the risk reward what's the average
Reserve word it Nets you what is the
average return in that's your weekly
whatsoever returning entry per month
what's the longest winning streak what's
the longest losing streak you need to
know that statistics of your model so
you can learn to trust the model so this
is my favorite model this is my go to
model
and Eva also only trade one model for
Life what model would that be
that's this one here the New York
optimal trade entry model
is what we're going to be discussing
today
so welcome to today's video and we're
going to go into Del Bean to the New
York optimal trade entry model
all right before we go into the
breakdown of what the model is let us
first Define what an OTE which stands
for ultimate trade entry let's define
what that is so we're gonna go from the
basics then go to the advanced or
complicated
I'm by the end of this video you already
have an insight into what this model is
all about
an ultimate trade entry simply is a
measure of discount or premium of price
now in every range we have premium we
have discount and we have our
beam Fellowship which is what we call
equilibrium
price is always valuated based off of a
range okay price is valid either inside
a range or external turretch and that's
why you have a Fibonacci extension
levels
at every given moment or every price
price would either be
overbought or oversold now we're not
talking about supply and demand we're
we're trying to measure the value of an
asset relative to its range
now
inside the range
anything above
the middle point of a range is what we
call Premium
anything below the middle part of the
range what we call Discount now let us
Define What premium is and what discount
is
premium is the measure of the
expensiveness
of an asset
or a commodity
discount is a measure of the cheapness
of an asset or a commodity if we're
looking to buy we do not want to buy
when the price is expensive now I'm
using layman terms to Define Premium
versus discount
you wouldn't want to go and buy the
iPhone
when it is worth two thousand dollars if
you know next week is going to be worth
a thousand dollars does it make sense
for you to go and buy it now it's a
thousand dollars when you know next is
going to be worth a thousand dollars of
course not because you know
by next week you're already losing a
thousand dollars are you losing half the
net worth the iPhone so you're gonna
have to wait until it is discounted from
its two thousand dollar price which is
expensive to then buy your iPhone
and that's what the term or that's where
the term discount comes from so discount
essentially if you're looking to be a
buyer always want to buy a discount if
you're looking to be a seller you always
want to sell a premium
now if we are buying we are aiming for
the most premium price available to us
on offer and that's always going to come
in form of the high of a range which is
the most premium price inside that range
and that's what we call it buys a
liquidable for every buy the market will
look to pair long entries with bicycle
because that is the most premier price
inside the training range same way in a
cell
Marco will look to pair cells at premium
against cell sound Equitable because
that is the most discount price inside
the range so this is the basic
understanding of what an ultimate trade
entry is an ultimate trade engine simply
is buying below discount and it builds Auto flow
and aiming for a bicycle equatorial pool
which is those premium price available
to us to exit our bodies or selling
above the mean of a range AKA premium
and aiming for the most discounted price
offered to us are available to us on the
sell side identified as our sell side
liquidatable and this is a big basic
understanding of what ultimate trade
entry is also my trailer entry simply is
buying order flow at discount or premium
and targeted counterparter liquidable
sounds easy right and here's the key
every successful model
always finds
itself thriving in its simplicity
okay and the problem is a lot of you
guys feel you need to complicate your
model for you to make money
you honestly don't and if you access
this model you're gonna see the return
will be literally insane
the accuracy is absolutely insane so I
don't want to do it myself I don't want
you to be a social whereby I'm the one
giving you these stats and seeing Oh
this is the stats for the model I want
you after you're done watching this
video so either go back test this over a
period of a month and give me your
feedback on Twitter or you can forward
test this over the next two or three
weeks and then give me your feedback on
Twitter and see the performance of the
model itself for your Trading now
obviously if you're going to apply this
model for your trading you need to be
free between a periods of 7am Eastern
titanium Eastern every Monday so
Thursdays because that's the window of
opportunity your trainer model you're
not with this model you're not sitting
in front of your charts every day you
have a very specific time you show up to
what I call work okay so when you're
showing up to work you're going to work
you couldn't go sit in front of your
charts to identify this model if your
model does not present you're not traded
to model presents you're taking a trick
there's no room for emotions
there is no room for excitement when
when you hit take profits there's no
room for sadness when you have a losing
trade our job is to identify our model
and trade if it is present if our risk
is not elevated which we're going to
talk about on video two now let's go
more into the model
let's go into the overview of what this
model is now we already understand that
our model is the New York ultimate trade
entry that's we're looking for but let's
flesh out the model and let's build up
into what the model looks like with our
model overview now even though we're
Trading day trades or intra session
trades
our sentiment stems from daily autoflow
without the daily autoflow
our model is useless
our model has no value if we don't
understand where the daily candle is
supposed to expand up or down into
so one of you
your daily analysis just like the fuel
or the gas to your car if there is no
gas in your car you cannot drive
so the car itself is your model
checklist and everything you need to do
with your model the gas which is what
allows the cat to actually function
is the daily autoflow or the daily
program if you don't have an
understanding of your daily program your
model is useless now why is this the
case why is this key because your lower
time from narrative stem from a daily
autoflow or a daily deliver
everything the lower time frame does is
always going to be in sync with the data
candles if the daily is supposed to
expand higher lower time frame would see
bullish expansion if the date is
supposed to expand lower
time frame would see the Irish expansion
if the daily spoils are consolidate
that's where I see a lot of back and
forth on the lower time frame and by
understanding the data program and also
the data profile you can select
favorable conditions to employee model
in now this is the condition we're
looking for to execute our model on
before I go into the breakdown of what
you're seeing in front of me we need to
understand what conditions actually suit
our model
okay and we're only looking to trade
inside these conditions
we are waiting for when the daily candle
or the daily time frame is poised to
expand higher lower into arterial
liquidity and that's where we go in and
we execute on our model
we don't want to go and trade our model
if the daily time frame is in a range or
if it's range bound or if it's shown on
the willingness to want to displace
what we're looking for is we're looking
for a data program that is a pause to
this place
to our Target objective on the dated
time frame or B already displacing
to our Target objective on The Daily or
weekly design frame
so usually this is the way the the daily
candle would expand
so you have the market expanding if it's
a bullish data program the market would
expand from a daily discount it could be
a daily Bush auto block or a daily
bullisher valid or breaker block
the market will start the expansion
higher and the market usually would seek
a premium Now the same one I just saw
you about discount versus premium you
don't necessarily need to aim for
a swing high on the daily time frame as
your terminals you can aim for a premium
range so you can look for a bear shadow
block or a breaker block or repair Gap
as a short-term level where the market
should displays up or down into
the problem with trading is when a lot
of you guys go and you're approach
trading you feel like there's so many
things you need to take into factor to
make money and I'm singing on this video
you don't
there's only two things the markets all
restored Market is always either seeking
to replace the level of liquidity
pressing it to repressive level of
inefficiency
everything you see on your chart
everything revolves around the instant
key Concepts both on the daily program
or time frame weekly time per monthly
time frame lower time frame it never
goes past this so this information alone
is already empowering because you know
if the market is doing something it's
either going to level of inefficiency or
it's going to level up liquidity those
two so your job on the daily time frames
identify daily conditions which are
poised to expand to an hour time frame
level of inefficient delivery or
counterparty liquidity that's all you're
looking for
once you validate conditions like this
you're good to go on your execution
in the process of the daily time from
expanding to our terminal so we're going
to call that premium array Terminals and
that could be in form of a weekly
premium like weekly version block weekly
proportion or weekly high or with the
rejection block or a daily rejection
block okay but it's going to be a daily
or a weekly level as our Terminals and
the process of the market expanding up
into the terminals it will offer
multiple opportunities to get in sync
with the daily buy program via the 4r or
1R discount
now here's the key
in a daily buy program there are only
two methods of delivering price now
remember I mentioned before
there's only two things a market does in
terms of
reprise into a level of liquidity or
across the level of inefficiency the
market will do so in two ways the market
would either seek counterpart the
liquidity via stops or your Market will
seek to reaccumulate in a buy program
via inefficiencies and Order blocks
that's all the market is doing
once you define the program AKA it's a
buy program around your key for or when
our discount array the market will
either retrace in an alternate trade
entry to a farewell Gap AKA inefficiency
or the market will have a run on Cell
stock and then reverse in the version of
daily autoflow
and these this is the only this is the
only model in which the market delivers
liquidity
their inefficiencies or fair value gaps
and you're you're probably seeing like
that does not make sense it's so simple
and that's the problem you've been
taught that for your model to actually
be successful it has to be complicated
which it really does not need to
all he needs to do is it needs to
identify the Baseline in terms of price
delivery and get in sync with that so
again we're looking for daily conditions
our posts will expand in the direction
of our Target on liquidity or is already
expanding in the direction of retired
drone liquidity and those are the
conditions that we trade in or
we don't trade at all if the market is
for a sustain a range or the market
that's just met a night time from a
projective these are the two times
whereby you don't trade when the market
is fringe round or when the market has
met and higher time frame objective and
we don't know what's going to happen
next this is where we'll stay aside or
step aside and we do nothing but in the
process of delivering to a daily
terminals the premium array the market
would do so trades are not to form
around
far time frame or one hour time from
discount what you're looking for our
model is identifying
15-minute time from executions inside
this for our o1r discount array it's
going to sync with other flow again we
don't necessarily need to aim for the
daily terminals
to take profits all we need to do is we
need to aim for a lower time frame by
solicitable
like I showed you here
and that's a model this is the entire
premise of a model be it buys for a
model or sells with a model
that's the entire premise so we're
looking for expansion and direction of
daily buy program and we're looking for
Bears expansion version of the cell
program the only time this model is
going to fill you or
the most types of others are actually
going to fill you is when you get your
daily Direction buyers from or if you
trade during conditions which I'm going
to list on video two which is going to
be another video to this one if you
trade in those conditions that's when
you're more likely to spell
as long as you're deity
program is correct
you are good to go you will find
consistency with this model you'll make
tons of money with this model
okay so now for
a daily cell program or daily bearish
order flow in which you're aiming for a
daily discount as our terminals we look
for 4r or 1R bearish Revival gaps or buy
Subs to sell firm
so we're selling inside 15 minute time
frame
um
uh Premium app for r1r biceps or fair
value Gap until the market gets to our
terminals
and this is
it looks so simplistic which is that's
the key right and again somebody has to
go not looking at this and you're like
oh well this is easy yeah it was but now
the problem is going to be how long can
you see discipline with the model this
is where a lot of you guys actually feel
because people would get models like
this and they'll go mess it up trying to
tweak and add different things right I'm
going to show you how you can go a
little bit more advanced with the model
but going a little bit more advanced
with the model does not necessarily
equate to more profits
okay the guys were making profits or the
guys who were doing the repetitive
simplistic things day in day out and
this is the truth with profitable
trading profitable trading is boring
profit option is not exciting
that's where a lot of guys don't really
understand when you're trading
profitably and consistently it is a very
boring things you're going through
periods of making profits sometimes
you're going through periods of drawdown
sometimes you're going through winning
streaks at the end of the day you
understand that your model has
statistics back in the model and you're
only trading in favor of that stat and
that's what makes you your money you
know when the odds are high for you to
go in and leverage or take risk you know
when the odds are low for you to step
aside and do nothing
and majority of profitable trading
involves stepping aside and doing
nothing that is what perhaps of training
tells or consistent training tools
consistent trading until is doing
nothing
in the periods where you're not doing
anything that's only preserve capital in
prayers where you're doing something
that's when you increase capital and
this is the mindset I want to go in to
with this model when you're going in and
you're doing your back testing and
you're coming back to watch this video I
want you to have this mindset okay for
you to do this successfully you have to
get comfortable with doing nothing
because there's going to be periods in
time especially when the day time frame
is consolidation there's going to be
tons of perit inside where you're going
to have to do nothing you're going to
have to get comfortable doing nothing
and maybe developing a new model which
you can trade for consolidations which I
I actually have one for but again it's
not this is not what this video is for
okay either you're doing that one or you
do nothing which is the best way to go
about trade you're not rushing anything
you're patient you're waiting for the
conditions to align and then you strike
and then you step aside and repeat the
same thing day in day out week in
weekend and then the difference with
this is that's why this being boring
eventually over a period of time the
action compounds and that's the action
compounds you start to realize oh
actually I have over seven figures worth
in terms of funding and I can make more
money and that's when life starts to get
exciting
but now the problem is no one is ready
to play the long game
obviously prop frames are made it easy
for you to leverage Capital they might
be demo Capital but they've still made
it easily they reduce sums of capital to
then increase your income or gains the
problem is everyone wants to go for a
Max I ever platform at once quickly they
don't want to do it in the process of a
week or two weeks or a month
whereas in reality actually takes a very
long time to do so you have to
consistently build and build and be
comfortable building and build it in
Beauty until it gets open whereby all
your actions have all compounded and
you're starting to rip the fear of your
labor and that is what I'm going to
teach you for the next two or three
videos
all right so now it's going to
our set of progression for a model
and what we're looking for is I'm gonna
use a bullish
trend for this example and you can just
reverse
what I'm teaching for the very side so I
don't have to go through for both the
blue side and the bear side because
they're essentially the same thing
they're both the same thing or just
after you just have to flip what I'm
saying for the bare side and then it
will make sense
so we're gonna go for our cell
progression for our model before we go
into the panel uh slide which is for the
model checklist AKA what you need to go
for every single time you're prepping
for your model uh the checklist you
actually need to visit now the set of
progression for a model is
we need to identify that the daily
program is a buy program and we need to
identify a discount a daily discount
where we're expecting the market to
expand from on The Daily time frame the
market will always expand from a daily
discount or the market will always start
a buyer program from daily discount what
you're looking for is you're looking for
that program you're look you're trying
to get in sync with to originate from a
daily or high time from discount if it
does not originate from Nighttime from
discount then most likely you're nearing
the end of that program
or you're going to see the market start
to retrace into a discount to then
continue the program or start the new
program
so what you're looking for is you're
looking for the daily time frame to
either retrace into a discount to start
the program or the dating program or
data time frame is just recently
expanding from a discount array and then
you can get in sync with that so
what you're identifying is you're
identifying the daily program
in a buy program you're looking for a
daily program to to be a buy or bullish
and they can transpose this to it for
our program and we're looking for if
you're looking for the far program to
also be a buy program now here's what I
mean with the transpose in the daily
program to a four hour program if
the daily is
poised to expand in direction of the
autoflow and it's bullish
what you don't want to do is you don't
want to go in and buy
a 15 minute time for execution because I
said or because I said your time for
execution is the 5 or 15 minute discount
or premium array you don't want to go in
and just buy any 5 or 15 minute discount
every New York session
not every session will see expansion in
Direction autoflow how do you select the
session because our job of the model let
me rephrase this and if you're taking
notes I want you to write this down your
notepad because it really is important
to the model and to the success of the
model
it's not just enough to identify
the data program
and that the daily program is willing to
see expansion to the terminals we also
need to identify that the lower time
frame is in sync with the daily profile
or program so what do I mean by that if
the daily is seen expansion higher we
want to see the 4r trade into a far
discount and continue the expansion
higher
don't want to buy if the 4r time frame
is retracing into a discount at a far
time Furniture trades into a discount
then the one hour time frame and the 15
minute time frame they're going to be
bearish and if you try to buy if their
Bearer should go on to lose money
and by the time the market retracing so
far uh discount for the for our program
to resume in the direction of daily
program you've already lost Equity by
then and when it's time for you to pick
your trade there's probably no
ammunition left for you to pick your
trades because maybe you've met your
risk limit for the week or for the day
and now you're pissed off and this is
where a lot of you guys are going to
struggle you're going to struggle with
the patient aspect of this model
the model involves patients every week
you're going to get two to three
opportunities to trade in direction of
the data program or weekly autoflow
essentially the weekly order flow is
going to be the data program
and your job is to wait for the four
hour time frame to align with the
thought with the data profile because
the far-time is aligning with big
profile then the 1R programs also go
into align with the for our program so
here's what I mean with this so we're
going to go into a blank chart I'm going
to describe exactly what this should
look like for a trading okay this part
of the model
which is the set of progression I'm
going to describe how it should look
like for your model
so now let's go and break the sound on a
daily time frame and I'm gonna do some
very quick drawings here and hopefully
this makes sense
if we have a let's assume that this is a
daily range okay
and
I'm gonna use this
and we're seeing lower prices on daily
time frame and we of course to believe
that the dating time frame should be
bullish
and we see
daily time frame actually start to
resume bullishness and we see a shift in
structure or the market break in a
previous high that is a shifting
structure when we're anticipating
bullshits that what we're looking for is
we don't want to buy
until the daily time retraces down into
a daily discount
because the market has to again remember
what I talked about with
Premium versus discount
don't want to buy while the price is
expensive want to buy when it is cheap
this goes for the daily time frame
for our time frame
one hour time frame and then ultimately
the 15 minute time frame so meaning if
we're looking to be a buyer in direction
of daily autoflow again the daily time
frame creates the entire framework
creates our sentiment
so if our conclusion from the daily time
frame is we're looking for bullishness
and we have an objective from liquidity
then we want to make sure that if we
want to be a buyer we're not buying at a
15 minute discount that is inside a 4r
premium I'm sure what it looks like
now inside this daily time frame let's
assume this leg is not actually formed
and this is a discount here we're
anticipating some kind of bullishness on
the daily time frame all right now as
the market retraces down into that
discount
on the far time frame on our time frame
you're going to see more Down Candles or
bearishness in bars as Market retraces
down there
while the markets are tracing lower like
this
now let's zoom in on this one here I
want to zoom in on this this retracement
lowering price
okay so inside this data type remember
this is a data time frame as the market
is retracing down into a daily high or
higher time from discount we're looking
at a daily uh some form of inefficiency
right as the markets are tracing down
there
on a for a time from a wisdom enclosure
what you're going to see is you're going
to see that the far time frame is
retracing like this or it's bearish
you're going to see bearishness on the
forest however now what you don't want
to do here is you don't want to go in
and try to buy
okay you don't want to buy any shift and
structure
because any shift and structure before
our time frame is just only going to set
the stage for a lower run because the
daily has to get done here for the
program to resume
now even though the daily program is
bullish
okay the 4r program is not bullish
because we're not yet at a dated
discount for bullishness so ensue on the
lower timer now this is what I mean when
I say the daily time frame is the
framework for a lower time from
understanding because what a lot of you
guys will do in terms of using this
model is you're not going to wait for
the daily to get down to a level where
we should see expansion higher and then
you're going to go in and look at every
shift and structure on the lower time
frame as a buying opportunity
whereas in fact it's not again remember
the lower time frame is simply to get in
sync with the daily program
go and look at your lower time frame
look at all the asset classes every
asset classes across all-time prayers
since the beginning of trading this is
how it's always been
lower time frame always out to subject
to so to the RSI from Price delivery
so if the data is supposed to expand
higher and there is a daily discount
that we should see price trade down into
for a bullish expansion we don't go in
and go and try to buy any shifting
structure or any uh for our inefficiency
inefficient so we don't try to
buy there now you can obviously go in
and say you want to sell this but that's
not what this model is teaching you the
model is teaching you to trading sync
with the daily program so if your daily
program is a buy program you want to
Traders Inc with that daily program and
how do you do this
by waiting for
the four programs online with the daily
program and the one hour programs along
with the daily program and then you can
go in on your 15-minute time frame
you're looking at a very specific time
window to trade in One Direction you're
not second guessing directions you're
not second guessing where the market
should up or down into you already know
what you're looking for your job is to
go within a certain time of the day and
look for one thing that's that's what
you're doing
that is all you're doing once you've
validated that the 1R and thorough
programmer aligns with the data program
AKA if the daily is trading down or
going down into a discount what you've
done here is you've identified a 4r
discount inside that daily discount and
then you don't take any action until the
daily time frame gets done there
and as soon as it gets down there guess
what you're going to see a lower time
frame shift and structure and that's all
called institutional sponsorship
the market will always give you Clues of
delivery
and that's what we'll call institution
sponsorship once you get that initial
pop higher
it's not going to be on the daily time
frame again on daily time frame Market
has to get all the way up here for you
to identify shifting structure and
continue other flow we don't need that
we don't need daily time frame expansion
press against it with other flow all we
need to see is we need to see the market
get down there into that high time from
discount and see willingness on a
displace on either the far time frame or
the one hour time frame and that's
enough once you see that then our job is
to then go in and identify
15 minute discount arrays inside that
one r or for our discount to buy in sync
with and once we buy from there and we
start to see the market the spacing the
version of autoflow we can repeat the
same process every single time we trade
out into a four hour one hour discount
we buy or every single time will run
below if for our o1r discount we'll look
for a lower time frame again 15 minute
shifting structure and then we buy
during that time window
it is
all right I think it's a easy peasy
Japanese or something I was just in the
uh Netflix movie I can't remember the
movie it was like easy peasy Japanese
and that's what this is all right it is
a straightforward model it is easy all
you got to do is just you have to wait
I'm gonna do more mindset calls on this
but let's go into the program so the
daily version of bias and Target
liquidity sets the stage for our model
it is the backbone of our model being
possible and once we've identified our
data program and the draw again it's not
just enough to identify the program we
also need to know where the daily time
frame is reaching for and that is what
creates what I call displacement or one
titlemeness again without displacement
you cannot make money without the market
expanding you're not going to make money
so you want to identify market
conditions that are poised to expand and
that's how you make money and they're
poised to expand into level of your
objective
we seek the H4 program to align with
database and we want to see the far
candles retracing to a4r discount for
our setup anticipation just like I
talked about here right so if you're
looking for daily bushness then you
don't want to go and buy Wayne the far
time frames are tracing to a daily
discount you want to wait for the far
time from also the one hour time going
to trace into that daily discount and
then you go and hunt your setup you
don't hunt your setup until the market
gets into your anticipated level of
expansion or unless the market has
started the expansion from that discount
then you can go and hunt your setup on
the lower time frame your M15 setups
will form inside each one Auto blocks
bullish Auto blocks so we're talking
about buy programming again uh for cell
programs you just want to reverse what
I'm saying and it'll work your soul side
or assault programs
all right so for buy programs we're
looking for a 15-minute setup which will
form inside a 1R either bullshitter
block forever Gap or cells now let me
talk about this a little bit more
there are only three periods we use for
a model again I'm not going to specify
what PD array on the model because we're
using three and it depends again on what
is present
during that time window where we're
hunting our setup we're only looking for
three
premium or discount per race either an
autoblock if you're about a gap or a
breaker block
this is the only three PD errors we're
looking for over hunting
nothing else
we're not looking for anything else just
no new terminology new complex theme or
any sort of thing where only idle
looking for an autoblock
breaker block
or inefficiency that's what we're
looking for
and we buy from there or we sell from
there depending on the data program
we want to trade our model when the 1R
and 4r program aligns with the data
program yeah we don't want to trade I'm
reiterating this multiple times because
it really is important to our model we
only want to execute on our model when
it is in alignment with the daily
program
don't want to trade our model when the
one hour time frame and for our time
frame does not align with our program
AKA if the data is retracing
and we see a one hour time frame shift
and structure on the buy side we don't
go and buy
any discount on the one hour time frame
because we understand that any shift
instructor hire only sets the stage for
a run lower into that high time from
discount and that's how you can frame
shift and structure versus random
liquidity or runs and stops using the
daily program or the daily levels that's
how your data levels are very key on
your intraday charts we want to Trader
model when the one hour program for our
program aligns with the daily program
and we do not need to Target data
liquidity to make money we simply need
to aim for a lower timeframe Target in
the direction of
of our daily buys to make consistent
income
our go with the model is not sniper
intros or Instagram entries or Twitter
enters I'll go with the model is to make
money and to get wealthy and enrich if
you prioritize this Opera looking for
Sniper interest and looking for entries
are good for social media you're going
to do extremely well
extremely well with this model I'm
promising you this and the reason I
promising this because I want to go and
back test this yourself and you'll be
mindful you're like I knew a lot of you
guys are listening to this right now you
already know this model you already knew
this model
all I'm doing is I'm giving you a
framework to operate with the model you
already know this model
but you're still shocked like this is so
simple yes it is that's what a model is
supposed to look like every model that
is successful Finds Its success in its
Simplicity that's all
let's go into the third progression um I
believe we've covered this on this slide
but we're gonna you know flesh this out
a little bit more on this slot here and
let's talk about the set of progression
what it looks like conceptually
all right so what you can see here is
the market starts delivery from a daily
discount and that the discount could
also be an item from discount like a
weekly discount
some time very rarely it could be a
monthly discount but we are more focused
on a daily discount because this is
where majority of your of the framework
of your setup will form
so we see a lower time frame again all
of this is all lower time from expansion
from a daily discount once you see this
lower time from expansion we already
know that we are now in a daily buy
program
what we're looking for is we're looking
to execute when the lower time frame
program aligns with the dated program
meaning we don't want to go and buy 15
times from here or here or here or here
because they are in a short-term sale
program even though they do a program
Supply program again if you're trading
you want your daily program to align
with your 1R and for our program so you
don't want to be buying in a one RSL
program when the daily program is
published since I don't want to be
selling in a one hour buy program when
the program is bearish you want them all
to align and this is how you get in sync
with your model so if the data program
is bullish you want your lower time from
program to align with the daily program
AKA you're not buying the lower time
frame when it is at premium you're
buying them where they are when they are
at discount relative to their own
trading range
now as a market retraces down into a
discount usually there's going to be a
one hour discount or far discount what
we see or what we seek is we seek a 15
minute shift in structure okay so as we
trade down into stock 4r or one hour
discount we're looking for is we're
looking for displacement on the lower
time frame that's going to be a five
minute time frame sorry that's gonna be
a fifth sermon time frame or a one hour
time from usually and our goal is to buy
a fair value gap on the 15 minute time
frame or a five minute time frame
between 7 A.M to 10 a.m Eastern Standard
Time and this is what I call the
standard rear condition protocol so
there are two protocols you're going to
use for this model again the model is
the New York Autumn Trail entry model
but for the New York option trade engine
model there are two protocols to employ
for the exact setup
you have your standard reaccumulation
protocol for bullish program if you're
looking for bearish programs you call
this your standard
redistribution protocol
and number two is your offset
reaccumulation protocol for buy programs
or offset redistribution protocol for
cell programs now let's differentiate
these two
a standard recognition protocol
essentially is this
the marker retraces down into a fair
ball Gap or other block inside this
range and sees expansion
usually is going to go below the main
threshold of the range or equilibrium of
the range tracing to a discount is going
to be some kind of inefficiency or
pollution block a discount then the
market says expansion this is your
standard for accumulation protocol
now for offset recognition protocol
which is a little more tricky but really
it's just straightforward the market
actually runs the range now with the
standard recognition protocol the market
maintains the range with the offset
recognition protocol the Marquette runs
the range okay and usually what you get
there is you get a flashing smt
Divergence oh I just showed you
something here
cool right
you learn more now what you can do here
and the problem is a lot because for the
standard break animation protocol
it's really straightforward right you
already know this you know you see
expansion with retracement you buy aim
for Journal quality shift forward that
you're looking for now with the officer
recognition protocol
the mark actually runs lower the range
and what a lot of Traders fall is sharp
into is they go in expecting this kind
of delivery here and the market just
falls short of that and then you think
you know maybe they're wrong in your
bias all along the market was just
straight down into a 4r or one hour
discount to see expansion from again
what gives context into this as a
manipulation is your daily directional
premise and what you can use as a
confirmation that this was simply a run
and stop it's comparing the Run lower to
a correlated asset so if this is euro
dollar and Euro dollar is running lower
into a 4r01r discount
is GBP US dollar running lower or is
dollar running higher because you're all
correlated assets right so if you're
always running lower we preferably want
to see dollar running higher which will
mean that probably to run lower euro
dollar is the shift in structure and not
even on stops
but if euro is running lower into a 4r
01r discount and dollar is failing to
run higher then this is simply a play on
salsa liquidity aka the market is just
running stops into a level of discount
where it would allow for reaccumulation
and then continue version of autoflow
now you have three options with this
entry you could either buy once you
confirm that Divergence you could have a
buy under the solo here which I believe
is a little bit scary for a lot of you
guys and obviously you're going to have
to grow into this or you could wait for
usually I wait for a five minute
displacement so you can wait for a five
minute displacement to create an
inefficiency or bullish on the Block and
then you buy the retracement into that
inefficiency or book on either
a five minute time frame or a 15 minute
time frame again nothing lower than a
five minute timer and either a five
minute time frame or 15 minute time
frame with stock below this log here and
you in for your usual Target or you
could still wait for the market to get
into the breaker block and once you see
the market displace through the breaker
block with a fair bottle Gap you buy the
retracement into the breaker block with
your stops below the breaker block
and that's how you have three inches
with your offset recognition model so
with your standard recognition model
you're buying your standard retracing
down into your
618 to 786 Fibonacci level again the
reason why I have this level on my
Fibonacci you can use this for your
Fibonacci when you're looking to be a
buyer or seller usually anything above
the mean of a range is what we call
Premium anything below is what we call
Discount but if you want to refine the
range even more you can use your 786 to
Fibonacci retracement level and then
what you're looking for is you're
looking for pdres inside the range so if
you're looking to be a seller you're
looking for premium arrays inside your
786618 Fibonacci level if you're looking
to be a buyer looking for Discount
already inside your 786 to 618 Fibonacci
level and that's where you buy from now
again I don't need them because I
already know how to eyeball premium or
disciplinary so again in my opinion is
not really necessary I don't really use
FIB natural levels like that
um and more of user the extension levels
but you can use this as a guy until you
start to trust your eyes with your model
you can use this short term
all right so I'm just get a sip of
coffee because I'm already
and uh we're almost getting into an R
with the model I was thinking it was
gonna be like 10 20 minutes and it's
almost an hour with the model that's
insane
so
listen to from where I left off and the
process of delivering to our daily
terminals AKA our premium the market
would do so for a standard
reaccumulation where just for tracing
down into a level of inefficiency in
form of a auto block or fair value Gap
and continue the program or
DeMarco actually run old lows in a
bullish program and then continue to run
higher now here's the key if you trust
your daily program whenever we run a
short-term load you don't view that as a
breaking structure you look for the
market to shift and here's the key here
the market will see the most explosive
displacement
in the version of bullishness after
running Soul stops
I saw one more time so you'll fully
grasp what I'm seeing
price would see the most explosive
displacement
bullish
in the version of a daily bullishness
after a run on Cell stops at discount
this has to happen at discount again the
key thing here for either of the
protocol
is a lower time from program meaning
once you've identified your daily
program in this example it is bullish
you're not doing anything onto your
lower timeframe program aligns with your
daily program AKA you want your lower
time frame on both the 4r and 1R to be
at the discount once your four hour one
hour time frame are both at discount
then you can go and hunt your setups on
your 15 minute time frame within your
time window which is 7 A.M to 10 a.m
Eastern Standard Time
and you're looking for either these two
protocols I'm going to show you on a
live setting or I'm going to use the
charts actually to show you and then
this week we're going to do more live
setting executions with the model
and this is what you're looking for this
essentially is your model
this is your this is your model and you
can see the time under here 7 A.M to 10
a.m Eastern that's the window of
opportunity for your model and nothing
outside that
this is when you're looking to trick
your model
are you looking to trade this in
direction of data autoflow
now let's go into the final part of the
video and painfully we're coming towards
the end of the video because I really
did enjoy this video I did enjoy this
video
um so we're going to talk about our
checklist what are the checklists that
we require for our model every single
time we stop on the charts before the
window of opportunity starts for us what
are we looking to go for to remind
ourselves the four ways to kit on our
model number what we need to define the
daily buy or sell program and identify
the journal liquidity we only Scout
setups when the daily Sports in the
space remember we make money when we see
the spaceman if there's a lack of
displacement we don't make money we
don't make money in ranges or
consolidations we make money when
both the daily 4r and 1R program is
poised to see expansion
number two we transpose key daily or
week levels to lower time frame charts
okay so we want to make sure that our
key data levels are on our intraday
chart so when you identify your daily
viewers I identify the key levels on
your daily time frame you don't remove
them from your charts
a lot of times when I say a lot of times
I mean 80 of the time intraday expansion
will form from those levels and that's
why it release kids of your daily levels
on your intraday chart
number three you want to identify your
H4 and H1 so when I say H4 I mean your
4r I'm going to say each one I mean
you're one R so you want to identify
your H4 and each one discount and
premium arrays around key daily or
weekly levels so once you've identified
your daily level that does not mean
you've removed that level from your
chart you keep them on your chart and
then go and look for lower time frame
discount or premium around those key
levels to even refine
your levels more for your intraday
training
okay the way you want to do after that
is number four you want to confirm that
your 4r and one hour program aligns with
the data program now this is really key
this is the base for execution you don't
execute until your for our program and
when our program aligns with your data
program and after you've done that then
number five you identify a lower time
frame buy side liquidity and the daily
buy program and a one hour time from
cell solid liquidity in a data cell
program so what you're looking for is
you're looking for a one now this is
supposed to be corrected here you're
looking for a 1R
buy solid liquidity or 15 minute Buy
sell liquidity predated by program and
then you just flip this for a you know a
data solve program once your 4r and 1R
program aligns okay
you want the low or high of the day to
form around a daily or weekly level
again 80 of the time the low or high
intraday will form around key higher
time from levels and that's why every
single time you go into your chart
always leave your hard time from levels
on your lower time frame charts they
will influence the delivery on the lower
time frame charts
number seven the daily buy program
you're looking for price to trade below
12 a.m Eastern Standard Time
and so I'll call the bullish
accumulation phase and in the daily cell
program you're looking for price to
trade above 12 a.m Eastern Standard Time
now I've taught about the daily candle
so let me just quickly do a reaction
this and I'll go into the next slide
this is what a daily bullish candle
looks like
you have your opening price
and then you have the low of that candle
the market will open from the opening
price from lower
and then go back up above the open price
and that point where it went lower
becomes the weak of the daily Bush
candle
and then from there it starts to expand
above the open price and goes up into a
short-term premium where when it gets up
into that it starts to pull back
and that point where I started to pull
back is what creates the high of your
daily bullish candle and this is all the
daily candle looks like
you have your open
low high close
no
in a daily bullish candle
we expect this for a daily buy program
and then for a daily cell program we're
expecting a daily bearish candle
all right now in a daily bullish candle
price will accumulate below true day
open now we don't use midnight GMT time
for our opening price we're using
midnight New York time for open products
so the same way it did the bullish
candle would see
initial run lower below the opening
price that open price is what we use as
Sofia
Eastern Standard Time
so if we're looking for bullshness we
want to see
price
on that day run below
tough air midnight time if we have not
seen price run below that time by New
York then we expect New York to do so if
we don't get that then we don't take any
trades
irregardless if the market expands guess
our Target objective this is the
protocol this is the checklist that's
what you have to follow
all right so for a daily Bush program we
want to see the market trade below 12
a.m in New York your daily self program
I want to see the market trade above 12
a.m New York because that is what sets
the initial accumulation phase for that
daily range
all right so going into the next part of
the checklist which number eight we like
to see the high of the day which stands
for hod or low of the day which stands
for LOD form around daily or weekly
levels and we aim to and we aim for the
previous day's low or high I'm sorry the
query drops now this is basic profit
taking
majority of the time the market would
trade above the purposes high in the
daily bullish program
or the previous stage low in a daily
bearish program and this is
quote unquote this is what we can use as
you know take profit areas as atrocity
profit areas right this is like basic
price understanding is markets expanded
lower obviously we need a short term low
to six cells on liquidity
I already showed you that here all right
so we have a bicycle to pull or lower
time from salsa liquid to pull if we are
buying a discount they want to see the
market seek the most premium price which
is a short-term high if we're buying or
if we're selling a premium you want to
see the market sick the most discounted
price which is self-sal equitable
and that is what the previously is high
or low offers for our intraday Traders
we identify standard rear accumulation
protocol or offset recognition protocol
based on proximity to key daily or for
our levels so if we have not carried out
into a key for our 1R daily level and we
see the market just making sure to know
just before that then we expect New York
to be a offset recognition protocol in
which
retail will look too long inside this
old range while we aim for the market to
run cell side and trade down into that
key level to buy from either we buy as
soon as we're touching that level or
we'll wait for a lower time frame
displacement so what lower type are we
looking at we're looking at a five
minute time frame or a 15-minute time
frame we seek a display spanning form of
a fair value gap or identify a bush of
the block and we buy from that expecting
immediate displacement when we trade
with this kind of protocol not the
standard recognition phase which is the
standard protocol for New York I'm
talking about the offset recognition
protocol
when we're using this protocol for our
trade entries we seek speed and delivery
the delivery after on a stop is usually
faster than the delivery with the
standard recognition because the market
has already run to see counterparty
liquidity and what price will do a lot
of times this price will sink to quickly
put all the chairs were selling the Run
lower here because there's going to be a
lot of shares who are selling short
they'll run below the the range as the
market runs lower there
retail is induced short and anyone who
was buying inside this range you're
stopped out and then Demarco is an
aggressive run in Russian autoflow
so the speed of delivery with offset
recognition is usually faster than that
of your standard recumulation right and
then um
number 10 your pair selection let's talk
about pair selection real quick if
you're going to trade an asset you want
to trade the pair that's shown a
willingness on a displace individual
digital autoflow against a reference
meaning you're looking to trade in
leadership
a lot of times you guys will have the
right bias for dollar less used all for
example so let's say your anticipating
in dollars to trade higher without the
right buyers for dollar trading high but
then you go and select a pair that's not
showing any winners want to trade
higher with dollar
and this is what messenger analysis are
because you have you have the right buys
you have the right sentiment but you're
just selecting the wrong pair because
the player selecting is what I call the
sympathetic pair or the seek pair you
don't want to select the sick pair the
sick pair is always the pair that has
shown a lack of willingness to want to
displace right so the parachute on the
lockableness want to displace
you're not training that this adds a
sick pair or the sympathetic pair you're
always looking for leadership meaning if
dollar is expanding higher
the payer trading if it's positively
correlated with dollar should be
expanded higher or if it is negative the
character with dollar should be
expanding lower
number 11 you want to identify Market
protraction at New York now the same way
I just taught you with your daily candle
where from the open price or microc and
initial false quote-unquote false front
lower which induces early results so
short and then incisions go and then buy
against veto sentiment you want to see
the same thing for New York so meaning
when I see you're looking for
marketraction and New York open
once New York starts which is 7 A.M and
ends which is 10 a.m if you're looking
for bullishness
you're looking for the market to do this
the price at which that session opened
is what we'll call the opening price for
New York if you want to be a buyer you
want to be buying anywhere below the
open price
or you want to see the market trade
below the open price for New York
again you don't necessarily need to buy
below.com prices you just need to see
that the market has traded below the
open price if you can buy below the open
price that is preferable preferable
that's what we prefer that's what we
want now sometimes you might not get the
Bible below the open price
but you want to see the market has done
that same way you want to see the market
trade below 12 a.m midnight New York in
a daily push overflow or daily bullish
program
you want to see the same thing happen
for New York so you want to see the
market tree below 7 A.M Eastern Standard
Time so there are two times in the daily
program running through the market trade
below onto the market trade below 12 a.m
Eastern Standard Time and 7 A.M it's
your Center time
and these are your checklist criteria
for your model
number 12 you're identifying a 15-minute
or one hour high or low for take profit
objective I already talked about this
before and number 13 which is the last
one you want to place your stop two PD
arrays above or below your 5 minute or
15 minute PD array selected so if you're
buying at a five minute farewell Gap if
there's a bullshitter block below the
farewell Gap they want to place your
stops not just below the farewell Gap
you're buying from but also below the
both shutter block because the market
could trade Through the Fair ball Gap
and trade into your auto block and still
be valid
or let's say if you're buying a five
minute CB or busy not not civi if you're
buying a five minute busy
and then you have the fair value Gap
below the busy that you want to place
your stops below the fair Volga okay
because marketing trade for the busy
trading to the fair value Gap and still
be valid so a general rule of thumb now
stops is not a fixed protocol okay there
it's something that you
depending on that current market profile
you utilize it and I'll do more videos
and stops and I think on the next one
right but a general rule of thumb is you
want to please if you stop to pierce
above or below the pdre selected for
your executions
and uh we are almost done with the model
and now let's go and look at some actual
examples and price
now I'm sure you guys are probably
thinking yourself well this model is
complicated it's too much there's so
many checklists I need to go through
there's this science student that means
you're stabbing to do
it's not I'm gonna show you how quickly
you can get all of this now obviously
it's easy for me because I've been doing
this for years and the Finish you just
need a few months to get acclimatized
with this model and you're good to go so
once you get that console with the model
you don't necessarily need to go through
long checklist you just know the key
things you're looking for and once you
open the charts either they're there or
they're not and you're good to go all
right so now we're gonna use
gbps dollar from last week's price
action to show examples with our model
all right so we're going to go and look
for cable
by the way jpu is always called cable
sometimes I write on my tweet I'll write
like cable should do this and people
still ask some questions like what's
Cable cable is pound dollar this is what
we call Cable your dollar is all called
fiber you as a cat is all called Looney
okay I want to call them those names by
those additional that's the name to call
them
all right so what we're gonna do here
with a pound
let me actually remove Tuesday's data
range we're going to use a replay tool
to simulate like uh if it's not
simulating real time trading because
there's no money involved we're gonna
use the replay so it's kind of like
Pretend We're trading live settings all
right so now listen to the analysis here
let's identify our key higher time frame
levels and then Define our program
all right so let me go to a forex.com
and see if I can identify that there
so I'm gonna again I'm gonna go back and
use the replay tool here
foreign
I'm going all the way out to a weekly
time frame
if you look to your left you can see
very closely that we have a weekly
volume and balance here so if you look
at this gap between these two candles
that's an actual Market Gap there
all right be I'll go remember that in
the future if that that's a long time
this formed around
April 22nd over a year ago the algo
still will remember these levels
so we have this weekly inefficiency here
and the primary of that Weekly
Gap starts at the close of this candle
which is 1.3 1.29 so we're going to use
1.31129
as the primary of our inefficiency and
usually what I like is I like to make
with levels red a very deep dark red
weekly monthly levels like to make them
that color scheme and then the discount
low of our weekly and efficiency
starts at the open price of this candle
which is
1.30950 okay so 1.3 is there
five zero that's a discount load there
and that's our premium and if we trade
through this level here then we have to
contend with the
projection block and then this small
loot of fair value so you look at the
slower Scandal high of the Scandal I
know we have a wrong balance here we
have a small wheelchair value Gap there
that we still have to contend with so
we're not really going to concern
ourselves with these levels here because
you're so far away from this level until
we trade for this level
we're really going to need to have all
these levels in our charts all right so
we're done with that on the weekly time
frame now let's go into can we identify
anything else on with the time frame uh
the only thing we can see is this weekly
work here so
we're gonna outline
the suitable shot block as our discount
so we have Wikipedia shutter block as
our discount and then we go to our daily
time frame and this is what we'll call
the top down analysis right so we're
going from a weaker time frame down to a
daily time frame
and what we can identify here
again let's use the money syringe you
can see here we have a daily
discount
okay and the daily discount is this
daily bullish per Volga
I like to use purple for my daily levels
to just a different shape both
now what we have with this DB discount
is
we have the discount load the
inefficiency the primary begin
efficiency and then if we use our
Fibonacci for mods low here
we have the 50 which is the constant
encroachment of our inefficiency
or discount array
and we're done
now the questions let's identify what
the program is
we have traded up we've seen serious
expansion up into a weekly premium
it makes sense to express a kind of
logical distribution lower now if we're
going to distribute from here
where is a discount that we can aim for
we can aim for a distribal gap here we
can also infer the cerebellum up here so
we have two inefficiencies lower to aim
for now I don't want to add those levels
here because it'll just clutter the
charts so I'm going to leave them until
we trade below this discount
and our key here is if we're looking for
weakness AKA we're looking for
distribution after all of this expansion
we don't want to see the market trade
above this as a premium now why because
if we trade Above This weak level as a
premium the next premium for us to trade
up into and see any bearish retracement
from is all the way up here if we go
back to a weaker time frame
you can see the next premium is here
and that is how many pictures is that
from here
that's around
if we measure the post
that's around 100 plus fips 100 plus
supposed to get to Next Level premium
and C bearish distribution from so we
know that if the market loses this level
on a daily time frame the lower time
frame is going to be in the buy program
because it has to get all the way up
here for its then retrace or see a
little bit of a consolidation so
we've created protocols for our daily
buys right so our daily device is a
bearish retracement until getting to a
discount and that discount can be either
this one this one or this weekly
discount before we see a resumption in
the buyer program now let's go on the
lower time frame we've already
identified our key date levels and what
you can see here is I'm leaving the key
weekly and daily levels here not doing
anything to it all right so the lower
time frame we're going to the one hour
time frame and I'm not going to go
through and look at the uh checklist one
by one because I already know them right
so I'm just going to run through each
and every one of them Okay so
and what I'm looking for is I'm looking
for the time window which is 7 AM to 10
a.m Eastern for my trade
so I'm not concerned really
with what price is doing until
a time without opportunity which is here
and also what the market wants to do so
so far in bearish as long as we don't
lose this level all right so now this is
what the market does living up into
our time frame
K and server time frame now the daily
program which we're anticipating is a
bearish program that's where
anticipating we are at a key weekly
level here but the lower time frame
program is a buy program
okay the lower time for program is not a
self-program yet because we're not
seeing bearish delivering price we're
still seeing consolidation and then a
run higher
now I could go a little bit more and say
well this is the one this consolidation
and this is your Judo swing and which is
he bearishness and price but I'm not
really interested in this so again we're
not really going to execute on this
because we're not confirmed yet that the
data program is bearish okay what we're
looking for is we're anticipating data
programs and bearish I want to see the
lower time frame aligned with that
program so far it's not aligned with
that program yet because I've not seen
the market show any Wellness on the
display slower so we're not really
interested until we spot a Wilderness
and price I want to split slower but
again remember where I saw the key
weekly premium
and our single Market shook willingness
I want to display slower
inside our time window from that key
with the level and what can we identify
on the one hour time frame what's the 1R
timeframe program
here
it's a cell program now because we've
taken out a short-term low
a hard time from inefficiency
after running out buy stop so what we
wanted to see here which is why we're
not buying here now if the market was
already bearish on the lower time frame
as we're running up here we're selling
into that run higher
but because we're anticipating reversal
and we're not sure that the lower time
frame autoflow is in alignment with r
again it's not confirmed yet it's just
anticipated with our anticipated Bears
delivery we're not selling up here we're
waiting for confirm nature displacement
That's What I Call institutional
sponsorship when you say lower time
frame displays like this from our time
from levels that's what causes Your
sponsorship now on the
one hour time per we can see that we've
seen bearishness in price and obviously
in the far time we can see there's very
system products now we go into a 15
minute timer and we're looking for
levels where we can identify areas to
sell from
now here you can see inside this as soon
as we shift structure lower
below this look here
we have a premium that's a fair value
Gap remember what I talked about
the only thing you should ever need is
either fair value Gap Auto Block Breaker
block that's all you don't need anything
else
okay so now if we have a favorite Gap
here does it come over at the premium we
have this week here that runs liquidity
because this week runs liquidity we
don't use this to measure our range
inside our range measurements that start
starts from this level here
so our range measurement starts from
here to here not from this one because
this is a run unstop this is more like a
gap on liquidity right so if we measure
our range
from all the way from the high all the
way down to the low
you can see it goes above our
equilibrium which is premium again
anything above equilibrium that's
premium so we have a 15 minute
inefficiency now watch it's not just
only a 15 minute inefficiency
also that's the discount low of that
Weekly level there
so we can sell short
that inefficiency
because it's our premium
aiming for again what I talk about
previously slow it's easy run on
liquidity at the same time we can also
see we have a short terminal here
excuse me which clear the market could
reach for
so we could aim for below the slow here
and then it previously is low
and where do we place our stops in this
example
we've recently had a run on buy stops
and this one here and on this shorts am
I here so because we had a run on bicep
here anyone who was buying here their an
hour chart so we don't see the market
run above the eye of this range first
stop goes above here so we can use this
again our stop is above the farewell Gap
and also above the bearish auto block
and also above the short-term high so
that is two period areas above this one
here what are the period areas other
block and
a rejection block right again a
rejection box also a pediary two so
autoblock rejection block ourselves goes
above that and
we're aiming for previously slow
okay we're in it for appears this low
and the market offers us that the moment
we see the split again I want to talk
about trade Management on the next video
because this model or this video is just
part one which discusses the model
itself part two talks about management
and everything like the other burning
part of trading
they can tell the market delivers and
eventually I think around on the close
it gets down into
uh let's see
gets down to our Target objective
now let's get rid of this and let's see
what happens on
day two
all right so that this is usually by the
way last week Tuesday on pound that's
what we saw
and
now going into Wednesday we've seen the
market close below 50 of the
inefficiency
now that means that there's a very
strong possibility that we trade into
this as a Target internal liquidity
there
okay so now you can see how it's not one
Java buys and data time frame it's just
end there and that's just it that's just
your bonus
every single day you have to constantly
confirm that the market is showing a
willingness want to get down there the
rock is not showing that Williams want
to change with your daily program or
your anticipated in the program then
again I've mentioned before I thought
the market is setting up manipulation or
the market your bias is just wrong just
wrong with price
deliver program for uh Tuesday which is
this one here this entry here
is our standard reaccumulation program
okay standard Recreation program here
whereby we're trading a fair ball Gap
Center recognition at premium or seven
short there
now again with the next day's trading
we're not really concerned with what
prices do it we have our key levels here
which is this daily inefficiency then we
have this daily inefficiency also here
and we have the premise of that daily
inefficiency
discount low and consequent
encroachments we're going to identify
Consular cultural here
they will do the same thing again we're
not really interested in what the market
does until our time without opportunity
and now our time Windows opportunity
starts here
here until here is what we're concerned
with looking for or hunting our model
so I'm gonna go back start from the time
all right so you can see here
heading into our
session start we've already seen the
spaceman lower
um one thing I also failed to confirm
here and which again I did not really
bother with is the Run above the B9 open
price and session open price I'm not
going to do them in the examples here
because this video is already
1R 18 minute long 18 minutes long all
right so I don't want this video to be
too long
um so I wanted to go and do this
yourself just go on your chart look for
a 12 family night New York 7 A.M
midnight uh morning New York and draw
them out and see how the market runs
against those levels for expanding
version of autofill
and here really I'm not going to trade a
day like this I'll talk about this on
video too so when London is overextended
so when I mean over extend I mean when
London has expanding integration of our
buys by hundreds of tips usually it's
done it's daily range for the day and
New York sessions low probability so
I'll teach you when to filter out
trading sessions like this okay there
are very specific conditions for when
not to trade during New York even though
your daily bias is correct like maybe
um
if we see a lack of symmetry during
London session or during like fomc NFP
or when London sessions over extended
during peers like this we don't trade
New York sessions because that lowers
the probability of continuation but now
let's just see our price delivers for
New York session all right so we see
bear snazz and we see more bears instant
primes but again does it really offer
anything significant
let's look at the range from the open
price
to the end of New York session about 26
Pips and this is why I don't trade New
York after I see over extension
during London session I'm going to show
you more examples on video too but this
is already a long one or it is a long
video
all right so I'm gonna remove all of
this and let's see how Wednesday this is
what is available let's say our
Wednesday's uh Kendall closed and
continue to confirm that
all right so now you can see on the
Wednesday we traded for this level here
we have this smaller differential Gap
let's identify the small overall Gap
here now it's very clear that the market
streams with our buys right and the bias
is looking for a bearish short-term
retracement from this high extension
level now what I wanted your attention
to is look at how the market forms
expansion around these key higher time
from levels that's why they are key in
terms of your price delivery now we have
a smaller farewell Gap year
look at how the low obviously candle
forms inside our typing level and then
we have a final Target objective here
which is that Weekly block
and now we can go into lower time frame
and continue the scene profile
and this is Thursday as far as action by
the way I will identify our winner of
opportunity which is this sign
and
this sign and we fast forward to those
times oh no let's go back actually
all right so now we're fast forwarding
to those slimes and what you can see is
obviously daily program is bearish for
our program is bearish one hour program
is fairs this is what we like to see all
right now here we have to wait we're
anticipating in the programs to bearish
but in a situation like this and this is
what usually happens when the market is
about to make the high or low for the
week and this is really important I want
you to write Zion you know when the
market is about to make the all your
load for the week the market is will see
a very extreme run against your intended
buys into a higher time frame premium or
a discount
I like to see things like this because
that sets the stage for the week we've
seen a run lower and now getting into
Thursday's price action
we have everything all aligned we have
the previous look here we have our
weekly objective down here
we have Source liquidity and what I like
even more is you can see the high for
the day which actually comes during
Asian session forms around this old
daily bullet Chevalier which now becomes
an inversion level look at the
consequent encryption of that level that
has become an inversion level and that
sourcing the I4 now if you go back to
the checklist
we want to see the higher love that they
form around key daily or weekly levels
that's what you see here
Tuesday
that's what I see here
on Monday
that's what we see here on the last two
weeks Friday
these Avatar repeating every single time
it's repetitive
that's why of this checklist you know
that you have to follow through anyways
let us continue with uh what we're
seeing all right so now we have a 1R
bearish autoblock
there's a trade up into this parachute
book here
Okay so
we actually have a 1R propulsion candle
all right so we're very sure the block
trades up there propulsion block we
don't necessarily need to see the market
straight up into this
and then we have an old inefficiency so
I have a smaller inefficiency within I
know my choice are to get me a little
bit
so inside Let's uh
this a little bit duh like this so
inside this daily level we have a
smelling inefficiency
and I always go down to a lower time
frame on the 15 20 frame so we have a 1R
inefficiency like this and we have what
when our proportion was so we don't
necessarily need to see the market trade
up into the proportion block when do you
not want to see the market trade up into
a
auto block so this is a form of a
bearish of the block which is what we
call propulsion block which forms after
the market creates an autoblock And
Trades up into that that's when you get
a proportion candle usually with
proportion candles the market sees very
extreme displacement because it's in the
name propulsion
fast delivery now we don't necessarily
need to see the market trade up into the
propulsion candle because we have a
balanced price range here so the balance
fraction should act as a stiff
resistance in price and not necessarily
shared up into this
now we'll go on a lower time frame
um the same time frame unless all the
market forms there we have a
lower time frame bearish other block and
a fair value Gap here now let's see the
opening price for the session
this is the session opening price what
we like to see is we'll access the
market Trader above the session opening
price
for our trade
all right so you can go into lower time
from here like a five minute time frame
again our executions form around a five
or 15 minute time frame
and what you can see here is you can see
the market is consolidating around that
opening price
and then
you have a hot here
we have a look actually this is open
price you have uh here low here take
your range from from the high all the
way down to the low
concentrate above
50 yes it does
again because this is going to act as a
stiff resistance in price you don't want
to see the market lose that bounce price
range
and guess what
that balance project on the one hour
time frame aligns with
a five minute sell selling balance bison
efficiency now what have I taught you
with protocols using this is and CVS
until the market runs an immediate your
own liquidity which would be the
previously is low here you do not want
to see the market close above the
consequent encroachment of that
efficiency
again cities and business are different
from fair value gaps they are a former
Fair volatile but they're different from
regular free Valentines they have
different cell protocols same way a
bounce fraction has a different set of
protocols with a fair Volga now with a
classic fair bow Gap we can anticipate
the entire range of that inefficiency
getting filled and still seeing
displacement but with CBS and buses and
balanced price ranges the protocols are
similar we don't like to see the market
trade completely through the
inefficiency until we run a level of
immediate liquidity which is sales sell
liquidity down here so we can trade
this level here because it is at a
premium with our stop
again where do you want to stop to be
above that
we have a city number one rather
farewell number so we have an auto block
number three so one two PD areas above
our period area of execution that's our
stock goes above
and we're aiming foreign
all the way down there to make money we
can take some partials off here but we
can leave a portion on for this target
objective and look at what
let's see what the market does and we
get the expansion and here supporters
come off here the old sick parts I'll
talk about partials on video so there's
actually supposed to be two videos
and then finally I don't know what
happens next uh but again consider more
the first session and if you took all
your profits
excuse me blow that low down there
that is an easy to almost three to one
versus reward I think the market
eventually drops out there during
monitors which it does I'll teach this
I'll teach profit taking using time and
price on video two so I'm going to write
this down my notes in terms of things to
talk about on video two videos is going
to be a lesson on modular thinking and
psychology and on lesson two we're gonna
talk about profit taking
okay we're gonna talk about
low probability conditions conditions
that will reduce the probability of your
trig and means you don't execute in
those kind of conditions
we're also going to talk about
um
stop placements
all right so
this this video took me four hours to
prepare and around almost two hours to
record it's one hour 30 minutes right
now so far to prepare 1R 10 minutes
record so I hope I really really hope
this video changes everything for you in
your Trading
and if you enjoyed this video I would
like for you to leave a feedback on my
Twitter you can find my Twitter in the
description below and thank you all for
being a part of this video I'll see you
on the video too and trade safe thank
you