thank you
notebooks
welcome back this is going to be a
Brief Review and then a short little
tutorial or amplification if you will
of my ICT breaker
so right away we're looking at the
dollar Index is a weekly chart
let's see the
inefficiency here between those candles
hello and this candle is high we worked
up inside of that
and had pretty much an indecisive candle
so it was kind of a
lackluster trading session for dollar
last week
this range in here I'd like to see it
prove to me that it wants to go higher
or lower and to go higher it needs to
get above the rejection block
here so the close of this candle
if it trades above that then I believe
will resume going higher
if we take out this low then I'm going
to look for liquidity below here because
we're in the middle of the range
the range being the low the high it's
indecisive it's not one-sided it's not
easy to see which side the marketplace
is going to reach for so when it's like
this we sit still we try not to force
our will or impose a a bias that's not
necessarily
predetermined yet
all right so here is daily chart
you can see again this is at weekly fair
value Gap the bodies were just outside
of that range and there's another reason
why I'm elected to
sit still not really have a hard bias
going into the new week here it's also
fourth July in the United States
the volume may be affected by that
greatly so I believe the latter part of
this week will be the real cleanest
price action
so we'll be looking for Price action
post Wednesday
daily fair value get down here you can
see it reached into that we mentioned
that as a downside draw
previously in previous commentary
and then we lose from this liquidity
below this low and inefficiency remember
price only goes down from one of those
two reasons and it rallies back up into
the short-term premium relative to
High
and the low midpoint in here
the beneficiency on the weekly chart
being transposed to the Daily you can
see that's where we drew into now that's
going to provide the backdrop for shorts
in year a dollar and pound dollar
here's euro dollar on
the weekly chart
weekly inefficiency
okay basically the opposite of what we
saw
one dollar Index as you would expect the
CE of this Wick
here
we treat Wicks as a gap this like the
algorithm no so the market saw the
weekly High form right at the previous
week's CE of its
premium
right here
and again indecisive
weekly range by trading down into a
discount
by seven balance cell sign efficiency
which is framed by the
eye of this candle and the lower that
candle so we traded down into it and
then back into
the weekly range
those weekly ranges apply to the daily
chart you can see how we traded up into
Friday Thursday Wednesday Tuesday high
of the week
where did it form the hide the week in
the previous week's CE on this weekly candle don't
take my word for it
go into it and you'll see it right here
all right let's drop down into
an hourly chart on Euro all right so you
can see how we worked
lower here here is that run onto the
previous weeks CE
oh it's wick on the weekly chart
creating the high on Tuesday if we're
bearish
we have a senate 70 likelihood of
creating
the high
on Tuesday
and we see it trading up into that CE
breaks down finds some support at the
old
fairy GAP orange and the higher time
frame try to rally and give up the ghost
broke lower
so we have
breaker in here down there it looks
rather sloppy and I'll be teaching a
little bit more about
Breakers in the united portion of this
lecture
so all of this run here
extend that over
you can see we're hitting that perfectly
there and it just so happens to be near
the upper end of that Odin efficiency so
we're blending a lot of things
in terms of inefficiency and buy side
liquidity eyesight would be resting
above this short term High here so we
round above
back into
a premium array which is a breaker
trades up into it and aggressively sells
off attacking the sell side below this
low and down into that low here and into
that discount pair that you got then
once we got into it we returned quickly
back up into the premium
if everybody got the Shaded in Orange I
promise you if you take the information
I showed you on the higher time frame on
your own chart it'll drop down to these
lower time frame charts like this you'll
see Euros was beautifully handled with
the elements I'm teaching in terms of
short-term premium High short term
discount low inefficiency of both
Marketplace inefficiency below the
marketplace
and day of the week
and then the opposite end of the range
forming here on Friday
[Music]
11 15 minute timer brain
you can see that we have
a very nice drop here
and the rally up now all of this back
and forth in here that's not a concern
for me
you might be looking at this saying okay
well isn't this a breaker from high to
low to higher high no
the range from this high down to that
low up that high
all of this price action from the high
to the low to the high right there I'm
ignoring all of this this is time
distortion you have to look at the time
of day when the highs are forming the
algorithm refers to time first not just
simply because there's a price run so
we're looking at high low higher high
this movement down here
that's where the Secret Sauce is if you
will
I'll get to that later on
but that down closed candle right there
that is the sweet spot right in here if
you extend that forward
that's where it's hitting that now we're
cutting through candles because we are
not supplying demand it's the fallacy
the market trades up into a cranium
relative to the range from high to low
and we're also reaching into the upper
portion of the Shaded Orange
inefficiency
breaker cut through candles bang hit it
what time of day New York open
aggressively runs for the sell side here
and the sell side liquidity
in the higher time frame and into that
discount care value
once it enters that then the algorithm
pulls right back up into the middle of
the range range being
the high and low of the week
and now we're in consolidation inside of
that premium for Vega
all right moving right along this is the
e-mini s p weekly chart
and I mentioned that we try to reach up
into
this weekly volume balance and we just
fell short of it it looks like it
touched it here but I promise you it
didn't get there it got real close to it
though but it's been acting as a drawing
liquidity as you remember
the NASDAQ reached up into its volume
balances on its weekly chart but we were
waiting for the sixth sister effect on s
p to draw this
specific index higher and we have seen
it deliver like gangbusters so bias
starts on a weekly chart we have to know
where it's likely to reach for and then
what we're doing is trying to predict
yes unfortunately we do try to predict
we don't react to price we need to
predict the likely expansion in the
weekly chart I'm not trying to pick the
closing price I have totals for that I'm
not trying to
demand that it closes on the high or the
low we don't need that
but we want to know where it's likely to
expand higher or lower
if you look real close there was a small
little inefficiency right there
between the previous weeks low
and this week's High
so that little inefficiency right there
it's more opened traded down into that
and it Rockets up taking out the
short-term high but drawing into this
area here
okay so I suspect that's still probably
a factor for this week
on the daily chart you can see we have
this inefficiency here and this
inefficiency here now I sent the Tweet
out now a week and a half ago stating
that these were the two reference points
I liked that initially at the time of
the tweet I said I favored the low end
we went down into it the top of the
market was not called by me I don't try
to do that when we're in primary buy
models
so we're looking for lungs
reaching for Discount and then expanding
into inefficiencies of the ball
Marketplace or by solid liquidity the
buy side would be resting right above
here and inefficiency would be the
weekly volume unbalance both being above
market price at the beginning of the
week and price Drew up higher throughout
the week so each individual day if you
would have been focusing only on longs
that's what you're doing you're
filtering out in the best case scenario
where the higher time frame weekly chart
is suggesting price may go ultimately
we stay with that bias each day every
session we go in looking for a reason to
be long when there's a buy program
underway and that's what we're seeing
here
[Music]
zooming in on the daily chart I want you
to see how we were beautifully delivered
into this candles hi you see that
trading right there and perfect delivery
rallies up and then we have this area
here which is a premium when it was down
here it was a premium for your value got
but if we're expecting to go higher
my anticipation is we're going to take
out this high and gravitate towards that
Weekly volume imbalance so the buy
program would send us into discovery of
buy side and premium volume and balance
you would grade this range with 25 50
and 75 percent respective levels or
gradients and you would treat each one
of them as a Target
well we only got As far as the buy side
here and just fell short of touching the
low end of that Weekly volume of valence
but this right here as we're climbing
back up into this range if you're
familiar with my market maker buy and
sell model I know that is not wake off
this area here that inefficiency
which will be reach for if we're bullish
we're expecting to expand through that
that will become my inversion pair value
cap find that in your Wyckoff textbooks
so there's our levels we're going to
show in two sets of
small little trend lines and we'll drop
down the lower time frame
right so we have the market trading down
into the lower fair value you got and
then we have an expansion higher and in
all of this range right there at range
is the last up close candle within the
low high lower low which trades into
what the inefficiency these two red
lines here
that's the lower discount for your value
you got the one I was telling you a week
and a half ago almost two weeks ago but
I favored the lower one and the market
did drop down into it then we have a
displacement to the upside
taking out short-term high if you're
aggressive you can use that high which
one do you do you use ICT whichever one
I'm trusting at the time
so if you want to be a conservative
Trader demanding a lot more behind the
trades then you would use this one here
so why that one because it's the hot
it's the high between this low
and this low which is a bullish breaker
so you could expand that to the right
and as price rallies about
comes down to find some support multiple
times here
then rallies up consolidates takes out
sell side there wants a stop run occurs
the market should expand higher it does
rip through that
premium fair value Gap that we would
expect to see it trade to and look at
that look at the bodies respecting the
high end of that inversion favorite you
have it does not need to trade down into
it it can
but these are instances where sometimes
when you'll see medium executions I'm
recording it I'll say it's better for
these inefficiencies or that particular
fair value Gap to remain unfilled
we want to see this be treated
as a measuring Gap or a breakaway Gap so
it's only necessary for me or you to see
this area right in here Provide support
we're seeing that in the body's clothes
and the body's opening and then for
traction
the inefficiency here doesn't look
inefficient on the lower time frame
hourly chart that it was based on what
the daily chart so you have to transpose
those levels under your lower time
frames otherwise you'll lose all the
plot narrative and storyline behind why
price should be reacting or drawing to
specific levels so that right there
would have been an area where I would
add if I was trading in many s p and
looking for a reason to go long and add
more say for instance say you bought uh
the breaker down here
and you wanted to see it rip through
this fair value cap anyone that simply
looks at gaps and price charts now you
may think that every inefficiency is a
buy or sell they lose the idea of
knowing where price is ultimately trying
to reach for which is the number one
rule I teach as my students coming in I
that press that very hard as your main
focus because it's going to be the one
that you're going to utilize for the
rest of your career that gives you all
the comfort and confidence to know what
you're doing and how you're operating
being foolish or bearish bias comes by
understanding where the higher time
frame weekly draw on liquidity is
you can't watch a video and there's
nobody else out there going to show you
a real shortcut always a winner approach
it takes time understanding price action
what is it reaching for
and
this is enough
to Warrant an expansion higher and until
we find it
providing support remember it's this red
line here is the high of that fair value
Gap
let me go back up into the daily chart
I'm going to show you this little area
right here
are these two candles right there are
occurring
and finding support at the high end it's
this
it's that level right there which is the
high of that fair value Gap
and we're expecting price to go higher
so we're not looking for it to go up
here to go down that's not the that's
not the
2022 model okay we're using this as a
stepping
stone or a wrong on the ladder to
provide us a reason to see more
injection of higher prices
so we see that occurring right there
so that's a a really good signature even
if I didn't take a partial
entry and scaling in with you know like
a pyramiding position
by seeing that that comforts me
in terms of being on side so I can
anticipate the market reaching up into
that buy solid quarter day over there
and it reaches up into it and look at
the bodies respecting what that old High
yes we Wick through it yes we fall just
short of the weekly volume and Bounds
but we're not trying to demanded to get
there we offer ourselves up the
opportunity for our best case scenario
should it trade there
but we're open to the idea that it may
need to do that the following week
because it's doing this on a Friday
all right s p
15 minute Candlestick you can see a
really good
illustration of that run into that
inversion fair value Gap hits it and
rallies inefficiency trades down into it
here
at the open rips higher consolidates
trades higher once more digs into
showed you execution on Twitter and the
link will be obviously shared in the
comment section which I'll only be the
one commenting and yes I see your
comments when you leave them but it's
it's personal for me and I'm not trying
to broadcast your adoration for me
it's I don't need to share that but I
enjoy reading them
it rips into that buy side there
and then comes all the way back down
into the inefficiency here with this
cluster of order flow right there
that's where we settle on the day
so on the 15 minute time frame if you
look at this we have obviously been
looking for higher prices on NASDAQ and
on ES and I'm focusing primarily yes
because I've been teaching conceptually
the sixth sister Concepts that I have
and we've already seen the upside
leadership by NASDAQ so we have been
focusing on ES
to show how that
particular index has been drawn higher
in sympathy trying to catch up to what
was delivered with the Run higher in
NASDAQ
so because we're published we want to
look for periods where there is
accumulation
accumulation of logs so we can see what
we have a low and a lower low in es
on NASDAQ we're seeing a Divergence
there NASDAQ say no I'm not willing to
make that lower low like we did in s p
respectively so this is smt Divergence
and we would expect price to go higher
if we were looking for the market to
trade with
the leadership issue
okay in other words say the NASDAQ
hadn't already established its dominance
higher
but it has been for weeks
and if this Divergence here then I would
have been trading NASDAQ but because
NASDAQ has already done a lot of upside
and I'm trading the six sister approach
the fact that we have this Divergence
down here which is a lower low but not
lower low in NASDAQ you're probably
wondering why wouldn't you trade in
NASDAQ you're not incorrect by doing
that
but I'm teaching you by using the sixth
sister approach that by sympathy this is
going to try to trade higher and a
little bit more
I don't want to say stronger but more
reliable because NASDAQ has already done
its upside delivery
so
the s p is basically going to have its
Better Days Ahead which is what we saw
last week well knob side so I would view
this low being taken out there as a stop
run and that's how you trust a turtle
soup entry okay buying sell stops and
this would be simply just buying the
stronger leadership issue at the time
and you wouldn't be incorrect by doing
it because you can see it does in fact
rally but look at the delivery of price
in comparison between the two
a lot more willingness to show it wants
to go higher because look we rallied
higher and then come back down and
touched the high end of that fair value
gap which is this red level here and now
we also have that breaker
extending It Forward inside of that
range
we can meet buying has a lot of support
of
discount behind this entry area here and
at the same time look what's occurring
in NASDAQ it's really muddy meaning that
it's not so sure footing
compared to that one where we have a
higher low here we don't see the higher
low here it's a slopping consolidation
so here rips higher comes back and
really wants to go Higher One More Time
touch to the inversion for your value
Gap and it's the low of the bullish
breaker and it rips higher and
consolidates the rest of the day and
then we have another confirmation that
we're looking for a higher delivery in
price
low lower low so this is a stop run
below those lows here so that's a run-on
sell side liquidity and it touches the
breaker bullish breaker
the same time NASDAQ is unwilling to
make a lower low that's smt it's telling
you that there's accumulation there's a
cracking correlation and this will never
stop working the markets will always
have these types of inefficiencies when
prices are running out highs and lows
respectively if you have a bias if you
know you're looking for higher prices
and you see these confirmations that's
what this is this is not a timing tool
it's not a selection tool it's a
confirmation
okay because we're using smt as a
qualifier
to indicate that we are in fact on one
side by trying to be bullish
and we can use this idea to
if you're a turtle soup type Trader if
you're
trying to train yourself to buy sell
stocks or sell buy stops
that means you're doing a run against
the existing
pending orders above the marketplace or
below the marketplace without this
Insight without understanding of where
the Market's going to go to
you're going to find it trading a turtle
soup pattern or a false Breakout
and Trigger it in the opposite direction
it's going to be very difficult for you
to do that and it's scary but this is
how you learn how to do it and you have
to do months of this type of analysis
then you can go in there and just buy
sell stops and sell buy stops and you've
seen me do executions of that recording
it
the primary function of smt behind this
is supporting the idea that we are in a
buy program and it's okay to keep
focusing on Longs or yes
so the market goes higher again another
area here
higher low
or low
so what is this this is reaching for the
relative equal lows for the sell side so
this is a run on sell side liquidity so
a Trader using NASDAQ they could use
that as a long entry
same here
buying sell side but we're seeing what
relative strength now show up in yes
higher low
or low
it's the time of the week where the
market wants to reach for it's
finale it's reaching high up into the
June 16 2023 High which is this level
right here and gravitating towards that
Weekly volume of balance which is that
blue shade of air here it's not shown
the entire range because I want to have
all the details being shown here but
again look how it's treating the top end
of that inversion figure value on the
daily chart
hits it and then rips higher reaching
into that buys a liquidity above June 16
2023 is high and then
the added benefit of knowing that that
Weekly volume and balance shaded in blue
that's a large magnet for the algorithm
that we're going to reach up into that
because inefficiency
so when we're down here
down here
in here
over here
in here they're all points of reference
for you to either be long add to
existing positions if you're short-term
or a swing Trader or just confirming
that your own side for bias and then you
can look for lower time frame order flow
like for a silver bullet in the 10 clock
to 11 o'clock morning hour or 2 pm to 3
P.M afternoon Silver Bullet so there's a
lot of things you can do to work with
this information but I leave it to you
to determine how you're going to use it
for your particular model and you can
use the multiplier of your choice it
could be a optical trade entry it could
be a bull shorter block that you're
trading on you could be buying sell side
liquidity you can be doing inversion
fair value gaps Vector fair value gaps
institutional River flow entry drills
the the list is endless in terms of what
it is that you want to trade and
whatever that multiplier is which is a
PV array that I've taught that's your
entry model but this is the framework to
determine where the Market's going to go
and when it's going to be confirming to
you that it wants to go higher all right
I'm going to take all this other extra
stuff off here so you can see
the divergences lower higher
lower
higher
lower all indicating that it wants to go
higher now many times my students when
they first seen it destruction or
lecture video about smt they think that
they need to go into the charts and look
for the discrepancy or difference
between lower low and then there's no
lower low here okay that means they can
go long that's not how you use smt it is
a qualifier okay it just gives you
confirmation that
order flow is probably
not in the direction that you see the
lower low being made
when a higher low is being formed in a
market that you're anticipating to be
bullish anyway so we were looking for
this area up here for weeks we've been
calling this month actually a draw up
here for ES
so we've been bullish on ES for months
and finally we just fell short of it
here and I'm I'm not convinced that we
had the high form here so we're likely
to see it draw up into that going into
this week's Trading
all right so here is the five minute
chart on ES and I'm showing it in
regular trading hours
so that way we're showing that Gap right
here so this is where we settled on
Thursday and we opened up at 9 30 on
Fridays trading regular trading hours
so if you add the details in here I sent
a tweet out on June 30th 2023 at 9 52
a.m this is always a New York local time
and right there is the candle I made
that post on Twitter
I said that this high
44.93 and three quarters
that high right there is the daily June
16 2023 High I said that that buy side
is Juicy meaning that it's going to want
to gravitate towards that so how would
you use that information well you can
use it with
Fairway gaps bull shorter blocks buying
sell side liquidity below this lowest
one sell side so you could be a buyer
down there oh wait a minute ICT didn't
you say that these opening range gaps
they can draw price down in yes
but there's also
Tendencies for the market to have these
large range gaps because it's in a hurry
to get somewhere we're in a hurry get to
that Weekly volume and balance in shaded
blue and the bias on the court that told
you
right here
so we drop down ahead of lunch in your
lunch hour we took out sell side there
rallied created a fair value cap that's
what I'm showing you here
right there okay Market drops down into
that
perfectly and then rallies away and
attacks what this area of relative equal
high so this is their first initial by
solid liquidity then the larger pool of
liquidity is here on the daily chart
well in June 16 2023 that daily High you
see we gravitated towards there we
worked around that level and finally
punched up and just fell short by
reaching into that Weekly volume
imbalance and then finding the last
portion of the day
the market rips back into the range and
trades into this inefficiency between
these two primary candles which is a 10
minute Fair Vega
zooming in here on a five minute chart
again here's where I said that we would
be looking for a draw to 44 93.75 buy
side this level right here is that high
on the daily chart
the market gravitates from this point
here
all the way up into that level there so
you do not look for shorts here you
don't lose your mind and become fearful
because we have a huge opening range gap
on Friday with unfinished business that
June 16th has buy side it wanted it
I indicated that here no other time
frame on Friday that I point to a lower
Target I did not say another level that
failed to hit okay we talked about this
as a draw on liquidity the weekly volume
balance but I gave a very specific level
for targeting
so when we look for
the
directional bias
to come into effect we're looking for
higher prices we did get a stop run on
sell side there and then we've seen
price go higher and inefficiency it
comes back down into it now we're in
lunch so where's the buy side
above here
so above those relative equal highs
that's what this is right there we're
down in a one minute chart now so 44.87
and a half that's buy side here is that
five minute
pure Bay Gap
I will be teaching and talking about
this coming week
the 11 50 to 12 10 macro it's a time of
day where the algorithm will begin a
price run it runs for liquidity
South Side is here it drops down right
there and then goes higher let me take
it back up to the five minutes that way
you know where you're at and get your
bearings
we're looking at this run here and drop
down between these two blue lines
targeting that initially but ultimately
above
the June 16 2023 so that those levels
here we're going to look at all this
price action and this run up here right
now it's on a five minute chart looking
at it now on a one minute chart it looks
like this here's the relative equal
highs
the drop down below the lowest sell sign
is and then at 11 50 the 12 10 the
algorithm will begin its buy model it
will run higher trades into the
inefficient it doesn't look like an
inefficiency here on a one minute chart
does it which is the reason why you have
to cycle through time frames
you have to be able to go through a five
four three two one minute chart when
you're day trading because you'll see
the inefficiency that the market will
reprice to
and then once it does that perfectly and
it's the time of day when we'd expect
what the lunch run on liquidity that's
here and we're blending not only is the
lunch hour
macro reaching up for the buy side but
it's also this would be a run in the
same direction of our higher time frame
bias reaching for
the June 16th High because in normal
instances like say little bearish we
would see the market rip up into here
take out the buy side and then work
lower because we're embarrassed cell
program on the higher time frame charts
we're not in a bearish Cell program
we're in a higher time frame bullish buy
program meaning that that shaded Blue
Area up here that Weekly volume
imbalance and the old high on June 16
2023 about that high is going to be buy
side someone went short large funds have
liquidity above there what kind buy side
buy stops they're protecting they were
holding shorts the algorithm runs
against that it's not running against
you
okay it's not looking for your order
it's going for where the large fund
liquidity is or it's running for a
higher time frame inefficiency which is
also
conveniently allowing that algorithm to
reprice against
the buy side liquidity resting above
June 16 2023
so this run higher it gets into here and
then you see there's a first partial
right above relative equal highs I'm
holding you want to catch the big runs
the big rips higher and lower and get
the lines portion of the daily range
that's what I've shown here
first partial here then I took the idea
of
the high here to that high and I did
gradients and you'll see that in the
execution video I want to see it reach
up into those levels and I layered out
the odors and then I had one up in here
and I had one ultimately just below the
weekly volume of mouse to see if it can
reach for it as the best case scenario I
didn't get that again and I'll come back
down and stop me out here on the final
single contract
[Music]
if you look at the
diagram here
this is my bearish breaker
this is not a break and retest okay it's
not an Fu candle it's not a like off it
is a schematic in terms of understanding
how runs on liquidity and then a
repricing lower occurs so what we need
to know is
where is liquidity
and there's two ways to use the breaker
this is a bearish breaker and what we're
understanding with this diagram is
there's obviously when you have a market
that is predisposed to go lower if
you're anticipating the market going
lower if you're looking for a bear
Market to provide a additional entry or
a point of reference for
pyramiding new short positions this is
what you're looking for okay this is one
of the strongest PD arrays I have
because the
characteristic behind this PD array is
that it is acting on pending orders so
if you've ever traded and had your stop
run hit and then see it run in your
favor after your stop loss was hit
that's what this pattern capitalizes on
it really takes you into the marketplace
in terms of a narrative
to attack the ill-informed or retail
Trader that tries to look for
continuations
some kind of trend following model if
they have no idea where liquidity is and
what narrative is and why that market
should be going lower they get many
times trapped by this move they will be
caught being a buyer of a breakout above
a short-term High
and then it only goes up to a higher
time frame Buy sell liquidity where the
actual reversal occurs
there's two stages of liquidity for the
highest form of precision with my
breaker you'll always have the
short-term by side liquidity of all the
short-term High
but it's going to want to reach into a
higher time frame by solid liquidity and
then you're waiting to see if it runs
away from that
and then inside of this price Lake from
A to B that right there is what you're
looking for for targeting
now I haven't taught this before this is
the first time even my charter members
and my private mentorship which nobody
can join anymore and I don't even make
videos for them anymore okay the only
thing they get to do is ask me questions
so this A to B leg
we're ignoring all this this is market
for traction okay this is the
manipulation
so with this out of the equation okay
think of this as
time distortion
it's running from the low to the high to
get that liquidity but once it does that
ignore it for a second because this is
not the 2022 model 2022 is something
entirely different where you would use
this price like oh you're confusing the
ICT I understand
if you watch the videos there's two
different approaches being used okay
we're using the price Lake from A to B
once this Market creates this run here
and starts to drop down
if I trust
that I'm on silent that means I'm
bearish okay I'm inspecting lower prices
I'm already
going short when it runs above the buy
side
it may not be my biggest position I
might scale in a larger portion I'll
give you an example um the model I've
been showing you
with trading ES
I'll go in and trade six contracts first
and then I'll add three and then I'll
add one for a 10 lot position so I'm
scaling in this type of trade here I
would go in with one
add three in here
and then six on a really good run into
the breaker
I'm building in
the likelihood of even if I'm wrong
and it goes against me on the six
contracts I have three and one
that help offset or mitigate most of the
drawdown that would be occurring if it
was to quickly reverse and take out that
high I'm not suggesting that you should
trade that way but I am trying to teach
you a little bit more in terms of an
amplification of the breaker pattern
because there's a lot of people on
YouTube a lot of people making courses
of internships and they really don't
know what you're doing and they're
really misguiding people
so to keep you from doing that and to
correct you this is this lesson's for
I'll have a lot more details about these
PDA rays in my books but uh I want to
give this today this A to B
price lag you take that leg from the
high down to the low and you lay your
Fibonacci on that and then you you do
your standard deviations lower
whatever this range is from here to here
one standard deviation lower that is the
easiest bread and butter approach to
using the breaker if you're
on side and you know you're looking for
it and you're in a fair market you don't
need it to come down into this level
here and trade back up many times you'll
see me annotate a breaker and I'm
entering in this price Lake Running
lower before it even breaks out that low
because I'm not a breakout Trader I'm
not a break and retest Trader and so
everybody thinks that I'm I'm chilling
when I do a breaker no they have no idea
you have no idea if you think that you
put zero understanding what I'm doing
I could be selling short throughout this
entire range using the 2022 model
and then use the breaker as an
additional area where I can add in
pyramid more or I can simply just wait
for it to come back down or you could do
that if you want to be very conservative
wait for it to provide some means to go
back up here now here's what you're
afraid of
what happens if I go short here and it
goes right up here or goes into my stop
loss and stops me out
you take a loss how's that for logic
then you consider does it still want to
go lower if it does and nothing's
changed you just got stopped out you
just go in again with half the position
size that you used on your first trade
that's all you do folks you're not going
to avoid a losing trade it's going to
happen you will lose okay I have losing
trades if I trade it every single day
every single session and try to trade
everything I've ever taught
invariably I would have losing trades
but what I have done over 30 years is
I've determined the ones I really favor
based on the Dynamics in the marketplace
at the time the present narrative where
it's likely to go where's the next
drawing liquidity what day of the week
it is what time frame what session all
those things it's 30 years behind me
doing that so when I talk about things
in advance on Twitter and I show you
executions I'm leaning on that 30 years
experience
that you don't have 30 years experience
and I'm not trying to talk down or be
condescending but if I try to do
everything all the time and through a
kitchen sink approach like many of you
try to do and you get frustrated
I'm looking at the best scenarios
because I have the experience to
determine it your time learning to use
these tools you will do that over time
too
it may not take you 30 years obviously
but I'm telling you it's going to take
you much longer than you probably
anticipate or hope to see it require and
it's okay that's normal everyone gets
excited about you want to go out there
and try to use it right away
but you're also dealing with the most
ruthless industry in this world
the financial markets they're they're
not easy for a reason if it was easy
everybody would be doing it but there's
language I'm teaching you allows you to
go in and see where there are
opportunities for you to go in and
exploit these inefficiencies or
imbalances
obviously like everything I teach
everything can be reversed and what we
want to see here if we're bullish
this could be a reversal pattern or it
could be a continuation in an existing
bull market okay so if we're present in
their buy program and we're expecting
higher prices this can be used intraday
any time frame by the way these patterns
form but you have to understand where
there's liquidity and the best Breakers
are going to see two levels of sell side
obviously the short term that would be
created with the short term though here
in the rally up and then a lower drop
into a much more significant or a higher
time frame South Side liquidity so
there's two pools of liquidity that's
being engaged here it's this one by by
default that makes the breaker and then
we're seeing it reach into another level
qualifier that I like to see is I
already anticipate this liquidity here
lower
drawn liquidity and I love when it goes
down real close to it and starts to
Rally because I know what that's doing
it's enticing folks to see that that's a
time to go long and this we're on higher
Engineers more liquidity below that well
it makes this a much more juicier
liquidity pool so it drops aggressively
down in here once it takes that sell
side out I could be going long if I'm
extremely bullish if on one side I'm
trusting all my analysis everything is
indicating that this Market whatever it
is is going to go higher I will buy
those sell stops
now you may not have the confidence to
do that that's okay you can treat this
price room here
you can use the model 2022 to enter in
that
any fair value you got in here that
forms you can anticipate that that run
or use the rules that takes out this
High here
any retracement back then later into
that price run that would be a 2022 real
rules but I can be entering in this
without any need to take out the higher
but once it gets down here my eye goes
right to that leg from A to B and I run
standard deviations off of that and the
easiest bread and butter setup would be
is using the low to the high
being long in here or somewhere in here
with a fair value gap for institutional
order flow entry drill or inversion for
your value got something in this leg
here there will be a fair bag up or two
back above it
find some support
Target here and then two
legs of this run so in other words
whatever this low is to this High add it
to this high up so that would be one
standard deviation of this price range A
to B that is the easiest easiest just
bread and butter set up you can
literally carve out an income a career
just with that but the wonderful thing
is it's not limited to that little ICT
is going to teach you how you take this
information and supercharge it if you
understand where the Market's going to
go on a higher time frame if you're
utilizing something like this pattern
here to get in sync with a higher time
frame buy model
you can then use the standard deviations
between point a and point B and see if
they agree with a larger higher time
frame pool of liquidity you may be
utilizing for the ultimate bias
or Draw that you're reaching for based
on the entire time frame trade
so I'll give you examples that
all right so here we are looking at
where we have opened for this week
presently we are at
July 2nd 2023 it's five minutes after
six on this candle here time in New York
is
almost 10 minutes after six always have
your charts shown on treating you within
New York
session there
so here we have
the low behind this is the five minute
chart by the way low high lower low so
this is a breaker
inside of this price Lake from a
to B remember we're bullish we're
looking for the run from this low to
high to do our standard deviations
I already went through the idea of
buying it here because we could be
buying inside this Lake right there we
don't need to see this High broken and
shaded back to this support that is one
way of using a breaker but when you
understand where the Market's likely to
go you can trade in this run before it
happens so you're you're not becoming a
break and retest type Trader like many
of the critics will say that I'm
teaching you to be no and I'm not a very
common test Trader
but this low to high to lower low if you
take that a
to B leg you're ignoring this as a run
on liquidity
so all this is time Distortion this drop
down
is both manipulation and time Distortion
you are getting knocked out if you're
long and using this as a stop loss the
mark comes back down reprices that level
does the Dirty Work of knocking those
traders that have a sell stop
below here when they're long but maybe
briefly profitable and then drops down
goes against them stops them out most
Traders will not want to go back in if
you did take a trade like that you get
stopped down you wait for this type of
scenario here where it creates an
imbalance once it does that you can be a
buyer right there and trust that we've
already did a stock run with this run
here below that low but A to B price lag
you use that for your standard
deviations
if I show you the FIB right away you
guys can see it if you want to take
notes and that's what my FIT looks like
okay from here to here you start running
some areas where you have standard
deviation of negative one so that's one
standard deviation
this leg from here to here projected
higher so it's a measured move
you're not measuring from here to here
you're measuring here to here so it
gives you 44.96 and a half that is easy
easy easy bread and butter set up for
entry right there
we don't even need this High to be
broken but
inside this price leg we're using the up
close candles
more specifically if you look at it like
this
we have this level here so I'm going to
annotate that
okay so you can see it now I'll take
this off
this down closed candle right there that
disrupts this price run so it's this
range right there we would use all of
that to be a buyer we would use all that
range there for a return back into the
breaker
so this is what you classically see
in some of my recordings where I'll show
if if I think that we're going to go
higher and need to pull back into a
larger retracement
we wouldn't want to expect that to hear
because it's number one it's Friday of
last week it's really close to that June
16th High anyway so we don't want to see
any deep retracements
so what makes me comfortable buying
inside of the price leg before a breaker
is ever
qualified
based on my initial teachings in it and
then you see it usually come back and
retest it and then Ron it rallies higher
we don't need that I don't need that
sometimes you'll see me annotate the
breaker and I'm getting along right in
here and adding to an existing position
or entering right away from there
because I understand that I'm on side
everything is indicated once I run to a
pool liquidity or an efficiency above
the marketplace and I'm including the
idea that we're on Friday so the
Market's going to be in a hurry to get
to that liquidity and draw maybe up into
that Weekly volume imbalance so we have
two real strong factors acting like a
magnet a draw on liquidity pulling price
up so the algorithm keeps repricing
higher it doesn't matter how many people
come in selling short it does not matter
what that volume is
all the sellers can come in all they
want
all the book maps all the level two
indicators of showing that there's a lot
of you know sellers that want to you
know come in the market doesn't matter
the market is on this key repricing
higher higher higher higher and you
can't fight that
so all this Insight here
allows you to differentiate how we use
my breaker
there is not just one approach to using
it you have to understand the narrative
the day of the week all the factors
involved and blending a lot of other
things which makes it a little bit more
complicated than your classic support
and resistance idea that you're already
failing with anyway because you can't
qualify retail support and resistance
based on what you see in books
with what I'm teaching you it helps
qualify very specific levels of dynamic
support and resistance
I'm not a support resistance Trader I
have
given you a language so that way you can
see how the algorithm itself that
delivers price will react and respect
specific price levels
now
if we take this information
and go one step further
we have
relative equal highs right in here
okay see that
so these relative equal highs what do we
see above this relative equal highs in
our mind we anticipate what by sound
liquidity so when it goes above it here
did it take out the buy side
at that 44.96 and a half that was
measured with this range here yet no
but we can now use this as a qualifier
for a new breaker so it could be
reaching up there to go lower and if it
was to do that
we can anticipate how far it's going to
retrace lower with the Friday
retracement we can use this information
with the breaker for targeting and not
that I would be want to go short
but we can frame if there is going to be
like a
TGIF trade where you anticipate the
market trading back into the weekly
range which is what we're seeing here
it needs to get to this liquidity before
it does that TGIF trade okay a lot of
you were anticipating on Twitter
reaching out to me saying TGIF is what
happened but you have to see it get to
the liquidity and fulfill its weekly
range before it wants to pull back in
so where does it
give us details for that if you look at
the high here which doesn't break above
that 44.96 and a half it trades to it
look at the high of that candle right
there
it's right here watch this one up here
it's exactly at 44.96 and a half folks
that's perfect remember that's this
A to B
it goes right to that level there but
doesn't go any higher
and it drops down
and it creates what
a breaker
right there
so now I'm not trying to go short I'm
watching and trying to see if they want
to reach up into here but how can you
use this information
if you want to be a TGI Trader and trade
inside the range or a weekly range as a
pullback
look at this breaker here
a b and this run higher this here is
this part of this run
so this is inside the range that would
take you above because look at the
bodies see if they're stopping these
little Mohawks that's what a mohawk is
by the way I ever have a level
identified on the chart if I say Mohawk
and I'm usually typing it out in advance
so we can anticipate this is going to
just do this and we expect that that's
reasonable okay there's going to be some
measure of coloring outside the lines
that you're going to have to be
comfortable with when you're trading and
I have ways of determining where that's
likely to occur my students are learning
that and you're learning it now too
the bodies are saying that okay we're
not done it's going to reach higher why
because this standard deviation of 44 96
and a half was just simply confirmed one
more time with the bodies that means
it's going to go higher
so we would still use this High to that
low Watch What Happens
a
to B why not this one this one's the
same one is this looked that low
44.91.25 you're looking right up here
that low is 44
91.25 it's the same low I'm showing here
40 44 91.25
but what I'm doing is I'm ignoring this
High here because it's unfinished it's
going to run higher it's either going to
go to the weekly volume bounce or one
not that high I don't need to know what
that is yet because the A to B leg is
already there
this one didn't go lower
but now Watch What Happens
how low can it retrace with TGIF
[Music]
two standard deviations
inside this inefficiency
inside of the breaker
get ready to drop your jaw
[Music]
sorry folks Dominion mentors trying to
teach my stuff don't have the authority
to do this you have
the range in which the breaker can pull
back into
the low when this candle comes in
exactly at 4480.75
standard deviation comes in at
4480.75 folks that's perfect that's not
Wyckoff that's not supply and demand
that's not any other thing out there
this is mine okay this is mine
you're listening to the guy who codified
it I am the person I'm the engineer I'm
the guy that put this together this
right there you're seeing it
okay I'm writing all the books that's
ever gonna be made around this right now
by teaching it they're all going to pair
it what you're hearing
but that's precision
you are not learning that
from anyone else look at the date
July 2nd 2023 everything changes with
Breakers after today
you don't know it yet so don't go out
there and start making videos with it
okay yeah you you're welcome to go out
and start making videos where you'll
observe this phenomenon that's that's
wonderful because that'll not only build
your confidence and share it with your
community
and you're part of my community whether
you like it or not and that is helpful
for you to teach yourself to see it
observe it that you're blending so many
things so many things come together
let's go down to a one minute chart
okay we're looking at a one minute chart
[Music]
okay so now we can see how we're
utilizing the upper portion of the
breaker here
one minute chart
you zero in on the change in the state
of delivery that last candle right there
inside that last candle I can be a buyer
anywhere in here I can use that order
block let me
let me change this okay you see it
better now see this down closed candle
right there it's inside of this breaker
it's the last up close candle when we're
in the lowest time frame so you want to
strip it down into the range remember we
showed this entire run here on the five
minute chart but for fine tuning your
entry it's the last up close candle
prior to the lower run to there
when it's trading in that range if I
have something else inside of this
little pocket of price action
[Music]
the ICT breaker
if we look at the high and the low
if we measure that range
okay and there's gradients to that
upper quarter fifty percent or mean
threshold because it's an order block
Theory Breakers are order blocks
and then the low and the lower quarter
okay
midpoint or mean threshold is
44.84.50 now if the algorithm is going
to allow price to be utilized there to
go long but for smart money for people
that see price
like this
what price does this Market need to
price to to get 44.84.50
it needs to at least print 4484.25
[Music]
inside of this consolidation it rallies
above it and drops back down what's the
low of that candle right there
44.84.25 that allows the spread to not
be a hindrance for a smart Lane to go
longer even if you don't take that as a
trade does the market show alone someone
will move away from that yes that's a
signature I'm watching that I'm seeing
price do that I'm going to see these
types of things come into the
marketplace to support the idea that
we're going to continuously grind
towards that buy sell liquidity and
maybe reach up into that Weekly volume
and balance
all of these things lead to a better
understanding of where price is going to
go and it's important for you to also
know that
once we're inside order flow we have
inefficiencies we've seen the long here
and then we're seeing an inefficiency
here but we're bullish so we're not
looking at this the trade up into here
and then sell off I've seen so many
people
tweeting things and other folks that are
in other mentorships and guys and gals
out there trying to put people in shorts
like this they say oh it's an
inefficiency let's get short and then
they have their faces ripped off
what I'm teaching you is how to identify
real order flow understand how the
algorithm will reprice where it's
repricing to and I'm giving you a level
Precision that is unrivaled look closely
you see this
low
High lower low
remember I'm long in here
here
I'm buying all that
all this in here I'm buying all that
stuff right here I'm buying it there
buying it there
and buying it there what am I utilizing
look at those levels look at them
what am I buying
CE of that five
minute favorite what's defined by this
level and that level then I'm buying
what CE of the
inversion parability gap which is this
level here I expect this to be support
and find a point of
accumulation to send it higher to attack
buy silicone and drop into the high on
the 16th of June 2023
so I'm using these reference points like
rungs on a ladder okay or think of it
like a mountain climber okay I would
never climb a mountain okay I would
never do that but when climbers Are
Climbing they're looking for the next
Anchor Point for
to Anchor the Rope or if they're a free
climber and they're not using any rows
which is absolutely Madness
they're planning their next grad point
okay where they're going to reach and
grab and hold on to that rock face and
pull themselves up higher well I'm
looking for all these areas as price
presents them so when price was down
here that fair value Gap was already
there so I'm I'm accumulating long
positions here right in the middle of it
which is constantly encouragement of the
five minute Fairbank which is these two
blank lines that Gap was already there
on a limited chart
I want to see it straight up there it
look at the body respecting it see it
it's staying inside that Gap
then it comes back down I'm buying it
when it's in the midpoint of it right
there
see a little little pathway point right
I'm
I'm sorry right there I'm buying it
there and then I'm buying the low end
range of it
there
so I'm accumulating and pyramiding with
logic I'm not just you know willy-nilly
throwing darts and throwing mud at the
ball and see what sticks and come back
and say haha look how smart I am no none
of this is Cherry Picked this is
absolutely
engineered
but now because we can see this low high
lower low
what else is occurring there that's a
breaker
that's a breaker I'm utilizing that all
that framework I'm going inside this
price leg with the support of this idea
as a breaker because this is an A to B
and this is all Distortion and
manipulation I'm using that as the entry
point but I'm going back into this
little short-term price leg right here
no way I see you're going to tell me
yeah I'm telling you I'm going to prove
it to you too
low
the high okay now watch
[Music]
all this is occurring by the way in the
1150 to 1210 macro okay it's a specific
sweet period of time where the algorithm
will start spooling reaching for
liquidity you have to understand there
too okay don't listen to these guys out
there to have 1150 or 12 10 you know or
maybe my 10 50 to 11 10 macro times and
they're trying to show you that they're
doing something none of you none of
looks listen none of you know what
you're talking about if you're talking
about macros you have no idea what
you're doing stop spreading this
information okay I'm not trying to be
mean to you I'm not trying to be rude
okay but you literally don't know what
you're talking about
but this lay here that's the A to B on
that breaker
if we take that
and we know
that that buy side liquidity is on June
16 2023 High the daily candle it's
drawing up into that and maybe even as
much as
the weekly volume and balance so we have
this range right here
that what I'm doing in other charts that
you don't see me doing because number
one for a long time I didn't want to
share this information
okay number one I'm not obligated to
teach it to you and my charter members
who paid me they're learning this too
for the first time so you're right in
here with mentorship this is mentorship
I'm not doing paid mentorships there's
not going to be an upsell later on come
and join my club okay I don't want to do
that anymore
I want you to learn it correctly and I
don't want people that are out there you
know rebranding my stuff
teaching incorrectly
if anything is taught outside of what
I'm teaching you here they have no idea
what they're talking about
but now we have three standard
deviations
four standard deviations
five standard deviations
six
seven and a half
where does seven and a half now if I
show you six and a half that's right at
that old high you see that 44 93.75 that
right there tells me that that will
definitely reach for that liquidity
remember
44.93.75 is the high of June 16 2023.
what I'm doing is I'm showing you how to
take the levels here for standard
deviation and when they agree with a
range of liquidity
what I mean by that
oh let's take this off
foreign
if we look at how
the negative
6.5 standard deviation comes in at the
daily high of June 16th I know some of
you already like man this is complicated
I understand everything's complicated
when you first started
when you're in kindergarten you know how
to write in the first few letters in the
alphabet was too complicated for you
then okay and that's all this is you're
just learning a language okay but what
I'm teaching you is we have an
expectation the market will reach up
into the liquidity Above This high at 44
93.75 remember so I tweeted
a couple minutes after nine o'clock on
Friday
to this range up here which is the
weekly volume of balance so in that
range right there okay if we take that
range and
use all the breakers for any standard
deviation idea or approach to look for
targeting you want to see a Confluence
of levels
anywhere in that range
so if we anticipate
44.96.50 which is based on that A to B
price leg
here to here
that's where we got that from so we have
that level then we have
44.95.75 and in one new qualifying and
confirming that the high on the 16th of
June 2023 that is in fact going to be
reached for how far above that level
well
44.95.75 is a good level
and 44.96 and a half is a good level so
any one of those two price levels is a
good price point to exit
44 95.25 you have to factor in the
spread so I give myself anywhere between
one and a half handles to a half of
handle and if I'm really trying to show
off I'll do one quarter of a point and
try to you know let the spread do that
but all those levels were based and
framed with all this information here
even though when I'm recording you'll
see the link in the in the comment
section or the description of this video
below you'll see me actually do this
trade and manage it throughout the whole
process
but I'm utilizing a lot of things that
you don't understand these levels
are dynamic
and it's going to pull price to them
all of the calculations that go behind
how these algorithms price
either commodities
index Futures 4X
all of them are using the information
I'm showing you here
this is not a harmonic pattern it's not
some kind of white call stuff it's not
supine to me and it's not Elliott wave
it's none of that stuff
it's understanding time first what time
of day is this occurring the beginning
of the lunch hour in New York
the algorithm will reprice against
existing liquidity what did the morning
session see lower prices
so it's going to roll back on what
the stops the resting above these
relative equal highs
that's why you see me entering
a exit of majority of the trade being
taken off there why did I take the
majority of the trade off there if you
think it's going to go up to your ICT
why'd you take the majority because it's
Friday and I might be wrong
this is a higher time frame Target that
Weekly volume and balance
so it doesn't have to deliver that one
Friday but I felt very strongly that the
June 16th high would be delivered but in
the event that I'm not correct about
that I got the lines portion of the move
off at a logical place because I'm
teaching you to do that very thing
now I could have simply took a small
portion off here in the larger portion
off right here
and then 15 contracts could have came
off there and then my final right there
and then eventually my single contract
got stopped out there and I tweeted
where I had my stock and where my target
was which was the weekly volume balance
just below it
but all that is in the trade execution
all the details you hear this is not
Market replay it's not Market replay
reports where it's fake okay we're not
using ninjatrader where we can pretend
to show profitability uh this is actual
real Market executions these are real
time
applications I mean you don't see a
replay up here it's it's real executions
so all this stuff
is helpful over time
when you're utilizing everything that
I've taught
you're going to have to eventually get
to the point where you
refrain from trying to get the simple
rate of right away figure it out and get
out there and start making money because
it doesn't work that way folks it does I
promise you it does not work that way
but if you want unbelievable levels of
precision
I'm teaching it to you but it's going to
take you some time to get there but you
don't need to have this level of
position
all you need is a simple bread and
butter set up I taught you that tonight
using a breaker you don't need to have
the break and retest
I'll talk to that tonight
I told you how to buy and sell inside of
the breaker before it even goes above
its trigger point that I've already
introduced initially when I taught
Breakers
foreign
I'll have much more to teach you with
each one of these PD arrays but for now
this should suffice
until talk to you next time
be safe