all right folks welcome back this is a
market review for
July 9th 2023.
we're looking at the dollar Index is our
weekly chart here
and I'll take you into
this candle here mean threshold that up
close candle
bearish water block you can see we
worked up into that level here several
weeks ago
uh you've known about this
fair value Gap here
and we have a liquidity pool
right here for sell side liquidity so
we're in a bit of a trading range so far
we've had
multiple instances of trying to get
above this imbalance
at both times we've had Anonymous to do
that
very short term sell side liquidity pool
here
a lot more
resting below here so it'll be
interesting to see how we open and trade
this week coming up
um I'm favoring
at least they run below this low and how
we trade there does it accelerate if it
does then obviously we'll be looking for
it to reach below here for the sell side
if we trade below it here and then
reject and then we may stay inside of
this range right in here a little bit
longer
all right so here's the daily chart on
dollar Index you can see again how we've
worked up into that weekly mean
threshold of the bear shorter block
this shaded area doesn't look as clean
you'll notice the weekly fair value you
got before we drop down into the daily
chart as you've noticed up here
it doesn't look like a fair value gap on
the daily chart that's why you have to
take your higher time frame PD arrays
and transpose them into the lower time
frames I'm having daily fair value Gap
here
and we see we worked into that level
there
and now we had a really nice sell-off
last Friday
um
this down close candle right here
1.I'm watching how we open on Sunday
2.and we trade on Monday
because we have this potential OB
we might again want to return back up into this area right in here
and the reason why I'm saying that is because we also have a -high -low -higher high which is a BRK
so it may want to come back up into this area here
and this entire down enclosed candle is the -BRK
so we have to be mindful of that going forward
so you know gone to my head
I favor a run below this low
and how we do? if at all trade below that low
if it accelerates then all this liquidity in here should be a likely draw longer term
hourly chart one dollar Index here's
that Weekly fair value Gap year
and I have the holiday fourth July
highlighted here
opening price
on Monday New York midnight opening
price
so we can see the weekly power three
which is the open
if we were looking for shorts obviously
you want to see it rally higher
the Thursday which is what I mentioned
in commentary earlier in the week that
they would be
more favorable cleaner price action
towards the end of the week because of
the holiday you know on Tuesday July 4th
whether you celebrate July 4th or not
and you're outside the states doesn't
matter the Market's going to reflect
that lower volume so
when we see this run here it's occurring
on Thursday so generally I talked about
this on my most recent Twitter space
the idea of trading Mondays and when not
the trade Mondays I covered that
yesterday in about an hour and a half
audio presentation on Twitter and the
normal procedure is we want to try to
find ourselves before Wednesday of the
week of non-farm payroll Friday
because there was a holiday and because
of that being the case I felt that we
would have a lot cleaner price action on
the lighter portion which would be
Thursday and Friday and I'm delineating
that Thursday here at midnight near
clinical time
and we see we dropped down return back
into the Monday New York midnight
opening price
we rally
and also notice all the work around that
price level here
a lot of respect of that and then we
have the Judah swing we rip higher take
out the buy side
here and then we drop back down look at
the bodies staying real close to the
high of that Weekly
fair value Gap
remember this pink area here is derived
from the weekly chart
so this right here indicates again as
soon as this candle closes and this one
opens rallies up and starts to trade
lower
we can trust the fact that this high and
that high here all of this was a run on
liquidity so
any rally up we would just watch and see
if it
is held at Bay
you know kept from going any higher at
the consequent encroachment of the high
to the close that candle so it would be
basically around the high of
103.42 one their balance
and then the market works it's way lower
on the lower end of that Weekly fair
value Gap the pink shaded area
we hit it as a resistance hit it as
resistance and then sharp break below
here we open come right back up for our
immediate rebalance
that right there as I taught you a month
ago
that immediate rebalance is very very
powerful so if we had to move lower than
that low here this is all the juice wing
so that Judas swing there is indicative
of manipulation stop run and before stop
run
we have to have a bias
and if we were looking for lower prices
and targeting this old load down here
using that old fair value gap on the
weekly chart
the displacement below that low is on
this candle right there
the very next candle we're opening up
rally back up to this candle's low so
there's no fair value Gap it's an
immediate rebalance the market does that
it's going to be in a quick hurry sudden
you know
urgent price delivery to get to a
specific level of liquidity or
inefficiency so we can see obviously the
liquid would be over here and it drops
down aggressively for that during the
non-prime payroll Friday
all of that again is the Judas swing so
weekly power three we open rally up
makes a high of the week and then trade
below all inside of the latter portions
of the week
Thursday and Friday
[Music]
zooming in onto a 15 minute time frame
for a dollar Index again here's that
Monday New York midnight opening price
we extend it throughout the entire day
of the week I have a fair value Gap in
here let me trade up into that during
the New York open
and it is the 8 30
payroll Friday
report
we break down
last up close candles consecutively that
is the bearish order block that closing
end of that price point right there
rallying right up to here perfectly to
that opening price
this is the change in the state of
delivery the algorithm will refer back
to that price right there
go right back up into it
drop aggressively for the sell side
you're a dollar everything you would
expect
in the dollar Index would be obviously
reversed here
I've been calling your attention to this
weekly volume and balance for months now
and while we did retrace back down to
this bullish order block uh we rallied
created a fair value Gap we had multiple
times trading down into it I told you we
would want to see this area here act as
an inversion fair value Gap that means
to trade above it find it as support and
then take into consideration the buy
side and then eventually up into the
weekly volume amount so if we do in fact
get lower prices on dollar Index I
really favor seeing us trade up into the
11 30 11 and a half and how far we get
into this weekly volume and balance you
know we'll have to see that but that's
the longer term draw on liquidity gun to
my head I think that's what we're going
to try to reach for
on the daily chart here's this relative
equal highs it's buy side in the weekly
volume imbalances above us there
weekly fair value Gap and again we're
treating this as an inversion for your
bank app so I'm just again making
reference to it here because it's a
weekly PD array but the logic is that
we're looking for it to act as support
it doesn't need to come back down and
touch it again this is something that
I'd like to see and if it does it would
promote the idea of maybe tape reading
it or demo trading it
last down closed candle is the Polish
order block and then we also had again
dug into this weekly fair value get
which is a discount we'll be looking for
a run up into these two premium arrays
right there short term would be the buy
side here how we treat above that
again think about what I said for the
dollar Index it's short-term low for the
dollar how we trade below that
would be
New Perspective of this this High here
as well we want to see it trade above it
and aggressively move towards these
relative equal highs I don't think it
we're going to bumped these highs and
then break them and then go lower I
think if we're going to go above there
we're going to treat definitely inside
that Weekly volume of balance so I would
be a little leery being bearish on your
own
all right here's the hourly chart for
euro dollar
you can see the buy side liquidity up
here again that Weekly inversion for
your value Gap and we have a buy side
and balance outside efficiency here
extending that forward
see we worked off of the daily bullet
order block which is that line right
there I made a little bit thicker so
that we can see it
and then we have this down closed candle
here
16 minute Bowl shoulder block
and then we have this here now what I'm
annotating here is really a two hour
order block
so this range from high to low all of
this right here
will be encapsulated in a two hour order
block so two hours of time
was a little bit longer term or larger
order block but I'm representing it on
the hourly chart so when I'm doing order
block Theory I'm actually toggling
through all the time frames even time
frames that are outside the normal range
like everybody's familiar with the
monthly weekly daily four hour one hour
15 minute time frame and then whatever
it is below 15 minute you might like I
will look for multiple time frames in
between the
standard go to time frames and a perfect
representation that would be is how I'm
teaching you the intraday charts on like
silver bullets and or the model 2022
on my YouTube channel I'll take you down
to a five minute chart then from five
minutes we drop down to a four minute
three two one
and
this year you've learned how I use even
less than a one minute chart for a 30
second 15 second five second chart
interval all of those ideas are a
top-down approach
the order block Theory really leans on
the understanding of where we are in the
price delivery Continuum so you're not
going to be able to just simply look at
one specific candle you know up or down
and didn't assume that that's an order
block there's a lot of things that have
to and come to
your understanding and I won't be doing
that in videos that the order block
Theory I'll be teaching that solely in
book format but I'll have things on this
YouTube channel that will be
helpful in in studying that
so we can see we have a breaker here
okay and that's what specifically the
order block is that's being referenced
and how is it a breaker we have a swing
low
swing High
swing low that's lower than that one
relative equal lows but inside of that
range between high low and low
what do I have here I have a order block
I have a breaker and I have a buy side
to balance outside and efficiency any
one of those PD arrays could be utilized
for you that would be your multiplier
I'm just annotating them that way you
can see and decide which one appeals to
you okay if neither of them appeal to
you and then it is what it is it's fine
but we can see
we rally here
we open
trade down hit the breaker then rally
really nice through the IFVG[weekly]
and I would have enjoyed seeing it trade back down
into it just to touch it one more time
much like this right here did
it might want to trade down into that
but with this Gap here
I would not want to see the high of that candle which is the low of the BISI
I would not want to see that or CE which is half of this
shaded area here I would not want to see
that traded through
okay so as long as we're above all that I'm bullish on EURUSD
15 at Tony Fremont Euro
okay you can see again New York open
not from payroll Friday
that we dropped down into the daily
publish order block inside of
consequent encroachment of the Bots and
balance cell standard efficiency again
before we drop down to the 15 minute
time frame into that blue shaded area
rewind the video
you'll see that this run into this
there's two PD eraser being hit
shaded area
and the daily bullish order block
so between that and add to it if you
want
you can use the last down closed candle
right in here so order block
consequent encroaching with Bessie in
Daily order blocks there's a Confluence
of multiple things with inside the New
York open Kill Zone
which is 7 A.M to 9 00 A.M
New York local time and the 8 30 News
embargo lifting at uh not our payroll
numbers
we rally up and come back down hit that
breaker rally down close candle here
even though we run away from it we trade
back down until once more that right
there would have been a buy and then
rally and then we have this Gap here so
think about the midpoint of the Shaded
area here as long as we're above that
we're looking for higher prices more
specifically aiming for buy side and or
the weekly volume of balance
e-mini s p
here is the weekly chart and we have a
weekly volume of balance there as well I
haven't quite got into it yet
we traded down about halfway of this
down close candle here so it's really
important to see how we trade this week
I'm not trying to pick the top but I
like the idea that we stopped halfway in
this down close candle here
now we've already traded into this
inefficiency there so I think this might
just be a reason to you know retrace
back into this range and then expand up
in that Weekly volume and balance
between this week and the next two weeks
or so I will work inside that range
that's what I'm expecting obviously all
that can change on Sunday's opening I'm
just giving you my forecast based on
what we have here I want to close the
basis of Friday
and not knowing how we're going to open
there's all kinds of things that could
obviously change it where we open how we
trade something going into Monday's
opening
daily shot here okay you can see we just
fell short of that Weekly volume balance
and we have several things in here I'm
looking at
we had the
Fairway Gap here that we worked off of
we have a volume imbalance right there
and if we trade down once more
that coupled with this last down closed
candle I wouldn't want to see anything
below 4 400.
on a closing basis I would wouldn't be
uncomfortable for it to go right down
there Sunday into Monday and then try to
make them you know another move higher
but until we take out that
4400 on a closing basis
I I don't want to try to pick a top
on ES so we could just bang around in
here as long as we keep this order block
intact you know we're good if we lose
this order block
is down closed candle here my attention
goes right to this area right there
okay so the spot's gonna balance outside
of efficiency you know 4300 or so that
would be if we take out that low that's
where we're going but I don't see that
yet and I would favor you know obviously
a little bit lower in this volume and
balance
and then if at all trading into this
candle's High how we do that if at all
will be helpful to me at that time
seeing it so it certainly looks heavy in
here
looks really like it wants to you know
it it opened rallied up immediate
rebalance
it can accelerate aggressively lower but
I'm trying to avoid like I preach and
teach to you all I'm trying to avoid
trying to pick a top so this could
easily just come right back up and make
a higher high into that Weekly volume
amount so then give up the ghost
entirely
and go lower or you know accelerate to
the upside I'm right now waiting and
electing to see how we open Sunday and
how we trade overnight into 9 30 opening
on Monday morning so it kind of like
gives you a wait and see motive that I'm
adopting for this beginning of the new
week
all right hourly chart
SMP
notice that we are on electronic trading
hours that will change as I go through
the slides because I'm going to teach
you how to utilize both to get a better
depiction of what price is actually
trying to do
I like the idea that they have very very
smooth highs up in here
a fair value Gap there
we rallied up into that fair value Gap
and then treat it back down into the
buy-time balance outside efficiency so
this is a sibi sauce on a balanced by
side efficiency classification
within the PD array category of a fair
value Gap this is a fair value Gap too
that's shaded in blue but this fair
value Gap is a busy so buy side and
balance outside of efficiency cell side
imbalance by silent efficiency what is
it inefficient by side that means upside
delivery you see it go right up in there
and hits it there once it fills that
little area up with upside delivery and
it leaves it's fine it's ready to go to
another discount array or sell side
liquidity
it's interesting to see that we didn't
take out that low
so I'll be looking to see how we do that
if at all on Sunday I'd like to see it
Gap blower trade up hit the low of this
efficiency and then rip into the cell
side liquidity here if we accelerate to
the downside your attention goes right
in here okay so what I was mentioning on
the daily chart this is a much more
refined area where sell side is residing
how far below those relative equal lows
can it go that Gap right there okay and
if we accelerate through that then
obviously you have to look at you know
below these lows as I was mentioning on
The Daily
all right so now we're gonna get to a
little bit more in depth discussion
about inefficiencies
uh gaps and how to you know use this
information
one hour chart now with regular trading
hours so the only thing I've done was
take the previous
amount of price data and toggle this
little right from electronic trading
hours to regular trading hours and
regular trading hours is where you're
going to see the gaps
from the previous session to where we
open up the next day at 9 30. so
at settlement price
previous day and then where we open at 9
30. whatever the distance is separating
the settlement price of the previous day
and where we open at 9 30 New York local
time
that's our opening range
okay so that opening range Gap acts and
performs in the same manner as we would
expect a weekly volume imbalance
okay so
um
when we look at price
gaps like this
okay I want you to think about
how markets efficiently deliver price
okay I taught this analogy using a paint
roller okay and imagine this white
shaded area background is a wall in your
house
and you want to paint
in these little areas where you need to
have pain applied okay so maybe you've
already painted your house
and the paint's now faded over there's
hand prints like like a child like I had
five kids and obviously they would put
their hands on the walls and make marks
and such and we'd have to have them
walls painted and some kind of blemish
or some kind of inefficiency and paint
exists between these two candle Bodies
Okay this candle's body here and this
candle's body here between that
opening price net
price there's a separation
of price delivery that did not have your
body
so I'm highlighting that and extending
it all the way through
when I show you these ranges I'm not
going to drop down to the lower time
frames the homework assignment for you
is to have these on your charts
and then drop down their lower time
frames on electronic Trading
okay so just know that I'm showing you
something so that way you can observe
and identify things and Discover it on
your own and have that aha moment
but this distinction here between these
two candles opening
opening here there's no bodies between
these two price points so that
inefficiency
you want to extend those out in time
because they'll eventually be offered by
side and sell side that means upside and
downside delivery
here we only had a partial delivery of
upside and then drops so from this point
here
up to here that is the real inefficiency
that remains because we've already had
this partial and this movement down so
think of it as a paint roller up and
down so from this opening price in that
opening price
up to right there
it has been offered
delivery of price so there's a real
separation between this high and net
candles opening price there's a distinct
inefficiency there
but nonetheless you can see how we
respected that
opening price there look how we're
treating it with these bodies here
and then we have another Gap there
we have a gap here but I'm showing you
how inside this range
you're anticipating an expecting price
to deliver both sides up and down that's
inefficiently delivered price
you can see how we worked off the low
here
and we had another Gap there
so it wants to reach up into that every
time I'm showing you one of these ranges
I want you to go into not regular
trading hours but electronic trading
hours and study how price delivers
you'll see how it is real Dynamic
support and resistance
it's not readily understood or seen by
most Traders I mean obviously I've been
teaching it this year but
you won't see it in books okay you're
gonna look at it right away and think
it's oh it's supply and demand oh or
it's a classic support resistance I
promise you there's no books out there
with support and resistance with this
idea it isn't there okay they may see a
gap but they're not looking at gaps
multiple times in the future okay and as
soon as price would go from
here to here they would consider that
Gap closed and there's no more concern
about it and that's What Separates Me
from retail
because the fact that Gat was created
the algorithm
will refer back to those three price
points which is the low consequent
protein which is midpoint of the Gap and
in the high
okay so whatever the extreme boundaries
high and low and whatever the middle
point is
those three specific price points are
very very sensitive and if you want to
go one degree beyond that
you can split that range up in quadrants
so the first 25 50 75 percent of the
entire inefficiency and then the high of
the inefficiency
and that's what I want you to do for
your electronic trading hours study so
look at all of the price action in here
even though there's gaps missing price
data here in electronic trading hours
there is no Gap it's it's actually being
traded through
and then from here to here
so
that's one there
the other one is here
okay and what you're doing again is
toggling it from regular trading hours
to electronic trading hours and you'll
study how price delivers inside this
range here you don't want to have all of
the inefficiencies on the chart the same
time that way it helps you track what
you're looking for in study time of the
day look for inefficiencies think like
silver bullets in the London session in
the New York session both am session and
PM session
up
you're going to be
surprised to see how much Precision that
these levels will offer not just the
high and the low but consequent
encouragement and 75 50 and 25 of those
respective ranges
and then lastly the one here
okay so that way you can see
these are three homework assignments I
want you to go through on your time
frames
lower than obviously the one hour chart
and you'll see that these respective
inefficiencies have a really interesting
characteristics where setups can form
all right 15 minute timer
I taught in the one setup for life
tutorial on my YouTube channel
it goes over how to
classify specific liquidity pools and
how I break down these and look back at
very specific points of liquidity I
mentioned the London session highs and
Loan session lows we have a sell-side
liquidity pool here Thursday New York PM
session Buy sell liquidity London
session Buy sell liquidity sell side
here that would be the London session
for this day here
and at non-form payroll Friday we open
up rally up
take the buy side here on the
Thursday New York PM session and then we
rip lower to take out the London session
then we rally up one more time
trade back down to a bullish order block
and rip higher attacking the Thursday
London session by side liquidity pool
then in the afternoon we reverse course
and go all the way back down to attack
the rejection Block in the original
South Side liquidity pool it was
interesting to see it not take out that
low so I think it has unfinished
business going into Sunday's openings so
again I'd like to see us open lower the
Gap lower
and how we trade lower if at all below
that low just be mindful this little
tiny Gap here it might give you a run
down there going through this Gap and
rip higher and defer a run below that
low if it's going to do it or if it does
break lower it can just be a quick
sudden run but I just want you to be
aware of that little Gap right there in
the event that should we start running
for this low this could be one of those
little speed bumps that cause us to you
know pull back up in the range and then
at a later time uh take that low out so
it's a matter of wait and see see how we
trade on Sunday's opening price and into
Monday
all right five minute chart one e mini s
p
same respective liquidity pools
annotated here okay you can see nice
order block
trading into it here this is a classic
optimal trade entry trade as well
and it starts at accumulate and rally
higher
tearing into the Thursday lemon session
Boston liquidity and the market reverses
it breaks down I did Longs all through
here on NASDAQ
and then I shorted it going into the PM
session
on NASDAQ so I didn't do any work on s p
here
here is the regular trading hours on a
five minute chart and taking this up
back up this low here now why am I using
this low
and that the closing price here
there's a specific pattern here
if you are a student of mine that have
been with me for a while you know what
this pattern is
I'll give you a second I'll I'll talk
about something else I'll come back that
in a minute but here's the Thursday
London session by sell liquidity it
rallies up into that
and then trades up into that low here
and then starts to break lower and
aggressively moves towards the relative
equal low side here so this is a classic
ICT Market maker cell model so we have
accumulation
reaccumulation
reversal low risk cell
distribution redistribution second stage
distribution basically and an aggressive
sell-off into cell signed liquidity
this pattern over here
is a breaker
okay so it's a high low higher high
so
you always want to refer to that even if
there's a gap
like this if there's ever a breaker
there
always give the opportunity to see if
the market will respect that not so much
this one here because this is a this is
an opening range as well so where we
close here and we opened down here you
would have that shaded so extending out
in the future you can see we dug up into
that as well
again you would note that opening
and the close respectively on these two
candles and extend that range forward
okay and you can see that's what we
basically did here we stayed inside that
range
and then we got down here
to that Gap
that huge in efficiency
you you don't want to just go right back
to the previous
sessions closing price where I like to
usually do that
if we have a breaker a breaker will many
times
disrupt that total closure of the gap
so how do I know certain gas won't
entirely close there are certain things
obviously that I've already taught you
this is another one here okay so if
there's a breaker inside the range that
would be considered for a gap closure
you want to consider where that
down closed candles low is and you can
see we have respected that here
all right one minute charts
s p you can see we have a higher low in
NASDAQ we have a lower low
so I elected to go with the NASDAQ
simply because I had some students
asking me you know why am I only doing
SMP can I do something with NASDAQ so I
went into NASDAQ and I basically beat it
all up you know I went long in it and
then I went shorter than it I didn't get
the last hole run lower on the PM
session I didn't explain it in a
recording when you can watch me do live
executions in a video on my YouTube
channel for Friday's PM session for
Nasdaq
I'll show all the executions on the
upside and I did some live executions
and management on the lower end for the
NASDAQ but I mentioned how I felt it you
know it could go lower but I didn't have
the time to be able to spend managing
the entirety until the close but a
really nice run into uh
a lower low here higher low on smt
diversions for s p s p rallied higher
NASDAQ followed suit and then we have a
disruption up here so we have short term
low here
which helped me time the potential
intermediate term High I did try to take
a trade you know
go into this here on this respective
area on NASDAQ which I'm not going to
show you here because I'm going to
actually include it in the discussion
tomorrow for my macros lecture
but the uh I was trying to show a losing
trade because everybody's like you
always show a winning trade each other
you know share a losing trade so I was
really trying to be facetious and put a
short on
and have a stop loss really really tight
so that way can stop me out and I was
going to show it on Twitter just you
know
be facetious but it ended up making a
run where I knew it was going to be
profitable so I closed the trade on
again it would be on that and you'll see
it it's actually on my
video prior to this one
so just go back one more day and you'll
see it
but the uh the idea was that you
the s p doesn't really have a clear
swing load that would be clear when we
drop lower but a NASDAQ does so I
mentioned it in one of the recordings I
placed on my Twitter feed
and
once I knew it was running in my favor I
was like okay I already know what this
is this is a
Market Excel model and all this
consolidation it wouldn't want to go
below these relative equal lows and we
saw that actually happen here but
counseling this rejection Block in
addition to all this here so that would
be a nice area for cell solid liquidity
you can see we did in fact reach down
into it for silver bullets between 10
o'clock in the morning and 11 o'clock in
the morning New York local time we have
a fair value Gap there after hitting an
older block and
fair value got there
we rally higher trade back down in
Silver Bullet run for relative equal
highs so buying here and getting out
there just at that high here that's
enough for a trade you don't even have
to hold on to any of this up here in the
PM session Silver Bullet same idea this
is in Reverse I'll hit consolidation so
when you take a silver bullet if you're
seeing consolidation like this have this
in your notes
wait for displacement we see that here
very energetic drop
if everybody got sell short there and
again reach four five handles minimum
and if we had this area down here for a
buy side it will many times want to
offer a re-delivery to that as well
because
every old liquidity pool acts like an
inefficiency it'll many times revisit it
and act as
the opposite so if we were seeing buy
side as a draw here
the algorithm will refer back to this
area here and draw back down into it
but it has to be some measure of why it
was drawn to for buy side it's not just
simply resistance resistance broken turn
support because notice it didn't do
anything for sport so I've already
canceled that idea you're already
thinking oh he's just talking about
scoring so it says no
it's a matter of taking this information
and really understanding what would be
support to buy or a target for a draw on
liquidity so again I have a lot of
lectures that will come that describe
how to do all this stuff but it can't be
taught obviously in one sitting there's
a lot of things that at my disposal and
I want to make it available to you but
everything a little bit at a time
because it's already probably too much
for most of you
but we found something in this that was
insightful and helpful and until I'll
talk to you next time
be safe