welcome back
folks this is the last
teaching lecture on the inner circle
Trader YouTube
channel before get into this one just
let you know that uh this is one of the
closest viewpoints to how I actually
trade now when I say that don't gloss
over at thinking well you know that's
all well and good what what does that
mean it means that you have to
understand all the PD
arrays you have to be familiar with them
because what you may or may not realize
is a market maker model
is relying on your understanding of
every PD I've made
available so if you're looking at price
you're going to see things in price that
are going to be Salient to your
understanding if you don't know what a
breaker is if you don't know what a
mitigation block is if you don't know
what a inversion fair value Gap
is the
observation of seeing it real time as a
market maker buy or sell model May
Escape you at the time when you're
looking at Price action live so one of
the things I've seen throughout teaching
this is that some of my students can see
a market maker model really really quick
and it's because they have been familiar
with a multitude of PD arrays not just
simply an order block or a breaker so
they can see things and have a better
understanding about price action and
that's what I mean by graduating in your
understanding and not rushing this
so while this is the last Model I'm
teaching
publicly
the I guess the the disclaimer going in
should be that this is going to be very
difficult for a lot of you and I'm not
going to Sugar Cod that um when I taught
my private mentorship students I told
them that you these are things that are
going
to require you to know all the things
that I taught in mentorship there's
going to be multitudes
of Market maker sell and buy models that
are going to escape you you won't see
them until after the fact but don't
discount that as wasted opportunity log
them Journal them mark them up okay and
then annotate them in a way where it
looks like you seen it coming in journal
just like that so that way when you look
at your Journal it'll be in your own
words that you saw it coming it's all
pseudo experience it's it's conditioning
your brain to see it as a positive thing
so that way when you see it again it's a
rewarding experience and your
subconscious is not trying to distract
you from a painful experience whereas if
you don't journal and you only have bad
experiences by trying to trade with real
money or try to do something where
incurred risk is real versus trying to
read price action and there's no
monetary risk or gain there's no ego
there's no Pride there's no pain all
these things are going to
help getting you closer to understanding
a market
model
but for the sake of brevity everything I
disclose in this teaching just reverse
it for a market maker buy model Okay
because I'm going to focus primarily on
a market maker sell model everything
here is shown in Reverse if you were
applying it to a market maker Bond model
now I do have lectures and teachings on
this in the YouTube channel so this
isn't meant to be a be all end all I'm
leaning on
the assumptions that you have already
studied a lot of the things I'm going to
talk about so if this is one of the
First videos you've ever watched by me
or if you're a relatively new student
this is probably going to go over your
head and that's a normal thing okay it's
it would be considered a little
Advanced and and that's why I'm saying
it's it's the closest thing to how I
internalize price action when I'm
engaging it so 99% of the time when I'm
taking a
trade it's usually something like this
that's the framework behind it okay and
I may or may not have the time or
interest even to disclose the model that
I'm actually trading inside of that
would be the market maker buy or sell
model but when you look at it
conceptually you can
fragmentize these price swings and make
one segment of the market maker model
whether it be a buy or sell model and
that in itself may be your unique model
that you trade not that you're trying to
trade the bottom of a market maker buy
model to the
top or vice versa for a sell you it's a
matter of preference what you want to do
because there's a buy and sell curve buy
side of the curve and the sell side of
the curve and we'll discuss that in here
now but uh this teaching is my market
maker models it's algorithmic price
delivery in institutional price
swings all right so I guess in a lot of
ways this is just basically my
interpretation and creating a language
around swing Trading
now when I say swing trading what I'm
referring to is if I'm bullish I'm
trading from discount to
premium riding the code tailes of buy
side
delivery if I'm bearish I'm trading from
premium to Discount writing the coat
Tales of sside
delivery now when I mentioned buy side
and sside you're thinking liquidity and
I'm going to draw a distinction between
the liquidity and the
delivery
all right so imagine if you will that
you were looking at price and those
relative equal highs right here that
we're looking at
conceptually uh we would
anticipate a run above
that now if you can get that far in your
understanding from what I've taught you
have the beginning building blocks of
understanding how to look for a market
maker sell
model but I want to flesh this out a
little bit because it's not just simply
understanding where relative equal highs
and relative equal lows are you have to
understand what the Market's trying to
do and gravitate to and for the premise
of doing it to go higher longer term or
to go up just to trick people into being
long and then going lower longer term
that's narrative so that's going to be
outside the scope of this teaching so
again it's going to be very frustrating
for you if you think this is going to be
like a really Elementary model like the
Silver Bullet which is relatively simple
or model 2022 which is relatively simple
uh this one's going to have a whole lot
of talking in it because I'm reminding
you of the things that going to be
supportive for you to understand how to
trade these
things if you're trying to trade like me
you're going to have to learn to do what
I'm talking about here if you're not
inspired to try to trade like me and you
just want to trade a silver bullet or a
model 2022 and that's all that you're
interested in and you're content with
being successful with that wonderful you
do not need to have this level of
understanding it is helpful to try to
look at Price action every day every
week every month and go through and see
if you can find these types of models in
price action and by collecting them
you'll have a better understanding of
what they look like in the future
because you've seen lots of examples of
it that you've fited out of price action
not me pointing to it or someone else
pointing to it after the fact you want
to be able to do this this on your own
but for the sake of this
discussion the understanding is we
should be able to see those relative
equal highs and that
being this here and this here now I'm
I'm using a a close line chart so it's
going to be a rather crude depiction of
a general idea okay we'll transition to
actual charts in a moment but for now I
want you to just think conceptu how if
the Market's going to run
eventually up above that and if we could
hold a bearish
stance meaning that we look at every
rally as a suspect rally if we're
bearish and then we're going to be
looking for some measure of reversal and
then once that reversal is qualified
that meets the criteria for a market
maker sell model then we can go in and
engage it now an advanced interpretation
of this would be
anticipating the Run above these
relative equal highs here and being long
prior to it and the most advanced form
of it would be to buy it during the buy
side of the curve and then short it
during the cells side of the curve that
is very Advanced and while I do have
students that can do that like me not
many of them can they can either trade
the long side of the side of the curve
or they can sell short on the cell side
of the curve so it's a matter of them
picking what they can see clearly based
on their present understanding and their
experience and don't try to rush it
don't try to keep up with me don't try
to keep up with my other students that
are doing well it's at your own pace
that you learn this that's the best Pace
to learn it at so don't try to feel like
you're you're behind or you're trying to
catch up with the class because I have
students that go back to 1996 so you're
never going to catch up to them
so I want you to take a look at that
price movement here if this is a market
that you'd be trading or interested in
learning uh these ideas are Universal so
it's not a matter of it only applies
to futures or it only applies to index
futures or Forex it's it's Universal
okay so as long as there's a price feed
attached to it and it can be traded
these conceptual ideas can be applied to
it okay
this whole idea from this run up to that
level there this is what I refer to as
buy side delivery okay so when price is
running higher it's offering buy
side it's giving the marketplace buy
side as it's running higher now for the
purposes of running Above This high and
this high it's running up to engage the
liquidity that would be resting above
these relative equal highs so the
distinction here is the directional
movement when it's going higher prices
in a buy side
delivery liquidity above a single or a
group of
highs that is buy side liquidity that's
orders that are pending whether they be
a buyer to break out and go long or to
protect a short position so liquidity is
a stagnant price level or
levels where stops would be reside buy
side delivery is the actual animated
movement of price moving higher and as
you probably would have guessed when
we're looking at Price going
lower this here is what I refer to as
sside delivery so the express purposes
of running above these relative equal
highs that function has been performed
so now price could if we're bearish move
lower and then trade back back below the
previous rally
low so it's buy side delivery to the
upside to engage
liquidity trap traders
[Music]
long and smart money would go short here
and write it back down to stop out any
individuals that were lucky enough to be
long in this but kept a stop loss here
or inside this run up during the buy
side delivery their stop loss will be
tagged
out and again with the premise of
reaching for the new
engineered cell side liquidity which
would be the cell stops on Longs that
anyone would have been going long here
their stop loss would be priced right
below
here so it's the rally up to take buy
side and then rip rate back down to take
the sell side on those individuals that
were trying to go long and weren't
astute enough to reverse or at the very
minimum close out in a profitable
position
now as I promised we're going to look at
it through the lens of open high low
Clos
candlesticks
so take a couple minutes look at this
before I continue pause the video before
I start talking and make observations
about what you think you see here what's
Salient to you and when you're ready
unpause the
video all right so what we're looking at
here is basically the same idea of price
action instead of a line close chart
where every fluctuation is only noted by
where the interval will be utilizing
that closing price only not the highest
high and the lowest load but the closing
price here we're looking at the highest
high and lowest low and the open and
close of every individual Candlestick of
this respective time frame so we see the
relative equal highs here with this high
and this High here
and the M the market rallies up here so
all of this is the buy side delivery and
the subsequent sell-side delivery
attacking the cell side that was created
after the run higher and this run higher
attacks the relative equal highs here
where liquidity is so markets go up for
two primary reasons one it goes up to
engage buy stops which is buy side
liquidity or it goes up to an
inefficient
what is that well if you look right here
that's an
inefficiency we have this small little
segment of price action where the
previous candle's low stops here the
next candle opens trades up a little bit
goes
lower the next candle we open trade up
stop here and then we move
lower this separation between these
three candles here one candle in the
middle this is what I call a fair value
Gap it's a very specific price level
that we look for and it's one of the
most visual things you can see from my
repertoire and the things I teach your
eye should jump right to it when you see
it and in this case if you missed it you
can see clearly now it's highlighted so
because it's a down closed
candle what kind of inefficiency is it a
fair value Gap classified as a CBI sibi
sells side inbalance buy side
inefficiency meaning when these form the
Market's algorithm that produces the
fluctu in price not because it's buying
and selling pressure but the market
rallies to these predetermined levels
because it has to offer what here this
one single candle went lower so what
does it need to do if it's going to be
an efficient market it needs to trade up
back in between these two price points
this candle's low this candle's High we
see that here this candle trades up to
it where does the close stop right at
the high of it the next candle we open
and we trade back down yes yes there was
a small Wick here yes there was a small
little Wick here that is acceptable
that's permissible but the bodies tell
us the narrative so all of this rally up
here was under the pretense that we
would see it just simply trade back to
this little area
here above the buy side above this high
and this high so ICT how far can it go
above these relative equal highs you'd
have to look to see if there's any close
proximity in efficiencies in this case
we have one right here notice this
candle's tail goes way lower then we
open trade back up making the low of the
fair value Gap and then we trade here
lower then the next candle we open went
lower so all of these three candles here
we've had a lot of back and forth price
action there's no fair value Gap here we
can clearly see there's a gap because
there's only one candle making that
defined range of that low of that candle
and that candle's high so that small
little area here is a fair value Gap the
algorithm will go back to that and repic
to it how by going back up to it and
offering a patch filling in this Only
One Singular down closed candle now we
have an up Clos candle laying directly
right over top of it so it patches over
the inefficiency here in price
so right away you can see while this
discussion is primarily Market maker
models to understand what my market
maker model is you have to understand a
plethora of other supporting studies
so while it may be one of those things
that you're all going to try to
gravitate to over time just understand
it's going to take a lot of time to
understand the the
full magnitude of what's available in
terms of deciphering and reading price
it's not to Simply here is a time of day
here is a fair value Gap and where's the
draw on liquidity when you're using a
market maker sell and buy model you're
looking at multiple draws on liquidity
and you have to be more Nimble so I'm
saying this not to discourage you but to
remind you that it's going to take a
whole lot more effort than you probably
realize going into this I've made
available very very simple
straightforward Elementary models using
the concepts I've created so if you get
discouraged after this just know that
you can always revert back to the silver
bullet or the 2022 or optimal trade
entry models they're very
simple so let's go into greater detail
here how the market ran up into this
area here and focus on how it went down
not just simply below the cell side of
that original rally up but it went down
to this old low right here look real
close you'll see that it went just below
that that's not
random this right here is a bid balance
cellid efficiency it's the opposite of
this singular candle here it's an
upclose candle so it wouldn't be a Cy it
would be a bissy bidon balance cellid
efficiency so it digs into this just by
a little bit but specifically right
below that low again that's not random
these are things I like to look for you
can also see how we had that same thing
occurring here this is a b balance
efficiency again the opposite of
this up closed candles that create a
fair value gap or inefficiency is
referred to as a
bissy the classification by PD aray is
fair value Gap but it's an up close
candle so it's a buy side IM balance
sell side and efficiency meaning the
price will want to go back down to it
eventually and in here we have that
inbalance and then trades where down
once it gets into there reprices to the
order block then it rallies back up
creating the initial stage of what a
shift in Market structure Above This
High here so now we can look for a
retracement back down in so is as it's
retracing we're anticipating the price
doing what eventually reaching for the
high here and here so we can look for a
lower time frame to give us a scenario
where if we think it's going to go above
these relative equal highs and we can
see that this Fair B Gap wasn't hiding
it's in plain view it should stand out
on your chart that's why it you're
encouraged by me to annotate them when
you see them so if you see a draw on
liquidity that's setting up above or
below the marketplace don't just limit
your focus to that look in close
proximity just above these buy side
liquidity highs here that are relatively
equal how far can it go above it well
looking over here there's no
inefficiency here but there is one right
there so how far can it go above these
relative equal High there and look where
the body stop okay so that's not
random
all right so we're going to zoom in here
a little
bit drop down into a lower time frame
chart here and don't worry I'll let you
know what this is as we get to the close
of the lecture but just stick to what
I'm showing you
here we
have the
low buy side delivery trading up
into the fair value Gap that was on a
time frame that was 60 minutes but now
we're on a
15minute so this time frame here is a
15-minute time frame it's one quarter of
what was shown as the previous chart so
there's four times the number of
candles and I've given you a reference
point that it was based on a 60 Minute
or hourly fair value Gap in the form of
a Cy sell sign and balance byy sign
efficiency and still you can see the
body is respecting and only the
candlesticks Wicks are piercing it see
see that so that's very very indicative
of qualifying the fact that we've went
up to a specific level and therefore we
can trust that the algorithm is kind of
like broadcasting to those that know how
to look at it and see it that it's
likely to now reic lower repic to where
below this low and any accelerated run
below this low how far can it go is
there any efficiencies over here don't
look at this one because that's above
that low we would already be
anticipating retracement back below that
where will we look the rejection block
which is the lowest down close and then
we have these relative equal lows here
and you see it just goes a little bit
below that low rate there we're going to
get into this in a moment for now just
notice that we have ran above that buy
side that old high here that old high
here shift in Market structure on the
hourly chart Above This High here so
it's retracing what's it retracing back
down into the fair value got order block
right there so now does the market offer
a
consolidation that's what we would be
expecting here is it consolidating is it
offering a small little pause in price
where it goes sideways for a little
while which would be accumulating long
positions that's allowing smart money to
accumulate
longs
I'm going to zoom in this is the same
time frame okay so it's 15
minute here's that low you can see how
we just went below it right here see
that here's that low inside the fair
value Gap with the order block which is
a down Clos candle again we would be
anticipating some measure of
consolidation not dropping
lower
consolidation because that means we
would be anticipating a run above the
buy side here and the previous height is
to the left outside the scope of what
I'm zoomed in on now but you can see
it's still being highlighted and then
that 60 Minute fair value got in the
form of a cell sign and balance byid
efficiency that's here okay so what
we're going to do is we're going to drop
down to a even lower time frame and see
if there's any more detail in here with
a f minute
chart so now we're inside of a lower
time frame five minute chart and I've
highlighted
now this little area right down here I
told you we would talk about that in
here we're looking at a balanced price
range a balanced price range is where
the market has both a
downside and upside or sells side
delivery and buy side delivery that
overlap one another in the same relative
range in price so you can see how this
candle's
high that candles low that would
normally be what a sell sign balance byy
side and efficiency but look what's
happened over here we have a high a big
up closed candle and this candle's low
so what does that make
this a bid balance cell efficiency so
there's an overlapping between a CBI and
a bissy within the general area of the
same price range so I'm using the low
here and the high here so that way we
can see how this becomes a balanced
price range these are trapped Traders
okay this in here is a trap Trader or
trap traders that would have been caught
short in the classic days of commodity
trading if you were
to see old patterns like what would be
considered an island reversal okay uh
this is the closest thing that I can
kind of use to describe what's occurring
when there is a balanced price range
when it's extreme like this so when we
have a big decline large range candle
that's down and then eventually not like
months later not weeks later but when
it's a big drop and a handful of
candlesticks like this it's not a whole
lot of candles then eventually you know
rip back higher that means that this was
someone that's been caught their short
and they quickly repriced and leave them
down there so when I see that I look to
see where those two reference points are
where the market drops quickly for sells
side delivery and then when it rallies
back up
quickly those one big candles down one
big candle's up all the price ACS and
below it I would view that as trap
Trader so that means by itself that
gives me narrative that it's probably
going to go higher so now cue up the
idea of what would it be reaching for
well we see it was dropping back down
into an inefficiency here the buy side
here and old high back to the left and
that 60 Minute fair value Gap that's a
Cy up
here we're still in a 15-minute time
frame by the way I'm I miscued it
earlier calling a five
minute see the idea of the market
consolidating that's what we're showing
here now how am I referencing this
consolidation this is the part of it
that becomes like a knack okay um you
might not have the exact candles framed
like this
when you see an original consolidation
so when I call a original consolidation
that is where the market is accumulating
so what I did here I seen these two
candles here and then the body of this
one and the body of this one so right
away my eye jumps to that because it's
what it's a smooth
edge so I want to use that as the high
of the original consolidation what's the
low the lowest low see how easy that was
so when I'm looking at the original
consolidations I'm looking for a
repetitive overlapping or reoccurrence
of a level that's being constantly
referred back to inside of
consolidation now I'm anticipating the
market to go higher to go above the buy
side here and then reach up into this
inefficiency up
here but I'm anticipating also that it
should offer some measure of
consolidation because if it's going to
do that my premise behind swing trading
is it's all on the basis of a market
maker sell model or a market maker buy
model that's what swing trading is
whether you realize it or not whether
you want to subscribe to it or not
that's what the Market's doing it's not
doing harmonic stuff it's not doing L8
wave stuff it's moving on the principles
of running to liquidity or it's running
to inefficiencies and if it's not doing
that it's consolidating and if it's not
doing that it's highly manipulated and
then you're having some kind of manual
intervention some kind of shockin all
surprise rate announcement some kind of
wartime event something that would
destabilize the marketplace that you
can't and I can't predict before it
happens okay so that's always always the
underlying incurred risk that we have as
speculators so this area here is where
I'm framing that you can see still look
how many times it's referring to that
same level that's based over here so
when I'm looking at consolidations I'm
looking at levels that constantly repeat
I'm not just going to lay over top of
this high or this high or this High I'm
looking for something that frames it
very
clearly now when you go back and look at
my examples when I'm doing this in the
past and I've been doing for a long long
long time since the 90s but the examples
I've made public look and see how I'm
drawing your attention to these specific
consolidations do you see it do you see
it as a consolidation go back and look
at your other annotations that maybe you
have journaled before start looking at
it like this so that way when you
understand it when the market does
eventually leave the original
consolidation because we're underlyingly
bullish we have traders that are trapped
down here they don't want to drop down
below to give them an opportunity to get
out even though the market does
eventually drop lower here they may not
come back down into this area until a
later time it could be weeks it could be
days it could be hours it could be you
know a time that's unknown to you that's
outside the scope of the the
presentation here what you're looking
for and what I'm looking for is trades
that make sense where the Market's
reaching for liquidity and efficiencies
and then reversing for the sake of going
back against the original consolidation
where people are going to see this as a
support level
and I don't trade support resistance I
attack support resistance I attack
liquidity above old highs I attack
liquidity below old lows and I use
inefficiencies as targets or means of
Entry to trade against those same ideas
which would be anti- retail Theory I'm
against it I'm opposed to retail Theory
anything retail if it's support
resistance harmonic patterns Elliot wave
G wi off all that stuff that's all
retail logic and my understanding is
that's the reason why that 90% people
that try to use all that stuff fail and
they and they fail rather
quickly
so when we can frame the original
consolidation properly then once we
leave it how do we how are we leaving it
here look at the body right
there yeah we had a wick here we had a
wick right there too but look at the
body St inside that original
consolidation see that that's
characteristic to algorithmic price
delivery it's indicating to individuals
that I'm trying to show you that this is
the language that traders that use this
information and the algorithms The High
Frequency trading algorithms they
highlight these things in price and so
it gets their highfrequency trading
algorithm in the hunt for long entries
when is it allowed to take the
long that candle right there tells you
so now we can then refer back to the
same level here if it trades back to
that
level what's it doing it's returning
back to the original
consolidation that's how I teach my
market maker in sell model and buy model
the original consolidation it can leave
it it doesn't have to touch it but if it
does that's usually a trade so this
would be your your original entry okay
so you could go long there but sometimes
it won't offer a return back to the
original consolidation so it might just
need a
higher order entry and not offer
something right at the high of the
original consolidation the market
rallies up trades right into that
60-minute fair Val got Cy bodies tell
the narrative it's not interest in going
any higher why because look at this big
candle drop down there
wonderful we have an inefficiency here
we have an inefficiency
here drops
aggressively below the original
consolidation right back to the high of
the Balan price range right there which
is also just below that old low right
there that make these relative equal
lows what suspect for cells side so
cells side liquidity resting below there
that's the draw if it's going to go well
beyond the low here where the original
consolidation cell side liquidity would
be resting so in in layman's terms what
saying is it's building up a lot of
interest to go higher then it rips
higher comes back down gives one more
chance okay one more
chance then takes off takes Above This
High here then reaches up into the INE
efficiency then at that
point does it indicate that it wants to
go lower because if you're bearish and
you're extremely bearish to the degree
where you think this is a good entry
point you could sell up here as it does
that and that's a little scary I
understand that
but eventually you get these multiple
entries in here where you can go short
we'll look at them in Greater detail in
a minute but eventually the idea was to
draw back down into this area here but
if it goes below this how far can it go
there's no inefficiency over here it's
these relative equal lows and that's
where the market drops
[Music]
to all right so now we have more
candlesticks and now this is the F
minute chart so here's the original
consolidation you see the market does in
fact drop back down in inversion fair
value Gap I don't have it highlighted
because it would be too many things on
the chart but for
you that's inversion fair value Gap
meaning that usually that would be sell
side and balance by side efficiency if
the market trades back up into it we
would see it what trade lower but if
it's an inversion fair value Gap it
means it's going to go above it come
back down and use it as a discount array
and it's inside of the original
consolidation and rallies takes the buy
side trades the 60-minute fair value Gap
cby even in the 5 minute look at the
candlesticks the bodies they're inside
that Cy it's indicating that yes there's
Wicks going on in here but that's just
the the the damage okay where it's
reaching for the best case for smart
money to get short
against and then we see it drop
lower zoomed in on that F minute chart
here we have the original consolidation
the rally up and I want you to pause the
video again and it if you're not doing
this I promise you you're really not
getting the same measure of
understanding and the opportunity to see
it in your own eyes and test your
observations you might not get it right
but that's okay trying and attempting to
do it and seeing things with
detail you might not have it exactly
right but what happens if you do have
the things I'm going to point out it's
encouraging so don't Rob yourself the
opportunity to have that so pause the
video take a look at all the price run
from here up to here and then down what
do you
see all right if you haven't paused the
video and want to you better have it
paused because I'm about to
continue when you're looking at
this my eye sees
this return to the original
consolidation the market rallies up we
have a down closed candle that's just
below this area right here what does
this up close candle
become bullish
breaker low high lower
low down closed candle inside of the
breaker candle over here that's a
bullish order block right there so when
it rallies Up And Trades back down in
our Target is what up here the initial
draw is the liquidity above that high in
the older High to the left it's not
inside this fractal price action anymore
but it's highlight with this line so
this drop down that could be if you're
not seeing the original consolidation
correctly and this would be your
original entry
or uh your first stage accumulation then
this would be second stage
reaccumulation here and it rallies up
but if you don't for the sake of those
individuals that wouldn't have it
identified correctly in terms of how big
the original consolidation is when it
leaves it and when it comes back down in
I'm making allowance for that for this
lecture here so you you might not have
that skill set in the beginning to see
exactly how to define the
consolidation then if that's the case
then the bullish order block here would
be your first stage accumulation for you
is it wrong to classify it this way no
it's based on your understanding they're
both correct based on the level of
experience and knowing what you're doing
the only distinction is is how you may
or may not have had the original
consolidation mapped out right so many
of you may not have seen this as a
return to the original consolidation you
may have seen this as relative equal
highs being taken and now it's going to
go lower not knowing all the other
narrative that I've outlined
here so down close candle here in the
scope of a bullish price run during
buyid delivery aiming for this area up
in here the down close candles traded to
here so there's your entry for a first
stage accumulation or it would be second
stage reaccumulation if you use this as
your first
entry so again just make sure you
understand that sometimes you will only
have one point of accumulation and not
have a return to original consolidation
it might just rip higher give you one to
go in and then run real quick to it then
and then after that bleed
lower so it has a lot of different
variances to it again which is why I
said that you have to understand
everything that I teach to be able to be
well versed with trading Market maker
models that doesn't mean that you can't
see a very generic plain as day obvious
Market maker sell or Market maker bu
model when it's in the price action it's
obvious it's real easy to see it but the
potential for more of them to be there
and in your fingertips to be able to
reach and see I can see more setups now
uh that's going to increase over time
okay so just understand that so what
have I said here so far well you have an
opportunity to be a long entry here or a
long entry there so there's two setups
which one of these without going any
further so far which one of these would
make sense for you as a Trader right now
with your present understanding
obviously it's a rhetorical question
because I I can't obviously get the
response from you here but I want you to
think about that because I have some
traders that would only be interested in
taking this as their entry and if they
never get a return to the original
consolidation they're not
long others want to see that then it
rallies and then the next buying
opportunity as long as we don't get to
the Target up here they're willing to
take this as the first stage
accumulation and that's their entry and
then they ride it up into that Target
they may or may not have the ability or
interest in trying to go short at that
time other Traders can identify this as
the first stage
accumulation maybe not see this one down
here and they see this and they want to
wait to see if price rallies up to that
point then they use this part as their
model where they go short and they
pyramid in here here and wait for the
Run below here and don't even consider
something like done here is that wrong
no I have other students that want to
see it do this then really prove it want
to go lower and then they'll trade that
one right there and then go into that
that's a unicorn okay unicorn is second
stage redistribution in a cell model
Market maker cell
model now when I say
unicorn meaning everything's in your
favor you got everything behind you it's
just so it's so one-sided and you can
see it It's usually the most energetic
um swing high that it drops down from if
you've classified everything correctly
and everything to the left on the B side
of the curve is identified correctly and
you have everything labeled right and
you have time and price in agreement
with you chances are you're probably
going to Ride the Lightning which is
really quick sudden drops and it's real
fun to be in those low resistance
liquidity runs but that's one of the
most qualifying factors in my trading
and how I teach it to my students is to
find the easist highe speed low
resistance liquidity runs they're going
to always be the second stage
redistribution in a market maker sell
model which is what this is right here
okay
so if you miss this one this is also
what I teach which is
a buy balance sell sign efficiency
consequent encouragement which is the
midpoint of this inefficiency did it get
to this level up here yet nope so this
here is a bullish fair value Gap
consequent encroachment second stage
reaccumulation right
there now for some of you you might be
going long in here and then adding and
pyramiding to that to ride into this
level here that might be your
trade is there anything wrong with that
nope absolutely
not others that are high high-end
students they have been doing for a long
time they're going to sell these Mohawks
because the bodies are already
indicating that what it's not one to go
outside of that 60-minute fair value Gap
Cy so to every rally up here they're
going to go short and anything outside
of that PD arrays High which is the 60
Minute fair value Gap that's an
extreme extremely overbought without an
indicator entry and you've seen me do
that in my executions you've seen me do
that with my pyramid entries you've
watched me trade just outside of the
fair V gaps when I'm bearish or bullish
and it becomes the usually within a tick
or two from the actual highest high or
lowest low of the individual
candlesticks and then it starts running
the direction I need to
go this is what I refer to as a smart
money reversal you are years away from
ever being able to do that consistently
I promise you that's not me trying to
talk down to you it takes a great deal
of understanding of knowing what it is
that we're trying to do here because
essentially what you're doing is you're
picking the tops in bearish
markets now did you hear what it just
said we're picking
the tops in bearish markets I'm not
afraid of that I don't try to discourage
that of my students but I do absolutely
discourage that in my own trading when
it's a bull market I'm not trying to
pick the top because they're always
going to go well beyond what I think and
what you think it's going to do but when
we're bearish we can really get refined
and trade the tops in bare markets
because they're predictable they have a
characteristic they have a a Rhyme or
Reason as to why price should be behave
a specific way versus when you're in an
extremely bullish Market how do you
know I don't know every single time that
they won't go in there and intervene one
more time and drive it one more time
higher that's why it's dangerous to try
to pick tops in Bull markets but when
the market is predisposed to go lower
and you have all these types of
characteristics in Play It's rather
simple to anticipate where the Market's
going to run create an extreme and do a
smart money reversal but that easy
perspective I'm talking about that comes
with 30 years experience you don't have
30 years experience some of you don't
even have 5 years experience so it's
going to take a long time and I mean
long time for you to be able to see
smart money reversals as your entry
points okay but you don't need that
anticipate it being there and then once
it does the market breaks lower and any
rally back up look at the bodies here
okay that is what that's consequent
encroachment of the 60-minute fair value
Gap CBI that's your lowrisk short
we're trusting that we've already
mohawked above here with these Wicks so
now we're back down in here so any any
attempt to trade in the middle point of
this shaded area here that could be your
lowrisk short stop loss right above
here what happens if you get stopped out
ICT same thing wait for it to go lower
lead the fair value Gap low and if it
can touch the bottom of it again I would
use it as my entry stop would be break
back above whatever the highest high was
formed or the consequent coach of the
wick if it formed a higher Wick here
that's how i' would use it I would not
be afraid to go back in but that low
risk
is scary for some of you probably most
of you I'll be honest with you you would
never look at to take the trade like
that but how many examples have I done
this I've done many examples of this in
index Futures in Commodities I've done
it
in Forex pairs I I've shown a plethora
of examples of this not just talking
about like I'm doing here I'm actually
executing I'm doing the entries I'm
annotating the chart as I'm doing it too
many times with a one minute chart time
frame so I have to know what I'm doing
to know not only what I intend to do
trade-wise and managing it with a stop
loss but also to outline it and type it
out as the Market's gting with no Market
replay all live so the market breaks
lower and now what do we have
we're on the right side of the curve
that means this hypothetical invisible
line where the market trades up during
buy side delivery trades into our Target
where we anticipate the likelihood of a
reversal if the market starts to reverse
then we use the highest high that it
forms to the left of that is what the
buy side of the curve that means
everything leading to buy side delivery
now on the left side is what the sell
side of the curve that means we're in
sells side delivery what is sells side
delivery going to be aiming for the
original consolidation low why because
it wants to repic under the original
accumulation for sell side liquidity the
stops that are resting below here for
Traders that rode this up they're
married to the idea it's going to the
Moon Bitcoin 100,000 that type of
mentality eventually it drops and goes
attacks them okay so we went above the
buy side here to a specific price point
we had have a
breaker high low high or high body
staying inside of the PD array on the 60
Minute so it's indicating everything is
there for this to start dropping
basically that low is taken out right
there what does it create Fair guy gap
between this candle's low that candle's
high that could be a trade in itself but
this is a breaker so how far is it going
to go back up into it right there so
your bearish breaker that is your first
stage
distribution so you want to wait for the
smart R reversal you want to see a
lowrisk short does it show a willing to
want to run away wonderful that's tape
reading now you have a fair value Gap
and you have a breaker trades up into it
Go short that's your first stage
distribution does it break lower yes it
does then it does what it trades back to
where we had buy side
outlined support resistance folks are
going to see that as well what remember
that relative equal high that was a
little bit higher than this one to the
left they're going to see that as a
break of resistance turn support that
stuff does not work okay it does not
work you have to understand what price
is going to do why it's going to do it
what's the present narrative and where's
the liquidity or inefficiency is going
to really draw to you can't just simply
look at hypothetical imaginary lines
that are horizontal or diagonal for
goodness sake when you call it trend
line me all that stuff is mythology it
doesn't work it doesn't hold up so you
have to know what price is trying to do
how it gravitates and very specific
precise elements to price
action the market
rallies up here into a bearish order
block which is the up close candle here
trades into it digs into half of the
body right there that's mean threshold
so that bearish order block is your
second stage
redistribution this is going to be the
fastest elevator ride of the move going
down now it doesn't mean it won't be a
you know a sharp drop consolidate sharp
drop consolidate sharp drop that it can
do that but this is the one you want to
be entered on because if usually if you
miss this one you're probably going to
be chasing price now what happens if you
don't see this as your lowrisk short and
you see this as your lowrisk short
where I had the first a distribution is
that wrong no based on your present
understanding you're going to see it
probably as this is the first stage of
distribution to get short and the smart
money reversal is up here wonderful you
don't see a low risk short here in the
middle of that PD array that's okay
that's experience I understand that
you're not going to see everything that
I had seen and I'm make an allowances
for that while I'm teaching it so you
might see this as your your your lowrisk
sell or short and then this is your
first stage distribution so where would
the second stage distribution be or
redistribution be and it's in other
words instead of saying this one is your
second stage redistribution which means
it's going to be the highest degree of
speed magnitude and impulsiveness to go
lower
quicker if it's not this
one and you've classified that
as your first stage distribution and
you're surprised with a sudden drop
and you're going to be standing there
like a deer in headlights thinking what
am I supposed to do this thing going way
faster than I thought it was you're
going to be dazzled because you're on
side and it's probably gonna scare you
to get out of the trade and if you've
never been trading with real money
you're going to experience that okay
it's a weird Paradigm but you have to
press into
that if you notice here I've said that
the buy side of the curve used in
Reverse in the cell side of the curve
meaning what this down closed candle is
a bullish order block so while we were
going up when it drops back down into
this it should be offering what
support so when we get to the other side
of the curve which is to the right of
this imaginary line which is divided by
the highest high where we anticipate
anticipate seeing the market reverse on
the right side of the curve that's the
cell side so anything on the right side
of the curve that was offered as support
or as a discount array needs to start
acting as what a premium array or
resistance what's the low of that candle
draw it through where's the body
stopping it's respecting it isn't it
it's not just simply that bearish order
Block it's not as simple as you want to
think it is folks everybody out there
trying to teach order block Theory you
have no idea what you're doing that's
why I'm writing the books you have no
idea you've only been introduced the
idea you're trying to use things that
you're making up as you go
along
we break lower same thing here buy side
of the curve used in reverse on the sell
side of the curve meaning what this down
close candle what was it a bull shoulder
block on the buy side of the curve but
now we're on the left side of the curve
everything should be going lower so what
is going on here the Market's trading
right back up to the butt end of that
body boom that would be your second
stage redistribution if you looked at
that as first stage and this is the low
risk short smart money reversal and you
didn't classify anything low risk
that would be your second stage
redistribution for me that would be a
pyramiding entry so I would have even
more going short and then we drop down
into original consolidation 80% of the
trade would come off and I would see do
we have the ability to get any deeper
and we can see it goes lower deep
retracement and finally lower in
[Music]
here so for the folks that want to know
this entire presentation was under the
discussion of the British pound versus
US dollar Forex
pair all of these things here folks this
occurs on every asset
class it's there all the time now one of
the wonderful elements that's not been
discussed so far but I mentioned
briefing in the beginning of the
discussion is when everything with price
is in agreement with time because time
sets the stage then price does the act
of precision so it's time and
price look what's occurring here on the
31st we have
consolidation we leave the consolidation
come back in return to original
consolidation when does that occur
London open rallies up right in here we
have an order block right there and then
we have what it rips into the buy side
trading up
into
New York open 7 o'clock in the
morning there's your Market reversal
profile part
of a market maker sell
model time and price everything that was
Illustrated over here now look what
we're at we're inside of the New York
open Kill Zone we have a
breaker we have a bearish order
block all within what the New York open
Kill Zone this is also op
trade
entry right
there this right here is model 2022 buy
side taken shift in Market structure
fair value Gap go short that's M
2022 this right here trading up into
that that is the 7 o'clock in the
morning to 9 o'clock in the morning New
York open Kill Zone Silver
Bullet man how many silver bullets I got
a whole rack of silver Worlds Fair Value
gaps are always forming folks you have
to understand what the narrative is in
play for that session or that operating
time that you're using for your trading
day I'm using times of the day that have
high intakes of volume where order flow
is increasing it's rapid there's a lot
of interest getting in the
marketplace so you frame what you want
to trade you want to trade as little as
an hour a day okay I I told you that you
want to trade a full Kill Zone two hours
three hours okay I've told you that too
I can't trade New York I got to trade
London okay I told I told you how to
trade that all these things are there
now what did I teach you about the
trading day in terms of the opposite end
the
range if the whole idea was to run up
have a market reversal profile and we
have a market maker sell model here this
Dro down below these relative equal lows
here what time can it arrive when can it
arrive at the target of reaching below
that London close 10 o'clock to noon New
York local
time 10
o'clock to
noon friends and neighbors that's not
random that's all part of the things
I've talked about all throughout the
teachings of this entire YouTube channel
you have to know more than just a couple
things that do the market maker sell
model and buy models so I've been very
honored to be your Mentor here I've been
honored to be a conduit to share all
these things that I've collected and
authored over the last 30 years it's
been a wonderful experience I've been
touched by so many of you as students I
have been moved to tears for some of you
with all the uh adoration and respect
you've shown to me and I'm so thankful
for that but like all things all good
things must come to an end and I am
married to a woman that demands more of
my personal time and social media and
mentoring has taken a great deal of that
so I want you all to know that it has
been a
pleasure to be able to be in this seat
as a teacher as a a role model for
learning how to trade and read price
action I want you all to know that none
of the content on this YouTube channel
or my Twitter will be deleted none of it
will be augmented and I wish you all
nothing but success with
it until I talk to you next
time good luck and good Trading