[Music]
so the idea was that NASDAQ was going to
attack this Range High
after
Turtles souping the range low right
so as we know we have a ranging Market
then a purge of either side is gonna
take us to the other side right
so
the monthly
and of course if you probe the order
flow then we are disrespecting
this bullish order block right we close
below it
we're supposed to accelerate downwards
if it was a valid bearish order block
but
it was invalidated
we did not respect the bearish Peter
right and
we created a bullish PD array which is
this uh
breaker right here right
and we have this bullish
order block right here
so we uh we trade above it we come back
into it and we rally so the monthly is
bullish the monthly is screaming bullish
and I've been saying it
in the replies on Twitter and I even
gave out a trade idea a couple of weeks
ago
a couple of weeks there was one two I
think it was two weeks ago
so
we're expecting the month of uh now I
was expecting it to happen in April but
they did not give me that
so we're expecting a bullish expansion
to the upside during the month of March
When You're Expecting a bullish
candle to print then you look to buy
below the open price
right so bullish candle
you'll see right now
you wait for the open if you're bullish
you wait for accumulation manipulation
into a discount PD array and a rally
right
which we'll see right now
so now down to the weekly
of course this is the the infamous bar
replay however this was called live on
Twitter
right I literally spoon fed you all a
trade idea
so you can't complain
and if you do then uh
I can't help you
so
let's probe first of all we have a range
right range range Low Range High we
purge the range low
so we have two Targets the 50 and the
Range High so
so the eyes are up here so the drawn
liquidity prices is is gravitating
towards the Range High
right
plus it's disrespecting bullish PD
arrays uh bearish PD Rays excuse me on
the monthly it's disrespecting bearish
speed areas on the monthly and
respecting bullish pteries on the
monthly now let's look at the weekly the
weekly is saying that
well it's not talking but the weekly
chart is telling you
the price is also again it's breaking
highs
it's rejecting lows
right it's breaking through bullish PD
rays
bearish not bullish it's breaking
through this this this uh bearish order
block
and it's respecting
this bullish weekly fvg
all right
so you got a turtle soup
and you go to Rally
so monthly is bullish
obviously is bullish
weekly is bullish so
price is
is uh is more likely to go upwards and
we have the range of course the range is
saying
the range is it's a cheat code
if you know what to look for it can tell
you a lot of stuff
um
so anyway
by all means we are we are bullish
as as we've said before as I've said
before because there's no we here
uh
I'm not your your typical Twitter ICT
influencer quote unquote
this is a one-man show
so
uh how do you probe border flow highs
and lows
Order Box
which is down close and up close candles
are up close candles providing
resistance or being broken through and
down close candles providing support
or vice versa and fvgs
these are the three ways to measure and
probe order flow as you can see right
now
so
lows and highs we are rejecting the low
and we're breaking the height that's one
thing another thing is we are breaking
through
we are breaking through
bearish PD arrays
on the weekly
this one as well
and we're respecting bullish PD arrays
right
uh which is the candles so the up close
candles are being broken through
and the down closed candles are
providing support
gaps same thing so order flow is bullish
on the weekly and when you have weekly
bullish order flow then you can't expect
resistance from a daily PD array right
until the weekly objective is met
and so on you can apply that to all time
frames
as time and price are both fractal
what's going on over here drawing small
dots so
monthly order flow is bullish
weekly bullish
now let's look at the daily
here
and it was precisely over here
that I called for the rally to the Range
High
another key level
is the monthly order block
all right
let's draw a line
order luck monthly
over here
I'd like to keep keep the charts clean
so let's just keep it
a bit
less
dense is that the word
I don't think so
but anyway
we're not here to learn about
photography or editing or whatever
design image imagery
we are here to learn about price
so we're breaking highs and we're
rejecting the lows right
eyes
broken
lows
rejected
bullish candles providing
bullish up close candles are being
broken through and down close candles
are providing support
so order flow is bullish right
order flow is bullish
highs lows
bearish candles and gaps
by all means
order flow is uh bullish so there is no
reason to expect any downside there is
no reason to expect a turtle soup over
here which takes us down here to the
range low right why because we're we're
respecting bullish PD arrays on the
monthly and weekly and daily
so as long as the order flow is being
respected turtle soup follows order flow
right you can't they go hand in hand if
you try and if you try and
trade turtle soup as a pattern you'll
get wrecked
you must understand order flow
so anyway
we were right here
right over here so we broke through the
high and I mentioned this a lot of times
we broke through the high so we're
breaking highs
how do you know broke through because
you closed above the high
when we close above a high
and multiple times right
look at the difference between this
close and this close
not even a wick right so this is a
rejection
and this is a break
and this is a rejection before a break
this is a common pattern which you'll
recognize uh before a rail breakout
right there is a
a quick sharp decline before a violent
move upwards
right that's a little bit more advanced
a more more intricate
uh but for those who are interested in
studying that you can you can enjoy
that little piece of
that little nugget of information which
I gave away
and yes it is a nugget which you can use
uh how to use that let's talk about that
how do you use that pattern or that
little price
uh fractal which repeats again and again
and again before a real Breakout
right of any uh range
there is a
a sharp
false breakout first and then a violent
uh break out right
same with the bearish there is a
before you before you break through the
range there is a violent for Trace
and then it breaks out
all right the purpose of this is
to
sucker in
more sellers at this previous resistance
level
right
and convince them of their positions
they add more and they get erect
plus that's one group of people getting
up
uh uh it also induces or entices unlike
the inducement to uh it's to uh cliche
everyone's using it
so it entices buyers above this high
they also get suckered in before being
right
but the movement is so violent that they
suck that they cower out again right
that's good number two being being
screwed over
group number three being screwed over is
the guy who was short down over here at
this turtle soup
when it breaks above the high
then he gives away his position
in fear of it going and rallying higher
and it comes back down he regrets he
sells again and he gets wrecked right so
uh
there's always these three groups of
people always in any price movement
there is uh these three groups of people
and usually they're the same person
who's just trying to catch every single
price swing and they're getting wrecked
up and down
uh and this is something you will not
understand unless you go and get wrecked
yourself again and again and again and
again
and uh you'll really understand each and
every single price movement why this
happens why that happens why this
happens
uh
that's on a personal loan but on a smart
money versus dumb money level that's the
explanation of of what's the what's the
purpose of this move because every
single price move as I say every single
price move has an explanation right
so
well it's nonsense
of course you use it how because over
here
before we remove it
how do you use this
well you can use it by being long from
the range low anyway
right that's the that's the cleanest
those are my moves I enter at the at the
extremities of the range
or the 50 or a higher time frame PD
array
however a model that has been uh showed
is
show it to you is uh the turtle soup at
the 50 of the range
and that is where this comes in play
before the breakout there's a turtle
soup that happens at or near the 50 of
the range
if that resonates with you you can use
it as a model
because as we as I mentioned before many
times you want to find one
model which you perfect
not try everything out right
you want to go and marry one one one
girl one woman
and create a nice long
long lasting
sustainable relationship
which means something right you got a
house together you got you got kids you
got you got a whole life together yeah
you got memories
you got
you have
going through adversity together right
you have all of this
with one person
as opposed to
one night stand here when I stand here
one here one here one here meaningless
meaningless meaningless this is a good
comparison an analogy of having a model
versus having no model
right
I'm not sure I went over there but uh
that is an analogy
so we remove all of this nonsense and we
focus on the trade idea
we broke through the high
and we created a PD array at the High
which is this fvg right
over here and that is when I said folks
my friends
ladies and gentlemen
we're gonna attack this
August High
from here
the trade idea I gave up was this
so
we trade back
into the high and this is where the SR
Philips work but they don't work because
they're Sr Phillips they work because of
the PD array created at the high which
is this order block fvg right
order block
fvg
combination
so
the idea I gave out was this was we
trade back into the fvg
into the broken High
and we rally
Off to the Races
to August High
obviously potentially a bit higher
because uh
uh
a liquidity Purge is going to be
is going to be a
it's not going to be add to the tick and
then it's going to decline no it's going
to be a bit higher it varies according
to the time frame
but that's the point
and you don't know if it's going to be a
break or Purge
you have to watch you have some
indications which I'm not going to speak
about over here
because there's not much time
but
um generally speaking you want to
anticipate a run slightly above the high
or below the low right
so
the anticipation was in summary
because I know some people like to hear
the Rants and others just want to get to
the point
so in summary we break the high we
create the PD array at the High
as soon as this happens we have
displacement
we have a break of the high we have
bullish order flow on the monthly weekly
and daily so we expect to retrace into
the fvg and a rally
and what happened that is precisely what
happened now right over here when you
see this dump
which happened right over here
right here now
how many of you would get suckered into
uh selling that
probably more than I would like to say
so
however the rule says if we're breaking
highs
then the dump below the low
is a fake turtle soup
plus it's into a pedia array
right also on the weekly time frame
which is I'm going to leave to you
so when we're bullish then then bearish
dumps
are to be bought right that is when you
buy the dip you don't buy the dip in a
down trending Market you buy the dip in
an uptrending Market
right on the right side of the curve so
oh
we uh
decline into the fvg
we give it a second touch and this is
where I call for ES to Rally that's also
another review which is going to come
out soon this uh this week
hopefully
inshallah
uh so
the dump below the low is expected to be
a fake false phony turtle soup and we
rally and that is precisely what
happened
right
just blast it off
now the stop loss was also given so this
is this was pretty much a spoon fed idea
which I used to do a lot back in the day
I do less of it now but I still do it
it's not as much
here is one the stop loss could have
been this
all right
but I'm a so I give
conservative stop losses on Twitter
which is this intermediate term low
right
and that was the trade idea which you
see I will either have posted the
picture before this video or after this
video
and um
that is it my friends
a short quick and much I'm not exactly
sure how long this video was
but that is a short quick
analysis of
the NASDAQ trade price wise
time wise
if you look at the open high low and close of the monthly chart
why is this not giving me the
uh
all right well if you look at the open high low and close of the monthly chart
exit yes
let's go to the monthly candle
and yes it's delayed data for the
because I don't trade NASDAQ I
trade Nas 100.
if I do trade NASDAQ or or yes I don't
trade Es at least now actually SPX 500
if I do right
so I don't need to buy this
uh you can buy it you can go and
do what you want
there was some some goofballs commenting
on the delayed data right it's always
funny because people always find
something to about
uh generally speaking I don't mind
I like to uh
uh
I like to uh you know just have a back
and forth a playful back and forth as
long as it's respectful
if you're disrespectful then I probably
won't engage with you right if you're
having a playful fun back and forth and
sure I'm game
so
the monthly candles
power of three so we're bullish what did
I say we expect to buy below the open
price right
there's so much more
but let's stay on topic
let us stay on topic
so let's go back
to the beginning of the month
right
let's go to daily
run or right now
why is this time messed up what is this
let's open a NASDAQ for this one let's
open a Nas 100.
Naz 100
cleaner
[Music]
let's go to the monthly
remove this
so
my expectation was a classic buy candle
literally an expansion to the upside why
I will leave that for you to figure out
good luck with it
I've mentioned it on my Twitter a couple
times
so if you haven't had the focus to go
and
dig deep then you don't deserve to know
oh but I don't have time I'm busy with
life you don't deserve to know
because if you really wanted to know you
would dig deep and you would know
oh but I got kids I got a fan you don't
deserve to know
so
monthly let's go to the
remove this
so
too many shows
but I just woke up so who cares
so the monthly candle opens as we said
when we're bullish
right
I'd like to see the multi of the poor
hour
gives me a nice view
when we are bullish
and we're expecting higher prices
then what do we do
then we simply
buy below the opening price
we wait for a manipulation below the
open price and we buy right
before the month opens we have the two
key levels which we expect to cap the
monthly candle right or the expansion
whatever candle it is before the candle
opens and you're expecting an expansion
candle then you
draw the two key levels which you expect
to provide the expansion
from the low to the high
so we have here a four hour
all right let's pretend this never
happened
all right here none of this happened
we have these two key levels
right over here we have this one
the August High and the monthly order
block up here
but as always when you have a Target
when you're in a trade then it's always
good to exit at 75 percent of the target
that's what I do
so
the month another so the month of the
monthly candle opens we decline below
the opening price
right so manipulation as soon as you see
a decline
obviously not blindly within context but
when you see a decline or a rally
below or above the opening price
then you should be on alert
you got this
you had a beautiful beautiful
open when we're bullish we buy below the
opening price
right so you buy here
your stop loss is going to be either
down here or you choose an intermediate
term low nearby
and then you
ride until
price reaches the opposite end of the
range you're expecting it to go
right
it's open you buy below the opening
price
and you wait for your trade to play out
now I was going to use the RR tool
that's too tacky you get the idea
right so entry would be this
so again open decline key level
higher time frame daily order block is
giving you a four hour expansion
right
while we're bullish on the monthly and
we're expecting a monthly bullish candle
so
that was Eddie as soon as as soon as it
hits to this top or even before you're
out of the trade idea
as a tape reading practice you can wait
you can you can watch it you can always
watch it
that's another thing is when you when
you miss a move don't be pissed when you
miss your entry you don't get a fill for
example that's an that's an opportunity
for you to learn
all right
so you should be happy when you lose you
should be happy when you miss
opportunities because that is a
that is a way for you to learn about
price
open
decline
expansion
right
and again before the break
a fake
decline
and then true break
right
anyway
that is the
NASDAQ described
from both lenses of time and price
and that is pretty much it my friends
and a quick bonus for those viewers who
who stuck it out till here there was a
trade over here
a trade idea which had formed
potentially but failed
let's look at Whitefield
right over here
the idea was breaker into these equal
lows right looks reasonable
breaker
into the equal loss
right
however
You could argue that it's a valid idea
it's not completely invalid because
it was a low that that did not Purge it
was a mere stop hunt of the high
breaker and two equal lows that's a
valid setup
however
which I had to give out by the way
now when you see
price approaching a breaker
then what do you want to see you want to
see the wicking through the body and
never closing above the
uh the closing price at the breaker
right
so what you don't want to see is this
this close inside that is a horrible
sign and that is usually a sign that is
going to Target the breaker's high
right so when you see when you have when
you're when you have a bearish bias and
you see a breaker
being
disrespected then you can reasonably
anticipate that the breaker is high is
going to be purged
right or attacked or targeted
so that in itself is a trade idea
so you're going to find a lower time
frame PD array
inside of that breaker right so it's a
sort of an inverted breaker
you see the beauty
breaker disrespected and flipped into
support
Target is Breakers High
that is a key
key aspect of watching Breakers when you
trade them and you'll notice this by
yourself
is you never want to see them close
above the closing price of the breaker
all right you want to see them Wick
through let's let's find you
let's see if we can find a a breaker
nearby a valid correct breaker
there should be one nearby
not too far away
furthermore it is a it is a smaller time
frame
so it should be pretty quick
let's say this one for example
right
high low high or high
we close below this candle this specific
candle right
now this is where controversy comes in
breaker selection
right some people like to choose uh the
two candles together
some people like to pinpoint the exact
candle that caused the
The Purge
right
to be safe you can do this right I mean
the risk reward is still pretty good
but to be precise there's always a
specific candle responsible
right but for the sake of uh this
recording let's say it's uh
these two candles together
right look at the close of the breaker
and look at the respect price has for
the close
right
so as with the other PD arrays
quick quick quick
and fast decline
as with the other PD arrays the
invalidation of PD array starts from a
close above the mean
threshold of the PD array right the 50
percent
so that's a way to cut half of the stop
loss
all right that's the purpose of knowing
that it's not just thick of it it's not
just for the sake of knowing it
so that's a quick breaker
explanation
and let's find another example of a
valid breaker for the
for the sickness of
completion
[Music]
shouldn't take too long
let's use
a normal one first which is right here
right
you gotta you got a high you got a low
you got a higher high and you break
through it
this is your breaker
this entire candle
is your breaker
now
this is why uh the signs of the failure
of a breaker
are as follows number one
a close
above the close
right
but these weren't so convincing right
it's closing but it's uh
it's never closing twice for example
right it's never closing twice here
closed once
it's going deep huh
one two
one
a week double close and then it closes
back uh below
one only one strong one and then a
second one below right also respecting
the fifty percent
right so the number of closes is also an
important factor
of determining a real versus versus a
fake Break whether it's a breakout
whether it's a an invalidation of a PD
array
that is something I leave for your
studies
same over here
how many closes did it close
just one
right one close below one above and so
on
so
same over here
just one over here
and the second one is below and decline
also this
respect to this bearish pdra
the 50 of the pdra
was respected
measuring the body of course
[Music]
all right so the number of clothes
doesn't matter
the number of closes
matter
and let's find another breaker
here's some breaker drill
this one right here
you got a low you got a high you got a
lower low and you got a green or an up
close candle that caused The Purge this
is a beautiful
this is how the Ideal breaker looks like
right
a thick high volume bulky candle which
preceded the the violent move downwards
turtle soup
rally
as soon as you close twice above the
breaker one two
right and then it consolidates
so we've closed we've we've unlocked
so we think about it we've unlocked the
breaker right
and then we also created a PD array at
this High which is fpg
Fiji
plus breaker
plus breaking through this high
plus rejecting the slow
right so we're breaking through
bullish candles
we're getting support from bearish
candles
right
here
support
breaking through the bullish candles
rejecting lows
and breaking highs
so order Flow by all means is bullish
right here
you got this nice breaker
which happens to be
happening after a purge of the range Low
Range High
so the target is the Range High anyway
right
you had that
entry
stop loss Target
and so on
so
that's pretty much uh
all there is to this video took way too
long
it took way way too long
but it is what it is
the main takeaway was the main focus was
on The Naz trade idea
right which was
let's take a last
summary
go over here
delete remove all
drawings and
that's a forbidden word
so we're here
good old bar replay because it's all
hindsight right
it's all hindsight
over here
August High
we are breaking the high
order flow is is bullish on the
on the monthly or bullish
on the weekly
we are also bullish
right
on The Daily
we are breaking
the high
retracing into an f v g
after spending a considerable amount of
time
now do you know how much time that was
which we spent
over
here before actually flying
the amount of time we spent
before providing the real move was
after the break of course right
around 20 days
so this is a prime turtle soup example
just beautiful
right you could have been separated by
this one
but if you had to stop us down here
you'd be fine
or you could have waited for the month
uh you could have waited for a
for the next month to enter
right up here after the turtle soup
forms itself because you can use turtle
soup either as an entry or as a
confirmation for your bias so it's never
a bad idea to understand turtle soup
because it happens all the time
all the time
turtle soup
with an smt of course it's a failure
swing Turtles with the bodies
you got a turtle soup here
you get a turtle soup all the time
there's always a turtle soup somewhere
happening at a higher time frame PD
array
right
false breakdown
false breakdown you get the idea right
so it's never bad to understand turtle
soup
never
either to use it as an entry or as a
a confirmation for your bias
so the 20 40 6A look back we are purging
a 20-day low
right
so it's very unlikely that we keep
rattling just like that
right because price is always moving in
trend
range Trend range Trend range and so on
so
[Music]
the idea was
for the last final time
I haven't done a video for so long that
I just
keep ranting and ranting and talking and
talking
but
um
deal with it
that's what you get
you get this
the expectation is to
decline into the fvg
the pdra created at the High
and then a violent rally
stop loss over here
or here
because it's a turtle soup low
right
which which uh holds a lot of Trapped
liquidity down here
plus these two consecutive Down Candles
so it would be a reasonable stop loss to
keep it up here if you kept yourself
lost here I wouldn't blame you
over here is a simply safer
but here's also a good one here was a
good saw box with a higher risk to
reward
so you get that
you got a decline and you get a violent
rally
far away
and she never stopped
is it a she is
are they gender neutral I don't know
but no one cares
so
that's all for now I hope you found that
insightful
and good luck
and good Trading
and a happy Sunday
for those who are watching today
[Music]