all right folks welcome back
this is a weekly review
of the dollar Index Euro
es and the NASDAQ
so we're looking at the weekly chart of
the dollar Index if you did not watch
July 9th 2023's market review videos on
the YouTube channel
uh go back and watch that first because
without having seen that first
you're really not going to fully
appreciate what's being shared here okay
so I'm going to assume that you are
going to stop the video and go watch
that one or you're really not gonna do
very well in terms of
benefiting from what was shown before
the fact
so we talked about
this fair value Gap here on the weekly
chart this is completely permissible for
price to do this type of thing looking
through it
and I mentioned that we would likely
draw
to the sell side below here
and then below here
it got a little animated on the downside
and I'll take your attention right over
here it was just I think one tick or so
short of actually reaching the high
of the Gap and this is
from the week beginning April 11 2022
okay so that's this week right here
and the week beginning March 28 2022 the
high
of that candle so that makes that fair
value Gap here and say five seven
balance outside efficiency
so we'll watch and see if it wants to
dig into that going into this week apart
from that I don't really have a whole
lot
this year in terms of prognostication I
give you
a barn burner last Sunday and it pretty
much was very explosive this past week
daily chart
okay in the commentary in July 9th 2023s
Sunday review and Analysis before the
market even opened up
I mentioned that this is the breaker
that you're going to be watching and
this is where we had closed for that
particular week
we opened traded up into the breaker
okay and what I'm showing you here is
the low
to the high mid point of that is mean
threshold order blocks the midpoint is
mean threshold gaps are inefficiencies
the midpoint is consequent encroachment
you can see we traded up into it here
hits it beautifully then delivery to the
downside
so there's Mondays trading Tuesday we
finally made our way into
this fair value Gap
and accelerated to the downside
attacking the sell side as I've
mentioned we would likely do if we
traded
accordingly on Monday go back and listen
to
July 9th 2023's analysis before the
market opened up
we were anticipating the return back
into this breaker does it deliver
off that breaker yes so that means we
can anticipate this area here
sell side draw okay
I'm just going to toss this in here
because you know I see a lot of comments
that people share with me that Me Maybe
are being made in other YouTubers
comment section sometimes it does appear
in my own comment section yes I can see
your comments it looks like the comment
section is open but what it is that I
have it set for review
and it's it's for me to read them their
personal messages to me okay so to keep
the people with a lot of uh hurt
feelings when there's a lot of adoration
shared towards me to prevent them from
being harmed or having their their
feelings hurt by seeing other people
appreciate what I've done for them I I
keep these messages private I've done it
in the past I've showed you why I keep
it private and when I open them up
publicly everybody pretty much was it
was like a sugar Fest but sometimes I'll
get a comment saying that I'm teaching
like for instance the sell side here
there's they'll suggest that I'm calling
sell side support
um no I'm teaching you to view how the
market will draw to that liquidity to it
and through it
okay to it and through it buy side is
not resistance buy side is a draw on
liquidity
for markets that are going to go higher
we want to tap into that by side
liquidity that's above old highs
relative equal highs or single highs
so it's not a matter of support and
resistance support and resistance is
garbage okay let's just be real Frank
with one another here I don't believe in
support and resistance but I have
methods that will teach you real Dynamic
support resistance and that's my
inefficiencies and gaps
okay so the way I use gaps they're not
filled and done away with the market
many times will revert back to an old
gaps high low or consequent encroachment
so we don't do trading in supply and
demand zones with whether it's ambiguous
you know or you have to determine where
you're going to buy or sell based on
that theory
there's three specific price levels that
I'm looking at I'd like to see and if
I'm going to use the range for targeting
for determining whether or not the
inefficiency is going to provide a means
of
stating off continuation then I'll put
the four gradients on that level too so
it's either
I'm looking for it as a Target or I'm
looking for it as a entry
and vice versa so we're not looking at
this level here anticipating this to be
some measure of support to buy from
that's not what I'm doing and that's the
infancy of most of these individuals
that are on the internet they will look
at something and it resembles because I
have a rectangle or I'm drawing a line
on that old load so they think naturally
that's
what I'm looking for is a buy there I
don't believe in that theory I I attack
old mode okay I don't look at trying to
find some reason to buy down here
because the market went up there before
I teach you to anticipate that the
retail Traders with that mindset they're
going to want to buy there
and the people that are already long
they have stops orders below there what
kind of stops sell stops so that's
perfect for me if I'm short because I'm
going to buy below those loads
not at those lows I want to go through
them and reach for some targets beyond
that so it's nonsensical to try to say
that what I'm teaching you is classic
smart resistance because I absolutely do
not have any faith in that at all and
you shouldn't either
so the breaker in here
you can see we hit that and we worked
off that Weekly fair value Gap and I
mentioned in the July 9th video that it
doesn't look like there's a gap at all
in here which is the reason why you want
to transpose your weekly inefficiencies
onto your daily chart
and you won't lose sight of what the
higher time frame context is if you do
that all right let's move on over to
euro
so you're a Dollar weekly chart I've
been counseling you all for months now
to anticipate this
weekly volume and balance okay so yes
this is not in any of your textbooks
it's not supplying demand it's not like
off it's not anything else out there
okay you can see how the market has
drawn price up into that that's
algorithmic price action you will not
find a retail book a retail educator you
will not find anybody that's going to
teach you to anticipate the market
wanting to go back into this area
they don't see it that way Steve Nielsen
would have never talked about this and
he's Mr candlestick okay so I say all
these things and for some of you it gets
under your your skin when I when I do
this I'm not trying to sound
right okay I'm not trying to belittle
anybody else but I have a constant flow
of new viewers
that will come to me in the previous
video or the video before it and they'll
say you know this looks like that or
this looks like this or this seems like
it's a rebranding or renaming of this or
that I'm going to challenge you to go
out and find these things
the way I use them okay
you're not going to find it prior to me
so I would love nothing more to be able
to point to someone else and say this
person taught me this so that way I
don't have to make all these videos okay
but it's nonsensical for any of you to
sit here and try to wrestle with the
idea that this has been rebranded from
from anything else out there because
this is nothing like anything else this
is the marketplace it's algorithmically
delivered AI runs the show here and
sometimes manual intervention steps in
and you you probably aren't going to
make money and if I traded that day I
probably would lose money too
so you have to submit yourself to that
potential risk and all of us understand
that especially if you're trading with
real money because you signed the risk
disclosures when you do so so we looked
at this weekly inversion fair value you
got okay and this again is not a
liquidity void find a sell signal here
and sell off that's not what you're
looking for okay we are looking for this
level to act as support so that's what
makes this a ICT inversion fair value
cap right and you can see how we opened
for the week we traded down admittedly
we did not match the low of this candle
with the low of that one don't so don't
don't be fooled by the visual
representation that's being shown here
but for the spread
you would have been you know you would
have been stopped out if you were long
this has been honest
the broker would open the spread up on
you and you would have been tagged and
stopped out before you would have been
capturing that move but the idea was I
was teaching you on Sunday July 9th 2023
that it would trade down to that and
then run up to the buy side here and
into this weekly volume and balance
I don't know folks this does your chart
show this I mean if you post
the euro dollar in your trading platform
and you put it on a weekly chart does it
look like this
do you have a huge big bullish candle
that closed on the high
I don't know you gotta decide whether or
not this is all made up or Cherry Picked
or whatnot but let's drop down to a
daily chart here
okay you see Mondays trading we opened
traded down towards the weekly inversion
fair value Gap
rallies
Tuesday we have a small little end of
decisive day
and then explosion on Wednesday
taking the buy side and trading rates of
the low looking very close right at the
low the weekly volume and balance and
then we open
find some support at the weekly volume
balance rallies
Friday we have a little bit of
continuation so the only thing I have
going into this week is I want to see it
completely close that in that's it
now
when I
share my analysis and the market runs
through these levels and it delivers as
a hotline
invariably and there's a small sect of
my community that will come out and go
right to Twitter and say okay what's
next what's it going to do next it's
like
I don't know if they're just waiting for
me to get it wrong okay and they want to
hurry up and get to the next one where I
can potentially get it wrong or
they're just not satisfied with this
event for study purposes there's so much
to go into this with and study like
there's so much detail going in in mine
for your own edification
and wasting it just looking for the next
opportunities so you can either
you know dog pile on the idea that I'm
expecting it to go higher or lower and
you try to find setups in that you
really like learning just with that you
got to go into and
back test all these individual days
individual trading sessions
[Music]
all right so here's the hourly chart
here and you can see how we just fell
short if you look real close we just
fell short
before touching the high end of that
Weekly inversion fair value go
and the market rallied
came back down found some support
great interfere Vega
rallies again
comes into another
you got and rallies and right in here it
creates
the measuring Gap
what makes this a measuring Gap well
we're anticipating price getting as high
as this shaded area up here which is a
weekly volume of balance and we
anticipated this here acting as what
some measure of instigation of a new
rally
so to speak in simple terms for you this
is not classic support and resistance
but I'm going to use the idea so that
way you can follow along in terms of
context we anticipated the top of this
area here that's shaded in Orange
I guess it's really not orange is it
it's a hue that's very close to Orange
and then we expected that to act as
support and then we would look to see it
get to this level here which is the old
buy side liquidity we didn't see it
going there and then coming back down we
did not talk about that I did not say
that was going to happen I said that we
would go to that through it and then
trade into this range now what what
levels am I talking about when we get
into these ranges I'm going to cover
that in a moment but let's go into a
little bit more details here
15-minute time frame
you can see two down closed candles here
that's a bullish order block consecutive
down closed candles
small little Gap there extend that
forward you can see how the market
trades down into that and then rallies
inversion fair value got Market find
support there rallies up I have lessons
and lectures and discussions with
inversion repair banking apps so you'll
understand more about that
you know but just let's get through this
year going through some examples because
I'm laying down a lot of foundation
and you're not going to learn this with
one video okay so I've said this many
times before the five minute trainer
guys out there to try to take my content
and make Cliff Notes out of it you're
not going to teach anybody efficiently
doing that but you can get a lot of
clicks doing it so here's that measuring
Gap
moves up into the low of the weekly
volume of balance and then we find
support at the weekly volume balance you
see that look at that that's beautiful
now if you would have never known about
the weekly volume abounds you would
never have seen that as a level to
anticipate the market wanting to go
higher
Mark calls back down into a small little
Gap in here
rallies again right in here we have a
bullshore block
right to extend the hearing optimal
trade entry as well and then it rallies
and continuously moves higher I've seen
a couple tweets that people were
complaining how you know the market did
in fact go where we were expecting it to
go from July 9th 2023's analysis
video shared on my YouTube channel
but they never mentioned you many times
not having a way to get into the trade
okay and this is the easiest ones that
are in the chart there's lots of other
smaller time frame entries that could
have been utilized okay and if you don't
see that that's okay it's because you're
still learning but this was a very fast
Market it was doing very sudden runs
and
we have a lot of things going on
and the way money is being transferred
uh is fundamentally changing so that
speeds up things a lot more
well expediently and you're seeing that
reaction here and there's a lot of other
things that's going on on the other side
of the world that's probably going to be
a burdensome thing for all of us but
we'll leave that out of the discussion
for now for your homework
as an additional study you want to take
this weekly volume imbalance and lay
your Fibonacci on it from the high to
the low make sure you get the actual
High and the low shown from the weekly
chart
that makes this weekly volume of ounce
so I'll just go back and watch the
beginning of the video you'll see the
candles I'm drawing from you can do a
Fibonacci overlay that has the zero 100
level
and then 0.25
0.50
0.75 and study where we are on the lower
time frames like one minute five minute
charts every time we traded at
or near
the 25
gradient to 50 gradient in the 75
gradient
all right moving on into enemy s p this
is the seasonal tendency chart for
e-mini s p
and I'm gonna take you back in time
for a couple minutes in our conversation
here and I talked about how I like
seeing the seasonal tendency that comes
in in the month of May leading into June
June typically makes a really strong low
and that's just about every single year
okay that one's really really strong but
I like having a shorting opportunity
going into the last week of April going
into May and then majority of may we see
some
measure of selling well this year while
we were anticipating it the market
internals did not present that idea in
technicals so while I was expecting and
looking for it we didn't do anything
that would get us short and take a loss
what we were doing is we were seeing the
market show us that it's not likely that
the season tendency was coming into
fruition this year so this little
movement right in here okay
that's what I was looking at that is a
really easy bread winner for the
springtime
and it was not there technically but I
want to take your attention into
how the third week of May
and third week of June okay see how we
have June July May April
this is approximately the third week of
May and the third week of June see that
this right here tends to be one of the
best times to be a buyer of index
futures for e-mini s p
so if you're looking for a really strong
mid-year point to buy if you are in a
bull market that you feel that is going
to continue because we didn't see a
seasonal tendency come to fruition here
okay and I counseled you to do this in
my mentorship
and you view the seasonal Tendencies if
they don't form
if they don't come to fruition that's
telling you something that's extremely
fundamental to the next Drive higher or
lower
if it's not moving in tandem with what
you would expect in terms of the
seasonal tendency that means it's doing
something opposite
so if we're anticipating what lower
prices for ES or e-mini s p and it's not
willing to do this that means we're
extremely bullish
so go into your charts on the third week
of May in the third week of June if you
like these charts by the way uh these
are old friends of mine these these
charts have been with me since 1995 and
this company uh it's headed by Steve
Moore and if you like seasonal
Tendencies or if you want to delve into
that his website is
www.mrci.com I do not get anything for
telling you that I don't have an
affiliation with him uh he probably
doesn't even know who I am I've sent a
ton of people to him
uh Steve if you're listening you're
welcome
um I just think that he is the Pinnacle
of all seasonal tendency work I don't
care who it is I don't care who you like
okay I don't care his research his work
is in my opinion Superior to everything
and everyone else
so that's why I use his resources for
looking at seasonal tendencies
there is no business relationship
between them not okay but if you want
seasonal tendency charts
his is the best that's my opinion
all right so here's a weekly chart of
e-mini s p this is a September contract
for 2023 and there is the weekly volume
and balance I mentioned multiple times
and I said right between these two
levels here
that point is the exposed area where
there is no
volume
so there's a real Gap there okay so that
makes it what
a liquidity board that my friends is a
liquidity void this from here to here
that is not a liquid okay
it's it's been unfortunately
called that
and because I wanted to teach on baby
Pips I stuck with the binocular that
other people were using because you know
why reinvent the wheel and try to cause
more confusion because at the time I
didn't want to go this far in teaching
but a real liquidity void is a void of
liquidity
all liquidity
so
that's what distinguishes me from
everybody else out there because I will
tell you this is an inefficiency it's a
sell side imbalance
buy side inefficiency
so it's inefficient in up
or by side offering the market only went
one side ahead of handily and it's more
likely to offer movement on the upside
and we see that over here on this this
camera easy one of these candles as a
weekly Candlestick by the way so we
traded
up into this
Gap
or real liquidity will be between this
week's low and this week's High
majority of the entire weekly volume and
balance so we finally got to that one
okay
let's take a closer look
right inside that small little Gap okay
so before I go to the next slide in our
presentation here I want you to
understand that what I'm going to do is
I'm going to zoom in to this small
little segment of price action and I'm
going to show you the relationship
between this week's low here this candle
in this week's High
we're going to measure that with the
Fibonacci and we're going to get the
midpoint of that which is consequent
encouragement because it's a gap
here we are zoomed in here's that
Candlestick we were looking at the low
for Monday April 4th okay that week of
2022 and then the 18th of April 2022. so
this candlesticks high of its respective
weekly candle this candle sticks low of
its respective weekly candle
drawing our Fib from that level to there
all we're doing we're using the FIB to
get a perfect halfway point fifty
percent that means 45 59 and a half
that is your consequent encouragement of
that small little Gap that's right here
that little Gap okay so I'm finding half
of this between this red line and that
red line I want to know what the
midpoint of that is the exact midpoint
that's what's being shown here 4 500 59
and a half
taking us over to the current present
week you can see how we traded right up
into that consequent encouragement here
a little above it just by a little bit
but look how beautiful the reaction was
from here back down in and we closed on
the highs not at the highs we just fell
short of going into the 20 retracement
for TGIF all right so let's go into a
daily chart here you can see the
if everybody got we mentioned that at
the time two down closed candles that's
your bullish order block extend that to
the right we had a start of the week we
traded down
into the order block and then ripped
higher ticking out by side digging into
the low of the weekly volume and balance
the consequent encroachment of the
entire shaded area which is the weekly
volume of balance and in those two red
levels up here and then it's respective
consequent approach or midpoint of that
Gap that's being shown within the weekly
volume of balance just a really
beautiful delivery for ES this week
NASDAQ was actually better but and we'll
look at that in a moment but let's drop
into a lower time frame here for the
hourly chart on ES
you see how we dropped down into your
block rally through
bull shorter block this is down close
here and we have a fair value Gap that
makes this a
proper
little shorter block
because we're in context of a buy
program we're looking for higher prices
everything should match there and we've
seen a noon
lunchtime New York local time
return back in to in Balance order block
sell side taken flow relative equal lows
and then starts to trade higher
another order block here trades higher
an aggressive run through the short-term
High here
so we're not looking at that as buy side
which is resistance right no we're
looking at it going to it being drawn to
that area and then through it
and I don't need it to trade back down
to this high
that's classic support and resistance I
don't need that
I want to see a trade inside of this
inefficiency right here
right there right in here that's
institutional order called entry drill
and then rallies again trades up into
that Weekly volume of balance
look at the bodies respecting the weekly
volume imbalance
yes we have these little Mohawks that's
in air price action it's normal to see
that it's perfectly normal and
acceptable
Market rallies
trades up into
the consequent encouragement of that
actual liquidity void in the upper
portion of that shaded pink area which
is a weekly volume imbalance
here's a five minute chart you can see
again with the es trading up internet
consequent encouragement of the actual
liquidity void at the entire portion of
that Weekly volume imbalance and right
in here you can see small little sibi
which is a fair bag you got it's also
gonna bounce efficiency yeah it means
the market will likely pull back up into
that
it does essentially the consequent
encroachment we can see those
measurements here Trace to it here and
then we want to see a sharp displacement
lower do we get it yes did it take out a
short term level yes what is this that's
the 2022 model I taught you on this
YouTube channel
very Gap trades up into it here boom
that's too short what do you aim for the
low under here
delivers and we have a small little Fair
bag up there
offering the two o'clock Silver Bullet
the market breaks lower relative equal
lows we pull back up retraces and then
aggressively runs lower off of hitting a
breaker
high low higher high this candles your
breaker trades to it here
sells off going into the three o'clock
hour small little fare bag you got there
as well so we have high low return back
in this is model 22 again
cell site hammers it in the final hour
of trading on Friday
all right here's NASDAQ this is our
weekly chart on NAS so you can see the
weekly fair value Gap there
you trade down into that two weeks ago
and this is this present week so we
opened traded down aggressively moved
higher
made it high and then come off the highs
I want to zoom in on that
so we're zoomed in on the weekly chart
for Nas and I'm taking the Fibonacci and
measuring from the low of the week to
the high of the week and I'm showing you
the respective
20 and 30 which is TGIF so whenever you
have a nice big run higher or lower
those are the times you want to look for
TGIF they're really
likely to have these pullbacks towards
the end of the week
and how far will it pull back 20 to 30
percent of the work the weekly range
entirely so you can see that 15 698 and
a half
is 20 of the weekly range for Nasdaq so
that level is going to be important
going forward in this presentation so 15
698 and a half
that levels being noted here and it's
the weekly TGIF 20 it's a short little
abbreviation for thank God it's Friday
okay so it's a way for you to remember
that that model
is a day of week specific model and it's
capitalizing on treating a reversal
of the entire weekly range to a 20 to 30
percent level of the entire weekly range
I got a teaching on it this is the first
time you heard about it just go on my
YouTube channel and you'll find a TGIF
setup
all right so let's go into the hourly
chart okay so we're going right to the
Brass tax with this because it's already
a long video
I want you to take a look at the low
here
the high and the lower low
in the market trades through this High
we don't look at that as resistance okay
there's buy side above that and we're
looking for higher prices beyond that
but what can we use this information for
in terms of finding range
well if you look at the teaching I gave
you on Advanced ICT Breakers
those ideas that I shared in that video
I'm applying it here so
when we see the stop run here
that takes out the sell side below here
my eye goes right to the low to the high
prior to the lower load it qualifies
this as a bullish ICT breaker
so this is your measuring range
so you take your Fibonacci apply it to
the low
to the high extend it do multiple
extensions you can do extension standard
deviation negative one
here negative
standard deviation two
comes in at what price
fifteen thousand eight hundred and fifty
six and a quarter
[Music]
it's not the actual high but look how
close it gets you
that's projecting a weekly Range High
now there's people out there who say oh
well you know you can't do that ICP
nobody can do that the Market's too
random nope nobody can do that well I'm
teaching you tools and Concepts that you
know I've been shown in my private group
doing this years and years of it
now my students can do it
you're learning how I'm able to do it
it's not imperative that you do this
every single week okay when the
technicals are there and you have a
strong bias that is
conducive for these ideas to pan out
that's when you want to do it okay so
this breaker we expected to trade
through it it does we come back down
into it the bodies are respecting the
breaker it's not the fact that it goes
up to this high and it repels price has
absolutely nothing to do with it has
nothing to do with it because if that's
the case why didn't it do it to him this
High that's the fallacy of retail
support and resistance ideas if you're
going to look at this High here and say
ICT is cherry picking because it's it
worked there well use that same logic in
in saying that this is rebranded because
it's not why don't you apply it to that
high there because it had a nice
retracement off of it too
so why is price not showing any
willingness or respect of it over here
I think because it has nothing to do
with why price goes up or down
the logic is this
short-term entries
those that are in in the pursuit of
trying to go long they were right
prematurely
until they were stopped out
so this perfect trap here
sets the stage for those individuals
that got stopped out trying to get along
they're too afraid to get back in
especially when this one more Wipeout
that takes out this low which also took
out that lap so we see a one two three
drives pattern that is a classic retail
pattern yes it does work if you have the
context you know in the drawing liquid
and where you're trying to aim for if
that's correct that pattern will work
for you if you see a level or a
direction fail after three attempts and
it breaks down and if you see a breaker
or a model 2022 inside of that
wow what a beautiful model I probably
said too much but
anyway
the Longs that have a cell stop below
here they get stopped out they're not
going to go back in they're scared
they're not going to get back in there
but now the market will revert back to
the individuals that are short here
someone's short so they're going to run
on them so the sales thoughts are being
accumulated by smart money going long
they're buying those cell stops with the
purpose of off setting
so offset distribution is being used
above this High that's not support
resistance that's selling above a level
for profit taking and waiting for
confirmation that it wants to go higher
it does
the bodies are respecting that high
which is a breaker
it's not showing any willingness to show
the bodies respecting this High anywhere
in here as support it's not happening
so the market resumes going higher pay
no attention to this level yet because
it has to make a high of the week first
so when we have this big capitulation
this is run up into a standard deviation
of negative two on this range which is
what I taught
on that Advanced breaker video that just
literally just did it like a week or so
ago on YouTube channel so watch that one
and you'll see me teaching this very
premise
that is beautiful delivery folks I'm
sorry I hate to break your hearts okay
I'm not trying to be mean but this stuff
isn't in your books okay and if someone
goes out there and they want to run out
make a Amazon book and try to include
this you're going to be coming up short
changed because there's a lot of things
I'm leaving for this idea for my own
book
so sorry
not sorry then we have these relative
equal lows
and the market draws down into that in
latter portion of the day but back down
more specifically into the weekly TGIF
20 so after we see this level hit we
want to see does it really wanna
break down from that and then when we
look at the lower time frames we
actually will see that actually
occurring
so here's the 15 minute time frame
here's the consolidation in the
beginning of the day
and we had a report come out
sends price higher
then we have this Gap right there
okay so this return back into this
sibi which is a cell sign of balance by
deficiency Market trades into it here we
Wick past it that's completely
permissible
breaks down again we have another Gap so
this is institutional order for entry
drill where it just trades one little
bit above
this candle here this happens with all
time frames but the context is you have
to know where the market is likely to go
and because we have
this Gap here
and then we have this Gap here in close
proximity that's what makes this an
Institutional referential otherwise if
this wasn't here I would expect it to
trade more into this inefficiency I'll
have more of that in my books but that's
enough right here to send you light
years ahead everybody else so the market
does in fact trade below here completely
runs over top of this buy Center balance
also efficiency okay does it here and we
have another Gap
there we trade up into this and then
rips right through cell side here and
cell side there
so we're not looking at that as
buy is because it was a turning point in
the past for class and support
resistance idea theories
we're looking for it to trade through it
because there's liquidity below that
um
20 of the weekly range is here so all of
these things match in terms of
a draw on liquidity there's a reason to
anticipate it happening the Market's
been going straight up all week and then
now we're at the end of the week so this
is completely acceptable and reasonable
to see in price delivery and it's not to
say that we've called the top of the
marketplace because as I mentioned in
July 9th 2023's analysis I'm teaching
you not to try to pick tops and bottoms
on higher time frame charts because you
can hurt yourself doing that
just wait for the market to clearly show
you it's reversed and when it does just
keep working that bias that's you know
in the Market at the time and try not to
you know fancy dance it and try to
pick a top or bottom because you're not
going to get it correct you're not going
to do it so to avoid that just simply
try to stay on side and trade with a
expectation at the higher time frame
weekly chart
moving into a lower time frame daily
chart that's enough for you to find
Opportunities and not need to be picking
tops and bottoms
[Music]
okay here's a five minute chart and I'll
show you the inversion pure Vega that's
why the market went up to that level
here it went beyond the previous
15 minute
right here see this Gap here this Gap
we're looking through that to the left
that's why we're not supplying demand
folks sorry Sam's Iden
this right here is a bison efficiency
the market trades down through it
now and you might look at this and say
oh well this is this is now it's filled
in we don't we don't worry about that
that's why you're wrong
because you're using flawed logic okay
my algorithm is going to refer back to
that candles high and that candle is low
it will refer back to it again
that's not support resistance okay it's
algorithmic
the market trades back up into it this
is a small little in-ear in price action
it's a mohawk it's a little nickname I
gave it small little tiny little
movement outside of it there's no body
outside of it it's just the wick that's
completely normal completely acceptable
we don't worry about those things
market shares it willingness to respect
the inversion for everybody got and then
breaks lower institutional overflow
entry drill
and then we have this Wick big wick here
okay which doesn't do much in terms of
damage below this low for sell side so
once we move through it
I like this Gap but I wanted to refer
back to this Wick so does this Market
respect that Wix consequent encroachment
I don't know does it it's perfect isn't
it look at these candles here the bodies
tell you the story The Wicks they do the
damage
and this is telling you narrative it
means the algorithm is in a Cell program
it's going to seek sell side liquidity
it's going to run on Cell stops it's
going to run to inefficiencies well
there's a smaller inefficiency remaining
here
it gets down to it there comes back up
into a small Gap there
and then does what Dives for the sell
side and gets below the weekly TGIF 20
of the weekly range
I went short on here trading inside of
the idea that we were in
this inversion favorite you got
there
I took a little bit of heat on it but
not much and then aggressively ran for
the south side and there you go so
that's why I used to teach my son on
Friday afternoon
notice where we closed
look at this
real close to the 20 percent
again you don't find that in your books
okay
there are so many things that people
will look at whether it be me or other
people
and
because we're looking at the same four
things open high low and close
we're forced to use geometric shapes
okay we're forced to use trend lines and
things to articulate you know an idea
with a audience member or for our own
journaling and when we make these things
available to other people invariably
they're gonna see oh well you know
you're doing the Classic this and the
classic that I'm not doing anything
that's classic I'm making the new
Classics okay I'm making the new
uh
future reference books okay everything
that you're learning here live you're in
that Gan moment okay you're in that
Livermore moment you're having someone
teach you something that no one's had
their fingerprints on before
and I say these things not to be
arrogant I'm not trying to be
condescending to anybody and I'm not
saying to hear myself talk
but I want you to appreciate the fact
that what you're being exposed to you're
not entitled to it
you're not entitled to know these things
so when I see other people claim they
know it claim they've been doing it
before me they have no
experience doing it they have no track
record with it they can't even go out
and do executions to prove they don't
even know how to do it right now let
alone say they did it before me
so
I want you to think about what you
watched happen last week
how explosive the market moved exactly
how I outlined it last Sunday before the
market opened up you had it in your hot
little hands
what do you think
your trading would be like
two years from now learning this what do
you think of Trades would be like 10
years from now
what do you think your trading is going
to be like three decades like mine today
my understanding of the marketplace
is rooted on things that I've codified
in 1996. so the things I'm talking about
and teaching I author these things
no one taught me these things no one
mentored me no one sat down and said
here here's my mentorship join this and
I'm going to teach you that it wasn't in
any of the books it wasn't in any of the
things I bought
and it's not easy I know it's not easy
you're learning it from the person that
created it
and it's a struggle sometimes for you to
learn
and it's not because I'm not that good
at teaching it's just this is a very
dense topic
it's very very very dense it's it
requires a lot of study it requires a
lot of case studies where you go back
and look at old moves and you study it
and you listen to the boring stuff I
talk about whether it be in a Twitter
space or whether it be in these parts of
the video where no one really likes to
listen to it
but you're not going to learn it without
having these things and that's what
mentorship is
if you want to sit down and learn
something from somebody that knows
something very well
and if they really want to teach you
they're not going to rush through the
topic they want to make sure that they
get into all the nooks and crannies they
want to get down to the small little
things that they're going to creep in
and mess you up because you're going to
make a big mountain out of something
that's not that significant
now I know what those things are going
to be so that's the reason why I talk to
you about these things
don't focus on that focus on this do
this don't do that
and for the folks that want to speed
through it and try to do you know an
abbreviated mentorship you're the one
that is going to fail
and I have a lot of failures because
they rushed through it
not because the content doesn't work or
the concepts don't work or I can't teach
it properly
but there's going to be a huge learning
curve for some of you and others you'll
pick it up faster than someone else
might
it's just a matter of personal
experience and each one of you are going
to have a
a duration that is unique to you and you
have to submit to that I'm a practical
person I know that not all of you are
going to be able to
resonate with me I'm not going to
scratch the itch as a mentor for all of
you and you're going to want to chase
something else I promise you folks I
promise you I swear to you that there is
not one single person on YouTube or
anywhere else that's going to teach you
like I'm teaching you
I promise you that
they're just familiar with what I've
already shared thus far
so there's nothing wrong with looking at
other people's
level of understanding and that's what
they're doing they're showing you their
level of understanding but they're not
in a position of authority to be able to
teach it because they don't even know
what they're teaching
they're just familiar with it
it's just like when you first
got a driver's license
and you handed or your parents handed
the keys to you and you get in and you
start it up just because you got your
driver's license doesn't mean you
understand exactly how that car is
designed what causes the ignition what
causes the you know the the engine to
stay running what's all the connections
that causes all of these instruments to
work like they do
you probably didn't do much thinking in
terms of that you just couldn't wait to
get behind the wheel and that's what
these mentors and that's what you many
times as a would-be student is like
you want to rush out there and just get
your hands dirty with it and sometimes
it ain't dirt it's blood you lose a few
fingers maybe more because you're
rushing in before you're ready and
you're learning from people that don't
know what they're doing
it's easy to talk about in hindsight
it's easy to use what I'm talking about
in real time analysis and then borrow my
Viewpoint in the marketplace and then
come out and say you know look at my
look at my students that pass their
evaluations when if I wouldn't have said
anything
you would have had no voice
and your students wouldn't be doing
anything
so
I'm going to leave that with you
and
remind you that these things aren't
Cherry Picked these things are not
coincidence they happen every single
week and sometimes there are certain
parameters that are met that allow for
explosive runs
what took place
what took place this week
think about it
what's occurring on the daily chart
Fairbank app
boom third week of what
third week of what June
just like that seasonal tendency calls
for
folks those things are like road maps
and we knew in May
when the seasonal fantasy that I like to
see where if it sells off if I can find
something technical that aligns with the
market to see it Go lower
if it's not providing that that means we
are really bullish
SCP went up over 400 handles
look at the NASDAQ
almost a thousand or more
from this turning point right there
and then rips again in July this move
right here this is a classic
in the summer months that part is that
That's a classic scenario
if you're in a bull market this is what
you expect in the months of June and May
if
we're in a bearish market a sell-off in
May into June they're very very good
that's how you use these Alternatives
the ID or a premise behind a seasonal
tendency that is failing
and being
instrumental to having a market go
explosive you know in the opposite
direction to what the seasonal tendency
would imply
I learned that from Larry Williams
and I learned that in 1995
from his four VHS tape I mentioned many
times over the years as uh
as a resource that I learned from and
it's a I believe it's titled the future
millionaires confidential trading course
and he talked about seasonal tendencies
in here he talked about how he was the
first one to write a book about seasonal
Tendencies and
we talked about Jake Bernstein who I'm
not a fan of I I never liked his work
even though Larry himself respected him
I didn't I didn't find anything of value
from him okay and I'm sure there were
people that found you know usefulness
from whatever he put out I just
personally wasn't able to do that but in
terms of seasonal Tendencies the idea of
winning seasonal tendency is failing to
manifest itself that
is many times not always but many times
it is conducive for an explosive price
run in the opposite direction to what
you would expect in the season of energy
so it's because we had the the
potential to sell off in May
didn't form it did not form at that time
so that gives more rocket fuel for the
June
loaded forms and that's classic
in stock index futures
so as a swing I'm saying all this stuff
to you because I know some of you that
don't want to day trade you can't do it
you don't want to do it doesn't fit your
your personality and I understand that
but what I'm showing you here on this
daily chart how's that any different
from what I'm teaching you on a
one-minute chart four minute chart five
minute chart 15 minute chart hourly
chart
it's nothing different except for the
time frame
isn't this
something that we would be looking to
get along on anyway if we're bolus yes
what is this here high and that high
that's relative equal highs that means
what there's buy side above that we're
not looking at that as going back out
through this here as resistance
we're looking for it to trade through it
it doesn't sound like resistance to you
what kind of resistance would that be
if you thought that this was a
resistance level these relative equal
highs you thought that same idea was the
same thing you would hope your roof on
your home is like would you want a roof
that performs like this
no
so I attack and I teach my students to
attack by side liquidity above a single
or relative equal High
I teach my students to attack
a single low or relative equal lows
where their cell side below it to it and
through it
that's what we teach here okay we do not
teach some garbage resistance and
support idea that is so ambiguous you
have no idea that there's never been a
book I'm telling you right now I have
over 2 000 books and there has never
been an author educator teacher that has
ever codified a single approach that
goes in and finds the right support and
resistance
it's not there folks
that's a religion
that's what it is it's a religion okay
they say we're cult the idea of support
and resistance you have to have more
faith in that than simply understanding
that what I'm teaching here is the real
Market
because it's subjective
no matter where you are in the world if
you're pulling up the NASDAQ daily chart
you're going to see this Gap
okay it's a fair value Gap in the form
of a buy Center balance outside
efficiency that does not hide from you
there's not other ones in this area that
you might get tricked by
but the idea of picking a support
resistance idea based on classic support
and resistance Theory what high are you
going to use what low are you going to
use what
what diagonal trend lines are you going
to draw to and which one's going to be
correct see I've wasted lots of money
doing that though and so have you other
people that have traded before I was
even born wasted and lost lots of money
doing that stuff too but hey it looks
great in the books
it looks great in hindsight look at this
level here this diagonal support this
diagonal resistance and I went in and I
created a concept that attacks that idea
that entire premise I tack it
that's my Phantom trend line
it's a specific approach to
going after retail thought processes
about that very idea
I've taken retail and turned it upside
down and I've made it useful to anyone
that simply wants to look at it
investigate the ideas and see if whether
or not I'm telling you the truth and if
you go into charts I promise you you're
going to find that truth in that proof
there's so many people there are
students of mine now there's so many
students of mine that used to be
detractors doubters in the beginning
they want to go in and prove that what I
was saying wasn't the case
and now they're long-term you know loyal
students they know what they have
learned from me is the truth
and you're seeing that you just saw it
again
how can you cherry pick the entire
weekly range how can you cherry pick the
entire weekly delivery of not just one
market but four
I gave you 4X I gave you the dollar
Index and I gave you the ES
it delivered
like gangbusters
and you should be excited about that not
hopped up on goofballs but you should be
inspired by thinking well you know this
is this is really encouraging for me I
now I have something to to go on because
everybody that watched that video
on July 9th of 2023 that analysis video
the commentary that I gave in terms of
you know what I felt the Mark was going
to do this week it's on YouTube it's
it's available to everyone you didn't
have to pay for it you don't have to do
any kind of subscriptions you have to
send me no money through PayPal you
ain't got to do any kind of crypto
payments which I wouldn't take anyway
all you have to do is watch the videos
take notes
and share your experience with me that's
it it's free folks
and there's people out there that simply
want to keep you from learning how to do
this
and the more closer we get to November
it's going to increase
because nothing else you're going to
learn can compete with this
nothing I promise you I promise you
there is nothing like this
because this is the truth behind the
marketplace this is exactly why markets
go up and down it has nothing to do with
the depth of Market it has nothing to do
with Market profile it has nothing to do
with supply and demand has nothing to do
with Elliott weave has nothing to do
with harmonic patterns none of that
stuff
is what causes markets going up and down
that's not there's no such thing as
buying and selling pressure
there's buying and selling going on I'm
not arguing that
but when the market goes
it's going to a very specific level and
I'm teaching you what they are
I'm telling you when they're going to do
it
there has never been a phenomenon like
what you're experiencing right now
and I'm honored
I'm very honored
to be sitting at this Helm with you as
your mentor
at a point where I have 771
000 students on this YouTube channel now
that to me is
Bonkers it's it's crazy that there's
that many people
wanting to sit down and listen to a guy
from Middle River Maryland
so I'm definitely blessed the Lord has
definitely made me the head not the tail
and I'm greatly appreciative of all of
you that want to sit down and spend time
until talk to you next time