foreign
welcome back folks this is lesson two of
the April 2017 Itt mentorship
content dealing with ICT day trading
model
this lesson is defining the DailyRange
okay the retail 24-hour trading day
now I teach through the mt4 platform
and everyone is aware that if you hold
down control when you tap the y letter
it'll pull up the
period separators for the respective
time frame you have on your chart
and the
retail version of the 24 hour trading
day is not what we focus on but I want
to highlight the contrast between the
two because this is what you see
in a typical mt4 platform
the interbank 24-hour IPDA trading day
is very different
so if it's going to be a high
probability trade scenario that we're
going to be looking for it stands the
reason we have to start with the same
reference point that IPDA itself the
interbank price delivery algorithm uses
in referencing time
so we're going to have to use the same
thing that IPDA does
when we view price in the element of
time of day
so when we see these retail delineations
and folks have these on your charts
that's pretty much a classic Telltale
sign they have no idea what they're
doing and they'll frame the day based on
these vertical lines
what we're going to show now is how a
interbank Trader views price in relative
terms to time
okay the first element we're going to
break down is the Asian range I get
questions a lot what is the kill zones
what is the Asian range when does it
begin when's it end all the things
dealing with time of day so this is the
definitive teaching so that way we can
go through the rest of the lessons for
April day trading this is the only one
you'll ever need to refer to so if
you've seen anything different in the
past this is the real one
foreign
PM Eastern Standard Time
in NewYork time
if this Begins the Asian range
every day at midnight Eastern Standard
Time NewYork
ends the Asian range
we will learn specific things concerning
this range later in April for now I want
to give you the beginning endings of all
the specifics that deals with the IPDA
trading day
okay the ICT London killZone
every day at 1am Eastern Standard Time
NewYork Begins the London killZone
every day at 5 00 AM Eastern Standard
Time NewYork ends the London Killzone
now we're going to learn specific things
concerning this Killzone later in April
but for now again
if you're ever questioning what I'm
referring to in terms of the beginning
and endings you have to have a NewYork
time clock so either on your smartphone
they give you an opportunity to do World
clocks whatever the time is in NewYork
use the times I'm giving you in this
specific teaching and set that as your
beginning and ending points for all the
references in time
okay the ICT NewYork Killzone
every day at 7 AM Eastern Standard Time
NewYork Begins the NewYork killZone
every day at 10 AM Eastern Standard
Time NewYork ends the NewYork Kill
Zone
we will learn specific things concerning
the skill Zone later in April but again
for now this is the actual times I use
to hunt the setup
the ICT London killZone for London
close every day at 10 AM Eastern
Standard Time NewYork Begins the London
closed killZone
every day at 12 PM noon NewYork time
ends the London close Killzone
we will learn specific things concerning
this killZone later in April
but for now
whenever refer to London clothes this is
the time window again always in whatever
NewYork time is whether it's daylight
savings time or regular time this is the
times I'm using
foreign
true day definition
every day at 12 AM midnight NewYork
time Begins the IPDA true day this is
the beginning of the 24-hour interbank
trading day
every day at 3 PM NewYork time ends
the IPDA true day 24-hour interbank
trading day
we will learn specific things concerning
this time range in April
but for now know that this is the
beginning and the ending of an interbank
24-hour cycle
okay so let's take a closer look at what
we've outlined here
what we have is a true day
for a Monday
April 3rd 2017.
we classify this as a IPDA true day open
at midnight
and Monday true day close at 3 PM
NewYork time
you can see that there are very very
specific time elements being shown here
not only are we blending elements of if
the data ranges and PD array Matrix
we're looking at institutional order
flow but now we have an element of time
that it gets so precise it's hard to
deny how anyone looking at this chart
can see there's an algorithmic pattern
and it's related to time
now we're not going to PDA arrays and
and all the institutional reference
points but I want you to focus at the
time Windows here
look at the turning points that we see
here look at the daily High
and look at the daily low
look at the swing points throughout the
rest of the day
there's logical reasons for why price
goes to these levels and why they go
specifically and precisely to a one
particular level or another
I want to add
the 8 20 AM NewYork time
this is the CME open
look at this line draw straight up with
your imagination and goes right to that
little short term low and price rallies
away from that that is not randomness
okay I'm going to teach you a lot about
8 20 AM CME open that I did not give you
and other teachings
this area here between the London and
NewYork kill zones this is London lunch
this is generally when we're not looking
for any major significant price moves
usually the market goes quiet or it
continues in the path it's set for
London open
framing the day like this
you can clearly see using Power3
the open at midnight
small little down move in the Asian
range we would not be concerned with
that the up move on the Asian range
resistance being broken out the high the
day forms right at the beginning of the
ICT London killZone that begins at 1am
NewYork time
folks that are using my free tutorials
they're waiting for two o'clock three
o'clock at four o'clock
this is the actual Killzone I use so the
time window begins at 1am it ends at 5am
look at the high that forms at 5 AM at
the very end of London Killzone
exactly right there
now look at the NewYork session
Killzone
we have a short-term High that's framed
inside of that NewYork killZone but
look at the low that forms in the actual
NewYork Hill Zone it forms at 8 20 AM
CME open
I'll tell you what the CME open is later
on but for now just keep that as a
reference point on your own
charts
the high that forms in the NewYork
session
okay there's a swing High forums and it
trades down into the London close
London close makes the LOD it
goes in consolidation And Trades off the
low for a close or what I refer to as
the NewYork close when I say NewYork
close
I'm referring to epta True day close it
just saves me the time of saying so true
day begins at midnight NewYork time and
ends at 3 PM
NewYork time now 3 PM is because bonds
close and the influence that interest
rates have on the currency markets will
have ended by then the last hour two
o'clock to 3 PM NewYork time will
always encapsulate any movement that's
related to FOMC so interest rate
announcements FOMC minutes all those
events that take place around the two
o'clock hour in NewYork time
that's what encapsulates that last
portion no matter what happens in FOMC
generally the move has ended or the bulk
of the move has ended by 3 PM NewYork
time
and that's how you frame the entire
DailyRange
open high low and close and that's the
delineations of each
so going forward in this month we'll
know exactly what we're referring to in
time
and how to use these elements for
precision
and until next lesson I wish you good
luck and good Trading