hi welcome back folks it's a quick
little review on NASDAQ features this is
the September delivery contract of 2023.
all right so
this morning overnight in the London
session
we had a little bit of a
rejection on the low
of Friday
so using this town close candle has a
bull shorter block
we teared up into this premium Wick
so consequent encroachments mid point of
that right there I'll let you figure
that out on your own using your fib
and we had the market trade up on Monday
and then this is the new day it starts
at 6 PM that's what we're seeing here
four hour chart
okay so we have relative
highs here so there's liquidity resting
rate above that
Market again traded
into the daily bullet shoulder block
we had a shift in Market structure we'll
look at that on Lower time frames
and really aggressively into the close
of today
on the hourly chart you can see there is
a city this is a sell Side imbalanced by
sine and efficiency
so after
four o'clock we sell Market trade up
into that
we want to take a lot of
details in this area in here
after this shift in Market structure so
this High here once we went lower it
lower low sell side taken leaving by
side here then by side taken but
extremely
aggressive through these highs SO
trading back down not taking out that
low
more specifically we're going to look at
that Wick as well and then all of the
marker structure in here
15 minute time frame here you can see
that I sell liquidity here
now these two levels are
the 60 Minute or hourly sell sign
amounts by sound efficiency respective
high and low
it doesn't look like a city
in here because we have multiple candles
let me go back up one more
time up into the hourly chart so you can
get your frame of reference these two
levels here are anchored on the hourly
chart
right here okay so this candle is low
this candle is high
they're not annotated here
but the same respective levels are going
to be here
so that's this 60 Minute or hourly sippy
low
60 Minute or hourly to be high
[Music]
now this time frame here
is a 15 minute time frame
but more specifically look down here in
the lower right hand corner rths regular
trading hours
so we had sell side below here we traded
down below that
and then we have aggressive shift above
these highs here and then leaving a gap
so that Gap there we're going to treat
that as a breakaway Gap in the brick
wake up high and Breakaway Gap
respective low
an initiated area here okay see that
yellow box this is Friday August 11 2023
opening range Gap
so you can only see these with the
regular trading hours toggled on your
trading bill
so
from here to here these two respective
candles
you traded around in here on Friday but
left that portion open these gas will be
referred to by the algorithm they don't
just fill and forget it's
traded all the way up into it here
and then look at the bodies respecting
the high
in here and then one more top right
there
in the afternoon session and then
aggressively runs for the relative equal
highs and that drawn liquidity
the 60-minute city this inefficiency is
this candle is high this candle is low
which is a busy it's the opposite of
what this was on the 60 Minute chart but
now on a 15 minute time frame this
exists on both regular trading hours and
electronic trading hours
so these levels here will be seen and
they'll be visible we look at the next
slide
again same 60 Minute City
high and low respectively
9 30 Friday
that starts the opening range Gap but we
don't see a gap there do we why because
we're looking at electronic trading
hours
right down here eth
okay so electronic trading hours you
have to refer to the Gap
on the rth regular trading hours once
you annotate them you want to toggle
back to electronic trading hours
and have your annotation stressed on
your chart
relative equal lows sales High liquidity
be pierced through that
then we have a wick okay so this is a
discount Wick midpoint of that is
consequent encroachment you can see we
hit that beautifully here
at the opening at 9 30. did not take out
the low we had a shift and marker
structure here very very energetic price
run
it drops down looks like a bull flag
retail wanted that to act as a bullfly
imbalance
rejection block lowest down close price
Trace through it consequent encroachment
of the discount Wick here trusting that
this low should not be taken or pierced
because of shift and Market structure
here
mark it trades aggressively higher above
what a short-term high right there on
the 15-minute time frame
we open trade down
to this candle is high which is an or
block
side here
buy side here and the inefficiency as
well
here's that 57 balance outside of
efficiency
respective high and low
and that Breakaway Gap that we
mentioned here on the regular trading
hours can be seen also on electronic
trading hours
and eventually after four o'clock we see
it trade up into that
hourly City
if I make Candlestick chart we're
looking at a little bit more detail here
we have the low
relative equal low So Below that's what
cell solid liquidity you drop down
there let me ride back above
that Wick that was seen on the 15 minute
time frame it doesn't show it here
but look at the bodies respecting
yeah
and it hits it here at 9 30. if they
open we trade through short-term shifts
in Market structure there much like we
saw it here on a higher time frame
we're seeing it now on a lower time
frame there and then we drop down into
the bullish order block this is also
immediate rebalance on the 15 minute
time frame
and we rally up now I did make a mistake
today while I was tweeting if you go to
look at my tweets I didn't did too many
of them today but I mentioned that there
was a fair value gap on the two minute
chart and that's not what I was looking
at I was looking at a five minute chart
and this is the fair value Gap I
mentioned that price was struggling with
initially and offering short-term
resistance
let me trade it back down into this down
closed candle and price rally through
came back down and touched the top of
that fair value got and reach for the
liquidity that I was mentioning prior to
all that anyway uh fifteen thousand one
thirty eight which was the
buy side in the afternoon on Friday I'm
looking at Friday's trading and not so
much emphasis on Sunday so if you're
using Sunday's highs
here for buy side and that's fine
there's nothing wrong with that
but I'm taking it back to Friday's price
trading in the afternoon
and then we have the relative equal
highs here
on Monday morning going around the seven
o'clock hour
so we ended up trading off of the five
minute Share value Gap
and if you look at a two-minute chart
you'll see there there's no fear about
you got there to draw on so I didn't
bother to take a look at the tweets I'm
sure some of you probably already
corrected me were trying to correct me
without doing other things today while I
was reading the tape the market rallies
creates the high of the Breakaway Gap
here
reps higher takes the 15 167 buy side
and then because my attention would be
elsewhere
I know some of you like to jump on board
when I'm pointing things out I just said
make sure that uh
you're content there you move to the
sidelines
eventually I took it out the buy side
here I made no mention of this by the
way but it's pretty obvious you know
when we're looking at things like this
this was where buy side would be and it
above that would be what the
inefficiency on the 60 Minute chart so
the level up here is the hourly City
High this level here is the hourly
Sibilo
it wasn't treated until we got to after
the day session ended
and again here's the immediate rebalance
here just a wonderful signature and I've
been getting a lot of feedback from this
one here from everyone now utilizing it
and if you have your bias correct if you
know that the draw on liquidity is
likely above or below the marketplace
and you're trading at the specific time
of day that would be indicative of
volatility coming in this is one of the
strongest absolutely strongest
signatures that I look for when price is
giving me that I know that the algorithm
will be in the spool price aggressively
in the direction I'm looking for
okay five minute chart zoomed in a
little bit here so here is the 15 minute
Candlestick that creates that discount
Wick the midpoint level here you see
what drops down into that I'm going to
type for the 9 30 opening you drop down
and
if I was just showing you this time
frame here you would see this and think
you know why didn't you use this
Candlestick ICT and that's generally
what has happened in the past
because I'm looking at things on a time
frame to talk about that
at the time in my teachings even old
videos
um one of the things that creep in is
you'll say well I see appointment that
Candlestick and why is it not the lowest
down closed candle it's because I'm
taking your attention to a specific time
frame and because The annotation may be
anchored to a higher time frame that may
have caused
confusion in the past okay so it's not
that I'm picking different candlesticks
or trying to hide something from you
it's just a matter of me moving from one
Higher time frame down to a lower time
frame and my annotations anchored to the
higher time frame
so it's going to look a little bit
different as you probably have already
been paying attention and noticing when
we look through that
continuum of price delivery from the
higher time frame to the lower time
frame you want to have the anchored PD
arrays on the higher time frame but
you're using the lower time frames to
refine
in terms of accuracy and such
but here's that five minute
array Gap here
you trade up and through it find some
support there and then we rally up take
the buy side 15 167.
now notice that we have this
inefficiency here
on the five minute chart but it's part
of the larger bicep imbalance also
inefficiency high and low that is the 15
minute time frame but notice there's a
small little Gap there at the bottom end
of the 15 minute python imbalance so
it's on efficiency
go back and Rewind the video back and
look at the 15 minute time frame these
two blue lines here are anchored on the
15-minute time frame but just to drop
down to the low of it it's also doing so
because there's a small little portion
of inefficiency right there between this
candlesticks high in this candlesticks
low if this didn't occur and say this
candle was trading all the way down to
that level there already
then I would only look for this little
area here in this drop down and not be
sufficient enough for me
to look for a long entry to get in sync
with the afternoon using the lunch macro
so
we actually see the bodies respecting
again the Boston amount cells on
efficiency on the 15-minute time frame
we have a little bit of a wick in here
but it trades down into what the Friday
August 11th opening range Gap
so it's treating it now as support
so these levels are like
creating an x-ray view in price action
these are the things that the algorithm
is looking at that most people are not
looking at now you might think oh well
you know everybody knows about the Gap
ICT come on you act like you invented a
gap now I invented the logic that I'm
teaching you with the algorithm will
follow
okay that's authorship so when the
market trades down and finds the the top
of that Gap it's going to treat it and
refer back to it
and re-capitalize allow smart money to
reclaim bullish entries on that same
premise there
okay so there's no there's no support or
resistance idea over here
it's the Gap in itself that it's traded
down into
and then we touch one more time device
outside efficiency High
and then all three races we go immediate
rebalance on the 15 minute time frame
and then zips up into after market hours
into the city
level here
okay in the one minute chart
you can see we drop down into I want to
take your attention over to this little
area right here so you can see that we
had this small little Gap right there
and the low that was not going to be
taken out because it's a 15 minute
Wick it trades down to take out the sell
side
so this drop down in here go back and
watch the beginning of the video it
drops down takes the sell side there and
then it leaves this Gap so we drop down
into that perfectly
and then we have Market rally up shift
the marker structure there bullish order
block and takes off and then this little
Gap right here I refer to that also real
time and
after this is the key okay after
I mentioned that the fifteen thousand
one thirty eight and fifteen thousand
one sixty seven buy side so if I'm
pointing that out and I'm saying watch
this fair value Gap
your mind should immediately jump to
okay he's pointing out this pure value
Gap with 138
and 167 by side
prior to that fair value Gap so how
would we use that
it's an inversion fair value
and we'll zoom in here in a couple
minutes
and the market rallies up creating
relative equal highs going into the
lunch hour dropping down taking sell
side repricing to the low of the
Boston amount of cell sign efficiency
here's the buy side imbalance also
efficiency low and the busy high it's
these blue levels are trades down to it
here that's a perfect area to go long
and run up into the buy side
you see that's in fact what we got here
and then it rallies up stop short of the
highs here so it creates a triple top
that is absolutely poison
retail Traders will see that say wow
that's really strong resistance and it
drops back down into the busy High by
some valve cell efficiency high and it
touches again that old Friday opening
range Gap High
touches it one more time gives a kiss
goodbye and then also the races will go
immediate rebalance there and then sends
it higher into the last hour of trading
uh here's the tweet I told you at 9 57
New York local time
look at the one minute I guess we're at
one minute chart here one minute NASDAQ
947 candle note that fair value Gap
that's this candle right here
okay and I'm telling you look at it
right there
after I pointed out fifteen thousand one
sixty seven by side
so the market draws up into there we
find some support at that five minute
fair value Gap and that's my fault for
miscalling the five minute the two
minute chart I apologize for that but
nonetheless even if you take that out
the context is we were going up the
fifteen thousand one sixty seven I
mentioned if we failed to get to these
levels all the focus would go down to
fifteen thousand zero twenty
but because we got that fifteen thousand
zero twenty is not likely
so it's going to continuously draw
higher and we saw that happen here
all right and looking at the last
portion of trading today
here's the two o'clock at three o'clock
Silver Bullet the entry is right here
and after that rally up did it take out
the buy side yet no so this fair value
Gap can be what
reclaimed it can trade back down into it
again so that's trading back down into
it finding some support rallies once
more creates a fair value Gap there
institutional order for entry drill and
volume and balance between these two
candles bodies
rallies in the last portion of the last
hour of trading in the New York session
in the park on close macro that sends
price careening into the buy side
liquidity here
and then we have an immediate rebalance
with an order block and a fair value Gap
really really strong really really
strong and it sends it higher aiming for
that hourly City low which you know did
after four o'clock trading today
all right folks hope you enjoyed that if
you found insightful give me a thumbs up
and I'll talk to you tomorrow
be safe