hey guys welcome back to the channel
it's Nova trades it's been a while since
the last video but today I'll be
covering a topic that has been requested
many times it is Sisty or change in
state of delivery of price and so what
we have in front of me is NQ and this is
live price action
so what we're looking at is:
when can we identify the end phase of the manipulation ?
when does price start to expand in the direction for the daily and weekly candle bias ?
so from our weekly Outlook & seasonality wise
August into September tends to be slower for QQQ or NQ
and what we're looking for is a simple external into internal move
so with that being said
if we were to take a look at NQ on the
monthly you can see that we've rated
a monthly High into a monthly fair value
Gap so it
just to highlight it
sorry
there's the monthly fair value Gap and
there is the monthly pivot High
and so what we have right now is July
expanded higher so we have open low high
close and now we have August retracing
back into that move towards the
quarterly and monthly open
so what we're looking for is whether or
not August has the momentum to continue
this move higher but in order to do so
it's going to do a move from external
liquidity right above an external Range
High
which is this pivot high right here and
retrace back into internal liquidity now
because this is a monthly candle it is
likely to have some sort of weekly
imbalance or daily imbalance that price
can retrace back into
so if we go to the weekly time frame
here is our
weekly fair value Gap or busy
and this is our internal liquidity so
we've gone from a external liquidity by
taking out an old monthly High
so this is a monthly
all right let's fix that letter
oops
inside a monthly fair value Gap
and then we are now looking to see
whether or not price is willing to trade
back into internal liquidity so we had
this move last week where it dropped
into internal liquidity and try to
expand higher now this week what we're
looking for is whether or not we have
the momentum to continue the move higher
or whether we will reverse back down and
possibly go back lower once again to
pick up some more liquidity and how we
recognize that is by using syste to our
advantage our Changing State of delivery
of price so for those of you that are
familiar with the term but are not too
sure what it is it is simply defining
order blocks and when price has shifted
its way of delivering price so for
example let's say we're in an uptrend
what you're looking for is
and the easiest way to say it is you're
looking for an opposing
reaction meaning if price is trending up
you are looking for a displacement down
you're looking for an order block to
form that supports price down as soon as
you see that first order block form in
your higher time frame point of interest
that confirms a change of state of
delivery of price
uh at an aggressive point so for example
let's say that we're utilizing the
monthly FEG to identify when price is
likely to start trading back down we
know price is trading higher
with this move higher we are looking for
price to Signal a possible uh end to
this move up with a change in state of
delivery price so what I like to utilize
is the hourly chart so if we were to go
back to the hourly chart
we are looking for an opposing
price move
that is a price move that supports
a bearish order block and then forms a
bearish PD array so going back to that
setup right here this is Wednesday July
19th of 2023
you see we have this attempt to move
higher one two three four times right on
the hourly time frame and then we get
this huge displacement down as soon as
this candle closes
and it engulfs this entire candle this
is our first bearish order block
by definition after we've taken out
external range liquidity
right in a higher time frame point of
Interest so a monthly fair value Gap
and a monthly order block to the left
and we had a massive displacement down
this also confirms our first bearish PD
array so let me get rid of this monthly
for Value go
because we know we're inside where we
want to be
so this first candle right here
this is your first order block that
forms
on this displacement lower
then we get the secondary candle that
closes
below the pivot low
so once this candle forms the downside
this is our
aggressive
meaning or changes to delivery price has
already begun when we are looking for a
clear confirmation we are looking for
the complete PD array to form that is we
go and if you're not familiar with this
it's in the previous video that I'll
have released maybe a month ago and I'll
link in the description below that
regards uh PD arrays and how they all
form but we can do a quick review right
here
external
high is rated
data rejection block forms
right so you have this rejection block
forming with this Wick
so here is
external
uh High
you have
rejection
so if price somehow managed to trade
back up above this line we'd expect them
to defend
this close and this open of these hourly
candles
so here's the OB we'll get rid of that
so external High rejection then what
comes next after a rejection forms is
your displacement lower and your order
block
so here's your OB
right and because it's a bearish or we
will put a minus sign beside it
then comes your
value yet
so we have one two three four components
we are looking for a pivot low to be
broken so the pivot low that forms this
pivot high is broken right there with
this confirmed on closed candle
and so we have a market structure shift
once this closes
and we have what is also going to be a
low high lower low after rating external
liquidity so we are going to have a
breaker right breaker or mitigation and
in this sense
you can look at
these down cools candles here
aligned with this OB here and so this
general area is going to act as your
mitigation
right because of how messy uh the Wicks
are in regards to or in relation to
where the bodies are we're going to say
that this area in general
are about to highlight this area
is going to provide the mitigation
so we have mitigation
and in breaker block we have liquidity
void or fair value Gap we have order
block we have rejection we have external
High so we have a complete PD array form
with respect to
uh
a bearish PDA reform with respect to
this bullish move higher so this is the
first opposing PD array opposing means
opposing the current direction
of price
this is the first opposing PDA that has
formed and is signaling aligned with the
economic calendar a possible retracement
from external liquidity into internal
liquidity and where does internal Equity
lie right underneath here
in the form of all of these imbalances
right so if we were to take
this move here
and Define the PD array
oops
all right
we took external liquidity with Wix on
the hourly time frame and we displaced
back lower so now we have our confirmed
change in state of delivery of price
so here is the confirmed move right
there
right so this is our sister
the more conservative approach to it
right
and so
this is your Market structure shift but
this is also indicating that price is
now aligned with the economic calendar
ready to move back lower and retrace
back into a discount oops this should be
flipped I just realized that
so let's do that like this whoops there
we go back into a discount and a
discount liquidity pool so we're looking
for price to retrace back into
uh this busy right here this hourly fair
value Gap to the upside
and so what happens is once price forms
it retraces back into that mitigation
slash breaker area almost Taps the order
block body
Rejects and then we have this overnight
move lower
right and then we get this uh
continuation into the next day with the
gap down and it trades all the way into
discount so there is your first complete
move that opposes the price action
leading up to this uh CISD right here
so this is from July
19th right now here it is again
albeit this time it's a little bit
different because it doesn't take out
the old high but it does take out an old
weekly high so for example
here is our
weekly High
previously High
price is currently trying to expand
higher after the sell-off
and look what happens right we reprice
all the way back up to the
inefficiencies over here and almost into
this Gap right it almost touches that uh
gap down so that would be a daily Vib
that is formed right here from Wednesday
sorry from the Wednesday session into
the Thursday session we form a daily bib
it almost Taps into it doesn't
and what we're looking for is
confirmation of a
change in state of delivery of price so
here's the load that forms as high and
we don't displace below it so we don't
have a confirmed
uh PD array that forms however we do
have
an aggressive approach to our changes
data deal of your price with right here
so this up close candle the rage
liquidity is completely displaced
through
and what you'll notice is we have
external liquidity taken we have
a rejection
the possibly forms right here
so we can label it
and what we're looking for next is
uh
displacement lower which we have we have
liquidity void or fair value Gap
on the hourly time frame right here
and we need
a
mitigation slash breaker deform and so
we need to see a low break
and an hourly bodily candle bodily uh
sorry candle body to close below that
low so in this instance
we don't get that move until right
around here
so here's the low that forms this high
and then we get this overnight move
lower heading into Tuesday of this week
so this is our first complete bearish PD
array that forms however our aggressive
60 right when our first opposing order
block that is farmed on uh
the open on Sunday into Monday overnight
has held up into Monday's trading and
Tuesday overnight
and then we get the confirmed hourly
displacement lower so now we have
our bearish PD array form
with respect to this move right here and
then we get the complete
bodily close
right here heading into Tuesday am
so we have our complete system now
with relation to the structure up here
so there's a rejection this previous
week high is also your external
you have your fair value Gap and now you
have your mitigation and breaker
so if I were to take this and then draw
it straight across
that's going to be your breaker
why is your breaker because this is the
low
that urges an old weekly High
and then this is the hourly confirmation
of a change in state of delivery of
price that occurs right on the more
conservative event so what we're looking
for is price to retrace back up into a
breaker
which also happens to have
fair value Gap or consecutive fair value
gaps so what you can do is
you can mark off all the way up to
where these fair value gaps form so let
me do the other way actually that's
right that's right
and we get into a premium right there
and so this is your premium fear value
Gap portion and up here is your premium
of your fair value Gap portion so these
are the fair value gaps of interest of
trying to engage price in a short and
very similar to what was happening up
here see how we have one two three four
drives higher with wix
we are looking for one two three four
five drives higher into a premium fair
value Gap inside a breaker after a
confirmed
bearish PD array or change in state of
delivery of price has been established
and so what we're looking for is shorts
to engage price uh from premium into
discount now the way price action
actually developed this day we didn't
get that sell-off until after hours due
to some news so they made it very
convenient to load up on puts all day
and then capitalize on those puts the
following day
so that is your hourly confirmation and
a retracement back up into your first
attempt to short and move down now then
what happens is overnight we get the gap
down and we obviously
then end up dropping into what
actually this is a swing low that starts
all this move
a discount right so we automatically
drop off into a liquidity pool of
discount liquidity by taking out these
hourly pivots
and then what happens then we retrace
and then we continue the confirm move
now so then what we're looking for is if
we want to play a continuation off this
move but you have to apply the same
logic here's a swing High
here's the swing low we are looking for
a premium engagement of this leg down so
there's premium
here is an hourly fair value Gap and we
want to see on the lower time frame now
a way to engage price
uh
inside the structure so here is
the week close of an hourly candle and
then we have this down close so this
confirms
that this is now an order block
and so we want to engage price with
respect to the structure
into a downside
heading into Wednesday equities open so
if we're going five minute
and then go back here
so here's the premium portion
right so New York attempts to trade
higher actually let me turn on
there we go
so New York attempts to trade higher
back into the hourly fair value Gap
and then what we're looking for is on
the 15 or five minute time frame with
respect to that area we are looking for
an order block to form
so here is that move right here so we
have a candle that fully engulfs the
previous candles that's an outside
candle or outside bar
and so this right here is piercing of
Premium liquidity a failure to displace
higher and then you have your first
little confirmation of an order block
and so this is an aggressive
lower time frame
idea of a
system now I'm doing it from the body
you can do it from the wick as well so
it's not going to change much
and so now what you're looking for is 15
minute order flow to confirm that it
wants to move lower
so you have
your rejection forming though
right we've had liquidity sweep
right here above an old pivot into
premium
so we have external high right with
relation to this 15 minute
leg down right here
so we've taken out the liquidity of this
leg
we have our first little rejection area
for me
we have our order block that forms what
this displacement lower now we we're now
we're looking for a fair value Gap so
it's right here
tiny little one on the 15 minute time
frame so there's our first little
liquidity void fair value Gap
so we'll do that
and we're looking for
a low
to the swing High to be broken to
confirm bearish order flow
so this is the conservative
system right
so we have a low high lower low so now
we have our mitigation
right slash breaker we have a rejection
block at the high our order block at the
high we have a fair value up at the High
we have very aggressive approach to an
entry at the high with this SD right so
the first order block that forms after
piercing liquidity and then we have our
confirmation down here and as you can
see
price immediately sells off and doesn't
really give a retracement at all
into this move
so the only way to have entered this
move would have been pre-market
with relation to news
and then if you were aggressive in your
approach to the open and you saw that as
price move lower and close below up
close candles so as price closed below
these up close candles the subsequent
candle should respect the previous up
close candle right so that's an order
block that's an order block so it
touches the order block rejects touches
the orderable order block and rejects
right touches the order block and
rejects so you're looking for these
Clues on the 15 minute time frame to
engage price on the five or one
so then going back to that area now that
we have a label on the 15
we can kind of dive down into the five
minute time frame and we'll so here's
your five minute order block that
pierces into that liquidity right and
here's your down close candle so now you
have a confirmed
order block on the five minute
that you can utilize too
start developing your PD array and so
then this is your five minute fair value
Gap
right here
and you have displacement lower you
break an old low so the five minute
confirms that it wants to move lower for
the time being right and we're using the
hourly time frame
sorry
we're using the hourly time frame to
determine that price is likely to go
lower and continue to move lower until
it hits a
discount sell side liquidity pool on a
higher time frame so such as the daily
or weekly
swing lows
so then back to the five minute
all right so now that we're here
we've had news in here and we're looking
for confirmation of the order flow which
we're getting on the 15s and the hour so
now in the five minute we have our high
purges and to a fair value Gap
right there
so barely enters into the fair Valley
Gap rejects displaces lower closes below
this up close candle so now this becomes
an order block
and we want to see the fair value Gap we
want to see price enter it close weekly
and then engage prices so once we see
this weakness in the five minute just
prior to open you can now start to
engage price so if I'm going to replay
and I go here
and then go to one minute
so you can see here's the piercing of
liquidity
and then we close below it and then you
can see how this candle try to move
higher in respect to the structure that
has formed inside
then it forms another fair value Gap
right there
price enters it and if we're looking for
lower prices the open should and now
this could also happen it could induce
higher
and then drop lower right that can also
happen so that's why it sometimes it's
better to wait for the open I usually
always wait for the open I can engage
price and catch it later on
um so that I don't get prematurely
stopped out
then what happens is here's the open
right so that's an immediate move down
in a way and you want to see it continue
you don't want to see it come back up
again
and then there's your second move down
and then obviously you get a little bit
of retracement
but now we have our fair value Gap that
is formed right off the open so if price
is going to
try to move lower you want to see
weakness out of the fair value Gap and
so now you can engage price based on the
weakness of this candle
and once you engage price you're in
short from here
so if you take a short position tool
right once this candle closes you can
place your stop at the high so 15 Point
stop
and with respect to price you are
targeting
right the low that is formed previously
so this is a 52 and a half point
set up with a 15.75 stop loss so you
have a three R trade setup
now
price is being volatile and it's
inefficient it could come out take you
out once more and then drop it lower so
you have to be cautious with these so as
soon as price starts to displace lower
you want to see a confirmed move lower
again you don't want to see a stall out
here so
if we move lower again perfect so we
have one move and two moves but notice
how there's Wicks forming at the lows
you don't want to see this move
aggressively back up again however you
have another fair value Gap
to now help you with your bearish order
flow to the downside so it could retrace
you want to see a retrace that's all
right you want to see a respect the
order block and you want to see it move
down
so in this instance it just kept moving
down and it hit the target so that's
perfect you're out so
even if we didn't take any entries here
right
all we have to do is wait for
confirmation
by the means of displacement right
energetic moves away from an area of
Interest right so if you're bullish you
want to see this these kind of areas
hold sweep and move higher but if you're
bearish you want to see confirmed
extended moves lower retracements
weakness extended moves lower right you
don't want to see it do
uh
chop stuff right where it comes like
here comes back up to here then tries to
do this and then goes lower right you
don't want to see that so this is a very
energetic and efficient move lower
but the clues to what was happening
started to form here for this session in
New York
so going back to the 15 minute time
frame
and obviously in terms of this entire
hourly leg we're looking for premium
premium liquidity above an old high
right in terms of this range
and then we want to see our first little
order block form so that's your
aggressive change in state of delivery
price so soon as you see that form based
on a hourly uh
hourly structure
so there's your hourly order block as
formed at the same time you want to see
confirmed order flow of price willing to
move lower and that is just simply by
observing price reject order blocks fair
value gaps
and continue to move lower
so you can see that we had this nice low
move up into news and then once that
occurred we start to deliver back down
with aggression and then if you wanted
to see the rest you can see that
right we sold off all the way into
a daily fair value Gap right
but yeah that was that move but the
confirmation of the entire week's move
started up here right so there's a whole
bunch of consolidation
that's occurring so this is untradable
the only trade that I was able to take
was the short here I think and
I actually missed this NQ move but I was
able to capture a move on rty instead so
my focus was on rty because NQ had moved
without me and I uh I missed the entry
at the open by like
uh fractions of a tick
so this is basically seconds right I
just was too slow to pull the trigger
but this is how you use syste on the
hourly time frame to identify when price
starts to oppose the move that has
happened and confirms when it is likely
to go from external to internal and
internal back into external so now if we
go back to live price action
for the date of August 3rd
I want to point out that we have
on the weekly time frame we've taken out
an old weekly law right we entered into
the weekly fair value Gap so here is
okay let me use
the horizontal Ray so it stays annotated
previous week's law so that's external
liquidity
so there's external liquidity
and
a failure to display slower right here
and what happens is you have an outside
candle that forms so it's an engulfs the
previous candle
and so you have an aggressive
syste right here
however it's albeit price is still
supporting Bearer structure we haven't
taken out the old hourly hi-hat and so
this is an aggressive way to approach a
possible short-term low being put in so
a failed swing lower and in fact we had
diversions with es here
so there's some sort of versions of the
lows
and then what you're looking for is
price to start to expand higher
and retrace back into what internal
liquidity so we go from external to
internal and internal into external
that's it
uh where is it right here
so what do you think price is likely
trying to do right here
see this high and see this high
it is likely trying to go for the Asian
Range High
and into an internal liquidity pool so
above an old high so the displacement
that occurred from yesterday is now
being repriced back into
simply it
we've gone from external and now we're
going back into internal now this setup
here isn't going to be clean because
it's fighting the down move
and is trying to establish
a retracement move higher
so you can see that it's pretty volatile
it trades up then trades lower trades up
trades lower and then finally
establishes a break of this high and
then you have respective structure
on the lower time frame so we have the
aggressive cyste and then we finally
have an approach on the five minute that
confirms that it is now willing to or at
least trying to move higher so it trades
above that high creates a fair value Gap
and then for about
an hour it ranges inside that and then
finally breaks out into the PM session
and it's breaking out to do what
attack and internal liquidity pool
and so that has been
the idea of syste
two approaches
once when you have an order block form
that opposes what the current price
action has been doing so for example
we've been trading down
and so we have
there's this order block
however we still haven't taken up high
yet so what we want to see is price
trade higher come back test it
create a failed swing lower
and then confirm and move back higher
and so now we're getting a bullish PD
array forming
into
this down move that has occurred all
week
right so external back into internal
and the way to approach it on the five
minute would have been what we just
covered right here
now you could have played it down here
too with more aggressiveness that is if
you are expecting
price to hold and move higher this is
where your aggressive approach
approaches would have been now if um
because we have the hourly order block
60 right here you're looking for some
sort of bullish
five minute PD array to form
or five minute supportive structure to
form to help you gauge an entry point uh
I didn't like anything in here today the
only thing I liked was actually the
short move from here back down and when
it failed uh
you had been stopped out for uh while
doing a stream it was about 55 and a
half points and if you captured the bulk
of it you would have gone in like 79
points
um but caution was also aired once we
saw price being supported here
chances are we are most likely due to
the inability of NQ to drive lower to
try pushing back higher into internal
liquidity
and so we're getting that move now and
so this is what it looks like on hourly
now so very messy
right in terms of the hourly Wix but if
you apply that logic right where you see
an order block form on the hourly time
frame and then you wait for a 15 minute
or five minute structure to support
price action higher
uh
you can and you will over Time Capture
big expansion moves now there's nothing
Pleasant about this
because we are going against
the entire move
for the week however this is also
signaling that chances are we are most
likely done selling off for the week as
well so we're probably going to end up
range Bound by range but I mean back
into what has already transpired so just
before I shut this video off another
thing you want to point out is that we
do have this trendline liquidity that's
formed all week and it seems to be
piercing it just now as well
so if we were to delete everything here
and simply just
address
the discount and premium
from the highs
to the lows
chances are we are probably going to try
to trade back into a premium
liquidity
pool or fair value Gap or order block
into Friday
and
so we're probably going to move up into
here and then it'll probably try to or
attempt to sell back down again right
and it'll probably get trapped in this
area somewhere between here and here
but yeah so that is uh how you use systy
to help you identify what is likely to
occur
in terms of price going from external
liquidity into internal liquidity
internal Equity back into external
liquidity
uh one thing I need to point out is that
if you're bearish then you want to see
raids of old highs hold
and then confirm to move lower if you're
bullish you can get a move like this
retraces into discount
and then begins to move higher again at
that point what you're looking for is a
confirmed hourly PD area back to the
upside similar to What's Happening Here
and the PD array is always going to be
the same it's going to be external
liquidity
rejection block
displacement that creates an order block
then you get some sort of liquidity void
or fair value Gap then you get your
breaker or mitigation that forms and so
if you look here here's your high here's
your low here's your higher high break
your medication
order block displacement
or waiting for a fair value Gap or a
liquidity point to be
created
and then we will have a confirmed
bullish PD array for the move into
Friday
hope you guys have enjoyed the video it
might be a little lengthy and obviously
my communication wasn't as crystal clear
I did Mumble a little bit I apologize
for that but the idea is there in the
video and if you guys have any questions
please do post them below or you can ask
me in my Discord
uh which will be linked in the
description or you can just DM me on
Twitter although I do suggest Discord is
the best route for that and I'll see you
guys next time
thank you