welcome back folks
so we're gonna be doing a another quick
review here
I'm gonna try to get to it pretty quick
I'm still not feeling too well so
the only chart dollar Index
you're looking for higher high
and we got that
here
and this is still a potential run even
though we failed
to get to it today I'm not convinced
that we're
we're done trying to reach with that yet
so
a very soft bias for a higher dollar
[Music]
you're a dollar you're looking for these
relative equal lows we pierced that
today
and that doesn't look like it's done so
but it has take a look at that
using the inversion pair value Gap I
chewed up into consequent crochet which
is this level here
so we hit that sold off and then dug
into this sell side
I think it would be
more likely to expect a deeper run below
these lows which is the opposite of what
we see or in it what I'm expecting
rather
for another higher high on the dollar
Index and that would be another lower
low
for Euro
four hour chart
here you can see the relative equal lows
just pierced it here
just really
the very difficult rings to trade in
so again I feel for you if you're in the
Forex
that's that class right now
British pound just to toss Us in here
you can see this thing is a mess too
can't get out of this range
[Music]
and this is what we've been seeing for
the whole entire month of August
so you want to trade
in the summer months and try to get it
funded account challenge passed
and good luck
that's why I tell you don't do it wait
until the fall okay
all right s p on the left hand side
daily chart I mentioned that we would
likely drop into this Gap here I did not
have the lines on it but they point to
it last night and I did mention that it
would certainly get to this one here on
NASDAQ we did get to it and through it
up into the very shorter block the
opening price here extend that through
so we can see hit one point trade it all
up to the bearish order block and then
closed on the day with a lower close
than its opening up to the same vein
that we saw here
for s p and again what I want to see is
do we start to roll over here and make a
run for the sell side here
okay
and
this sell side liquidity pool on the S P
would be where my focus would be
hourly chart on the s p
this is the inefficiency on the daily
chart okay let me take you back up to
the dealers that we can follow along
this candle's high this candle is low
the respective levels here so it's these
two red levels that makes the spare bag
up on the daily chart I mentioned last
night
this fair value Gap is for the NASDAQ I
did not include the order Block Level
here I added that today
[Music]
all right buy side
taken look at the bodies respecting the
lower level that dealing fair value Gap
then we had the market trading lower
gravitate back towards the consequent
encouragement of the inefficiency on the
daily chart
straight down to the low or the
inefficiency just outside of it
and then the Consolidated inside of that
range
daily bearish order block we traded
outside of the inefficiency this is the
high and the low of its respective daily
if everybody got
and we had sell side here so we ran up
broke lower consequent encroachment
which is midpoint between this high and
this low on The Daily fair value Gap
that's what these two levels are
because encroachments here for that
and we sold off and they were
consolidated
15 minute time frame you can see how we
each end up in the s p into the low of
the daily fair value Gap we were
expecting to be traded to last night
for today's Trading
Market broke lower
entered all the way down to the low only
down to a lot of daily inefficiency
just a real sloppy afternoon if you were
to ask me
on the NASDAQ
you see a trip into the parish order
block so we're really in a premium on
this one and we have relative equal lows
down here where South Side would be
residing
we broke lower we'll look at a smaller
fair value Gap in here
over time frames we broke lower
Breakaway Gap
unable to get back up into this area
here working over for breaker high low
higher high
consolidation breaks lower attacks the
cell side
[Music]
five minute chart again s p digs into
that daily fair value Gap breaks lower
consolidation breaks again and we have a
nice little fair value Gap there trades
up into it and then the displacement the
lower look at the bodies respecting the
inefficiency here on the cell side of
bounds by side and efficiency
that candles low there's your bodies the
Wicks do the damage
breaks lower the consequent encroachment
consolidation rather sloppy and digs
down into the low of the inefficiency
from the daily chart
NASDAQ
you see we trade up into the bearish
order block here which is above the
daily inefficiencies High
short term low
displacement the fair value Gap this is
model 2022.
sell short
wait for displacement attack this low
here it does creates another
inefficiency here but what is it doing
trading inside of this one the high the
low consequent encroachment consequent
encroachment
failed
break lower or sell side right there
breaks lower
creates a fair value Gap there trades up
into it
then makes a lower low
and then consolidates into the close
appreciate your patience with me well
I'm recuperating
and if um I'll obviously chat with you
on Twitter tomorrow
and do another review if it's possible
until talk to you then be safe