welcome back folks this is lesson 4.1
implementing macro analysis
we're going to be teaching applying
seasonal Tendencies to hire time frame
analysis
this module is going to be teaching
bullish seasonals in higher time frame
analysis
okay you've probably seen this chart
before I've made uh available a few of
these templates over the years but we're
gonna be teaching specifically only on
the buy side for seasonal tendencies in
this teaching
and we'll be using the Canadian dollar
to begin with
and what this is is it's a 40-year
seasonal tendency where the price on
polish years and bearish years
have been compiled and compressed into a
file where the output gives us a
tendency for what price usually does for
each contract delivery month
I'm going to get into that in a minute
before we get into it deeper let's bring
up some points here seasonal Tendencies
are merely a proverbial roadmap of past
performance
and they are not to be viewed as a
Panacea or be all end-all concept
despite what you may see in this
teaching and the subsequent teaching in
4.2
please let me remind you that simply
because it's done something in the past
doesn't that in any way guarantee it's
going to do the same thing in the future
this is just one more tool to add a
Confluence of things that would already
lead you to an expectation that the
market should go higher or lower
okay folks this is the Canadian dollar
40-year seasonal tendency this is the
expanded view of the same chart you just
saw
and I want you to take a look at
something real quick
up here we have it says March
abbreviation June abbreviation
September's abbreviation December and
then back to March again
what this is delineating is the contract
delivery months for the Canadian dollar
now currencies they deliver on March
June September and December every single
year these months expire
these charts that I'm sharing with you
are a compilation of data over all the
delivery months price action for the
last 40 plus years
beginning in 1976 now this data is only
compiled up to 2015 but I can tell you
that the output is hardly changed at all
if you're concerned about it being 2017
is there any there is there any
deviation no there's not any deviation
at all so how do we look at these things
and what benefit does it give us well
let me ask you a question
if you were to if you were to ask the
average Trader that just now getting
into trading maybe it's not Forex maybe
it's stocks or or Commodities and you
ask them hey look
if I were to ask you today is the
markets manipulated to a degree where
well before Price ever starts to trade a
specific time of year would it be
inclined to go higher or lower based on
some underlying influence that repeats
itself and as a new Trader I could tell
you I would have never answered that
question with yeah I could probably
agree to that
um I it felt like a random thing to me
and one of the things that I like about
seasonal Tendencies is it gave a
characteristic to price that proved to
me that there is a rhyming reason behind
everything that goes on
if there's something that's measured and
again this is 40 years worth of data
okay 40 years worth of data
in the blue line the red line is a
15-year average so you can see between
looking at 40 years worth of data and 15
years worth of data there's very little
discrepancy in terms of what the overall
strong seasonal Tendencies are for this
particular currency
now since we're primarily dealing with
bullish seasonal tendencies in higher
time frame analysis for this module
we're going to not focus on bearish
patterns but we're going to be looking
for tendencies that lend well to being a
buyer
and if we're going to be doing higher
time frame analysis and we want to be
buying on these higher time frame charts
and using it for ideas for being
position Trader
looking at this seasonal tendency I'm
going to ask you what
time of year now time of year is going
to be delineate at the bottom of the
chart down here you can see it's all
dated here's December November October
this is all calendar month based this is
contract delivery months okay you can
see the vertical lines delineating when
that contract
March would end trading here that would
be the beginning of June's trading
contract and then June would end here
and it would pick up at September's
contract and so on going through the
season sanity chart
if I were to ask you what would be your
first choice in deciding when would be a
good time to buy
well if you were
paying attention you can see that this
is probably a really good time to be
buying around mid-march
all the way up into the May June time
period
so between March and June there
typically is a strong tendency for the
Canadian dollar to Rally
now some of you may think to yourself
well that's great you know if this is
the contract month for Canadian dollar
what does that mean to me if I'm not
really a Futures Trader
well the main thing is is this is the
seasonal tendency that you would expect
Canadian dollar Futures to Rally now it
does not mean that it's going to Rally
every single year march to June doesn't
mean that it just means that there's a
strong probability that historically
looking back over 40 years worth of data
and comparing it against 15 years worth
of data there is a strong underlying
well there I say it element of Truth to
the fact that there is a tendency for
this to Rally problem is
if you're not a Futures Contract Trader
this doesn't do anything for you
or does it if we are trading foreign
exchange we have to remember that the
Canadian dollar is paired with the
dollar Index
now the dollar Index is the first in in
the pair's name so that means if we're
bearish one Canadian dollar the U.S CAD
is going to go
up if we're bullish on Canadian dollar
that means the U.S CAD pair is going to
go down
that means Canadian Dollars are bullish
while that would suppress the U.S dollar
Index
so since the pair's name begins with U.S
dollar
opposite would be seen in what we expect
to see in the Futures Contract so
what we have to do is focus in on a
seasonal tendency on the Futures
Contract that shows us a bearish tone in
the marketplace
so you can see we're here between
September and around Christmas time in
December there typically is a strong
tendency
for the Canadian dollar to decline on
in the underlying Futures Contract so we
have to take this into account when
we're looking at foreign exchange
because the U.S CAD pair is an inversion
of what the Futures Contract shows for
Canadian dollar Futures price
so if there's a strong tenancy for
September October November and December
to have a decline in the Canadian dollar
that should be a bullish scenario for
U.S CAD
let's take this over to the charts and
see if this in fact has any validity to
it
okay we're focusing on the bullish
seasonal Tendencies we have our U.S CAD
chart this is a weekly chart and I went
back to 2008
just to give you a nice sample size of
data and I started the line at the
beginning of September and I carried it
out in time to about midpoint of
December
you can see that shaded area all the way
to the left here
this is when we'd expect to see the
Canadian dollar
to be bearish
on the Futures underlying contract price
but because we're foreign exchange
Traders we have to be looking at it to
be reversed or inverted so that means it
would be bullish for the U.S CAD pair
because this is how we're trading the
major U.S against the cad
so this is the buying opportunity that
would be presented and look at the look
at the performance here on us CAD
as a relationship to the seasonal
tendency look how strong that buy was
look how many Pips it moved notice also
in here
this is the next time period very next
year
in 2009
this is a time when the season 10 should
should take place and that means the
Canadian dollar should be bearish on the
underlying Futures Contract but that
would be an inversion on U.S CAD pairs
that means we would expect bullishness
in here now while we didn't press up to
make new higher highs there was a nice
little pop nice little rally in here but
overall the direction was down so you
can see how the season tendency really
wasn't much help in terms of seeing much
like this
higher prices
very next year same thing very weak it
was lower now I'm going to ask you a
question look at these last two years
what was the underlying price Direction
on the weekly chart was it bullish or
bearish
bearish has been going lower
so would you be focusing on buying that
time of year
versus looking for opportunity to be a
seller
there's a hint for the next tutorial
4.2
going to 2011 we can see that the
seasonal tendency had a really nice
effect here after we made a nice low and
Market structures shifted to the bullish
side
and station overflow is now bullish and
during a time of year when the
underlying Futures Contract for Canadian
prices should be going lower
that's bullish for U.S CAD so for a
foreign exchange Trader we're looking
for buys we had to look for weakness in
the online Futures Contract of the
Canadian dollar that would Propel price
higher at a time of the year when we
would expect prices to come in
same thing here the very next year 2012
we can see price again rallied up during
this time of the year
and now we're still bullish now look at
the effects of the seasonal tenancy
again we have a low and it starts
rallying up again
again same time of year September to
almost Christmas seasonal tendency
rallies again
same time period here rallies again and
again 2016 just passed we have a nice
rally up here as well seasonal tendency
come again once again strong now looking
at this again let me remind you what
we're looking at is underlying weakness
in the Futures Contract so if it's
underlying weakness in the Futures
Contract for a Canadian dollar the
inversion puts it to a bullish stance
for U.S CAD
so it's very important that's why I
taught this one specifically because I'm
showing you how we have to take the
seasonal tendency from the Futures
Contract for some of the majors that are
appeared with a dollar
their currencies start with U.S CAD so
it's going to be an inversion so what
you would expect to see in the Futures
Contract has to be reversed in some of
the currencies that are paired out with
the dollar
so now
by itself it doesn't mean anything but a
coupled with other things
like quarterly shifts
remember that
every three or four months there's going
to be a move on a hard time frame
now we're adding another dimension to
that
it's one thing they expect to move every
three to four months but where is that
move going what what should we be
focusing on should we be buying or
should we be selling
seasonal Tendencies give us a road map
to help build the idea that okay there's
certain quarters of the year that we
want to be a buyer and there's certain
quarters of the year that we want to be
a seller
and we anticipate this year in and year
out the only difference is is we're
going to be looking for markets that
already predisposed to go higher and
then coupling that with the bullishness
of seasonal tendencies
if we're looking at the Canadian dollar
we'd have to reverse it look for
weakness in the seasonal Tendencies on
the underlying creatures contract and
then apply it to the U.S cat as
bullishness because it's an inversion of
Futures Contract prices for Canadian
dollar
if we see times when the Canadian dollar
is bullish underlying U.S CAD payer and
this seasonal tenancy September to
almost Christmas every single year
there's a strong tendency for it to be
bullish between that time period that
means there's many weeks where you can
be a bullish
U.S CAD Trader if the underlying pair of
us cat is bullish this is going back
several years and I only gave you this
sample size because if I'll give you any
more data it'll ruin all the discoveries
if you go back and study for yourself
but you can see here clearly many
instances when the underlying Market
moves are in line with the macro trend
seasonal Tendencies are absolutely a
barn burner for delivering what you
should be doing for each quarter of the
year in this case you have a loaded deal
if you're looking for a buying
opportunity for us CAD it's between
September and getting close to Christmas
every single year when the Market's
predisposed to go higher
what quarterly shift are you gonna be
looking for now
looking for longs
okay so now we're going to look at a
market that's closely related to
Canadian dollar
its number one export is crude oil
and here we have another example
just as a supporting idea
if he looked at this Market over here
you would expect to see bullish prices
for a rally in the crude oil market and
that rally comes in around coming in
about mid February going into March and
carrying into May June time period
so we're expecting bullishness in the
crude oil market and since
Canadian dollar generally moves almost
in tandem with a little the strong
tendency for the Canadian dollar the
rally
and the crude oil Market to rally at
this time of year that means we have a
march to June basically a
bullish effect for Canadian dollar and
crude oil coupled together so that's a
strong tendency
but again because we're looking at
Canadian dollar in the Foreign Exchange
Market this would have to be reversed
so we'll save that study for you in
addition to what's already been
presented here but I want to show you
the Futures Contract price for crude oil
between around March to June time period
okay here's the crude oil markets the
weekly chart and I just went back to
January uh 14 2014.
and obviously you can see here's this is
a bearish market here it's been in a
long-term downtrend when the collapse of
the oil Market from around the 105 level
but let's take a look at the bullishness
of that seasonal tendency again looking
for that march to June time period
okay so here's March all the way through
to June you can see the rally in the
crude oil Market
rate when it made its high and
the 2014 time period
and the next year we'd be looking for
the same seasonal tendency between March
and June all the way up into the first
of July
we can see it again here rallies once
more even in a bear Market it's still
there
we don't force the trades but I'm just
showing you the seasonal tendency that's
existing in the marketplace that should
convince you that there is an absolute
program to everything that goes on
despite fly-in domain factors there are
very routine things that take place and
they repeat themselves over and over
again
and again in 2016 we have March 2 the
1st of July encompassing the whole month
of June you can see that rally again
comes in for crude oil now my question
to you is this if you can see these
opportunities
repeating themselves based on the data
that I'm sharing with these reports and
seasonal tendency charts
is it hard not to feel like they're
treasure maps because that's exactly
what it felt like for me as a young man
when I was in my 20s and I saw these
seasonal tendency charts and I
admittedly pushed them aside for a first
couple months and then finally I got
into the study of seasonal Tendencies
and I realized that quickly right away
that there is something to them now
admittedly I've lost money traded them
in the beginning I had no idea what I
was doing I just thought every time it
would work so therefore I loaded up the
boat and traded way too many things and
too many times got burned doing it
so put on the back burner until I
realize there's this quarterly shift
that takes place in the marketplace and
I'm matured now and I can look back and
I can pick out where the highest
probability seasonal Tendencies are for
certain times of the year certain
markets have really strong seasonal
Tendencies to move a specific three to
four month cycle every single year when
it's bullish and when it's bearish
if we can focus in on those Quarters on
those particular currency pairs or those
asset classes we have a loaded deal in
the form of odds it doesn't mean it's
going to be profitable every time it
doesn't mean it's a guaranteed it's
going to be accurate it just means that
we have a high odds probability that our
prognostication will lead us to a
successful outcome this is just one
example of how correlated pairs between
Canadian dollar and cruel both can lean
well with one another in terms of
seasonal Tendencies and even in the
bearish market the crude oil Market's
been in you can see that the nice big
rallies that's occurred happened to
script
with a seasonal tendency we're going to
teach more about this in module 4.2 and
I'm going to talk about the bearishness
as well and in that module I'm actually
going to share all of the seasonal
Tendencies I have for all the currencies
and until next time wish you good luck
and good Trading