welcome back folks this is lesson 4.3 of
the January 2017 ICT mentorship
continuing our discussion on seasonal
Tendencies we're going to be
highlighting ideal seasonal Tendencies
and higher time frame analysis this is
going to be specifically dealing with
foreign exchange or FX payers
okay before we begin uh just a reminder
that seasonal Tendencies are a tendency
they're not a Panacea they're not a be
all in all they're not a absolution
they're just road maps of what has
happened in the past with price action
so when we look at these charts the
orientation is for instance for the
Forex pair all the dollar the chart on
the left is the Australian dollar
Futures price seasonal tendency
and the chart on the right US dollar
Index seasonal tendency for the Futures
price what I'm sharing with you the
ideal seasonal Tendencies what we're
actually looking at is we're comparing
the two seasonal tendency charts we're
looking for the most diametrically
opposed price action between the two so
when we're focusing on high probability
or in my definition an ideal seasonal
tendency is when the underlying Market
is predisposed to go in a direction that
c Zone tenancy is being outlined in here
so it doesn't mean every single year the
seasonal tendency May
may not come to fruition but that's okay
it's a general rule of thumb there's
plenty of these seasonal Tendencies as
we go through the major pairs so there's
something always every year that would
set up a potential long-term trade
you see here on the Australian dollar
the strongest seasonal tenancy in
contrast to that of the dollar Index on
the right
the Shaded in area here shows the
strongest tendency for Australian dollar
Futures prices to Rally in March and
make a top sometime in May
now if this is true we should see a
sell-off in the dollar Index and we do
in fact see that same thing occurring
between March and a decline making a low
in May so between the two we have a
qualified ideal scenario for the
Australian US dollar pair in FX to Rally
because it's the first currency in the
name of the pair Australian dollar
Aussie looks at the rally at time of
year same time the dollar Index so the
pair Construction in ways design when we
watch price of Aussie dollar when we see
price rallying on that chart we're
actually seeing the rise of Australian
dollar futures or I'll show you in
prices
versus lower prices on the dollar Index
so in an ideal scenario this trade would
be best suited to be found on a
long-term primary bullish Market or if
we made a long-term low
we could potentially test this theory in
terms of catching a long-term trade
okay our next pair we're going to look
at is the New Zealand dollar or kiwi
coupled with the dollar Index on the
left hand side that's the New Zealand
dollar Futures Contract seasonal
tendency
and again on the right hand side it is
the US dollar Index features seasonal
tendency
see here again just like we saw in the
Australian dollar we can see a rally
that's typical for a March April time
period making a high in May for the New
Zealand dollar Futures price and again
if this is true we're going to see a
contrasting sell-off at the same time of
the year again we do see that May April
High and a low forming in May
now these are only focusing on the
highest ideal
long-term setup I'm not looking for
every possible scenario for a seasonal
play but for long-term analysis we're
focusing only on the most obvious ones
that jump off the chart and they have
historical data to support it and again
because it's a tendency it doesn't mean
it's going to happen every single year
so the best scenario would be when
you're in a bullish condition and you're
seeing underlying bullishness for a New
Zealand dollar this seasonal tendency
should have an effect on price that time
of year between March and April we
should be seeing a seasonal low and for
a couple months you see a rally up into
around May
the next pair we're going to look at is
the euro dollar or Fiber
and we're going to be focusing on the
left-hand chart for the Euro Futures
price and then we're going to look at
the chart on the right
for the Futures price on the US dollar
Index
as you see here we have a seasonal load
it usually forms between June and July
and that should be seen with a high that
forms in the dollar Index so as a
long-term High time frame scenario this
is the ideal scenario you would look for
a load of form in the summer of euro
dollar
okay next one we're looking at is the
cable or British pound versus US dollar
the chart on the left is the British
pound Futures price and seasonal
tendency
and the dollar Index is on the right
hand side seasonal tendency for the
Futures price as well
for the British pound we have the
strongest tendency to make a low
in March with a high forming in May and
if this is true
we would be seeing a high form between
March and April with a low forming in
May and we do see that here so this is
the highest probable or ideal scenario
for seasonal Tendencies again not a
Panacea or a BL Indo but it is a really
good time to expect a bullish scenario
at least for a long-term trade if the
underlying market for the British pound
is bullish so if you're studying the
Futures price of the British pound or if
you're just watching the pound dollar FX
pair and on the higher time frame charts
we're expecting to see higher prices
were in the long-term uptrend if we
enter this time of year between March
and April we would be expecting some
seasonal low to form
and we can see that actually is
supported with Ace sell-off in the
dollar
seasonally as well
I want to contrast also the difference
between these blue and red lines on the
chart on the left hand side that's the
British pounds Futures seasonal tendency
the Blue Line represents 40 Years of
data
and the red line represents 15 years of
so by contrasting that you have a lot of
time factored into these tendencies so
it's to me in my opinion this is a
really strong one because it's many
years worth of data and it's also
contrasting it with a smaller short-term
view of the marketplace where in the
last 15 years it was there and in the
last 40 years it was still there so
between March and April there's usually
a seasonal load of the forums and then
it rallies up to making a spring high
around May
and again it's really really uh
positive
and most likely expected to see happen
when you have the underlying British
pound in a strong uptrend or you've
suspected a turn has taken place long
term and we haven't started trending up
higher we can test this Theory by taking
a trade and see if it does in fact pay
now
foreign
X pair is the dollar swissy okay or US
dollar versus Swiss franc dollar Index
is on the left hand side it's a seasonal
tendency for the Futures price of the
dollar Index
and on the right hand side it is the
Futures chart seasonal tendency for the
Swiss francaise so what we have on the
dollar Index we have a seasonal tendency
for the dollar to make a seasonal High
in the June July time period so summer
highs forming in dollar Index
and the contrasting low that forms in
June July in the Swiss franc so we have
a strong tendency for that to make a
major turning point in the summer months
for this particular pair and again this
would be an ideal scenario where the
dollar is in a bearish market uh primary
downtrend or if we are in a primary
option for the Swiss franc this will be
a good scenario to trade this as well
okay the dollar versus Japanese Yen
on the left hand side we have again the
seasonal tendency for the Futures price
for the dollar Index
and then on the right we have the
seasonal tenancy chart for the Futures
price of the Japanese Yen
strongest tendency on the dollar is to
see a high form and a sell-off into May
and the opposite is seen with a seasonal
low forming in March in April and we see
that that generally makes the long-term
low
for the Japanese Yen at that time across
the calendar year foreign
if we're looking at seasonal Tendencies
again the way you could trade this is if
you are in a downtrend for the dollar
Index this would be a really good one to
sell
dollar versus Japanese Yen or if you are
in a bullish uptrend for the Japanese
Yen this is a good time to
sell short this currency pair because
you'd be buying strength of the Japanese
Yen while selling dollars
okay our next pair is the dollar CAD
or US dollar versus Canadian dollar on
the left-hand side we have the dollar
Index Futures seasonal tendency and on
the right we have Canadian dollar
Futures seasonal tendency
and for the dollar we have a strong
tendency to create a high again in that
March April time period McNiel low in
May
and we see the opposite is seen with the
Canadian dollar making a low in March
April and that high forming in May so
the way you would use this seasonal
tendency is if you're bearish on the
dollar Index this is a good time to be
selling short dollar CAD or if you're
long-term bullish on Canadian dollar
this is a good time to sell this pair
because you can see the weakness in the
dollar Index and the strength underlying
with the Canadian dollar
so I went kind of like go back in
summary with these seasonal tendencies
just because we're looking at one
seasonal tendency for instance when
we're looking to the season seasonal
Tendencies for the dollar Index uh when
that occurs like for instance between
March and April time period we expect
the dollar Index to create some measure
of a high long term seasonally it
doesn't mean it's going to happen but
we're expecting it to occur
by itself it means that if we're
primarily bearish on the dollar Index
this is an ideal scenario to be selling
dollars
now that may not be apparent in the
dollar Index but if we see a pair or a
currency that is coupled with a dollar
that has a strong seasonal tendency to
Rally in a specific time of the year
like that March April time period like
we're seeing here with the Canadian
dollar that means we don't have to be in
the uptrend for dollar Index we could be
in a long-term consolidation but
save the save the Canadian dollars in a
bullish uptrend
you're focusing in on that time of year
where March April creates a low in
Canadian dollar and it rise up into May
so with that seasonal tendency
underlying strength for the Canadian
dollar that also would sell off the
dollar versus CAD pair so it's a it's a
blending of the ideas it's not simply
well it has to be the uh downtrend for
the dollar and it has to be uptrend for
the Canadian dollar you only really need
one
and by blending these two elements
together and applying the seasonal
tendency you're really focusing in on
when seasonally the highest probability
for a big move is to occur you narrow it
down to a specific time of the year
certain calendar months and highest
probability seasonal Tendencies so you
can go through your calendar
ahead of time and write down certain
months where you want to be focusing on
specific plays that may unfold in price
it's real easy to forget about these
seasonal Tendencies when you get caught
up in the day trading and short-term
trading and reading other stuff about
ICT material but you want to have this
stuff in your in your calendar on your
trading desk there should always be
things to watch this month things to
watch the coming month okay and these
are the types of things you want to have
in your notes so when you're working at
your desk and you have your your your
trade desk open you're looking for
trades always start your trading day
every single day with reviewing a macro
perspective like this are we coming on a
time period where there's a high
probability for a sustainable move and
it's seen by these types of seasonal
tendencies very rarely do you have
things that would line up or give you
clues that feature price should do
certain things or have a rhythm to it
like seasonal Tendencies and when we
study these you're going to see that
we're gonna go we're going to refer to
these actually uh multiple times
throughout the disciplines of trading
we're going to use them again in swing
trading and in short-term trading so
we're not done with them because we're
doing High time frame analysis but for
higher time frame analysis these are
scenarios you want to be focusing on
specifically for these respective pairs
so until we talk again I wish you good
luck and good Trading