welcome back folks this is lesson 4.2
continuing our teaching on
applying seasonal tendencies to higher
time frame analysis
okay we'll be highlighting our topic of
seasonals with a deeper focus on fair
seasonals and higher time frame analysis
and our
market of study for this teaching
is going to be the new zealand dollar or
kiwi
okay and when we looked at
lesson 4.1 we we looked at the canadian
dollar
and we noticed that
while the seasonal tendencies that i'm
sharing here there's seasonal tendencies
with the utilization of the futures
market so since it's the futures market
that we're using the seasonal tenancy
it's important to understand that
the seasonal tenancy may
if it's bullish for the seasonal
tendency chart
for a particular time of year
that may or may not be bullish for a
particular pair like for instance
in 4.1 lesson
we used that u.s cad pair and since the
seasonal tendency is on the canadian
dollar
we are looking at a time when
the
canadian dollar seasonal tendency for
the futures contract would be
bullish
in our seasonal tenancy but would be
bearish
in the u.s cad pair
because it would be inverted that would
be
a little bit of a
sticking point for someone that's just
rushing through this lesson
but we're going to talk about
a currency this time where it's going to
move basically in tandem with what you
expect to see in the seasonal tenancy
chart
we're looking at the kiwi or the new
zealand dollar which is a com dial
commodity currency that means the
currency is traded as a futures market
this teaching also is going to go a
little bit deeper in the understanding
of seasonal tenants and how i employ
them
i've been able to call pretty
significant price swings in the
marketplace using hard time frame charts
and many of them youtube have
witnessed that happen some of you seen
it in this mentorship all of it comes by
way of the things i'm teaching
in
these two lessons here 4.1 4.2
the way we're going to approach the
seasonal tendencies in this teaching is
going to be applying
bear seasonals
but we're also going to segue into
how this helps us get in sync with
hopefully a quarterly shift in the
marketplace which is the goal of
position trading or long-term trading as
i understand and teach it powerful moves
that occur on these higher time frame
charts
monthly weekly and daily
they're in the hundreds of pips for
foreign exchange
so
it behooves you to look at this
marketplace when these higher time frame
charts because regardless of what type
of trade you're going to be
and if you can use seasonal tendencies
like a road map it's literally like
knowing the most probable direction
certain times of the year for certain
currencies or markets because it's not
limited to just foreign exchange or
currencies it's
limited to nothing really i mean
everything has a seasonal tendency but
you have to study it and go through a
long
process of you know compiling all that
data to get to the outcome what would
highlight a seasonal tendency where it
rests most predominantly
if you're looking at this chart here
obviously you can see that there are
certain points in where price generally
on the blue line and on the red line
okay and it's comparing a long period
blue line of time
and a shorter period of data
and when both of them move in tandem
direction in other words they all
are basically moving in the same
direction up or down at any given
particular time
that highlights a high probability
seasonal tendency now when it gets real
muddy and it's choppy back and forth
then it makes it a little bit less
likely there's a seasonal tendency there
but just quickly going over this chart
here
it should be obvious to you what time of
year there is a significant decline in
price
expected and when should there be a
significant increase in price for the
kiwi dollar
let's zoom in and take a closer look and
we'll break this down into real
specifics
okay we have that same chart now just
zoomed in
and i want to highlight
a few things going into this
these seasonal tendencies while we're
trying to aim at
where the conditions lie that would set
up a quarterly shift in other words a
move that may take
two to three months to unfold we're
using these higher time frame charts
with the attempt to hone in on an area
where we can capture
several hundred pips
in a long-term position trade
or
looking for
the ideas to get us in sync with the
institutional mindset where the
direction of the market should go in
these higher time frame charts
since it's the smart money entities that
move price on these higher time frame
charts we know there's a high
probability if there's a certain time of
year or a tendency for the market to
rally or decline and it's shown itself
over a large sample size of data
the blue line in the kiwi here
represents 19 years worth of data
the red line represents 15 years worth
of data
and the only thing it's doing is
contrasting
for 15 years worth of data versus 19
years worth of data the seasonal
tendencies pretty much are locked in
tandem you can see pretty much it's the
same scenario all the time
because it's traded in march contracts
june contracts september contracts and
december contracts they are the futures
contract delivery months in other words
these are the months that you would be
buying or selling if you're gonna be
trading
as you can see the june contract has the
strongest tendency to rally and decline
all in that same contract month
beginning first
trading day and last trading day before
the contract would expire
then december's contract has a very
strong tendency to rally
late in the year
and
understanding that it's pretty obvious
that if you're going to be trading the
kiwi you want to be focusing on the june
contract and the december contract
that's the powerful nature of
understanding these seasonal tendencies
that doesn't mean that the march
contract won't see
specific
price action that
sets up
moves that we see in the june and
december contract or that we won't see
things in the september contract that
would lead into december's
contract month unfolding as we see here
in the seasonal tenancy
again they're not panaceas they're not
be all end-alls but they're road maps as
to what price
has done in the past historically year
after year by compiling the data we can
see that these contract delivery months
do this type of thing over a large
sample size of data will it happen every
single year absolutely not in fact i
went back all the way to 2007 and we're
going to look at every single year from
2007 to now and we're going to see what
influence these seasonal tendencies had
and how it helped us or it would have
helped us let's say it that way we can
go back in time and look at how
hypothetically
knowing this information back then we
could have used it to get in sync with a
quarterly shift or it could have been
just a unique trade setup by itself
since we're focusing primarily on
bearish conditions
we're going to be looking for
areas at which the market is most likely
to see a
significant drop in price now we can go
back in time and look at the years like
we're going to now
and use it to build our confidence in
the fact that these seasonal tendencies
do in fact hold up over a long period of
time
now again we're looking at about nine
years or so
worth of
seasonal tendency price study in the new
zealand dollar futures contract
now this is not to say that you're going
to see the exact same type of move
dollar for dollar you know pip for pip
in the foreign exchange market but by
far and large they're going to be moved
moving in the same direction generally
so i have that as a a point of
reference when we go over this because
i'm not trying to force
a
perfect pip to point ratio
of uh movement in both the futures and
the foreign exchange market there's
going to be a slight dis difference
between the two but by far and large
you're going to see that they generally
move in the same direction
so if we're going to look at this with a
sober mind and understand that yes there
are opportunities to be a seller in kiwi
there's high probability conditions
certain times of the year where it it
positions itself for an opportunity to
sell off with a great deal of
tendency to do so
seasonally and historically
but we're going to focus on how we can
use these bearish ideas to get us in
sync with a long-term
bullish quarterly shift now you're
probably saying wait a minute michael
you're coloring outside the lines we're
supposed to be talking about bearish
seasonal tendencies yes
teaching is really how to use bearish
seasonal tendencies not just myopically
and only focus on just being a short
seller we got to be able to understand
that that short selling opportunity may
be leading us to a quarterly move on
these higher time frame charts so a
decline while could be traded we have to
be mindful that there's certain times of
the year when the kiwi has a predisposed
nature to go higher
so let's take a look at a few examples
in here
there's obviously this one i like is uh
mid february to mid march
really significant uh time point where
you can see there's a really nice
movement between the red and the blue
line that means the 19 year seasonal
tendency in the 15 year seasonal
tendency and again i'm going to remind
you
that it's taking 19 years worth of price
action year after year what did these
months deliver in terms of price and you
can see here the
mid february to mid-march time period
both
the red and the blue lines and again
i'll remind you here that the
19-year is the blue and the 15-year is
the red
and what it is is a compiling of 19
years worth of data
showing the historical movement of the
march delivery contract
and the june contract the september
contract and the december contract
and by showing a historical record and
compiling the data the overall price
direction generally is
from mid february down to mid-march
there's a strong tendency for the kiwi
dollar to decline
and you can see it very clearly in both
the contrasting 19 years worth of data
and 15 years worth of data
so if it was the shift in and out
between the two
then it's most likely probably not a
good time to be a buyer or seller but
when they both move in the same
direction
and it's a sizable price swing as we can
see here in the shaded area
it's in my opinion
that it's a pretty good chance that
we'll see a decline there
the second one
to be noteworthy of is that notice that
if we drop down into mid-march and in
april
the market tends to have a significant
rally at that time
and it rallies up to about may and both
the
19 and 15-year seasonal tendency
compilation
shows that it does in fact make a high
in may and then it sells off again
giving us another bare seasonal tendency
and then we have an area where we have
consolidation
between
around the june
month going into july but it makes
another seasonal low around june and
july and it balances bullishly and then
it sells off again around mid august
down into october but look what happens
in september and october it generally
makes a significant point of uh
bullishness
and puts the a large degree of buying
in your scope as far as a trader you
look at buying the kiwi around that
september october time period now
when we use seasonal tendencies
the the way we want to use them are
limited only to what the current market
conditions are
we do not go into
our charts forcing the seasonal tenancy
for instance we're not forcing the idea
that kiwi has to make a high or top in
may
therefore we're going to sell in may and
just hold on to it forever and then wait
for it to be june july and just collect
our money that's not what we're saying
here
what i want you to focus on is that if
this seasonal tendency is in fact true
and i believe it shows validity here
the idea is is there something
technically in price that would support
that seasonal tendency are we in a
bearish market did we rally up into a
bearish order block did we run an old
high did we see a market structure break
have we in fact been moving up for the
last two or three months and then are we
likely to you know sell off because of
an uber ball premium market and then
maybe we would anticipate seeing some
breakdown in the marketplace and then we
can take a short or position ourselves
for a bearish move lower
so it's a matter of lining up what the
current market conditions are it's not
just take this thing apply it to the
marketplace and you're going to get rich
it's taking these ideas when there are
strong tendencies for the market to move
one side or the other any particular
time of the year
as you as you can see across this chart
there's several other opportunities you
can use you don't have to be a long-term
position trader which is what i'm
focusing on here using the bearish moves
okay that's seen in mid-february to
mid-march
and then you have another move in may
that takes you down into june july so
there's other opportunities you can use
you can see that there's a typical
sell-off in
the first week or so of january that
goes down into february
there's another sell-off that takes
place
around mid-june down into the first or
second week of july
both lines blue and red are in agreement
with that
and then you see another sell-off that
takes place around mid-august down into
the september-october time period making
in the low
but there is a small short-term little
move that drops off mid september down
into october that's the one that
generally sets up a really strong buying
opportunity so we're going to be a
quarterly shift trader if we are going
to trade these seasonal tendencies
and we are short around that time period
just be mindful that around september
october generally makes a very strong
tendency for the kiwi to rally
but now let's go back and have a
contrasting view as well since we're
focusing on various seasonal tendencies
and we're using them in a higher
timeframe analysis we can take all of
these bearish ideas and trade them
respectively or we can go in the
marketplace and say okay i'm going to
anticipate these bare seasonal
tendencies not trade them i'm going to
anticipate them
showing me the the signs that the market
is in fact dropping down into
the quarterly bullish scenarios that i
could be a buyer so we can use bearish
seasonal tendencies to trade with or we
can use them as guides to lead us to the
next trading opportunity that would be a
quarterly shift
this teaching is going to show you both
okay we're going to go from 2007 all the
way up to 2016.
but if you're going to be a bullish
trader on kiwi and we're going to be
looking for bullish quarterly shifts
they occur in march to april time period
that's generally making a low
okay make a note of this because when we
go through each year
i want you to keep these reference
points in mind we are focusing on
sell-offs between mid-february to
mid-march and we're focusing on
sell-offs around may going into june in
july
but primarily we're looking at
how these moves could set up bullish
conditions
for quarterly shifts and the first one
we're watching is it sets up a move
between march and april for a quarterly
low
the next one is june july low
that you could expect a seasonal low
to form for that quarter
to be a buyer and then the other one is
september to october
giving us a strong tendency to be a
buyer okay so now think about this for a
minute
i just outlined the general
road map on what kiwi dollar does on a
12 month cycle
now if that didn't floor you
you're not paying attention now you
probably didn't get it and you didn't
you didn't register if you're a new
trader it's probably going right over
your head
but think about what we've just did
we've outlined the macro view
on what kiwi dollar does generally over
a course of 12 months
there's seasonal tendencies that shift
in and out of the marketplace
and depending on what the market
conditions are for that particular time
or that year
one seasonal tendency is going to be
favored over the other if we're in a
bullish market obviously the march april
june july and september october time
periods are going to be phenomenal
buying opportunities
if we're in a bearish market that means
mid february to mid march is going to be
amazing sell-off
and may is going to be an amazing
sell-off and you have august can create
a nice sell-off as well leading down to
the fall lows
there's also another long in here that i
don't have an arrow to highlight but
it's that last week of november going
into
the first week of december that's a nice
little buying opportunity as well
so in your notes as we go through these
slides okay you can obviously go after
you watch the video and go back and look
at it as well but as we go through each
year just be mindful that march april
june july september october are really
strong buying opportunities
when it's bullish
when it's non-bullish we can focus
primarily on being a seller look for
selling scenarios around the february to
march time period
and may into june for sell-offs and in
august into september giving us
weak points to sell on
so let's go into our first year and
start breaking this down give us some
real examples to see if it really does
appear in the charts
okay you can see here this is 2007
and what i'm showing is december from
the previous year 2006 all the way up to
the january first of the following year
so we're getting the entire year shown
in every slide that we show this is
2007's price chart
and here we have
mid february into march that weakness
that we expect to see a bearish scenario
okay and also notice also
that we have a small little decline here
as well in may
both seasonal tendencies while in
contrast to the larger moves
so there's several hundred pips on these
declines here
but now notice also these sell-offs that
we expected bearishness in the
marketplace
they set up what opportunities
remember we have that march april time
period for bullish scenarios or
expected bullish scenarios for
tendencies to go higher
june july
and september october
do you not see those occurring here we
have the march
april time period
creating the very low and look at the
move up from there
at several hundred pips
then we have the may june
decline but june starts off that rally
that sends us all the way up to the 81
big figure huge move
then we have another opportunity where
the market dips down
and trades off into
the september
time period where we see that september
october seasonal tendency to rally
so while we're focusing on the bears
seasonal tendencies
the other seasonal tendencies that we've
went through is beginning this teaching
we were looking at the actual seasonal
tendency chart
all of the seasonal tendencies are going
to have some measure of influence
now
again keeping in mind what the current
market conditions are at that particular
year
it's going to be helpful for you in that
regards because again we're not trying
to form fit just a seasonal tendency in
price we're looking for clues to justify
why that scenario would be
more inclined to unfold than the other
in other words is it better to be a
buyer on the bullish seasonal tendency
or better to be a seller on the bare
seasonal tenancy and years sometimes
we'll work in concert with another where
the bearish
move will lead into the bullish move the
bullish move lead into the bearish move
that's perfect market symmetry and it
rarely exists but sometimes in my
23 plus years doing it i've seen it a
few times where it's been astonishing
but as we go to our next year in kiwi
here's 2008
for the kiwi
and obviously everybody remembers what
happened in 2008
the market uh
imploded we had the financial meltdown
and we have mid-march
i'm sorry mid-february to mid-march uh
creating the actual high
in the kiwi
and then we had the uh the may
creating another high here where we sold
off as well
and notice because we are all completely
all bearish on all foreign currencies
the kiwi was no exception here just kept
on following the rest of the year so you
have to also keep that in mind too
there's going to be larger
big picture macro events that are going
to take precedence over whatever
short-term quarterly effect that you may
be expecting even if it's a seasonal
tendency that holds up for a long period
of time you're going to have these wild
card scenarios where you know just it
isn't going to pan out regardless of
what you would expect
there's 2009
and we can see the sell-off between
mid-february going into march uh that
decline in there was
600 pips
and we see also
during the may
period we did not get any decline at all
on the bear side
but in contrast
keeping in mind how we're using these
bear seasonal tendencies the one that
dropped down in february into march
leads us into the march april bullish
scenario
and it was a very strong buying
opportunity there and then we had the
month of june july we had a
consolidation and july sent us higher
going into the late fall
october highs
september and october had just a
continuation
2010 you can see here for the kiwi
we had basically a flat market in mid
february to march nothing bullish
nothing bearish
but we had our may decline
and look how many pips this thing moved
this thing moves about 700 pips as a
decline
in the month of may
but again
that may
decline set up the june july
bullish seasonal tendency that took off
and sent price higher
and we also see
there was a scenario for the bearish
august to october time period
august we had a little decline
which had a small seasonal tendency to
be bearish if you go back and look at
the slide
and all i did was retrace back down into
a bearish candle which is a bullet
shorter block and uptrend and it rallied
off that 70 big figure moving all the
way up to 79.50 sets 950 points or pips
that it moved
off of just retracing into an area at
which institutional overflow would give
us bullishness
and then we had the
september october time period give us
that last little leg price higher from
that 74
to the 79.50 level so 550 pips there as
well using the seasonal tendencies as a
roadmap
okay we can see 2011 here
see we are declined mid february going
to mid march we had a nice decline there
but that leads us to what the bullish
march april seasonal tenancy nails it
look at the rally off of that huge
extrapolated move from that time period
and then we have a small little decline
from
our may time period where we expect
bearishness
and that's
about 350 pips just been made on a
decline but finds us trading back down
into the
january
highs
so old resistance turns support there
the market creates that
retracement down in may just to set up
another leg higher june july gives us a
nice seasonal low
off of a previous down
candle which is a bullish order block
around that
80 big figure and then it rallies all
the way up to 8 800 so 800 pips using
the seasonal tendency
where we saw a decline in may
and it rallied away and created a longer
term price move
very significant price moves higher and
in september october gave us a swing
from the 7500
to the 8200 so there's 700 pips there
okay 2012.
you see we had our decline mid february
to mid-march
several hundred pips declined about uh
400 or so
on the downside and then in may we had a
very significant sell-off
and price moved
almost
800 pips
on the downside in the month of may
and that gives us that june low
seasonally
where we saw bullishness expected and
that thing took off from june lows from
7 500
all the way up to 8 450.
so that's a massive move
okay we see our decline here in
mid-february to mid-march
several hundred pips as well
and then a
another decline in may
which leads us to
our bullish june july low
and it rallies away from that
and in 2014
we don't get anything bearish at all
between february march mark was in
consolidation and it rallied out of the
consolidation so it's not expected to be
a bearish area there we're looking for
continuation on the upside because it's
left area consolidation
and in may we have a little bit of a
retracement that leads to a june rally
creating the high up at the 88 big
figure
then we had a
sell-off in mid-august which was the
other bearish opportunity taking it down
into october again look at your seasonal
tendency
about the first or second week of august
all the way down into october and you
can see that seasonal tendency takes
uh effect in this market here
okay on 2015
you can see we had a little bit of a
move down here
in mid february to mid march and again
these are weekly charts
so be mindful that we're not looking at
uh your five-minute charts here
and then we have our decline in may
seasonally speaking
and june july just kept on being weak
which led us into
the next bullish scenario which is the
quarterly shift that would be bullish
that occurs in september october and
that gives us a really nice rally from
the 60 to 50 level
up to the 6850 level almost 69. so very
very handsome rally from that price
point there
and then finally for 2016
unchanged consolidation nothing
happening in mid february to mid-march
we have our decline in may
it comes down into
previous bullish order blocks and
rallies away created another higher high
up into 74.50 so it moved from the may
decline
into the week before june
rallying away from the 67 big figure all
the way up to
almost 7 500
big figures so rather significant price
moves as a closing note i want you to
think about how these ideas
lead to
a roadmap idea of where price should go
generally speaking
and when to focus in on very significant
price moves when they when do they
usually occur
see it's one thing to say okay i can see
when an indicator bearishly diverges and
it should give us a sell signal or it
should some you know suggest some
consolidation in a strong uptrend we can
understand that but it doesn't really
tell us when the divergence should occur
and seasonal tendencies tell us a
specific time element that escapes most
people that don't use them most traders
don't even have any understanding these
things exist
now because you've been exposed to them
with a great deal
more detail
much more than we saw when i was
teaching in the free tutorial area we
can see how we blend these two ideas
time and price with quarterly shifts
and when the seasonal tendencies come
into the picture as well
there's a strong tendency for the market
to react when a few things come into
confluence
if we have a seasonal tendency to
suggest bullish prices
when the market's already predisposed to
go higher because it's in a bullish
market
and
it's in a time of the day
when the market should be bullish
and it's also at a time when the market
is indicating that interest rates are
supporting that bullish idea it's also
supported in the dollar index
when all these things come together they
dovetail into a beautiful tapestry where
you're going to see a profitable outcome
in your analysis now as long as you
stick to those types of trades
you're going to do very very well
you don't need a whole lot of trades
throughout the year and notice that
there's not a whole lot of overlapping
going on between what we've shown so far
certain currency pairs have certain
seasonal tendencies
now by far and large
they're all going to bend the knee to
the dollar index
and we're going to have a 4.3 teaching
with seasonal tendencies where i'm going
to show you the seasonal tendency of the
dollar index
and we'll actually apply that to other
studies as well but for now i want you
to be
encouraged right now i don't want you to
get so excited you feel like you won the
lottery okay but
these seasonal tendencies are very very
powerful and when you use them in the
right context they lead to an analysis
perspective that again most aren't going
to be able to attain
everyone looks at just price action
alone but if you look at what price has
done historically and dare i say it
hindsight it's a gold mine of
information because it leads to and
understanding what should take place
and it shows that there's
yes there is manipulation in the
marketplace but by far and large
these markets move by a certain script
and they repeat themselves over and over
and over again and if something comes in
the marketplace to upset what would be
otherwise a
bearish time of the year but yet it
posts something bullish for instance
look what we're seeing here
mid february to mid march
we're not seeing bearishness there we're
seeing consolidation and the market
rallies away and it falls in may but it
only falls down to the mid consolidation
point or around that 67 big figure
then it creates another rally higher
if you remember all through 2016 i i was
telling everyone that the new zealand
dollar was going higher it was strong
relatively spanking just like the aussie
dollar was
those two currencies were the ones that
held up the most during 2016
when all the other pairs variously moved
lower against the strength of the dollar
also notice that we had that sell-off as
a short-term
uh
bearish idea in january it actually
materializes here as well so think about
if you're a day trader if you're a
short-term trader
okay you can use those ideas to get you
in sync with long-term position trades
on these higher time frame
seasonal tendencies
you're gonna be able to blend all these
things by the time you're done with this
mentorship you'll be able to go in and
dissect any marks call any market you'll
be able to dissect any asset class and
know right away if there's an
opportunity if there isn't an
opportunity move to the sidelines
and by having a seasonal tendency in
your toolbox it'll give you when you
should be looking for something that's
really loaded in your favor to move
because seasonally and historically
these times of the year in this
particular currency there are times when
it makes significant price moves and if
we can focus on trading on those time
frames and those setups alone we are
really basically framing high
probability setups
you're not going to get perfect winners
but you're going to have high
probability conditions where even if
you use this as a directional bias tool
it'll help you in all facets of your
trading no matter what discipline you
use
swing trade short term day trade or
scalp
until next lesson i wish good luck and
good trading
you