good morning folks
the enemy is trying
he's trying to keep you from learning today
almost choked to death before I got on here today
and then the audio was acting up
so give me one second here
it looks like it's a little too aggressive
in one second please
this should be a little bit better
and it is a good morning
despite being a little tardy or reasons outside
my reasons and circumstances outside my control
yeah I was trying to rush down some bone
broth before I got in there and I went
down the wrong hole and then the audio
acted up a little bit so I'm checking
Twitter right now if you all would help
me out if you can hear me if the volume
is good everything is five by five
awesome yeah it looks like the title
I have
I think I put the title on
for Friday
sorry apologize today is Thursday you're
not
you're not time traveling with me just
yet maybe after November this year and
you'll be able to do some time travel
all right so
I got a little bit of a
wild hair up my ass yesterday or
whenever it was a sent a tweet out
saying let's do a workshop
so I usually go on these long-winded
Twitter spaces and I promise we're gonna
be doing a lot of teaching today okay so
if you're here to learn I promise you
you will learn a lot today you'll learn
about FVG you'll learn about
PD you'll learn about
time of day
bias
daily bias
session bias
stops where should you look for stops so
you don't need a book map or any kind of
gimmick out there that requires you to
subscribe to something
I'm placing Insight in your hands so
that way you don't have to have any kind
of service whatsoever all you need is
the Open high loan close how to work
within the time frames I'm going to work
from the HTFs down to the
LTFs I'm going to teach you
how to back test today we're going to be
here for a while okay I'm not going to
be able to
promise you
a rant won't come in and out throughout
this session so I've allowed of 8
o'clock to 11. it might go longer I
don't know but everything will be
recorded
so if you can't stay here for the
duration if you're at work and you're
sneaking in here to listen in
shame on you you're stealing from your
boss I'm not trying to encourage that I
told you to call out
So today we're going to cover a lot of
stuff I'm going to cover 4X I'm going to
cover index futures
I'm going to cover a lot of things that
would otherwise be
kind of like the first day
when in the in the mid 90s I did
one-on-one teachings and every time I
would have a schedule or an appointment
with someone I would tell them
what would happen
the previous week
so that way when we would meet on our
first session together I would have
everything already in the charts that
already told them the week prior
so everything that I do and have taught
for years has always been on the premise
of me telling you before it happens
explaining what it's going to do
then we wait for price to do it and then
I can go in and teach more Amplified
approaches to what it is already taught
you conceptually on this YouTube video
or YouTube series Channel whatever you
want to call it in my mentorship all
those lectures and lessons
if you are
looking for that real quick watch give
me something to start studying if you're
new you don't know where to begin I kind
of want to place this in the beginning
so give me like like 10 minutes of your
time and if you are
seasoned and you've been around me for a
while the next 10 minutes is not
necessary so if you want to go grab
something to drink go to the bathroom
real quick use that time here this part
is for the very very brand new you've
never been here you've never watched any
of my stuff or you've watched a couple
videos and you just feel like this is
too much information where do I begin
I want to kind of like put this in here
because it's also
a video
that I'm gonna
refer to in my first book
so there's a lot of things that I'm
going to be placing in this channel
throughout the duration of 2023 that
will help amplify the things I'm going
to teach in the book because obviously
books and charts that are static they're
not as Dynamic and as good as a teaching
tool whereas you'll hear and see me
doing here and you also knew on the 13th
of this week
what I said was going to happen in the
PA and it happened so that way
it's not like I'm cherry picking like
you hear people like to say I tell you
exactly what's going to happen and then
we go in and you see how the setups form
so I'm telling you with experience when
you watch my live streams or if you're
watching on Twitter or if I say
something in a Twitter space that leads
to my opinion about where I think price
is going to go
your
task as a student here is to borrow that
experience from me okay it's not meant
to be a signal service a lot of you want
Johnny on the spot give it to me right
now so I can copy you that that part I
don't want to do
but I tell you what it's going to do
beforehand I do it on HTF
charts so it allows you enough time to
study it okay
so where would you begin if you're brand
new and you're a little lost in all this
information go to the 2022 mentorship
playlist there's 41 videos in there you
could probably ignore the first video
you know if if you're really in a rush
but don't skip anything a lot of people
like this to watch the first few and
they think they understand it you don't
so and you're gonna you're gonna see
that you don't know that because I'm
going to talk about a lot of things with
the 2022 model in today's discussion I'm
going to talk about Silver-Bullets
those setups as well there's a lot of
things here I got like two pages of
stuff we're going to cover
and my whole day is open it depends on
how
how much energy I got okay so I
rested well
but you can go right into finding setups
and
being convinced that there's enough
information in that 2022 playlist
on this YouTube channel to help you go
in start looking at things and watching
real right now go out there and start
looking for setups the practice
observing not trading okay don't think
you can watch it real quick and and try
to trade with real money okay it's
important that you understand you have
to slow down your impulsiveness to want
to make money I know it's an exciting
seeing the things I'm sharing and my
students sharing and all these people
that are claiming that they found
success with my stuff and that's
wonderful I'm honored I'm such a
in a position of privilege
to be considered your mentor and having
so many people around the world being
profitable now
but it's not a rush to get to that point
every single one of my failed students
and I have them I don't have just
winners I don't have just success
stories like anything in life there's
going to be folks that just simply can't
do it or can't do it yet and eventually
they get there
how much effort and time you put into
this is going to decide how fast
not that that should be a factor
but how long is it going to take you to
find your setup
what is your setup how do you determine
what that is because I teach a lot of
ways to get into a market we're going to
teach that today too
so
this meeting today this come together
come to Jesus meeting with the ICT
content is really focused on
where you should be
in your pursuit of learning
what you should be focusing on
and how to determine your path through
all this content because I teach a lot
of things a lot of ways to trade
different time frames to trade different
setups different entry mechanisms
different ways to take profits where to
take partials how to take partials we're
going to cover all that stuff today I'm
cramming everything in here
there's like a nuts and bolt kitchen
sink approach to ICT so that way you can
go through today's presentation and
determine where your area of study would
be best served for your personal
interest so that way you'll hit the
ground running or it'll highlight where
you're lacking
in your personal study right now you may
be hit and miss where you make some
profits in your demo account and then
you lose it and you go back down to
break even but you just don't blow out
the account that's a wonderful position
to be in you may not feel like that is
but it's a wonderful position to be in
because
if you're in there impulsively just
pushing the button you're probably
blowing your account you have no idea no
model no no frame of reference to to
anticipate anything happening in price
and we're going to remove that today so
that way at least you give yourself a
framework to go forward and study and
then you can start measuring progress
which is really important because if you
just simply watch my videos and this is
the part you need to listen to carefully
if you simply watch my videos or wait
for my next video to come out and you're
just a viewer
and you don't go into your own charts
looking for this information not China
demo real time
going back and look at old price moves
and we're going to do that today I'm
going to show you exactly what you're
supposed to be doing it's not hard
it's a little bit tedious in the
beginning because it feels like it's
counterproductive you're looking at
something that's already happened but
everything technical everything worth
doing is always based on studying
something as a case study that's
happened in the past how else can you
determine
you know a foundations or something you
have to have a a good foundation in
observing repeating phenomenon at
specific times of the day
with repeating characteristics that's
what I teach
so those Hallmark signatures and PA
that's that's the whole basis of what I
do as a mentor I'm teaching you how to
observe and find that I don't and I
can't promise you profitability that's
something that you're going to determine
based on how much time and effort and
organization you bring into this
last point and then we get into it
if you are lazy you will fail here
if you have an entitlement mindset where I owe you something
I have to do everything for you
or I can't learn this unless it's one-on-one
or it has to be done live
I'm not going to be a good help for you
I will call moves
I will outline things watch my live streams
I call every smallest time frame Candlestick one at a time
where it's going to go
how it's going to behave
there is no better performance measurement than that
if there is no way of doing that real time then
there's no need for you to ask for
statements and give me a live trade and
trade live in front of me because I've
already I've already done that that's in
my live streams and I have a live
account with TD Ameritrade you can
actually see statements where I logged
in showed every single day
win loss exercise of drawdown came out
of drawdown just to teach students
there's nothing to be afraid of there's
no fear of losing you should respect
risk
you will lose trades everybody that
trades
every single method every single teacher
educator
um
everybody if you're going to put risk in
the marketplace invariably you're going
to incur a loss and you have to accept
the fact that's going to happen
how you handle yourself
how you handle your perception about
your ability to work through that
and stick to the model that you have
trusted that it doesn't have to be
perfect 100 strike rate is not possible
it's not realistic for you okay
but you don't need a high rate of return
or success rate in terms of Trades to be
profitable
and I'm not promising you get rich I'm
not promising you Millions but the
things that I teach in money management
and all those things factored together
can you become wealthy absolutely
can you quit your job absolutely can you
have a secondary incoming still keep
your job and just treat this as a
another side hustle sure
it's completely scalable to you
do you want to win competitions yes you
can do that too
so it's a matter of what you're doing
and why are you trying to trade and if
you're here to try to be the next social
media Superstar
that's probably not the best way of
doing it because you're going to be
impulsive everything you're doing is
trying to get ahead of somebody else
when it should be just about making sure
you don't lose money
and that you're working towards learning
how to be consistently profitable
and consistently profitable doesn't
equate to Everyday Trading
day trading is not everyday Trading
I promise you if you try to do it every
single day especially in the first two
years or so
you're going to have a whole lot more
losses than is necessary
which is the reason why I teach with a
lot of lectures and in the dry parts of
my discussions they're the parts that
you're going to come back to after you
tried to do this you made a little bit
of money or you found some success in it
you're hooked now
you want to keep doing it and have more
of that experience and then you have a
losing trade then you want to hurt let
me race it and fix it I gotta close the
day with fixing that loss and you make
it bigger and then you start that
routine of
chasing break even on the day and all
that does generally makes it a larger drawdown
so you want to avoid those those periods
and be content with okay you did
something wrong it doesn't mean
everything's broken but you can derail
yourself in your learning or if you're
trying to trade with live funds before
you're supposed to
you won't do well and it makes it harder
so when I teach
I give you 30 years of experience the
things that I'm talking about I went
through it I lost lots of money lots of
accounts I did it to myself nobody else
was the blame I did every single time
called I caused all that and you have to
be responsible with your own actions as
well
so if you make money using what I teach
you well done
I'm not responsible for that
if you lose money
well
you did that own it so I I'm giving you
my experience I'm proving that I can
tell you what's going to happen in the
marketplace with a great deal of
precision and you can learn that
precision
you can grow into having a very clean
understanding about price
what to anticipate and more importantly
when not to try to trade that is an
important lesson
and not too many people are over aware
really that that's an important factor
in trading
and that sometimes is the boring
conversations but I promise you once you
go in the drawdown
you're going to want to listen to those
parts in the videos again
and then you're going to wish that you
listened and follow follow the advice I
gave you
I want you to do well
I really really want to see you succeed
more so than you do
but there's got to be rules that you
have to follow and you have to give
yourself time to grow into it okay so
with that mindset and that
I guess goal in mind let's begin
after this presentation today over the
weekend you know you know I don't know
how much time you have to devote to this
today or the or the next couple days but
I did a live stream
on the 13th of June
and I talked about
some of the things we'll talk about in
the first hour of the presentation here
I'll do one hour
and then I'll break for like five ten
minutes I'll leave the recording going
so that way if you have to tend to
something relieve yourself or whatever
I'm going to want to stretch out as well
and then I'll come back so we'll do that
like every hour of like a 10 10 5 10
minute break but the recording will
still keep going
for those that are really helpful in
their own recording and documentation
where I talk about certain things and I
have very
studious students that like to do this
if you would help me create a little
timeline for if I transition from one
topic to the next or if I go from one
market to the next if you want to send
me those minute markers on Twitter that
would be wonderful and I'll use those in
the comment section of the the video so
that way it helps people go right to
those moments I am not going to go
through this and do that myself but I
know I have a lot of students that do
that for their own purposes in my other
videos so
just let you know I'll appreciate that
help but
on the 13th I covered
my opinion about what I thought was
going to happen this week and when I was
doing one-on-one mentorships back in the
mid 90s
folks would
learn about me by me advertising
and I was it was a high-end
advertisement so it was people that
had a lot of money
and wanted to come to me and learn how
to do something with that money on their
own and had either already been in the
marketplace or was looking to do
something to get into it
so one of the greater selling points I
had was I would tell them much like I
did on the 13th of June 2023 it's on my
YouTube it was live streamed it wasn't a
pre-recorded thing everybody blocked me
out on it and
we talked about the CPI number and I
walked you through CPI real time
and I walked you through a 15 second
Candlestick chart so every single
Candlestick represented a fluctuation of
the highest high and the lowest low and
open and close of every 15 second
increment
now you don't see that in books you
don't you don't see anybody teaching
with that type of time frame but
everything that I teach
is fractal because it's the same price
whether you're looking at it from a
weekly chart monthly chart three quarter
I'm sorry three month chart a yearly
chart it doesn't matter
price is price what I'm going to teach
you today is a secret of breaking down
price and looking for that price
delivery continuum
so how to go in like if you ever watch
me do a presentation where I'm recording
my trades
if the comment sections are open or if I
share it on Twitter
most of the time you'll see a handful of
folks come in and say why did you pick
that time frame and why didn't you trade
this time frame why didn't you trade
that time frame I'm going to answer that
for you today and that way you'll know
what time frame you're going to be
looking at okay
some of the lessons today
won't be so impactful for you because of
where you are in your learning if you're
brand new a lot of this stuff is going
to go right over your head
if you stick with this and you study it
I promise three months from now if you
come back to this presentation
and you watch it you're going to swear
that I added something new but it's just
because your focus is on things that
aren't important to you at the time that
I believe I believe are more Paramount
and the most important thing is is
understand where price is going to go
so the selling point I gave to my
students that would come with me
one-on-one they would spend a whole
entire week with me Monday through
Friday
and we would be at the charts live when
the market opened up
I would show them bonds in s p
that's it it's all we'll talk about
and I would give them the previous week
I would say okay here's what it's going
to do
this is where it's going to go to and
we'll cover it next week
think about that
and treat it like what I gave you on the
13th of this week in a live stream I
talked about very specific points of
reference
in price for the dollar
euro dollar pound dollar gold
NASDAQ and Es
and DOW futures
so I'm going to go through those
individually
and kind of like it'll be somewhat of a
review but I'm going to teach also the
main takeaways and what you're supposed
to do with this information because it's
not like I saw
it's unfortunate I get new people all
the time on Twitter
and because they don't know me they
don't know my personality don't know how
to teach when I show examples
and we'll cover the reasons why I took
the NASDAQ trade in detail also for
those that are asking from yesterday's
Trading
post FOMC I'm going to teach you how to
trade CPI today I'm going to teach you
how to trade FOMC I'm going to teach you
how to trade NFP Friday
um it's MythBusters ICT Edition today
too we're removing all the talking
points that people like to use that
attract you from trying to study with me
I I teach you to avoid trying to trade
ahead of CPI I teach you try to try to
teach you to stay away from trying to
trade ahead of FOMC and a head of
non-prone payroll I have done many
examples of me Trading Post FOMC Post
CPI post
NFP I've I've done years of
that my students that were with me every
single day in private mentorship for
years
saw me explain where I think it was
going to go and watch it happen
so it's not that I'm trying to prevent
you or teach you that no one can make
money on those days it's because I'm
assuming when you're watching you aren't
a new I'm sorry you're you're a new
Trader that you're
experience is very small
you don't know what you're doing so I'm
trying to protect you from yourself
because I was my worst enemy and you're
you're worth anything right now you
don't realize it
but you are so if you listen to me
I'm talk I'm trying my best to try to
give you everything
in the perfect proper order
how you're going to develop because I've
done this for a long time and I already
know what the questions you're going to
ask me
but many of the questions you're going
to ask are that's coming up
in normal development is already in the
videos it's on my YouTube video channel
it's it's it's it's layered across lots
of time because this can't be learned
real quick
because you're going to discover what
you think you're going into this to try
to do because a lot of you think you
want to trade the Silver-Bullet
a lot of you came in think you're going
to trade OTE but you
discovered the 2022 model
and that that makes sense to you so
right now your initial expectations
you're probably going to lose that maybe
in this discussion today
and you may develop a better focus on
what it is that you want to do and
that's that's a success for me and you
if that if you arrive at Ted today
that's a success that's a good use of
your time today but I promise you if you
take good notes not just simply watch me
take good notes and here's what I want
you to do
while you're listening to me today
don't try to write down every single
point
that I'm trying to cover when I'm
talking about FOMC and how to trade that
or trading CPI
or if I'm talking about Silver-Bullets
FVG or whatever that topic
is
write that topic or Focus point and
where I am in the minute marker or hour
marker on the playback all you gotta do
is hover over top of the
the little time thing at the bottom of
this video and it'll tell you where you
are when I'm talking about it and it
makes it easier for you to go back in
and dig into that that's good
note-taking because then you can go back
and go in and get the real nitty-gritty
to it and I'm going to talk a lot about
it in detail so it's important you do
that otherwise watching it alone is not
going to be enough and I know get to the
point get I hear you
all right so let's go over to the dollar
Index all right and this is a weekly
chart
and
I shared all this business on
the 13th
I added this a little area in here
this is a FVG
and I
have to be careful when I'm talking
because I noticed in the 13th live
stream
when I was referring to certain things
my cursor wasn't really where I wanted
to be when I was making points I'm
trying to make a conscious
um
note of making sure I have my cursor
where I want to talk about it so where I
have my cursor near that candle is high
and the specific close is what I'm
looking at
for that range
to that candle's low
okay
the candle to the left of this one this
one here that body of that candle
that is encapsulated between the range
of this
this candle is low here
that makes the high of the fair value
yeah
this candle's high or closed and I just
dropped it there it's so close it
doesn't make a difference
that candle's High
and or closing point
represents the low of the fair value go
the Shaded area is highlighting this
particular candle's body not the entire
body of the candle just the reins that's
being shaded here okay
between those two reference points
that is considered by my definition if I
call it a FVG its
classification is a BS imbalanced
cell side inefficiency meaning that the
delivery of price was on the upside
so
think about a paint roller okay and I've
used this analogy before if you want to
paint a wall in your home and you'll you
apply the paint to the roller and you
apply that roller to the wall okay
you're getting that delivery
up
if you keep doing that
from the bottom of the wall to the top
eventually paint will run out
and you'll see these little pockets
these little little pits on the wall
where paint didn't make its way to the
wall
so you already know what do you have to
do you got to roll back down over top of
that to fill in those little pockets and
gaps where paint was not distributed
think about price the same way
between these two reference points that
being this candle's High
and this candle is low
that one candle right here
in that shaded area that's purple
there's going to be small inefficiencies
in that range that's shaded in purple
the easiest way to to simplify it is
we don't need to know yet where those small little pockets are on the LTF
because this is a weekly candlestick
so inside that range that range I'm
highlighting here with my cursor
somewhere along the line in that very
weak
of data there are gaps inefficiencies
we don't need to know exactly where they
are but we can identify that range right
here as soon as this
as soon as that candle closes
and we begin a new week
that Gap that's shaded in purple
we know that there's a likelihood that
the market will want to at some future
time
want to reprice to that
that is not balanced
all it means is that shaded area that's
purple
it's BS imbalance so the Market's
shown an imbalance meaning it wants to
go up it did go up so what is it
inefficient
is inefficient in the sense that it
hasn't had a SS delivery sell
side is when price is being offered
downward a down down close candle my
down closed candles are are black my up
close candles or bullish candles are
green
for that purple shaded area here
for that to be repriced to
and offset
the inefficiency of SS because
it's by side imbalance it's imbalanced
it has to be balanced later on and I'll
tell you how it becomes balanced but
right now it what is it lacking
it's lacking SS delivery that
means a candle must trade down
in between the high and low of that
purple range
and it's defined by the two candles I
mentioned here
this candle's High
that candle's low
so in our mind and my mind as an analyst
I'm looking at this and thinking
okay well we've seen a lot of back and
forth PA all through here
let me add a rectangle here
highlight because I knew I may or may
not have
my cursor exactly where I want it
as I'm talking because the live stream
okay so inside that darker shaded pink area
inside that rectangle notice how there
was a lot of back and forth up and down PD
you see how it's created like a small
little trading range in there
where is there a break
in all that back and forth movement it's
in that shaded purple area here
so up and down back and forth think
about that pain analogy all inside this
pink area
if price was paint in the canvas that is
the background of my chart is the wall
in that shaded area price has done a
very good job of moving back and forth
inside that pink shaded area but it
didn't do a very good job of efficiently
offering
SS delivery in that little area
right there
so what the algorithm does it seeks
those areas there because it's easily
defined by arrays old highs and lows
that are separated across the spectrum
of
three 24-hour periods
any separation between
this time frame or any other time frame
I'm going to teach you the price
delivery Continuum today so you can see
from one time frame down to the smaller
time frame how did you pick that fair
value Gap and not this sphere Vega
you're going to know all that today okay
but you won't retain it unless you're
paying attention and probably watch this
video a few times
so we know that there is a strong
tendency
for the market to want to come back and
re-price into these areas
now let's take us into what I was
mentioning on the 13th
for those that you want to go back and
revisit you've already watched the 13th
video I think it's a little less than
two hours long for the people that want
to get right to the point I'm going to
help you here okay you should watch the
entire video
and some wonderful information but for
those that want to just simply go right
to the points for the dollar Index on
the June 13 2023
PA lecture in market review
I was teaching on CPI
the
minute marker four minutes
you'll hear me talk about a price level
of 102.705
I want you to think about what I just
covered here on the weekly chart okay
I'm going to keep this just as it is
here
and drop down to a daily chart
so when I'm looking at price
I have all of this HTF
weekly perspective in mind
so if I were asked which time frame do I
spend the most time on? it's the weekly chart
now why do I spend the most time on the weekly chart?
number one as I taught my students one-on-one in the mid 90s
and the way I teach my students in mentorship
and the way I've taught and shared in those mentorship lectures on my YouTube
don't buy people pirating my stuff and trying to sell it to you
it's been made available to you on this YouTube channel for free
go and study it at your leisure go your
own pace there's no rush
I'm not taking the videos down in November
they're staying up
that premise of how I go into the
marketplace and what I'm looking for on
the weekend usually either on a late
Friday evening once my whole family goes
to bed and they've turned down for the
night
I don't sleep like a normal person so I
do a lot of study really really late
night or early in the morning before
they wake up
or if I don't get that I do it on a
Saturday
I look at the weekly chart
in reference to a monthly chart a three
month chart a yearly chart and I'm
looking at it the same way I'm doing
here okay and I'm trying not to steal
too much Thunder from future lessons but
just know that what I'm doing here I've
done that with a monthly chart I do it
with a three month chart
and on trading view it's really nice
because if you go in you type 1 m
takes you into a monthly charges like
that
and right away you can see things that
you may not have noticed before
so you have a one month chart here and
right away
my long-term students can see right away
they're thinking wow that thing used the
volume imbalance right there the
separation between this body's clothes
and this body's open
that monthly candle went right up into
it there
and then went lower all month
so I'm looking at those types of
relationships
and you can look at
3M
it'll give you three months of data
you can see how we're drawing down into
this by side of balance outside
efficiency which is the same thing I
just highlighted in purple
on the weekly chart
that's this here it's the same thing
so in my mind
I like to look for those first
and if there is no inefficiency
then I'm looking for liquidity
so in summary let me rephrase everything
I just said
when I sit down on the weekends whatever
time I'm going to be doing my analysis
the market is not Trading
all of my analysis
is done when the market is not Trading
what I'm trying to
predict
to anticipate not react to
what I'm trying to predict and or
anticipate is where is the present
weekly candle reaching for
higher or lower prices
if I see an inefficiency
like this
right here that purple shaded area
I'm expecting price to try to draw down
into that
if this inefficiency wasn't there
I would look for that low because that's
where SS would reside
or consequent encouragement which is the
midpoint of this candle's tail
so it'll be this let me make sure I have
my cursor sitting here for a second
before I started saying anything more I
would either look for that midpoint of
that candles tail which is consequent
encroachment or I would use the low of
that Wick
there if folks listen if there was no
inefficiency that's shaped in purple
if that wasn't there
I would be expecting price to draw down
now why would I expect that
what makes me say that because we
already hit our targets that I covered
in the previous weeks
for those that weren't here I was
talking about how dollar was going to go
higher that we were going to use this
shaded area here as an inversion fair
that you got and treat it as something
bullish they're trade up into the weekly
order block which is this opening price
of this candle here this candle's
opening price that's the weekly bear
shorter block
it was acting as a Target then I said
the mean threshold of that candle which
is the middle point of its body in here
that's the
bare shorter block mean threshold that
was also a Target
so once it hit that we want to see
what's going to happen once the target's
met
whether for the week or a day
you have to get comfortable grow real
comfortable with just simply sitting
still
and waiting move very very slowly when you're trying to make money
and I learned this lesson from Larry Williams
it didn't make any sense when I first
learned it or heard him say it and it
took dozens of times of blowing out
accounts
not listening to advice
move slow when you're trying to make money
move fast when you're trying to preserve it or protect it
if you watch something paying out that
you have done analysis on and you've
been successful with it
don't be in a rush to get another
dopamine hit because that feels good
that's a neophyte that's a brand new
Traders trap you see many times
individuals that are open about what
they've done wrong
and they use social media like a
confessional father I've sinned look
what I did and I blew my account okay
you don't need to do that don't do that
once you see something pan out
meditate on that let there be a period
of time between where you've seen
something pan out you were successful
and then
really record how that felt for you
because in
the future you're going to have periods
where you do something wrong
and it may be a week long of that a
series of doing things incorrectly and
if you don't journal the times that
you've done it right not just when
you've done it wrong but when you do it
right
and you encourage yourself you remind
yourself that you follow the rules the
market panned out like you were hoping
it would and you anticipated that you're
conditioning your subconscious
to hold on to that as a positive
experience
but when you're journaling you're not
recording your negative results in a
manner that is
condemning you don't use language or
terms like oh I was stupid or this stuff
is never going to work for me never ever
ever in your Journal ever
record anything negative you can still
highlight the fact that you did
something incorrect but how you describe
it how you encapsulate that in your
Journal your subconscious is going to
remember that because if you write down
that you were an idiot in that trade I
should have did this I knew better but I
did this or that
you're actually creating scar tissue
and there's no elasticity there's no
elasticity in Scar Tissue you you can't
grow without a whole lot of tearing and
pain
so to remove that growth of Scar Tissue
on your subconscious and the psyche
that's required to to do this as an
industry
you have to make sure that you're
conscious of what you're doing and
you're guarding your mind
social media
is a a very big factor in why people are
not successful
so you think social media is going to
encourage you
and it might initially but what you'll
find is it's very toxic
and you don't want to bring that
toxicity into your Journal because if
you put it in your journal what you're
doing is you're making a ledger
of every single time that you have an
engagement with your expectations your
model and price
and what price does ultimately is
outside your control but how you
perceive what you are expecting and how
you record that that is Paramount
in how you will walk forward
by recording your negative experiences
in a light that is devoid of any kind of
judgment no kind of condemnation new
kind of ridicule or criticism that is
Harsh
what you want to do is record in your
Journal if you've done something wrong
say
I'm happy that I can see that this is
where I can improve on this is my area
of study that I need to work on versus I
got stopped out here and I didn't listen
to what the Mark was telling me and I
kept trading against it and I you know
went into serious drawdown or I would
have blew my account there
all that stuff
that you're putting in your Journal
their memories but they're happening in
a level that's way deeper than just
short-term memory
you're
you're charging it
with emotion and energy that you will
tap into subconsciously
the effect happens when you like when
you're a child and you saw a scary movie
do you think every time the lights go
off that event that what scared you in
the movie
you think that's what's under your bed
it's in your closet okay
your conditioning is called priming so
when you're journaling you're priming
yourself for future success
it's brainwashing yourself it's really
what it is you are tricking your brain
to only see the Silver Lining which is
critical it's critical because it's easy
to talk yourself out of this because
it's highly technical and nobody's going
to cheerlead you nobody's going to
coddle you you have to be able to find
your own cheerleader inside you to keep
yourself going because in the beginning
stages of this stuff it's very very
challenging because you don't know where
you're going to go as a Trader and we're
going to cover more about where you
should go and how to determine that for
yourself but you take all this
information
from a HTF I do this and I
look at where price is likely to go
it's only going to go up for one of two
reasons okay PD
PD continuum
is the movement from where price is
right now
to Future delivery so where it's going
to be five minutes from now a week from
now two days from now two sessions from
now
it's going up
to take out buy stops
or it's going up the trade into some
kind of inefficiency like a fair value
guy
that is it
that's the only two reasons why price
goes up period it's not buying pressure
I'm sorry but that's the truth it does
not go up because of buying pressure it
doesn't matter
how many people buy it
perfect excuses if you look at price and
study volume
okay 30 volume how many contracts does
it take
for a limit up move
in wheat
not that you probably trade weed you
only need one contract rated
it opens up at the limit up move boom
who can trade there nobody it's locked
limit
what was the what was the volume
whatever that trade was that marked it
that wasn't buying pressure
that wasn't buying pressure it was only
one transaction it opened it up here
boom
nobody else can buy it
that's not buying pressure right so
that's that was the biggest wake-up call
to me when I was a commodity Trader in a
million years that's how I started by
the way
um
I realize that volume is important yes
it does have a a place in analysis but
too much emphasis is placed on that as a
reason why price goes up or down and
it's not
price goes up to seek liquidity and if
it's going up what liquidity is that buy
side liquidity buy stops okay
if it doesn't run for liquidity on that
particular time frame it's going up for
an inefficiency that means a gap
a gap would be like that purple shaded
area here
or this
I don't know what that color would be
called we'll call it the a pale orange
that gap between this candle is low
that candles low over here
and this candle is high
that's what's being shown here in that
little pale orange shaded area that's
noted as the weekly inversion pair that
you got that Gap
and this purple one here they are called
inefficiencies think about the pain
analogy I gave you when price is moving
back and forth in a defined range
what's the Divine range here where your
eye looks at Price just like I have it
shaded here in pink
price has moved
rather efficiently
inside that pink area up and down
okay when price entered the low end of
this pink shaded area now we don't know
that pink shaded area is the range yet
what I'm saying is when I'm looking at
Price I'm looking at how price was
delivered during a period of time
in whatever time frame I'm looking at so
this is applicable to whatever time
frame you're looking at whether it be a
weekly chart a daily chart four hour
chart six hour chart 15 minute chart
second chart it doesn't matter okay it
does not matter
what matters is
where are the inefficiencies and where
are the stops
above old highs
is BS or by stops below old lows
is sell stocks or SS liquidity
those are the two things I'm looking for
after my eye goes through the chart and
I'm looking for the inefficiency so the
first thing I'm looking for is
inefficiencies
that's the first thing I'm looking for
because that's the that's the array that
the algorithm reaches for first
it pans for
any inefficiency
if there if there's no inefficiency
and we're in a premium and we're likely
to go lower
then it's going to be looking for sell
sign
reverse that if we are in a range and
we're in a discount
and there is no inefficiency above price
but there's a short-term High
it's going to run for the BS
thank you
that's what I'm doing on the weekly
chart
so for the folks that are hammering
themselves and beating themselves up
please teach bias I just did
I just did but what you're wrestling
with is you don't have time looking at
charts like I'm showing you here you see
this pink shaded area how the market
entered it went up to this candle's High
the next week we opened up here then we
traded higher up to this point here
then the next candle or next week we
open we trade down and overlap all the
way and into the previous high so
there's no FVG formation
whatsoever in the candle I'm
highlighting right now notice that the
candle to the left of it's high and the
candle to the right of its low there is
no separation like you see in that
purple shaded range
that's a FVG there is no fair
value gap between the candle I'm
highlighting here with my cursor
using the candle to the left and the
candle to the right
so what is actually happening there the
price has gone up and down up and down
that's like that wall being painted very
efficiently is there any inefficiency
there no
so at that time when we start on this
week we open
we rally up make the high and then we
close after making a low here so there's
been a lot of delivery up and down
in between the Range High
of this week
and the close of this candle here now
why am I picking that close it's because
I'm showing you how prices reacted in
here and why I was telling you on the
13th in a live stream that can't be
Cherry Picked it was told to everybody
watching it that I want to see dollar
reach lower
okay and we haven't even got off the
weekly chart yet
I'm teaching what I'm looking at and
this is what I'm trying to tell you I
spend the majority of my time on the
weekly chart I'm looking at how price
delivered
think about what I'm showing you here
and how that relates to this area right
over here
think about that right in here
that same idea
we can apply it to over here
I promise you I'm taking you somewhere
even though if you think you don't know
what you're understanding and
confusion is probably peaking right now
just keep staying with it I promise
it'll make sense as I'm going
same thing here price opens up trades
higher back and forth delivery all up to
the high back and forth and then we
leave it
so before this broke down
is there any efficiency over here
below this pink shade there is there any
inefficiency inefficiency would be like
this
this candle here
how has that separation between the
candles High to the left of it and the
candles low to the right of it does that
occur or form anywhere underneath this
pain shaded area in all this
do you see that
yes
right here
I'm just going to use a short little
trend line
promise you folks
this is the stuff you're looking for
even though you may not
feel like it's important right now or it
doesn't make any sense
take you light years ahead
moves to everybody else out there today
so there's a gap there
so I would take
like this rectangle here I would
highlight this but I'm only showing it
as a small little section with the
rectangle not being here but just simply
using the trend line sections
so we have an inefficiency here so when
the market leaves this range it's in a
premium
relative to the low and where it traded
to it's in this range consolidate and
then it leaves it
where's it going to go well there's
several things you can use the
consequent encroachment of this Wick
midpoint of that
then you have the gap
here that this traded down into but left
the majority of the Gap still untouched
right
so
when it drops here price is going to
want to trade into this area here
does it do so yes
and again that would be bias that would
be bias for that particular week for the
dollar what do you think that would mean
for you Forex traders that want to trade
pound dollar what would you anticipate
that week this week I'm highlighting
right here how would you use that
information
you would go into your charts and back
test any long positions during the
London open between two o'clock and five
o'clock in the morning New York local
time you would look at your am session
Kill Zone
the New York Killzone between seven
o'clock in the morning and nine o'clock
in New York local time
you would look for the model of 20202
you would look for optimal trade entries
you could look for Silver-Bullets
because Silver-Bullets form in the kill
zones between seven o'clock and nine
o'clock what'd I say yep we're teaching
that again today too it's not limited to
just index Futures and 10 o'clock to 11
or 2 o'clock to three o'clock in the
afternoon for index Futures if you're a
Forex Trader everything that I teach is
applicable
even though you see me predominantly
teaching it in e-mini s p and Futures
contracts
it's applicable to Forex
you just
there's subtle little rules that you
have to worry about in time is the the
the factor that's got to be considered
because yes there are Silver-Bullets
between 10 o'clock and one o'clock in
Forex yes
but they are really
good ones between the seven o'clock and
nine o'clock in New York Brooklyn
Killzone in between
three o'clock and five o'clock long open
Killzone
they're there every day every single day
you have a reason for you to find a
setup now
again that is not an invitation for you
to go in and try to trade every single
day Okay so
I want you to think about how the market
moves in these ranges
this is a balanced price range
why is that a balanced price range
because the market has moved up and down
within it and then it left the range
so it's going to leave the range what is
the algorithm that's
make an argument for a sake of folks
that don't want to believe there's an
algorithm that controls price and
there's no amount of buying and selling
pressure that's going to change that
Market's going to go where the Market's
going to go it's predetermined your
daily high and low is predetermined
whether you like it or not it is what it
is okay
how can we determine where that likely
higher low is going to form or where
would it likely reach to
start on these HTFs and
charts
and if we know that we can see prices
likely to want to expand lower think
about because we're on what chart what
time frame up here
weekly so my analysis everything I'm
doing on the weekend when the markets
are not Trading
I'm trying to determine what's the
strongest directional bias
that can be derived by looking at the
weekly chart what is it likely to be
reaching for on a weekly Candlestick
chart
it's going to either be reaching up
for buy stops or it's going to be
reaching up for a FVG above
where the market is right now
if it's
likely to go lower
then I believe it's going down to a fair
value Gap below current market price
or it's going to go down to reach for
SS liquidity below some old low
that is not complicated folks
these things on your chart they're not
hiding from you they've been in plain
sight you just never been told to look
at it this way because you're trying to
apply indicators and all these things
and frankly you know
when you look at like this you should be
able to see it really quick you're
seeing when I'm looking at the chart
like this my eye jumps real quick to
inefficiencies my eye jumps to that
my eye jump to that
that
I'm probably moving faster in the
live stream can keep up
and then obviously the Gap that I just
showed
in every High
every weekly Candlestick high and low
is a factor as well
they're going to be used again
they don't just get used one time and
they expire
Okay so
I teach
there's a 60-day look back
and the highest form of
precision
or highest form of accuracy in terms of
my key levels
I Define it with within that 60-day
range and it's 60 Market Days not 60
calendar days obviously but it's looking
back 60 days so what I'm looking for is
the highest high and the lowest low in
the last 60 days I'm looking for
inefficiencies in the last 60 days
whether it be premium or discount that
means a FVG like that per one
here was before we traded down here
in the beginning of the week the dollar
Index was up here
and on the 13th I explained it I felt
like we would draw them I'm teaching the
part that was not made available to you
on the 13th live stream okay so I'm I'm
filling in that gap of insight that
wasn't made available in that
presentation but this is the logic that
went behind it
so let me take this off and we'll drop
down finally into a daily chart
okay so here's the daily chart
and let me take all this business off
because
they're all distractions
and I want you to focus only on the
things
I'm making a
point about
all right so this inversion fair value
Gap was an old Gap notice that it does
not look like a gap on the daily chart
where it did look like it on a weekly
let me just for completeness sake drop
back up to a
weekly chart
that separation from this candle is low
and that candle is high the candle to
the left of that it's only SS
delivery
it's a SS imbalance
BS inefficiency sibi s-i-b-i
it's a FVG but the
classification is a city meaning that
some future time the market is going to
trade up and deliver price on the upside
so it's offering BS delivery
we see that happen here on this candle
but I said that we would treat that as a
inversion FVG go back and
look at all the presentations and
commentary around at the time
but then on the 13th of this week June
13 2023 I said that we would
look for this
old Gap
okay this is What Separates Me from
folks like Chris Laurie where they look
at inefficiency and then he'll tell you
it's done that's his terms it's done
it's not meant to be disrespectful but
when I tell people you can learn how to
read PA with Chris Laura if
you don't like me that's that's fine but
you won't learn what I'm teaching from
Chris Laurie that you can learn how to
see inefficiency in the price I didn't
learn inefficiency from from Chris
Laurie okay I was trading before Chris
Laurie but
long story short this whole business of
inefficiencies
we can use them as real Dynamic support
and resistance because that's in fact
really how the algorithm refers back to
them
meaning this
when I look at this range this shaded
area it doesn't look like a fair value
gap on the daily chart
whereas that is a FVG you see
that right there look look where I have
my cursor at right here on this candle
here go up
that candle I'm laying my cursor on top
of to the left of it that candle is low
here and the next camel to the right of
this one
that came as high that is a fair Vega it
is a civi so it's not a balanced by
sound efficiency notice that that is not
what you see inside of the Shaded area
here that was the weekly inversion for
your radica
so the PD Continuum is when
you have these HTF
inefficiencies
regardless of whatever time frame it is
when you drop down to a LTF
you cannot ignore or forget
the impact that those HTF
inefficiencies will have on the lower
time frame
the LTFs you can use for
precision like refining risk and and
making it much smaller so larger
positions can be assumed that's not to
say that you should take on larger risk
but this is safer the sake of argument
that you want to use a one percent risk
model that means whatever your Equity is
in your account
times that by one percent whatever that
amount is you can look at a range
from where you think you're going to get
in at the entry point and where you want
to Define your stop loss
and whatever that amount is you divide
that by the one percent equity
that you define as your maximum risk you
want to incur
having that the math will tell you how
many contracts or lots that you can
trade and still be within that one
percent
using LTF charts helps you
define that risk rather small I mean you
watched me to do it this week where I
was using less than one handle on index
features
you cannot do that consistently in Forex
promise you I promise you you cannot do
that consistently in Forex
the reason why is because Forex Brokers
many times you're trading inside their
specific pool of liquidity
and they have the benefit of being able
to open the spread on you when you're
trading index Futures you're seeing the
same price everybody sees
everybody's high is the same everybody's
low is the same
that's why it's a gentleman's Market
in reference to the ladies that's not as
snub against you it's just a more
refined professional Market
it doesn't mean that you can't trade
Forex and use small stop losses but
don't don't fall into the traffic you
got to do these Ultra less than two pip
two pit one pip stop losses because I'm
telling you
if I ran a brokerage firm and I was a
Forex brokerage firm I would open the
spread all the time on all of you
and I'm I'm teaching you so wouldn't
they want to do it to you
of course they're going to do it to you
especially if you're if you're trying to
trade size and you get frustrated and
when everybody was trading Forex you
know in the early 2000s
um there was bucket shops all the time
and I got burned by several of them and
fxcm was one of them okay and it's just
they did it they they did things that
were not good and
it's better now obviously but I don't
ever talk about workers so I know some
of you are hoping that I'm going to talk
about Book Broker would you recommend I
don't do that I'm not an introducing
broker it's for you to determine that
okay so I'm not in an affiliation with
anybody no brokerage firm new funding
accounts nothing and that's the reason
why I'm Point Blank and sometimes not
always the best person to talk about
your company because if I don't like it
I'm going to tell you but I'm not going
to sugarcoat something and say here
I have an affiliation with this company
I like them no
whatever I tell you is the truth if it's
good I'll tell you if it's bad it's it
is but I'm not trying to tell you to go
with any broker they all suck and
they're all great it depends on what
your personal experience is so there you
go there's my opinion
but these inefficiencies these gaps from
the HTF you have to have
them annotated
on your chart now in the future you'll
probably graduate to a point where I
haven't just on a piece of paper like I
have a pad
I have a small little yellow pad that I
work with all the time
and whatever Market I'm following I have
those levels noted what levels am I
talking about the highest high and the
lowest low in the midpoint of every
inefficiency on a HTF for
that particular market so we're looking
at the dollar Index
so it obviously is taking me more time
to tell you what you're doing with this
chart and what you're supposed to focus
on and what you're supposed to utilize
but once you understand it's like riding
a bike you'll go through the motions and
it won't take this long to go through it
but the majority of the time your
analysis will be done on the higher time
frame weekly chart you'll be doing these
things looking at where is it likely to
gravitate to now
rewind back to the 13th of June 2023
earlier in the week in the live stream I
talked about how
I felt that this shaded area here the
weekly inversion for everybody got would
then now act as an inversion fair value
gap for the downside in other words it
would act as resistance we would want to
see signatures in price
showing a willingness to put a dollar
Index to go up to it
treat it like a ceiling
reject it and send it lower
now
I am not a support resistance Trader I
know I supply and demand Trader okay
even though that that shaded area May
quickly look like if you're someone
that's traded with the same side and
Online Trading Academy and all that
stuff I get accused of using Supply
demand all the time it's not that okay I
use very very specific levels
and they would never consider that Gap
back their nuclear chart ever again and
they wouldn't considered anyway really
but this is what I refer to that shaded
area that pale orange range I'm looking
at the highest point of it
the midpoint
and the low
there's three specific levels there I'm
not in is I am big U.S it's not like
here's a tree it's a supply Zone okay
that's wonderful
what are you going to trade at what
level are you looking at
so
from a
I don't know I guess a grade school
perspective supply and demand may help
someone you maybe you have been
profitable with it but it doesn't give
you a very specific level to trade on
you have to determine where you're going
to trade at so it's like here in this
general area let's try to find something
that's a buyer sell
what I'm telling you is the algorithm
itself will refer to one of those three
price levels
which price level do I use which one is
it hidden at the time of the day did I
tell you to look at it
that's where time comes in so when I'm
teaching you I'm teaching how the
algorithm Works how it delivers price it
operates on time delivery that means
everything every price run is scheduled
sorry I know you probably worked in an
industry for a long time and you're
probably cussing and laughing saying
this guy's full of I don't see you
out here telling everybody where it's
going to go before it's going to go
there to the infinite degree of
precision that I'm showing
so I'm I'm proving you I can't take you
I can't take you somewhere on a field
trip and say Here's Where the algorithm
is ran from I can't take you to a place
and say here is where it's operating
from okay
the only thing I can do is tell you the
truth it is there
it's running it's delivering price all
the time it's completely manipulated
it's absolutely controlled always and
you shouldn't be fearful that you
shouldn't be upset about that you should
be thankful that that is an advantage
because once you understand how it
operates you can exploit that
they're not going to change it because
the way that price is offered and how
markets are traded isn't going to change
that's never going to change so there's
no reason for you to worry about oh this
is a fad it's gonna it's gonna stop
working because everybody likes to use
ICT Concepts
folks this is the market the markets are
until they do away with the markets
entirely this is going to continue to
work so put that aside don't be don't be
afraid of that stuff you're wasting time
worrying about things that aren't even a
factor
so the 13th of June I said that I want
to look for and anticipate rather the
Market's going to go up into that shaded
area that's the weekly inversion
Fairbank I've been treat that as a form
of resistance and then
gravitate down to
I said this very candle right there that
down closed candle I told you it was a
bullish order block
it's a change in a state of delivery
that's what an order block is it's not
every down closed candle or every
up-close candle
it's not the things you see people
talking about on YouTube either
many of the things that people are
saying about my order block they're
trying to use supply and demand logic
and it's flawed
that that's that's not that's not the
same thing okay it's not
I promise you it's not
what's occurring here is at that candles
open okay that candles opening price
was the only
marker
where price can be measured in this time
frame where price was offered down
where was the next down closed candle
right there
so between those two down closed candles
if we're looking for a cell model to
begin which is what I was outlining on
the 13th of June
where could we expect that to form
the FVG that I shaded and I
told you on the 13th it's an old weekly
imbalance so if we leave and in Balance
what was I teaching you on the weekly
chart the market can be efficiently
traded back and forth up and down think
about that pain analogy when you paint
your wall are you going to paint up the
wall and when the paint runs out of a
supply of paint on that roller you're
just going to leave the areas where the
paint didn't make it you're just going
to go to somewhere else on the other
part of the wall no you're going to roll
right back over top of it why because
you want your wall to be efficiently
painted right well when I look at Price
I'm looking at where price has been
where it went to recently and was is
there any pockets of inefficiency in
there and because I start my analysis on
the weekly chart why am I starting on
the weekly chart because the whole
weekly range is going to be
predicated by what we anticipate on that
Weekly Candlestick what's it going to do
is it going to go higher or is it going
to go lower and you only need to
determine one of two things is going to
go up for buy stops above an old High
or it's going to go up to it in
efficiency which is a FVG
above market price
if it's going to go lower it's reaching
for some inefficiency which is a fair
value Gap below price which is
what was being shown here on the weekly
chart that I did not talk about on the
13th but I told you this candle is the
order block I felt it was going to reach
down to
and I highlighted that range right there
and I mentioned there was
a likelihood that we would draw down
into that after we treat this shaded
area up here
as resistance
so we can take this idea
and dig into the LTFs
and see if there is any
signatures that we can look at a lower
time frame we'll look at an hourly chart
now
oh right away look at that
so if you look at what we've done here's
the 13th okay so the Mark wasn't me
moving around in here I said I want to
see price show willingness to treat this
this Gap here let me go up one more time
because I want to make sure you're
following along in this little area
right here
okay I'm gonna just draw one more
rectangle because that way you can see
is our frame of reference
this high
down to present Market
right there okay
that shaded area here is this Camp
underneath my cursor that day which is
the 12th from the 12th and then the 13th
is when I gave you the analysis okay I
told you it's the live stream it was not
a pre-recorded video I told you I want
to see it treat that Weekly inversion
fair value you got which is this one
here which is anchored on a weekly
Candlestick chart right now we're
looking at a daily chart you can track
that by looking up here so the 1D is a
daily
so in this range here
in my mind I was seeing this delivery of
price this is what I'm anticipating this
is what I'm predicting I'm not reacting
to price
okay I see this forming and I'm
articulating that
in the live stream of June 13th 2023
so because I have this range now shaded
when we drop down to the 60 Minute chart
inside this area here
and I'm going to scrub that little
rectangle over
to the 13th and that would be the
perspective
okay so what we're looking for is in
this area here
did
true or false folks okay
you're you're judging me now I put out
my expectation
I anticipated in this time here before
we closed the week I said later in the
week going into Thursday and Friday I
believe and I say this in the 13th live
stream for the dollar Index I believe
that we will likely draw down into this
order block which is that level right
there 102.705
right there so I'm going to take this
box off here so now we can see that this
is where we're looking at
did it use
whether you believe there's an algorithm
or not okay
did price use this shaded area as it
means to dig into go up into
and then repel it lower
I mean I think there's sufficient
evidence to suggest that what I was
outlining and anticipating price is
doing that is it not
it did it here
what time of day is that
look at the bottom chart
that's Wednesday June 14th 2 A.M what
time of day is that in terms of ICT kill
zones
that is the London open Kill Zone
that's two o'clock in the morning to
five o'clock in the morning New York
local time every single time you look at
your time references it's always in New
York local time I don't care where you
live there's no disrespect to you or
where you're at
but the algorithm runs on New York time
the day the trading day is not defined
by Wellington New Zealand okay I don't
know where this idea came from but it's
it's straight up New York local time
that's the way it is okay so everything
runs on that and if you keep your time
relative to New York and when you're
trading view set up here you can see
it's always set to New York
if you do that you'll know when to
anticipate when to anticipate when do
these moves form when do they begin
where do the highs and the lows of the
sessions begin and end
within those time winners I've given you
now
by itself just knowing that the higher
low of of a market in Forex forms
in the London session between two
o'clock and five o'clock in the morning
that in itself is a huge advantage
because if you can have a weekly bias
determining that okay
you know if we suspect that the dollar
Index is going to be bearish for the
week to come
and forget the economic counter for a
moment because we're going to get into
that too
if we think that the price is likely to
draw down into these levels here
now I'm going to take that purple shade
Berry off because that's the
weekly Fair Aid Gap that I did not
mention but I didn't need to because I
took your attention right to that level
there which is the daily bush
over block
a daily bullish order block doesn't
always mean it's an entry to go long
it's
it's a draw on liquidity okay it's a re
it's a PD array that the market will
want to reach into obviously you can see
that that order block did in fact cause
a nice little run up we're going to go
up into
look closely where to go into that same
shaded area that old weekly fair value
got the inversion for your bank account
the mentioning of it being used as what
resistance so in here we're talking
about it it's likely to go up we're
going to see it treated as resistance
does it yes
does it go down to the level I talked
about on the 13th as a draw on liquidity
or Target yes then what does it do it
repels price higher again
and goes into what
look at these three up close candles
right in here
see all that
listen close
ICT why do you use the last candle on
some
examples and other times you use the
consecutive candles well
all of these are inside of this fair
value Gap that shaded area which is an
old weekly fair value
if they're consecutive like this and
they're inside that range I'm going to
use the entirety of all that because the
beginning of this
opening on this candle here in the next
candle the next candle that's all one
PD for BS it's
delivering BS delivery so that
means there's movement up
so I want to refer back to that opening
price right there because that starts
the order block and the mean threshold
would be the middle
of the low of this candle to the high of
that one and that would look like this
so we have the low of this candle up to
the high
mean threshold is
103.324 okay so we allow listen folks we
allow for price to trade to and through
but not close listen not close
above mean threshold
so the Wicks due to damage the bodies
tell you the story
look what's going on over here
see all that we'll get to that in a
second opening price
let me drop this here
it hits differently when you know I've
already talked about beforehand huh
oh man I can't use a cherry picking
analogy on it now
so here's mean threshold so that's what
I'm identifying here but this level
that opening price
there
that is the change in the state of
delivery
meaning on the 13th of June I stated
that I want to see you want to study
if I have any validity Behind these
things if it's not going to hold up if
it doesn't react the way I'm talking
about in the future then there is no
algorithm that means that I'm a fraud
that means that there's none of none of
these things should be even studied
because it's all
hindsight okay so what I do is I tell
you in the analysis where I think price
is going to gravitate to and then you as
the student you go back through price
action and you look for what PD array
you like
what does that mean
what's what's that mean
what do you use for your setup what's
your multiplier is it the optimal trade
entry is that what you is that what you
use to get into a trade do you use a
FVG now do you use the 2022
model as your as your trade do you use
Breakers
it depends on what you feel comfortable
trading there is no listen there is no
better PD array than another one
because not every single price run will
have every single one of my PD arrays in
it not every single price move
that I'm trading has a breaker in it not
every single one of the trades I'm
entering is using a FVG not
all of them are an older order block
entry not all of them well when's it
when's the last time you see me talk
about optimal trade injury but you
probably still trade them right
I'm teaching you a wide spectrum of
opportunities for you as the trader to
gravitate to whichever one makes the
most sense to you all of them are
equally profitable
all of them are equally capable of
blowing your account if you misuse them
so I'm a I'm a realist
I have 81 ways to get into a Marketplace
you don't need but just one
you just need one and whatever that one
is you stick with it until you get
really really good with it and once you
find consistency with it if you want to
graduate into something else and Dabble
into you know trying to build another
model in addition to the one you find
consistency and profitability in you
know have at it but don't try to apply
all of them that's what everybody does
wrong when they come to my content they
try to apply everything to every single
Market condition and that's not what I'm
teaching you to do
now if you go to Tom Dick and Harry
Styles menu mentorship where they take
my stuff Rebrand it and try to condense
it down into a five minute trainer video
you know that's that's the perspective
you're going to get you're going to get
like you know watered-down approach to
what it is I'm teaching and you're not
going to come to the real understanding
of what it is that's available to you
these consecutive up close candles is
one
order block
meaning that inside this shaded area
right before this Market changed and
went lower my eye goes right to that
opening price because I'm using all
three of these candlesticks because it's
inside of a range I've already told you
on the 13th we want to treat that range
as a inversion fair value in other words
it's an area where the algorithm will go
up
spend some time in there allowing smart
Money traders that will see what I'm
teaching you that isn't in books
they're using this frame of reference
because they want to sell short here and
buy at a lower price down where the
order block is here
an order block is not orders
you can't see an order block the way I'm
telling you you can't see that on level
two there's people that say oh you know
level it's not level two it has nothing
to do with the orders has nothing to do
with it
nothing okay so stop the
it's where the market changes its data
delivery meaning that inside this shaded
area we want to see the price go up into
does it do it yes and then once this
candles opening price that is the
beginning of these three consecutive
candles and I'm using all three because
it's inside the area I told you to
Define as a reason to anticipate price
going lower from the beginning right
on the 13th of June I said we want to
see signatures that means
evidence in PD in price
action itself does price show a
willingness to treat this shaded area as
resistance
does it want to send price lower when it
enters into it where
the low midpoint consequent encroachment
and the high we don't
listen we don't want to see the high end
of a old FVG if it's being
treated as an inversion FVG
the better setups form if the high if
you're looking at it as a resistance or
using it as a beginning point or
Inception of a SS delivery or
cell program
we don't want to see the high traded to
treat that like the same thing I treat a
breakaway gap which is a FVG
that won't completely fill in
if it gives you that signature which is
what we're seeing here as soon as price
breaks below the opening price here and
leaves the Shaded area that's in like a
pale Orange
once it does that that qualifies that
right there as a bearish order block
why because the state of delivery
changes from BS delivery
then it crosses over the opening price
there just because it crossed below an
opening price of a series of up close
candles doesn't make it an order block
The Narrative behind where that order
block resides
that is the imperative point that
everybody is missing
that's why everybody has books and
out there they want to call
mentorships and courses talking about is
an order block you have no I you're
making up
you're making it up as you go you're on
the Fly you're looking at something in
hindsight trying to explain something
in this shaded area this is what I I
told you to look at it on the 13th and
then we look for signatures inside that
range
what does that mean well you have an
order block here
you also have a breaker
what mm-hmm there's a breaker there
high low higher high
consecutive down closed candles same
thing we're applying here all these
ranges here Push It Forward in time
you're getting the same entry here
stop above here
we're not trading the dollar Index but
I'm trying to tell you that
you can pick your own model and every
one of you can be trading differently
using what I've taught and you're all
can find profitability you don't need
the same entries the entries are the
least important thing
I'm going to say it again
where you enter is the least important
factor in consistency it is the least
important thing
you have to know this
where is it going
because if you can determine
where it's likely to go to what is what
I've outlined here in this beginning of
this presentation today
you can find a myriad of entry points
when price returned back up into
this low here right there you can be
short
what would you anticipate
this rejection block which is the lowest
down close
that's your first draw
below it SS
and then you can start doing projections
on all this price around here lower to
see if it wants to dig in lower
it's Friday it's already hit the mark
here
did I out outline the card before on the
13th of June
you can use this as an entry going short
well look at this look it did Michael it
ran up here yeah I know but you're
trading with a higher time premise
meaning you're entering here where's the
model call for for stop loss it's got to
be above that high
if you're using the last up close candle
the same thing you don't get short here
but you can be short here the stops got
to be above here
we're not using the dollar Index as a
tradable vehicle
I'm just teaching the logic that you're
applying to whatever Market you're
Trading
whether you're trading the breaker which
would have been a fill here or here
price alone
price alone those as that's the
instances where price returned to the PD
array now here is where you separate the
men from the boys and the lions from the
Sheep
time
just because price went up to that level
right there
at two o'clock in the afternoon are you
factoring a great deal of emphasis on a
late afternoon dollar
no
you want to focus on the relationships
of what the dollars doing during key
kill zones
dollar is going to be highly sensitive
to Forex
s p NASDAQ Dao it will use the longer
term higher time draw of risk on risk
off with a dollar but sometimes
sometimes this is where it makes a
little bit difficult for some of you
the index can Flex against that
that you don't see that with Euro and
cable
unless dollars being manipulated held in
consolidation which it's not being here
it's being allowed to move
gyrate move around that means that your
Forex pairs can be free to move around
and have a lot more volatility as well
so if there's a emphasis on dollar usage
in your analysis just know that there is
a much more
impactful
driver of price when you're using dollar
when it comes to currencies
longer term
yes dollar risk on risk off will
eventually weigh on
stocks but stocks are also highly
manipulated right now they shouldn't
even be at these levels
none of these companies should be
trading at these into these multiples
it's ridiculous but we have to stick
with what the Market's showing us if we
were trying to make money we're not
trying to be predicting the crash okay I
mean in my opinion the market should
have crashed dozens of times in the last
three years it should have
but it hasn't and even though I know and
everybody with the common sense knows
that these markets in in stock rather
they they're not justified at the levels
they're trading in
but are we going to sit around and arm
wrestle which should be taking place
from a practical sense versus what can
we take as an opportunity
because we have to trade with the
Market's giving us as opportunity and
that's what I'm teaching you to do focus
on what is available based on time
now we have the market run up into
during Wednesday at two o'clock what's
going on there
on Wednesday we had another Market event
that day big calendar event medium
impact high impact news drivers
we can anticipate on that Weekly chart
where the
the Inception of the majority of
manipulation will begin based on the
calendar so when we look at an economic
calendar we're looking at
a medium medium impact or a high impact
news driver something that's going to be
many times used as a smoke screen I'm
not of the opinion I've never really had
this opinion anyway but I'm not of the
opinion that because it's a high impact
news event
that the Market's moving based on that
information
that is sometimes
in a way you could study this is go back
through history and look at the the
releases of the data I'm not a
fundamental Trader okay I don't I don't
consider the information that's being
released at the time I never even refer
to it I never look at what the numbers
were I've done it in the past when I was
teaching mentorship just to prove to
them that sometimes the the data will
come out and from a classical
perspective the data may be perceived as
good or bad
and if it's suggested in historical
terms that whatever data that came out
if it's
beneficiary or a positive for that
currency or that market but then how
many times has the market rejected that
and traded down and then they come back
after the fact say well the market
already priced that in you weren't
telling us that they already factored in
that and priced it in it's just an
excuse because these things are being
used as a smoke screen so I just use a
high impact or a medium impact news
driver on economic calendar it's a Time
just like a TV Guide you know when time
the the game is going to come on right
you go on there and you look on your TV
and say okay the the Knicks are
playing today at this time or tonight at
that time you know the Super Bowl begins
at this time on this channel the markets
are delivering price the same way
I know it sounds crazy I know but that's
how I'm accurate I'm following the
schedule of when price is likely to move
and you can time when these Market moves
are going to occur to something looking
at the economic calendar and blending in
the key times of the day I've told you
to focus on
all New York local time
so
two o'clock on Wednesday
where are we at here on Thursday what
time of day is this
London open
typically forms what what did I teach if
you've been with me for a long time
between two o'clock and five o'clock in
the morning New York local time London
generally
70 of the time and for the folks that
like to do these little number crunches
I have people in the past say well
that's I went through the
number you're looking at every single
week you have to look at when the bias
is suggested that we're going to
entering a a sell-off okay if we're in a
position and I've told you on the 13th
this week
I said that dollar is going to go here
we went there
now your question is you're like well
how would you know that it wouldn't just
reverse here and treat that as a
long-term little shorter block I know I
just read your mind right
you just drop your potato chips thing
longer term perspective
we've already spent time reaching into
premiums on that Weekly chart for the
dollar we met multiple premium arrays as
Targets on the upside
and
we've worked all of any inefficiencies
out
and now we've worked into the discount
arrays so it's reasonable to anticipate
that the dollar wants to go lower we
still have time it's Friday
and everybody that sees this low here
that went long
they're trying to catch the bottom
and that's why you're seeing what we're
seeing here
we traded down into this low deeper into
the order block
what order block let's go back out to
the Daily for a second
this entire down close candle here
that range is the order block if we're a
bearish we want to see it trade
initially into the open of it because
that's this change in the state of
delivery and then we want to see it try
to reach for the mean threshold how we
know if it's going to continue going
lower is how we close after hitting mean
threshold
that's part of order block Theory
if it closes below the mean threshold
chances are we're likely to see it one
it continues going lower
if it were to go lower we have a small
little portion of this Gap that's being
shown from this candle's High
and that candle is low
looks like that
so that little Gap right there that's a
small little area that's still exposed
so if we were to close
below this
middle of this candle which I'm
highlighting here that's the little
shoulder block
wait a minute you're calling it a
bullish order block and you're calling
it right
when it was up here
earlier in the week it was a discount
array but it's classified as a bullish
order block again bullish order blocks
are not always buying opportunities
they're targets and it also means of
measuring order flow if we close below
the mean threshold half of that candle's
body if it closes below that it is
indicating that it might want to still
keep going lower into next week
if it does where would it reach for
SS below this candle is low
let me move it out of the way I'm sorry
below that candle is low and into that
small little inefficiency and if it
accelerates we have another fear they
got right here
the candle I'm pointing to
is a FVG in the form of a buy
side and balanced cell sign efficiency
look at the candle to the left of the
one I'm highlighting here
that candle is high to the left and the
candles low to the right that makes this
a fair bank account
I don't know what we're going to do over
the weekend
this is why I don't I don't trade on the
weekend I used to trade over the weekend
like the whole positions over but
because of the Gap risk
what does that mean where we close on
Fridays and where we open up on Sunday
can be dramatic now because of all the
things that's been going on over the
last three years and we're not going to
talk about all these topics but the
nonsense that's been going on all around
the world you know all the geopolitical
things and
Health and Welfare issues that
everyone's having to deal with they have
caused a great deal of Gap risk so most
of your trading in my opinion should be
settled intraday
unless you're really you know
comfortable with gap risk even the
restart is at 6 PM when there's a lull
in trading you know for five o'clock to
six o'clock if you're trading stock
indices sometimes those gaps can be a
little bit jarring and it can be a
little bit more than you anticipated
sometimes it's in positive but sometimes
can be a negative so I think if there's
ever been a time in history where
Traders should be primarily focused on
day trading
we're in it this is the this is the
climate for that to be sleeping
soundly at night
so anyway I covered a lot here and I'm
going to go LTFd we're
going to go to a 15 minute Candlestick
chart
and we're going to take a 10 minute
pause here so right now at the time it's
9 53 I want a little bit longer than the
hour I apologize but that's typical ICT
and obviously we've delivered
let's come back exactly at 10 o'clock
it's not quite 10 minutes but let's
take a break you can go relieve yourself
refresh your drinks and
go tell your wife and husband that
you're learning something you can't wait
to get back to it so I'll see you in a
few minutes
[Music]
okay
foreign
all right folks
I'm checking Twitter
before I start talking I want to make
sure that you can hear me we've taken
a couple minutes break
you guys can hear me this could be a 5x5
that audio is back
again just checking to see if Twitter
can confirm you can hear me
thank you Emmanuel
thank you folks appreciate that
all right so
usually
I like to ask you all the
give it a thumbs up and such but um if
you like what you're learning here today
and we're not even close to being done
um just give this a like it doesn't cost
you anything to do it just a little
quick little thumb you're going to want
to use this as a marker to go into your
liked videos to find this one
it promises a whole lot of stuff in here
you're going to enjoy
all right so
back to discussion we have just made our
way into the 15-minute Candlestick chart
for the dollar Index so obviously I'm
taking you through a very detailed
top-down analysis of what it is that you
look for
whenever I talk about
where I think the Market's going to draw
to
that's my experience in three decades of
knowing
what I've seen over the years with the
algorithm is likely to be doing unless
manual intervention steps in these are
the things that we expect to see and
that's what makes what I teach and what
I share and what I call it in advance
um so accurate a lot of people that have
odds against me because they're running
a service paying you know paid service
something they're selling or whatever
they'll say what I do is easy anybody
can do it but they're not nowhere
anywhere near is accurate they don't
call the levels to the degree they don't
have the experience I'm sharing with you
and all I'm saying is
if you listen to other people
and you haven't spent time here seeing
what it is that's being shared and
taught you really aren't making an
informed decision you're just using
someone else's opinion and that's that's
the the mistake or
um
I guess trap of social media so with
that said let's get into the
nitty-gritty here
all right so we have the dollar Index on
the 15-minute time frame we've been
talking about this weekly inefficiency
that was a weekly inversion fair value
Gap I stated on the 13th of June 2023
that we would look for signatures that
this is being
utilized by the algorithm for resistance
now when we look at
the dollar for Forex Traders you're
really going to be focusing on like the
London open Kill Zone the New York open
Killzone and again for the London open
Kill Zone it's all New York local time
it begins at 2 A.M
and ends at 5am now
I personally
personally I use 1am as a buffer and to
me that kind of like cancels out any
tomfoolery that would occur because of
daylight savings time which I wish they
would abolish it I mean it was the
stupidest thing to implement anyway in
some parts of the world don't even use
daylight savings time but to remove all
the the uncertainty about time I've
always used my personal is 1am to 5 A.M
okay that's the time so that means any
setup that I like to look for can occur
that early which is kind of like the the
European open
and then you have at two o'clock it's
the
London open but two and it usually
closes up shop in the volume Peters off
at 5am and in between five o'clock in
the morning to seven o'clock in the
morning I refer to that as dead time
don't don't try to do too much anything
in here but I have taken trades as early
as six o'clock in the morning trading
the New York session over to New York
open Killzone which is classically
defined by
seven o'clock in the morning to 10
o'clock in the morning and
you can look at seven o'clock to nine
o'clock as that little sweet spot where
the majority of your trades are going to
form buy or sell for Forex Trading
between seven o'clock in the morning and
nine o'clock in the morning
the London open
I I talked about this moments before we
took our first break
at seven o'clock I'm sorry at one open
at two o'clock in the morning
and five o'clock in the morning New York
local time
that is the ICT
loan open Kill Zone that if you know
where the weekly Candlestick is likely
to draw to
everything I've been talking about up to
this point is how I do it there is no
shortcut version of it it says the
Market's going to go up to a gap
or it's going to go up to Old High
if it's going to go up if it's going to
go down it's going to go down to a gap
below price or go below an old low
that's it how you define which one it is
is what is it done recently
how has it traded is it leaving a range
that we've worked multiple times back
and forth
and it's been efficiently delivered and
we left that range chances are it's
probably going to expand lower reaching
for an old low or inefficiency in the
form of a fair Gap FVG below
price
or reverse it it's it's that simple and
what you're wrestling with is you're
trying to bring other things that you
either know you learn from somebody else
some kind of other indicator based idea
or retail perspective maybe supplying
demand maybe harmonic stuff you're
trying to bring that into this and see
where you know you can help your
understanding by bringing that in then
that's the mistake leave all that stuff
at the door
like what I'm teaching is not
complicated it's either going up or it's
going down for one of two reasons
and if you spend the time on the weekly
chart to Define that you can come away
with what I've shared many times for
years
in the witness of hundreds of thousands
of people
and they're watching it pan out and
you're if you're new you're now just
discovering that and I envy you because
I I know what it was like when I first
discovered it it's it's crazy it
literally is mind-boggling to see how
much precision and everything is
scheduled but like every price run that
you see in PA is not a
surprise
unless it's a a wartime event or some
kind of you know
event that would be
destructive we'll say it like that
or a manual intervention come in like a
surprise rate announcement it's happened
those things I'm not prepared for
that and that because of that it incurs
risk and that's why you have to always
understand that
as good as my stuff is and as good as
anybody else's stuff might be you know I
mean people can show profitability and
show statements and show live streams
and they can do this and do that it does
not change the fact that any one of us
me somebody else that's teaching selling
courses or whatever any one of us can be
a victim
of some unexpected event that can
completely
take everybody's best surprise
and I use the analogy many times with
the deepegging of Euro in the Swiss
franc
where brokerage firms immediately were
made insolvent
and people lost their money they lost
money billions and billions of dollars
were lost that day
because of that de-pegging between the
Euro and the swissy
so
did anybody see that coming you know did
did anybody warn you in advance about
that stuff chances are probably not
so that's real risk and all of these
markets have that kind of risk so is it
something mindful of yes is it something
that paralyzed you and never you know
allow you to go in and trade well that's
up for you you do the side okay I don't
tell people to trade with live money
you'll determine when you're comfortable
doing that I don't ever sit down and say
you're ready to do it now but I know the
ones that aren't
so if you look at the range here we're
going to measure the high
I'm trying to find a point where I can
lay it on the boat okay so we can see
that the highest point here
and it might not be the very
pipette and I could care less about that
but the low and the high I've dropped
the Fibonacci on that
and the only thing I'm using the
Fibonacci for is to show you the
relationship of the three specific price
levels that I teach my students to look
at
so if we're looking at the High
okay I'm trying to see what that note is
here
okay one zero three point four four five
the low
103.226 okay they may or may not be the
actual high and low of the weekly
candles that are used to define that
range but I think this is close enough
for government work so the midpoint is
one zero three point three three six
the midpoint of any Gap that being a
FVG or a real liquidity a
liquidity boy would be like this little
area right there see there's no there's
no overlapping of any Wick or candle
body is it opened here
and it closed here there's no price data
here at all that's a real liquidity
board that's a real Gap
we refer to things like this here
as a fair value guy and this would be in
the form of a buy-sided male and cell
sign efficiency
this is a real liquidity boy
any Gap
whether it be liquidity void
or inefficiency or like I have a shaded
here up here
they're measured
from the highest high and the lowest low
of that respective inefficiency or Gap
and the midpoint is always referred to
as consequent encroachment meaning that
as it starts to fill in and re-price to
the high or low of these levels
as it encroaches it's
most likely to refer to the midpoint of
the gap
or inefficiency than the extreme high or
the low and that's the basis of why we
like to see
if we're bearish we want to see the
upper end of the inefficiency or Gap
respected and treated as a premium and
not be dug into meaning as I mentioned
before we took our break we don't want
to see the high end of any inefficiency
be retraded to if we're bearish if the
market is really in fact in a cell model
the best ones the strongest delivering
obvious Runners will always have this
signature Hallmark part to it where the
upper portion of it doesn't get treated
to
look at the bodies of the candles
we have just a little bit of movement
above it here but look at these right
there right on that midpoint of that you
think that's random
when I talked about it on the 13th of
June in that live stream I said I want
to see does this show signatures in
PA that confirms it suggests
that my assumptions by anticipating this
level that's shaded in in a pale orange
that that would be treated as resistance
or a means of
beginning short trades for smart money
and in targeting
this level down here which is the bull
shorter block on the daily chart
so in your mind
as a Trader going forward whenever I say
things like that or I say I'm looking at
this as a premium array I want to see it
be treated as a wrist of resistance
and then enter a cell program and I
point to where I think it's going to go
right away in your mind you start
thinking okay
he just told me where he believes with
30 years of experience where it's likely
to go so I just told you bias
I cut through all the I got
right to the point if I sat down with
you
and taught you every single week what
I'm doing you like first of all I would
never get that we're we're still in
dollar we just finally made our way into
the 15-minute chart it does not take you
this long to do the analysis
but it does take me this long
and as long as it's going to take the
day for me to teach you what it is
that's going on in my mind to make the
decisions to tell you before it happens
and it happens in your chart later on
perfectly you want to know you show up
you want to ask me these questions and
I'm giving you the answers don't
at how long it takes me to give it to
you because it's not an easy and you get
the information like you have to weigh
out a lot of things
which it's not an easy one two three
program there is no easy one two three
Precision out there outside of this
there's things you can make money with
but you're never going to come to the
conclusion that I'm showing you as
consistent as I am with anything else
this is the market
so when you hear me talk about in a
tweet a Twitter space
or if I share the analysis on a
presentation whether it be live streamed
or a recording review and I'll give you
opinion about what I think it's going to
do next that's the time when you start
paying attention the most okay you want
to say all right
he anticipates me ICT is telling you
that we're expecting to see this area
that shaded
be treated as an Inception of a Down
move
and terminus
the end of the move
the low hanging fruit that's all I'm
stating when I say that it doesn't mean
it's the end of the line
it can't go any further than that
no I'm telling you how to frame a setup
an element to every element
that makes up a trade has to have
several factors
it's the Inception of a move
where it begins
but by itself there has to be some
narrative reason why that trade should
even form
which is what I've spent all this time
thus far explaining why we're seeing
what we're seeing in the chart right now
which is what I outlined and told you
was going to happen on the 13th of June
you look for
in time periods of the day where I teach
you as kill zones
London
two o'clock to five o'clock in the
morning New York local time
if we have a bias okay for the number
crunchers out there if we have a bias
that is indicating that the market is
likely to expand lower on the weekly
chart that means the candle is going to
expand down right away 80 of your bias
problem has already been solved by
itself with that alum
to have to wait for all the calendar
events to either support or negate the
idea
so we had a series of what big news and
Friends news drivers this week
FOMC CPI
all those things you watched me told you
how to navigate them
not to trade ahead of them but after you
see that information come into the
marketplace and all the sentiments shift
that they create
we're not looking at the data we're not
seeing what the raw number suggests and
I could care less I never look at that
stuff folks it's never a factor but I'm
anticipating the medium or high impact
news driver to create and present
volatility and in that volatility we're
looking for where does the stops rest
after that first initial move
where do stop losses reside above old
highs or below where are those highs and
lows we don't know where they're going
to form before CPI we don't know where
they're going to form before FOMC
does its first move
we don't know where NFP is
going to use the high and low that it
creates after the initial run at E30
when that news driver comes out which is
the reason why I tell you as my students
don't trade those you don't know what
you're doing I don't know what they're
going to do they could manual intervene
and send these things wherever
that's gambling I'm not gambling I'm not
trying to inspire any of you to try to
throw darts and see if you can get a
bullseye where there's no skill involved
that's happenstance if you make money
but mostly you're going to lose
so what we do is we wait for that
initial manipulation to come into the
marketplace that you can schedule and
set your watch to and it's all on the
economic calendar
the economic calendar is going to tell
you the time of these reports that are
coming up
the market is not moving because of the
report
period okay that data
it's in an envelope somewhere okay weeks
in advance
you think that the people the powers
that be that really are greedy you think
that they're waiting around for that
same amount of information that
everybody else is getting no
no
so all of this is a lie it's a myth to
believe that fundamentals can be timed
on a report release
that report being released
is a smoke screen and they're always
going to use these as a
justification for okay the market
reacted to this data when it works in
the favor they try to say it is but when
it doesn't they always say well the
market priced it in
and I was mentioning that before we went
into our break so
when I tell you where I think the
Market's going to react
okay that's a key point of reference in
the either the market I'm talking about
or a specific time frame
so we were working with the daily chart
which is where most of your decision
making
for either a day trade a short-term
trade or whatever the bias is derived
from the weekly chart and and where it's
likely to draw to that's it then you're
moving on to the daily chart and daily
chart is you're watching and monitoring
how each individual daily candle forms
if you're bearish as we've been
expecting since the 13th of this week
we want to see how does price gravitate
to
this level down here which is that
bullish order block
so each individual day we have to weigh
out does it run into that shaded area up
here which is what I outlined this we
want to see does the algorithm offer
price there and if it does once it
enters it at what time of day well what
Market are we looking at
dollar
so primary interest is
nailing down the high of the day
where is the high of the day going to
form in a market
that is trading at a level we expect the
price to react to
so we've been we're expecting the
Inception of a Down move between
one of three levels in here right no
midpoint or the low of that shaded area
remember what I said if we're bearish
every inefficiency
if we're going to use it as a basis or a
framework for a trade we want to see in
a
premium array that's going to be used to
sell off and send price lower
we don't want the upper portion to be
respected
because if it doesn't get up there like
we're seeing right here
that's really indicating that this is
going to be a strong probability
for what the trade down two and through
that order block
time of day now okay
got this fancy Kill Zone indicator right
here
I drove my annotations out Folks by
hand I know that you like to have these
little gizmos that do it
but nothing beats
High touch over high tech
it makes it more meaningful to you it's
like meditation for me and you know it's
a little tedious
sometimes when I have to do a whole lot
of annotations but
with my heart's in it like this you know
I don't mind doing it so here's London
open and we're dealing with the dollar
Index and I mentioned on the 13th that
we would want to see the price of dollar
go up into this shaded area which is the
old inversion for your recap on the
weekly chart so we've taken that Weekly
chart for your vegap and transposed it
to all time frames lower than it so that
way whenever annotations you put on your
weekly chart you want to make sure that
you show that annotation on all time
frames and how do you do that
you highlight the the array that you're
you know annotating on your weekly chart
and then
current interval and Below or all
intervals is basically the same thing
then you'll see on every time frame when
you go through your HTF
weekly daily
four hour eight hour 15 minute chart 30
second chart every it'll always be there
okay
inside this window of time that begins
at the left side of that London open
Killzone annotation box
to the right side in this area
is when
when
the trade begins when the shift in
Market structure will occur when the
high of the day forms
seventy percent
you have a probability that the high of
the day
will form between two o'clock in the
morning and five o'clock in the morning
New York local time but you have to have
the other ingredients you can't just
simply say Okay highs and lows let's run
some numbers and calculate does the high
of the day form on two o'clock to
five o'clock on this day this day this
day now you have to have the the
narrative in mind and I gave it to you
on the 13th I told you what to use this
shaded area
my longer term students to know that if
we're bearish we don't want to see all
of the inefficiency respected
which is a breakaway Gap if it's a fair
value Gap but we've already worked
inside this range already but now we're
treating it as
a resistance that means it can trade up
to the low and reject and go lower or we
permit
we permit our analysis to see price
trade up into the midpoint which is
consequent increasing right here
so
I'm going to take that level off
here we go
so when we're trading at consequent
encroachment here
and it's in London open
we bumped the high
we want to see price do what
showing willingness to want to go lower
does it sharply leave
once it trades up in here hits the buy
side here and then all this back and
forth movement that I'm showing you
right here all this here
price is spending time in that range is
it efficiently delivered
yes why because it's moved up
down
up
but it's only keying off of the levels
I've told you to focus on inside that
shaded area
consequent encroachment
we want to see does it reject after
bumping the high here yes
once it leaves that shaded area how did
it leave it
energetically yes
so now enter model 2022.
BS taken
here
shift in Market structure there
very bad you got there
I know I don't know corners of your
mouth is hurting now
foreign
happening all right so
we have our shift in Market structure we
have our FVG and then over
here
what is this
what time of day is that
8 am
so you're in the heart of what New York
open Killzone
seven o'clock to nine o'clock that's
your little sweet spot
your your setup is going to form
continuation
you hold down control and drag by the
way in case you're gonna I learned that
from my students
all right seven o'clock
it can be left at 10 o'clock but I'm
going to show you the
oops don't want to do that
9 A.M
and this is New York
okay so inside this little window of
opportunity here
you're focusing on what
we've already worked up inside that
consequent encroachment here we've
already seen the evidence that it wants
to reject that we have a shift in Market
structure we have a FVG in
the market rallies up into what
time of day that's when the move is
going to happen New York local time
seven o'clock in the morning to nine
o'clock in the morning that's your New
York open ICT Killzone
this is the London open Killzone
this is your premium array
the range is from this high down to that
low that's the lowest low
here's 50 a premium is at or higher than
that does that fair value got qualify as
a premium array relative to that high in
that low yes
is price returning back up to
that shaded area yes where specifically
the low end of it
it doesn't need to go back up to
consequent encouragement
oh
consequent encroachment it showed the
signature that we would look for it left
the upper portion untraded to again
worked off the low of that Gap
if you don't have these levels on your
chart or have them at least annotated in
your notes that you're referring to
throughout the day now in the beginning
you want to definitely have them
in your chart because it's going to take
you some time to get used to seeing the
market like this but over years and
years of time doing it you'll be able to
work off of a notepad and you won't have
anything on your chart at all it'll be a
naked chart and it's okay
but it takes experience to do that okay
and obviously you can see how quickly if
you're not organized you can get really
really lost working from one Higher time
frame down the LTF but by
having the HTF logic and
all these reference points in mind
suddenly these mystifying moves that
come out of nowhere for you and you
don't know where it came from and
everybody's on social media saying what
the hell just happened where'd that come
from we don't have that here you know in
this community we come across as
arrogant and many times as narcissistic
because we know what the we're
doing we know exactly what we're looking
for we know exactly how it's going to
form when it's going to form and when we
take it down and we share it with our
tribe the people on the outside they get
pissed off they think oh they they think
their doesn't stink right here well
it doesn't baby it smells like roses and
chocolate chip cookies fresh
from the oven whether you like it or not
I don't care you don't have to stay here
but this stuff repeats every single week
every single week it happens every
single week
now every single day is not the same in
terms of opportunity sometimes you'll
see setups that are much more favorable
than like we're seeing
in lesser volatile days but when we
anticipate a direction in the
marketplace and it's derived from a
HTF weekly chart using the
logic that I teach my students that I've
been teaching them publicly on the
YouTube channel
it gives you the framework for one shot
one kill setups where you can get in and
take a lines portion of the weekly range
out doesn't mean you're trying to get
the entire weekly range it just means
that you need a small piece of it that
will satisfy you
and if you consider like a chicken bone
I use this analogy a lot
um do you eat the small little scraps on
the the ends of a chicken bone
I mean if you're really a fan of chicken
I guess you do but when I eat it I just
took the meat on the one thicker end of
it and sometimes it'd be something left
on the boom but I'm taking the majority
of the off
I'm not worrying about starting the
eating process at the end of the boom
regardless of what end it is so I'm
looking for where the meat of the move
is and my Concepts have been aimed at
trying to get you to where
the meat is but you don't need the
highest high in the lowest low but I
teach you how to find that too
so if you want to nitpick and get in
like you're eating crabs and dig into
all the little crevices and nooks and
crannies to get every little morsel out
that's what my mentorship does it's for
freaks that want to be like that I'm a
freak I'd like to know everything I like
to be in everything I'm a control freak
I want to know everything I want to know
why it's going to happen when it's going
to happen when is it going to fail how
will it fail and because I know those
things I know when not to tread in the
marketplace I know when not to touch the
marketplace that's what makes me
consistent that's what makes me better
than everybody else out there because
nobody else has spent any sufficient
time trying to Define where they're
likely to fail
because they're so focused on trying to
find how they can be better and right
and profitable all the time and think
that it's limited to whatever their stop
loss is and that's all they need no I
want to know when the market can trick
me even with my content there are times
that if I don't know by experience and I
had to learn this you know with decades
there are times that even though I
believe that my analysis concepts are
superior to everything and everything
that ever will exist because it is the
market it's tied into the algorithm
I can as the operator you as the
operator you as the user you will read
into price
like a Rorschach an inkblot you'll see
something that you want to see
and many times social media will
cultivate that atmosphere where you get
mad you get jealous you can get
competitive you can get offended by
somebody or I'm going to show him I'm
going to show her or I didn't do as good
as that person that means just try to
outdo them and you go in and you try to
find something as a reason to get into a
trade we don't do that here
we do not do that here you have to stick
to the rules time and price
where are you at in that Weekly outline
that you spent time on when the market
wasn't trading after Friday's close and
before Sunday's opening wherever that is
for you
if you're a church goer you know
whatever you know find some time in the
weekend you know if you want to have a
day of rest and You observe the sabbath
I don't tell you what day to use you
know you have to have one day at rest
period don't anybody tell you what day
it has to be just one day
don't do anything on the market that day
but between Friday's close and Sunday's
opening you have to find time to sit
down
and meditate on that Weekly chart what
is it likely to do what's it likely to
what momentum is presently in play and
what is it gravitating to and by Framing
those ideas on that Weekly chart and
transposing them to LTFs
suddenly everything jumps off and it
means so much more and it's much more
clearer
to see what it is that you've missed
you've missed all this time
all right so
the the idea of
how far price runs can go I'm going to
use that here
just for a frame of reference I'm gonna
go back up to the daily chart
encapsulate that entire down closed
candle here
we'll use
a yellow I don't really like yellow
all right so that's the entirety of the
bullish over block and the expectation
is we want to see does it want to
gravitate lower and get into this area
down here okay and I'll I'll hold off
I'll Reserve doing that you just have
that on your chart as well I'm gonna
drop down into a 15 minute chart again
I know it's ugly
but this range is the entirety of the
order block and the expectation is we
want to we want to see it trade down to
consequent encroachment and go below it
we want to see that weakness that
heaviness because we want to see the
move
protract further lower which would give
momentum to being a long holder to stock
index Futures and foreign currency
this move right here
this move right there that is your
trigger swing that's the that's the
measuring point for what you want to see
for protractions or Fibonacci extensions
you take your FIB you anchor it
draw it down to the low of that price
swing
okay I'm going to show you where my
settings are again I've done this in the
past
I don't need them
standard deviation three and two and a
half
so here's where we're at
close it so we have a high
to low and the entirety of that daily
order block is shaded in yellow notice
that that Fibonacci extension negative
2.5 which is two and a half times the
range of the low to the high here this
is all I use a Fibonacci for folks
that's it okay I'm not in here looking
for bat patterns and crab patterns and
butterflies and all that stuff I'm
looking at math okay that's it this is
the range that matters
and there has to be a Confluence of time
time being London close London close
begins at 10 o'clock in the morning New
York over time and ends at noon there is
a buffer I add to it when there's a big
runoff day
it can extend into one o'clock it's far
and few between if you use just the 10
o'clock in the morning to 12 noon New
York local time is your London close
Killzone it will serve you well okay
huge huge step forward and watch
at 10 o'clock in the morning
to noon
I hope you're having fun with this I'm
loving this
should have charged admission
close
okay so there's your London closed
Killzone
there's things in my way kind of pisses
me off now actually
so now here's what I want you to look at
all right
these mysterious markets
okay we want to know where price can
begin a move
and where it can gravitate to where is
it drawing to Let's draw on liquidity
and we want to frame it in the form of a
low hanging fruit terminus
the Inception of a move can be timed
the Inception of the move
can be determined
within a specific price level or within
a range like an inefficiency and in that
range there's three specific price
levels
three
that
three levels
is used on a basis of whether we're
bullish or bearish so as I was
mentioning earlier we were
expecting this shaded area up here on
the weekly chart that old inversion fair
value Gap to be treated as resistance
the algorithm would trade up into it
during time notice that it reacted here
this is the essentially the midpoint
or consequent approaching of the entire
range but look at the time of the day
it's one o'clock in the morning
that's European European open yes but
the heart of the move and what I teach
by rules is the higher the low the
higher the low of the day is for between
two o'clock
and five o'clock in the morning
when we get here at 2 45
we're doing two things number one we're
bumping the high
so anyone that went short up here on
valid based ideas in Long foreign
currency
I'm tempted to put the Euro up here real
quick but I don't want to mess up the
chart before I finish what I'm deciding
but we'll come back to this this here
okay in a second but during the London
open Kill Zone then it creates the high
you have a 70 probability of the high
forming when you're bearish when you're
expecting the market to deliver as I
outlined on the 13th of June 2023
going to a level I've outlined on the
13th
this level right here is your low
hanging fruit objective
that's not the end of the road it means
that you frame that idea of taking a
trade
with this as your draw on liquidity but
every single trade I enter
every single trade I enter I always look
for some kind of a best case scenario
something more than I expected okay
many times I don't ever get that
sometimes I'll get stopped out sometimes
it just simply doesn't give it to me and
I change my opinion or mind about where
I'm at and I Collapse the trade or take
too many Parcels off to justify
holding on and it's just it's an
evolving thing and that's one of the
weaknesses I've been very candid about
my exits are always a work in progress
and I've been doing this for three
decades so I'm not satisfied my entries
if I never develop another entry
strategy I'll be fine I got 81 of them
but you only need one
you only need one of them so if you were
to look at a breaker here you have a
high low higher high extend the breaker
over you'd be entering short there if
you're using OTE okay I
had to FIB up earlier let me do it again
if you're just using the flagship the
old Flagship pattern
of
my YouTube channel
and this one's gonna come off
all right so these two blue lines here
that is the classic ICT optimal trade
entry which is a standard three-quarter
pullback
high to low it trades up into
I'm quite certain that's probably 70.5
which is The Sweet Spot I teach on the
OTE if you want to watch
anything about OTE if
it's peaking your interest I have many
videos in this YouTube channel just do a
search on my channel for OTE optimal
trade entry that trade up into that
right there is perfect
and it's just a beautiful run from there
down
so you could use that as your entry
pattern okay entering on the fair value
guy
here which is the 2022 model so right
away there's three ways of getting in it
there's three different models to get in
that same price move
which one which one do you like
it's a matter of preference
but we have this run here
to here and we have a standard deviation
of negative 2.5 which is just outside
the scope of the entirety of that daily
bullet shoulder block which is that
shaded area in yellow
let me take it back up so that way you
know what I'm referring to
this down closed candle here on the
daily chart
right there I mentioned on the 13th that
full entire range
as soon as we start moving past midpoint
which is consequently I'm sorry mean
threshold and Order blocks midpoint is
mean threshold any inefficiency or gaps
midpoint is consequent encroachment
the mean the mean threshold here if we
trade through that when we're looking
for you know lower prices and such that
really bodes well for leaving something
on like a partial but it's Friday so
I've already told you I don't want to
hold anything over Friday into the
weekend starting up on Sunday because of
the Gap risk that is available now
because of everything that's been going
on in the world so if anything can
happen you know and cause a major
sentiment shift
where we start trading from where we
ended trading on Friday so that Gap risk
is not something I'm comfortable with
and you may you may not have that
concern you may be trading with such an
insignificant amount of money and don't
want to incur a great deal of risk
and you you are willing to take those
larger
risks
based on points or Pips
but they won't be so impeccable because
of the the money management they're
using but if I'm taking a trade I'm not
I'm not taking a trade with a micro lot
you know what I mean I'm done trying to
take something that has real risk behind
it and it will be much more impactful if
I'm wrong and I absorb a gap that is
adverse to my position that I held over
the weekend
so that's why I'm saying it's
better to be a day trader right now than
there ever Go's been so we have a
Confluence of a negative 2.5 level on
the FIB based on this price swing and
again why am I using this price swing
here because this is a trigger
it's occurring up to a level where we
want to see it being re respected as
resistance which is the low end of that
old weekly Gap
it's during the time of day New York
open where continuations would form
because the logic is we've already
formed a high today
we're trusting okay how do you know ICT
how do you know it's not going to keep
going that's why you use a stop loss for
remember I said it's a 70 likelihood if
you have the narrative on side that
means you pick the right direction on
the weekly chart sometimes I get it
wrong I I get stopped out folks I mean
I've shared where I've gotten stopped
out you've seen where my winning trades
stopped me out and I don't get the full
run
like I don't know why you're acting like
I don't show it I show it and most of
you are ignoring the fact that I'm
telling you what's going to happen
beforehand and you're not using it to
study it real time when I'm pointing to
it in advance are you going through your
charts and looking at it like this are
you marking up your charts like this
this is a perfect example what I'm
telling this you should be doing these
things
this is what you do when I say back test
I'm not talking about go back in there
and using a Forex tester and testing
what it feels like to be in there
that I'm not seeing that that's not
useful but that's a mock-up forward walk
test
I'm not suggesting that I'm saying you
go back and look at all moves and you
annotate your chart like this and you
save these and in these little areas
over here you talk about and you
annotate how the hide was formed here at
this time and the continuation in the
high in the New York session formed here
and it delivered to a Confluence of
standard deviation negative 2.5 and
breach the low of the order block
this level right here is the daily order
block
first
threshold where that's where you start
to trade as a not soccer trade but
you think of it as your low hanging
fruit objective you don't need it to do
all this you just needed to get here
right there and that's not even your
first partial your first partial would
be something like below here
or at the mean I'm sorry the consequent
approach of this Wick right there
so mid Pawn that Wick
that low or that low which one do you
choose as your first partial neither one
of them are incorrect
but you're framing with this is where
you think that the low hanging fruit
objective is so that's your initial draw
and then you watch and see once it gets
there you leave a partial on how much
whatever you're willing to hold on to
you have to allow and I'm allowing for
you as your teacher and Mentor I'm
allowing for you to bring in your
personality to this you're bringing your
own personal touch to this that means
you decide how much you're going to take
off at your first partial in the
beginning when you're first learning
take the most off
because you're going to see many times
you're doing it incorrectly while you're
learning and that's fine but you can be
happy about being profitable quote
unquote with your results
and still be incorrect about what you
thought was going to happen meaning that
if you thought this was going to happen
as I was co-signing on the 13th of June
I said I think it was going to go down
here
if it would have failed to go below
there and I was talking to you today I
would be saying well if if it would have
done that
going below this low or that low here
you would have taken partials and it
wouldn't matter if it went down here so
that's how your your analysis needs to
make room for you to be wrong but not un
unprofitable you're always looking for a
way to take something out but there has
to be predetermined so if you're
anticipating the move from up here and
going down to this level here
in that range from here
to here looking left where is the pools
of liquidity or inefficiencies you can't
use this one because we're all we're
we're acting on that as a term
meaning this is what I'm talking about
by that
all of this movement here is just this
by Sun and balance cell sign efficiency
now has been what is SS's been
offered to it now
look at the bodies of these candles look
at that candle stopping right there
after this BS has been repriced
with SS so the down closed candle
now has provided a repricing to this
inefficiency
that starts the framework of this Judas
swing for the New York open this little
run from here to here
is power three power three is not
limited to the Daily Candlestick power
three can be utilized in any time frame
but this Market Per traction this false
move up to a level which is the low of
that old weekly fair value got which is
what I've told you to watch for that
does this give you the signature that
it's likely to go lower you had
confirmation in London
I teach you in this YouTube channel in
my lectures that if you're bearish if
you see the London High form when you're
bearish and it's breaking down and you
retrace in New York chances are you're
retracing to have a continuation lower
and here you have it
so you can't use this as a target from
up here you want to see it go at minimum
below that low here and would you be
incorrect by taking the largest portion
off of your first partial if you're
brand new doing that no you're not wrong
about doing that
you're not getting a lot of movement
you know but you're not trading the
dollar either you're trading euro dollar
pound dollar Aussie dollar New Zealand
dollar something that out effect but
we're looking for how prices want to go
down to this level minimum
so you want to take a partial here you
might want to take a partial below that
blow here and the wick whenever there's
a wick okay if if your position affords
it always always always always
every single trade I don't care who told
you it's going to go where if it
includes me if the price trades to a
consequent encroachment of a wick you
must take partials if you're if you're
short just above it because that means
it might trade right to that midpoint of
that stop on a dime and retrace and
spend some time consolidate or oh all
right just reverse
so consequent encroachment of Wicks and
Tails are imperative partial places to
take partials at so if you're short you
have to factor in that price level and
the spread so you want to see the
midpoint of that in a little bit above
it
if it trades down to that level here you
want to take that as a partial always
always always always always
cast in stone it's never going to be a
deviation from that rule if you are
trading inside of a range meaning this
High to that Target down here which is
that old daily order block
that line
is where you think that the low-hanging
fruit objective is you're not saying
that it can't go lower you're saying
that that's where you're expecting it to
draw to on the downside it is trying to
get there in your opinion between that
level in this high you're looking
through all of this
for inefficiencies and I already
disqualified this one
you have this Gap here okay that's a
real liquidity boy if it if you extend
it forward you can use that as an
objective as a partial
below this low here but these Wicks
these Tails okay
when you have two of them back to back
like that you're taking the longest one
take the longest one divide it in half
what you're measuring is to close to the
low half of that plus a little bit for
spread
when when it gets there
you'll take a partial we just happen to
happen to have a low here if that low
wasn't here and it was just a wick it
would be even further reason for you to
want to take a partial there
I have learned
many times when I held onto trades that
didn't go to my objectives
these Tails or Wicks were always the
culprit that I didn't notice in my first
few years of trading
and it's the consequent approach in the
midpoint of that where the algorithm
comes back down to it and doesn't need
to go back down here
it just goes enough into that Wick to
upset any liquidity
and then ultimately it would reverse if
I'm wrong so that's the reason why I'm
teaching you that whenever you have a a
wick or a tail inside of the range that
you're trading in and you're expecting
that range to be you know broken out
you're anticipating that breakout but
you can't ignore any of these
these Wicks because many times they can
completely reverse you and run your
run your stop out if you've trailed it
or completely reverse on your initial um
stop loss
so
entry at New York open at a time between
seven o'clock and nine o'clock
at a level at a price that's been
determined and told to you on the 13th
of June
what level the low of the inefficiency
and the middle or consequent encroaching
of the inefficiency time button open New
York open price consequent correction of
the gap lower the gap
all other factors being there the market
starts breaks once this low is broken we
don't know if it's going to go down here
we don't even know if it's going to go
here we're trusting that it's going to
go there which is why you have a stop
loss if we knew
with absolute assertion that we're going
to see it it's not going to fail we
would never need to use a stop loss
so you have to trade with managing risk
and the stop loss is essential for you
to be able to do that so we measure how
we trade once we take that low out does
it do it energetically I would say
that's the energetic
the next candle we open here
best opening when this I'm sorry to open
here the market trades up
into the range of this high and this low
essentially about half of it
when we see that the next candle we want
to see it break lower and treat this
as an order block
we open rally up trade down we trade
through it
it does not need to close below it
mean threshold is important when we're
trading down to an order block for
targeting purposes and or continuation
if it closes below mean threshold that's
an indication that it's likely not a
promise it's an indication that it's
likely to continue moving lower
but if we're seeing a new brand new up
close candle in a Cell program this
target here is our objective remember
that's the daily bullish order block the
full range of that order block is shaded
in yellow
so consequent encroachment I'm sorry the
mean threshold of that order block
I'm just going to eyeball it here
is
102.565 so
we went through that easily and then
traded outside of the
the range of that order block so now
since we've done this this level here
mean threshold now becomes critical
and we would rather see it not
trade up into
oops
we don't want to see this range
like this
didn't do that right
let's do it like this
we want to see this portion of the the
range be Revisited if I can get it all
right I wanted that
and that was the high end of that
right here this was the high older block
this is the low this is the mean
threshold this section of PA
if it's going to continue it's best for
it not to trade back up into this area
here
and because of that I would treat this
as an area of a fairway Gap that I want
to see stay open
so say say this was like the euro dollar
or it was the es or NQ or something on
trading I don't trade the dollar Index I
use it as a barometer
everything I'm showing you here should
be a mirror image on Euro it should be a
mirror image on pound dollar
but because of this idea of the order
block and now because we went below the
mean threshold of it
I don't want to see the upper portion of
that order block now retraded to it can
it's this best if it doesn't now because
I've encapsulated that relative to the
mean threshold or midpoint up to the
highest point of that daily order block
this section of PA when I'm
looking at price now you can see right
away while I'm trading on a one minute
and five minute chart imagine me trying
to do all of this annotation and justify
why I'm doing it and still watching
price managing the position it's
impossible but these are all the things
that it's in my mind that I'm referring
to and weighing out when I'm moving a
stop when I'm not moving a stop when I'm
taking a partial when I say I want to
see a certain range stay open like this
would be a a gap
you will all would see that and clearly
see that as a fair Vegas right there
this low and this high that one candle
here that's a city
I wouldn't want to see it trade up any
now it can trade up to the midpoint
which is mean threshold
go just above this candle's high and
then resume going lower that would be
institutional order flow entry drill
trusting that this is not needed to be
traded to or up into this area here as I
had indicated oops
from this high down to the midpoint
so again you don't know order blocks so
stop trying to teach them but the um
the point is is
we trade down okay we trade down into
targets
until we get to time
the high that they formed in London
opened exactly how I teach the second
final time if you're bearish the high is
going to form between two o'clock and
five o'clock in the morning New York
local time
if that is true
New York session
will have a high probability of
continuation of the same direction that
London already establishes that means
the highest formed in London
we have a price area that we want to see
respected we've already worked the
midpoint of that old Gap the low is now
the sensitive price point that's the
level of price
but it has to be traded to at the time
of day that the algorithm will refer to
for new delivery new delivery is a lower
low in the day
this protraction higher up into New York
open and the time and price is meeting
right here then we have this
acceleration to the downside
until we get to when London close starts
at 10 A.M now at 10 A.M you're watching
does price hit your target or multiple
targets if it does now you're in a
position where you could potentially see
a market reversal profile London close
generally makes the extreme end
of the day so if we see the high of the
day form in London the low of the day
forms generally in this little time
window here between 10 o'clock and noon
don't take my word for it go back and
look at your data look at your old moves
your charts every single day would take
seven of those are here get that out
there you should have the minimum of
just that
that in itself and all The annotation
areas over here that you can fill in
with all your observations and you
cheerlead yourself and you say it was
amazing to see how the level I expected
on the 13th of June to be respected as
resistance which is that old weekly
inversion for everybody being respected
here and then it started this framework
in the London open cream high today and
it traded all the way down to just like
I teach on a YouTube listen
this is all in videos
all in videos years and years and years
and years of it and the rules have never
changed it's always the same stuff the
algorithm is not changing it's not it's
not it hasn't it won't period what will
happen that causes it to stop working we
are not trading anymore we won't be
permitted to trade anymore there you go
that's how it ends so you got a bigger
problem you know than than worrying
about whether it's going to work or stop
working if that happens so as long as
there's markets being offered to trade
this logic is always going to be used
period in the story rest
all right so now I'm gonna take all this
information here
and I want you to keep that in mind and
we're going to go back up into a
daily chart
and we're going to segue over to and
then beautiful look at that how it looks
on a daily chart now
completely random
euro dollar
we'll take our next break at
11 30.
it'll just be a five minute break in
case you're wondering I got a p-i-c-t
when can I take a break
so here is you're a dollar and if you
remember I was talking to you about how
on the 13th I said that there's a small
little Gap in here
and then we have this order block right
there
okay so I encapsulate that entire range
of the order Block in that area here
yesterday we traded up into it there and
then today we had this
gargantuan move outside of it which is
supported by the weakness that we've
seen in a dollar Index so I'm not going
to spend a great deal of time going
through this one because everything I
just showed you in dollar
will be a mirror image or should be a
mirror image of everything you see here
in Europe so we're just going to drop
down into an alley chart because a lot
of things I want to cover and if I'm not
careful we could be into this thing
until eight o'clock tonight
and while I make
allowances for that because of energy
God could do it my wife probably won't
permit that
I want to stay married folks okay all
right
um yeah here's your hourly chart and we
were looking for a price wanting to
eventually gravitate from the 13th we
want to see it gravitate up into that
Gap let me scrub it over here
so it's this high and that low okay one
of the things that I would counsel you
to do if you're going to be doing a lot
of annotations and journaling which is
what I'm trying to cultivate in you as a
student
whenever you anchor your annotations and
lines on from the HTF
charts when they drop down the lower
time frame like I'm showing you here
the
the highs you want to make sure they
toggle onto the very specific levels so
that way it makes your charts near I'm
saying that because I'm obsessively
compulsive it probably may not be a big
deal to you but if you don't have that
in the beginning stages it would be easy
for you to gloss over key levels and
where they were referencing from you
know respective times of the day
and if you're going to learn you're
going to do it right otherwise you just
you know waste an opportunity
so we have on the 13th which is here
Market drops down takes out SS
what is this high right here
last up close candle what is that
it's not a breaker
what is the what is the purpose or
function of a breaker
mitigation
so a breaker if it was a bullish breaker
we would see a hot I'm sorry a low a
high and a lower low than that low here
but we're not seeing that we see a high
I'm sorry low high low a higher low
so it didn't go lower here so that makes
this High here
a mitigation block
similar in in scope but the definition
of what makes it a mitigation block is
that distinctive feature
so if you take that range here
time
perfect
what's the low of this candle here look
right
here okay upper left hand corner what is
the low of that candle
1.07746 that's the low of this candle
here
what's the low of this candle right
there
1.07741
so it respects it
colors outside the line just a little
bit
rallies but look at the bodies
but did I tell you about the Blicks
versus the bodies
the Wicks do the damage that means you
have to allow for these little Mohawks
okay I got a lot of questions about
folks saw that video where I was trading
the index Futures and I annotated
where it was trading down outside of the
FVG
and anytime it does that
the
my mindset is
it's allowing for spread
so I don't lose my mind if it just makes
a little small little Wick outside of a
level or if it's outside of a fair Vega
if it's like one tick or two ticks and
it immediately comes back inside the
range I'm comfortable with that
you might be freaking out if you're
trying to trade before you're supposed
to be and you're you're prepared to do
it you'll get scared out of the trade
or not trust the level where if you
watch when I'm doing executions I'm
allowing for these things and many times
I'm annotating it right then real time
saying you know this is a mohawk if I
ever see if you ever see a mohawk or
hear me talk about a mohawk it's just
when the PA has a little tiny
little movement with a wick that's just
outside the the lines that I would see
as if it was everything perfect
like no deviations from the actual high
or low or the range that's defining an
imbalance
it can go it can color outside the lines
and it's completely permissible it does
not upset my expectation it doesn't
unsettle me and you get used to seeing
that when you do these annotations you
trust yourself and your observation and
reading price when you see these things
repeating over and over and over again
so anyway that's a mitigation block
in the market accelerates during the
New York I'm sorry the London open Kill
Zone on the 14th at 2 A.M
so we had
SS in here we drop down to it
that's your Judas swing the market then
rallies quickly up into the levels I
told you on the 13th it would do all the
way up to the high here today and
through it just like we saw happen on
the dollar Index so if you are a euro
dollar Trader
okay you want to have
a reference between that and
we're looking at the dollar Index with
it so
you want to constantly be referring to
what you're seeing on the market that
you're Trading
versus the dollar Index
so everything you're looking at in price
for your Market of study or Trading
you're constantly getting feedback in
relationship to the dollar Index so if
you're looking for the dollar Index to
go lower
and you feel like you're you just can't
hold on to a trade that's running for
you and you have a partial on and you
just if you're traded with real money
you know exactly what I'm talking about
it's stressful to be in a winning trade
like that we just don't know when to
close it you don't want to close it too
soon because if it runs it's just going
to keep
reminding you you just got out on a
motion you should just held on to it or
put a stop loss at a point where you can
be comfortable with it you move up half
of the open
profit and just leave it there if it
stops you who cares because you've taken
a larger portion of already in partials
but the way you beat that uncertainty or
that nagging feeling of I don't know
when to get out when to get out you're
constantly referring to the dollar index
in relationship to your Market of Choice
so if you're if you're trading euro
dollar and it trades through the high
end of the order block here and it
trades to the low the order block over
here you're already looking for
signatures to support it complete runoff
and keep on going lower
but when we get time of day like we have
here
as soon as we enter in underline clothes
you have you have to have the the
majority of your trade off
you have to number one it's Friday two
London close is generally the time when
it makes the opposite end of the daily
range so we have the London High forming
here the high of the day
we had all this
SS delivery and over delivering
in terms of what we were expecting which
is wonderful
but when we entered a time of 10 o'clock
to noon New York local time
generally a lot of the volume for index
I'm not sorry for Forex and currency
trading starts to dry up between 10 and
noon and later in the afternoon yes you
might see these little fluctuations but
I'm not a fan of afternoon trading and
currencies like I'm not a fan of it the
bulk of the volume is going to be
encapsulated between two o'clock in the
morning and noon local time in New York
so
the way I just ignore any potential
blow-off moves is I have rules and I
have to have closed up shop sometime
between 10 o'clock in the morning and
noon New York local time
especially if we've had targets you know
hit in these multiple targets have been
hit
if you need to leave a very small
portion on
then it's okay to do that but just know
that it's probably going to stop you out
and it's okay because you're holding a
small portion on but if it runs it will
satisfy that I need to be in there in
case it runs but you're still going to
regret not having the full position on
so you're always going to be wrong in
that regard and that's why I'm telling
you my exits I'm never I'm never
satisfied with that I don't have a
strategy that satisfies me every single
time I think a tree but I can find
profitability in every trade I'm getting
into because there's partials always
available
and
that part is a personal aspect of
trading that I teach and make allowance
for you might not understand that
allowance as being a factor coming into
this
but that's what you're doing when you
take my information and Concepts and
they make it makes your model it's
Uniquely Yours how you engage with price
action what you're comfortable with
you're never going to outside trade
outside these parameters that you
defined for yourself
how do you start there what what
parameters and what framework do you
apply these right here which is time and
price Theory
this is not form fitted today this is
exactly how I teach it my students have
seen these things for years
you're going to see these things for the
rest of your life if you study price
action and you trade you'll see these
things repeat every week it happens
every single week which is why am I My
slogan is this every week every day and
it won't stop because this is the
marketplace
all right so let's go into
[Music]
five minute chart
and take a look at how we traded up into
[Music]
on the 15th we had SS here
then we drop down
classic signature of London open
is a stop run
London opened classically seeks sell
side or BS liquidity you don't
have to have the confidence
to go in and buy the sell stops I can my
students have learned how to do that but
it's a very very hard thing to learn
because you have to see years of this
type of stuff to desensitize you
it's easier for you to wait for this run
here
and then judge does it have displacement
higher
swing High
after take stops
it drops down into it here
rally we want to see energetic run once
it clears this high does it do it yes in
itself at this time of day is 355. what
time of day is that
between two o'clock in the morning and
five o'clock in the morning this Fair
bag you got right here is the
Silver-Bullet for Euro for today
you only need this love right here to
trade to
there what time is that 4 20.
sorry just a joke
some of you probably won't get that no I
don't smoke weed
but there's your Silver-Bullet for
London open
and it rallies up to what the low of
that FVG I told you on the
13th of June that is what what is that
that is your low hanging fruit objective
you don't need it to go all the way up
to mean threshold which is half of that
shaded area in purple which is the order
block on the daily chart
you don't need to go there it can
but you are framing on the basis of
getting into that fairbanka
now why am I not using the low of the
order block because that Gap is there
the inefficiency takes precedence over
the order block
yes the inefficiency
takes precedence over the order block
this is where you would see it reach for
minimum does it react there
sure does trades back down in to what
what you're trading into
a low
High lower low what does that make this
a bullish breaker
extend it in time
what time of day is that
New York open Killzone seven o'clock in
the morning to nine o'clock in the
morning there's your little sweet spot
what does it do
rallies how high can it go well we have
to determine a fulcrum point
fulcrum point is here why is that
important
if it runs through this High we can
start doing measurements in form of
standard deviation so we can take that
low
project it up this High here
standard deviation negative two
negative one and a half
one this is a measured move okay so from
this low to that high these classic ABCD
type thing or measured move
and that's it right here
you want to absolutely have the lines
portion of your your trade off there
because what else is that in close
proximity to
the high of the order block remember
this shaded area here
the Shaded area is let me drop up into
go up into this
this up close candle right here
right there right above my cursor that's
what I'm highlighting here the low to
the high of that
that's what I'm showing so back down in
measuring that low
to high and this is the fulcrum Point
meaning that when price trades to it and
through it it has to go through it
before you can get any of these
measurements
that's the measured move
Lions portion of the trade should be
taken off there
because it's in close proximity to the
high of that order block it could very
easily stop there and consolidate into
the rest of the day and then continue on
Sunday into Monday
but allowing for continuation when it
gets to the high of the order block you
need to consider taking partial there
negative one and a half and two that's
two times this move here whenever you
get that type of move that's very very
extended so stand two standard
deviations I teach in
mentorship that
two standard deviations of like the
Asian range or flout or Central Bank
dealers range attention like digital
currency hear that Central Bank dealers
range those
ranges that I use for measuring
protraction and how far a high or low
can move before it makes it that same
principle applies here with all price
swings negative two standard deviation
is one of those levels where
there's a lot of reason for you to be
wanting to be either out of the trade or
have such a small little piece on
if you're going to leave a runner on
it's about at that time we usually Peter
out especially if
we do so when time is met and that being
10 o'clock in the morning New York local
time to noon that's London close so for
your notes especially for the folks that
are brand new when markets are going
down or we're expecting a daily candle
to be a down closed candle
between two o'clock and five o'clock in
the morning generally you're going to
see the high form
and generally the New York session
between seven o'clock in the morning
nine o'clock in the morning New York
local time will create a continuation
pattern now sometimes
there's a reversal of that where London
creates a high sells off and in New York
runs out to London high but then
reverses and makes the lower close in
the day
those are always on the heels of a
higher medium impact news driver
that's the only time that occurs so how
do you know when the low is not going to
be taken out or the high is going to be
taken out in London you can trust the
New York session I just told you
man I should have charged money for this
one so we can see there's a lot of
consolidation in here we had a high it
right above it if I was long on Euro
this is running down Equity this is the
principle you see me doing all the time
in trades if I'm long and admittedly I
was sleeping last night preparing for
all this so I didn't trade Euro and I
even trading Forex for a while now
as soon as it trades about this High you
want to be taking parcel and exiting
your position it's offset distribution
and the principle is running down Equity
that means you're you're selling to buy
stops you're selling at new highs you're
buying low and selling High where do you
define High every time it takes out a
swing High when you're long if it's long
in a tooth or it's been going for a long
time like we did here since eight
o'clock this morning
it's
good money practice for you to be
selling every time it makes a new high
if you have position available to do so
in my personal opinion
if you look at what we're seeing here
do you see how the Euro has made higher
high
and the dollar didn't make that lower
yet low at the same time
Market symmetry suggests that in a
perfect world
the US dollar should have made a lower
low there
in concert with the higher high in Euro
this is a USDX smt Divergence that means
dollar which is USDX and
Euro
are not in agreement with what they've
done at a time of day that is critical
loving clothes
so this would make me very very cautious
to expect higher prices and I'd be real
content with closing all of my position
in Longs on euro dollar and going into
the weekend happy that I destroyed it
so
anyway that's the business there
um for your study you want to go into
um the June 13th
live stream on my YouTube Channel June
13 2023 for the folks that watching this
in the future
you can go to the 7 minute and 22nd
time on that video and you'll hear me
outlining these two levels here in this
entire range here and that would be the
draw and liquidity that was mentioned on
the 13th that means we were over here
we get here
yeah we're um somewhere in here on the
time of day we were talking but
we were using this um idea that we would
expand up into that
on the 13th and today
we're up here and through it okay
so when I'm looking for smt diversions
smt diversions is I've never really
settled on the real name for it it's a
smart money technique or smart money
tool I use it interchangeably
um it's just a matter of looking at the
relationship between closely
correlated assets or inversely
correlated assets meaning that euro
dollar usually goes higher when dollar
goes lower but if you look at times when
they don't agree so if dollar makes a
lower low
a symmetrical Market is a euro dollar
going higher high
a euro dollar making a lower low and a
dollar Index making a lower high that is
not symmetrical they have to agree so
Euro higher high lower low in dollar
euro lower low
higher high in dollar if ever at any
time that it's doing that during key
times of the day which key times
which key Titans is the day for 4X and
currency pairs
London open New York open one and close
yes you can trade Asia yes there's
opportunities in Asia but
the scope of this
Workshop today
I I don't want to focus on the lowest
volatility I want to take you to where
the meat of these daily range moves and
for the weekly opportunities that are
available I'm telling you how to go in
and see where these algorithmic price
swings are going to occur okay so every
institutional Priceline that forms in
PA in 4X and dollar are going
to be primarily inside the timeline as
I'm telling you Now by itself you know
when I first started teaching this you
know septics and Skeptics alike would
come out and say you know
this is nonsense or hindsight but it's
free it was for you to learn how to
trust where these things will occur and
by pattern of recognition seeing it
repeat over and over again you learn to
trust that these are the times when
things really happen
now the problem is
everything I've done so far in this live
stream today that's all foundational for
you to determine how price is going to
react and how it trades to where but you
can quickly see how
many of the opportunities that you think
are a surprise sometimes you know after
they happen because you're you're really
not that versed in trading the idea of
knowing how they form and why they form
what they're reaching for helps you know
remove all that uncertainty now here's
another here's an interesting thing here
you can see how I told you that I would
be done
I would be done I would hold on anything
longer for euro dollar it's 11 24 I
would have already closed the trade on
this
if the euro dollar goes higher and the
dollar makes a lower low
I would miss whatever that move is on
the upside on Euro
I would admittedly
because I'm obsessively compulsive I
would go back in there and try to
justify I'm not suggesting that you do
this but I want you to know that as your
Mentor this is a struggling point for me
so I had to have rules that stated that
once I come to the conclusion that time
is now at a period of time in a day
where the opposite end of the range is
formed where we've been seeing it Go
lower that means that the low is
probably forming sometime between 10
o'clock and noon New York local time for
a dollar
that means that the high is forming
sometime between 10 o'clock and noon on
euro dollar
there can be like I mentioned earlier in
Forex and in currency pairs there can be
a bleed over into the afternoon in New
York session I am not worrying about the
dollar or
Futures contracts or even the Forex
currencies
during that time of day my focus would
transition from Forex to stock index
futures
so that would be my my trading day would
move from 4X overnight and then go into
bond trading in the morning the morning
session and then I would either do an
overlap with
you know index futures or finish my day
in Forex and then at London close all my
focus goes to New York lunch hour
trading the run-on stops that was taking
place on the holders of Longs or shorts
in stock index Futures and then I would
prepare for the afternoon session
and then I would do some kind of a bond
trade in the last you know 30 minutes or
whatever on Market on close and that
would be my trading day that's that was
how I did things and when I stopped
trading Forex and went back to my roots
of which is index Futures Trading
um because that's where my focus is I'm
teaching PA with that Medium
but you can clearly see all the things
I'm teaching you here that are already
in my YouTube videos I'm taking my
opinion
of how I would teach the folks
one-on-one this is exactly what we'll be
doing every day all week long we'll be
going through every single thing that I
told the person the previous week what
would happen and it would give them a
foundation and then come the middle of
the week I would say Okay based on what
we're showing you where would you focus
on your trading where do you feel
compelled to trade do you want to trade
on an hourly time frame and try to get
like short-term intraday trades or do
you want to scalp where you're using a
15 minute or less or do you want to be a
short-term Trader using primarily just
the daily chart and using the Open high
low and close for power three to get
your setups to trade for you know one to
three days of short-term Trading
and depending upon what the student you
know would tell me then I would spend
the latter portions of the week framing
that out in a model for them so they can
go home and start working with that
that's what I did in the mid 90s so
I want to kind of get through the other
markets and then
teach you how to trade the FMC not from
payroll and CPI stuff
so let's go back up to it daily
[Music]
and go over to the pound and as soon as
I load the chart up and get it set up
we'll take a five minute break
so you want to be a Trader
foreign
folks
one more time if you could just give me
a 5x5 on Twitter
let me know before I start talking again
that you can hear me fine
foreign
can you hear me
I'm not sure you can hear me now
I'm checking Twitter by the way
thank you Mo Professor Shelby thank you
appreciate it
all right so
we're looking at the cable market so on
the 13th of June 2023 the live stream
for your notes if you go to the 14
minute and 25 seconds through the 16
minute and 10 second
you'll hear me talk about what I'm going
to refer to here so that's not J picked
it's not hindsight it's foresight being
shown to you in your face okay so
I mentioned that
pound
would likely move higher now why would
pound move higher because we are
expecting the dollar Index to go lower
so
we measure
again the same way we were doing with
the euro dollar moments ago you're
constantly looking at the relationship
between the dollar Index
and the the market you're trading so if
it's in Forex if you're trading you're
constantly referring back you don't just
simply look at the the market you're
looking at as a trade and that's it
I don't know if
this
splitting the screen and the two
requires
a a specific membership or whatever God
I don't know I can't recall I know I
have the highest one that is available
but
it is what it is I mean you're gonna
have to have some kind of way of having
two charts up
and while you don't need 12 monitors
like I do I don't need it I'm saying but
I have 12 minors available to me I'm
constantly referring to all the markets
I'm looking at to keep a good measure of
I don't have them open now I'm in my
trading office but I'm literally just
talking to you on a laptop the one I
used when I'm making my presentations
all the time so I'm only limited to see
what I'm showing you here
but at a minimum you have to look at if
you're trading Forex you want to have
the dollar Index
and whatever Market you're Trading
and you you have to cycle through the
time frames okay
so on
the 13th of June 2023 I did a live
stream and talked about how the British
pound
would need to go into this
Fairway Gap go above it and treat it as
support before we would see a meaningful
move up and I said I wanted to see it
trade up into this
shaded area here which
I'll take it over to
that's the weekly Gap okay it's a fair
value Gap right there
so this inefficiency
this inefficiency right here that has
that big down closed candle it's defined
by the candle to the right
that candle's High
and
this candle's low
so the candlets right there that's what
I'm encapsulating in the analysis and
that was in the June 13th 2023
live stream I said that we would
expected the trade up into that because
it has unfinished business up here than
the terms I used
to drop into a 60 Minute chart
okay you can see on the 13th is here we
were talking and doing our business on
the 13th all through here and I said I
want to see how
we try to trade up into
that Gap that doesn't appear on the
chart now let me go back into the weekly
visibility of all intervals
so now when I drop in the 60 Minute
chart it should appear
here we go
but this this Gap here is on the daily
chart as I mentioned I wanted to see it
act as support
we have a down close camera here which
is an order block which is at the near
top end of that range we expand outside
of it we come back down into the order
block which is a down closed candle
right there and then look what we're
doing we're working this level here
here and then it
that time right there on that candle
what time is that
I mean
[Music]
that candle right there touching the top
end
of that daily favor I got that I told
you on the 13th between
14 minutes 25 seconds and the 16 minute
and 10 second
that minute marker
for the June 13 2023 live stream for
pound dollar I stated that I want to see
it trade using that
Fairway Gap as support permitting it to
trade as much as consequent encroachment
which is the midpoint okay
because we have this down closed candle
and because we have the breaker
low high lower low extended in future or
um
bullish breaker we have an order block
here
Trace down into it and it's also working
and respecting that old daily
guy which we're treating as a inversion
pair of how you got
remember on a daily chart it looked like
this
it's this inefficiency on the downside
here
and if you think you understand what I'm
teaching because you watch one or two
videos and you think oh let's just this
is one of those optimal trade entries
it's got a FVG let's go short
there that that's not what you heard me
say on the 13th of June I said we want
to see a tree outside of it come back
down and you can see it happening here
on the daily Candlestick right there
so before I drop down again think about
power three power three
is my accumulation manipulation and
distribution Theory
and it was the
the major transition from relying on
everything that I had learned from Larry
Williams and capitalizing on something
that he admitted much like I admit my
weaknesses are my exits I'm never
satisfied no matter how good they are at
the time you know afterwards I'm never
satisfied with it so I'm highly critical
of myself in that regard when I
shouldn't be and that's why I try to
teach you all try not to do those things
because it's plagued me my entire career
I don't find any satisfaction in any of
it but it's not about being perfect and
I'm pursuing Perfection and I already
know I'm not going to obtain it but one
of the things I heard Larry talk about
in 1995
he said that the
his struggling point
was understanding how to be a buyer
below the opening price because most of
what I was learning from him at the time
and what he was teaching that I don't I
haven't kept up with him I don't know
what he's doing now and what he's done
and evolved from what it was I was
learning from in the 90s but at the time
I bought everything he had everything so
either it was given to me by friends in
the industry
sorry Larry but
or I paid for it outright and
at the time I loved everything and I
wanted to use everything that he was
teaching and that was a problem and
that's what many of you do with my
Concepts don't do that
find your model look for what it is
you're trying to trade what type of
trade you're trying to be is it swing
trading short-term trading day trading
intraday scalping and then what asset
are you going to focus on Futures index
futures
current season 4X crypto I don't trade
crypto but I have students that have
made lots of money trading crypto and I
can't co-sign for it but they swear by
it working in there so I have to be very
careful because I do nothing with crypto
nothing
and I have no affinity for it so that's
why we won't talk about it we don't talk
about it I do think Bitcoin is going to
zero anyway the low
of this candle right there
after the opening it trades down now I'm
not using this opening price
I'm using
levels that I taught in the core content
for the day trading I'll refer you back
to that for the life now I wanted to
make a note of this in my notes so I can
tell you what month it is
but if you follow me on Twitter right
now
um if you
can recall what month it was that I did
all the day trading stuff
where I focused on day trading I taught
a lot about opening prices in there just
for the life of me I can't remember
which module month it was but it's
already on YouTube channel so I promise
you it's there it's free you can go look
at it but you can still use the trading
view settings I don't trust them
entirely with this setting but the
principle is this
if you're bullish if we are bullish if I
am bullish I'm looking for the market to
create these up close candles and draw
into
a level that I've already predetermined
so right away we had BS here
resting well here we want to see get up
into here because this is an unfinished
business this is all this range up here
this is
the 14th so this was the actionable day
because we were talking about it live
on the 13th
but the day that you would be using the
information would be the very next day
on the 14th so we have the open it
trades down from the opening into the
high of this Gap
that's not supplying demand
that's that's not it's not even trading
back to this down closed Scandal which
you would see is an order block right
this was the level I told you to watch
but permissible
to the extent that it could trade down
to half off which is essentially about
right there which would be mean what it
can trade to the opening price of that
down close candle which would be in what
a bullish order block which is the
reason why I said that
focusing primarily on using the February
Gap as a form of support before we would
see any meaningful run higher this
signature has to make its
self-present we happen to open here
and trade down that little movement down
is what I refer to as a Juda swing it's
a fake Moon and all that's occurring on
the 14th or Wednesday yesterday I know I
have the title of this live stream that
it is Friday the reason why I did that
is because my notes
right here I have the thought Friday
Workshop so that's why I keep saying
Friday when I every time I look at my
notes to keep myself on track
my subconscious is saying it's Friday I
know it's not Friday but because I wrote
it incorrectly this morning I keep
running with that so the live streams
title will change to a Thursday
obviously but that's not me editing
anything except for the title all the
content and everything's here live
you're all watching it I don't know how
many people are watching and if I looked
I'd probably be nervous about how many
people are doing that but to say on
track I just know that I mentioned that
this occurrence here will be what we
would be favoring and then we would want
to trade up into this range now I taught
recently and I don't recall what video
it was and this is where I'm weak as a
mentor
um
I don't do a lot of
indexing or table of content stuff
because
if I start that I'll want to go nuts
with it and I just don't have the time
to do it and this is more than enough
you're doing you're getting this for
free
and it's it's worth more than any other
thing out there you would buy as a
course because it's been proven to you
before it happened I told you what to
look for and I'm telling you now what I
used to get that
understanding and it will repeat it
doesn't change it doesn't fall away
these are the same things that I've been
using for 30 years that work
continuously over and over and over
again to be able to call these moves in
the marketplace which is the only thing
I promise I can promise you that you
will read PA very very
precisely
whether you find profitability with it
or not that's the hard question because
you will bring in your own character
flaws just like I have a character flaw
with my acceptance of whatever I do as
an exit on my positions
whether they're profitable or not I'm
not satisfied with that
so I want you to understand that I'm not
AI I'm a human being that I that that
frustrates me and um it's plagued me for
30 years don't do those things with your
development or create those things where
you're trading because if you do that
early on
they will derail you and I I actually
learned majority of what I know in my
first three years
but I messed up by trying to change
things improve things that were already
perfect
and one of the things that I had said in
my mind that I would have a perfect exit
and I'm never gonna have that I'm
convinced I'm never gonna have it but
because I'm wired to be obsessively
compulsive I wrestle with that so I
teach you how to overcome that by not
trying to go into it in the early stages
of your training
because if you create character flaws in
your trading early on you wrestle with
them for the rest of your life
and there is no Magic Eraser to get rid
of them you wrestle with them the rest
of your life
every time I look at a market move
if if it's something I wasn't watching
and it happened
even though I know I didn't need that
move
it pisses me off that I didn't have it
recorded and executed so I can show it
to the community
because I know I would be in that trade
I'm sometimes thinking about a trade
that I got hurt in
and because I see something that my
subconscious I've looked at things for
30 years and if I see something
and I got hurt in it in the past
I remember that and it's a distraction
and I wrestle with that you don't have
that yet you're brand new you don't have
those War Stories and scars that you
have to go yeah I remember that happened
but that's not this trade so
that's the reality of this you're going
to pick up a lot of painful scars and
wrestle through that the rest of your
career nobody nobody ever gets to a
point of Mastery where they don't have
any kind of emotional tug of war that
takes place because if they have real
experience
invariably your mind's going to go back
to a time when you run a trade that
looks similar to this one and then you
gotta push through it and stick to the
rules the rules say stay with the trade
I don't care if it hurt me this many
times years and years ago it looks like
the way it does you see all these guys
that make I'm getting somewhere by the
way with this the
the folks that draw out these charts and
says look at this the last time in 1929
the chart looked like this and it's
gonna crash and everybody's been calling
for the crash you know through the
summer and I said I don't think we're
gonna crash I don't think we're going to
consolidate we could consolidate but I
think we're going to go up higher
and we've been going higher so
my rules stated that I should have
looked for and expected as you know I
wanted to see the seasonal influence
that I'd like to see that takes us into
a low on June and have that little bit
of a drop but that seasonal tendency
didn't didn't materialize and throughout
that seasonal tendency you heard me
calling it higher that was only learned
by experience
but I also stated that when a seasonal
tendency is likely to occur
a seasonal tendency by the way if you're
new is simply a certain time of the year
certain month of the year
a certain asset classes or a particular
Market performs a certain way more times
than not so it's like a
well it's like a season tendency for for
snow you know it's not likely to snow in
New York in July
and it's not likely to go to 90 degrees
in February in New York
when that stuff happens we probably need
to be paying attention but generally
seasonal Tendencies state that those are
the normalcy well there's there's a
factor in the marketplace that we refer
to as acetyl tendency that I was
expecting not used many times over the
years that the the low forms in June
and there's a decline the last week of
April going down into mid midweek of the
second week of June
now it doesn't form all the time but as
I indicated in my lessons about seasonal
tendency on my YouTube channel and also
as I mentioned recently in the last few
months
that if a seasonal tendency does not
form or continue like it does in the
past
the fact that it's not there many times
is a
very strong indication like for instance
I'll give you an example I would like I
would have liked rather to see the stock
index Futures the trade lower throughout
May into the first or second of June
that's what I wanted to see
now wanting to see something and then
taking that one and then trying to
impose your will in the marketplace and
try to force a trade into it that's what
I did when I was 20 years old and that's
how I blew my accounts when I did those
things I was forcing my will and what I
wanted to see happen versus sticking to
what the Market's telling me now as a
more refined analyst when I look at
PA now
I defer all the I want I want versus
what is this algorithm telling me what's
PA showing me in the chart
and a lot of people were trying to you
know look for shorts you know the older
timer guys were saying the Market's
going to consolidate and I said okay
well if the older crowd saying we're
going to consolidate and the retail
saying we're going to crash
I'm going to trust everything that's
saying that's going to go higher so if
they're going to go higher what's it
going to reach for buy stops and
inefficiencies and that's why I took you
to the weekly chart in a daily chart to
also answer the folks that don't want to
day trade they want to see longer higher
term frame entire time frame rather
perspective they don't like the one
minute chart stuff okay because they
think that that's you know useless to
them but that same thing that I'm using
in an hour I'm sorry a one minute chart
I'm using one a 15 an hourly four hour
daily weekly monthly it's the same thing
the same idea that I'm using
inefficiencies in liquidity
in Market structure there's a there's a
plethora of setups that are happening
all day long
and you're never going to run out of
setups but the problem is is you're not
giving yourself a chance to trust what
you're learning is going to give you
more than you ever need
like I could be here all day long every
single day all night long
finding setups here they're all over the
place
if I pushed like that I will take losing
trades more than you see me showing you
but I've learned where I want to take
initiative and say I want to only work
here
I have Insight that you know allows me
to be more
accurate in that regard but I teach you
how to find that and I'm doing it today
how to find the choices the cream of the
crop setups for the week and live there
once you nail down a win like that stop
don't don't trade again if you're a
YouTuber stop let your audience see that
you're controlling yourself and you have
discipline it doesn't matter that you
come back the next day and you trade and
you're live and you say oh I think I
should be done if you're asking your
audience whether you should stop trading
or not you're not in control
you're being driven by your audience so
that's another thing that you have to
ask yourself why are you learning how to
trade are you wanting to be a YouTuber
where you're allowing the in the
influence of your viewers
while you're trying to act like the
influencer if you act
in a manner that you're trying to teach
or showcase what you're doing and you're
allowing this audience to influence
whether you take a trade or not
you're not in control
you're letting outward things create
impulsive decisions about you taking on
risk
so it's important not to get wrapped up
in it I don't listen to people that say
dance for me monkey out I'm not doing it
I know what I make mistakes in and when
I get impulsive my emotions and I'm
bipolar I can't trade
when I'm in a manic episode I can't
trade when I'm in a euphoric episode so
it takes a great deal of focus for me to
even have these kinds of discussions
with you
sometimes it's next to Impossible and if
you listen to
you know
episodes in the past where you know I
get either emotional
or I go off the rails and get a little
bit more belligerent than I should it's
not because I plan to do it it's because
I have a chemical imbalance so I have
very rigid rules that I've had to place
on myself much more rigid than the
average person because I battle a mental
illness that is very hard for me to
wrestle sometimes
and trying to trade and be in the
industry it's highly technical like this
it's it's not easy it's really not easy
so anyway talking about the power 3
concept is the accumulation
accumulation manipulation and
distribution
concept of using it on a interval any
time frame but I introduced it with the
daily chart because like I mentioned in
the beginning of all that rant I've
warned you they could probably come up
I learned that Larry Williams died I
never found out if he ever figured it
out because he mentioned at the time in
1995 that he had a
a weakness or an uncertainty as to how
to determine when to be a buyer below
the opening price before you see these
big ranges and at the time I was
learning under his tutelage of his books
and his VHS tapes and courses that's how
I was learning he was my first real
mentor and I still have a great deal of
respect for him but I did move away from
most of what he taught and what I
learned from him but there is a Hallmark
to a lot of the things
that stayed with me because they're just
Market tourisms a market day that has a
big range
he taught that usually the open is near
the low or the high of the day so how do
you use that information if it's
expected to be a bullish day
and remember go back into the 13th of
live stream if you haven't watched that
live stream I promise you
don't watch it after this one because
we're going a long time today tomorrow
or over the weekend sometime watch the
13th of June 2023's live stream
and all these things I'm talking about
you'll be able to see this forming here
but when you're looking at a day when
you're anticipating bullishness
You're Expecting not just one day of
movement up which is why I take you
into the weekly chart
that Weekly chart might have only a one
day event that creates the run to what
we would expect as a draw on liquidity a
draw on liquidity is where price is
likely to reach to whether it's reaching
down for sales thoughts below an old low
or to reaching down to a FVG
that's the only reason my price goes
down that's that's it in reverse when
it's likely to go higher but we look at
the weekly chart
with the expectation that there's an
expansion move
we don't need to predict the close of
the weekly candle we're just looking for
this
price movement with magnitude reaching
into an objective that we've identified
on a weekly chart
so because of that we're taking that
insight and we're transposing it to our
LTF charts daily four hour
one hour and anything less all the way
down to five second charts
I said that correctly five second charts
so
if we're bullish and we've arrived at
the dollar going lower
cable or pound dollar as we see here is
likely to go higher and move up into
this shaded area which is what I refer
to as the unfinished business if it's
going to go higher where is it going to
go well you have this high
to this low and what has already
happened we went to this High here so
what's resting above that High by side
so the minimum threshold would be to
what reach up to
where
this is a trick question by the way
if you're buying here
at the top of this fairbankment outline
then we would be expecting something at
the form when we did our livestream on
the third 13th
of June
we would expect the market to open trade
down any down movement into this Gap
will be treated as a Juda swing or a
fake decline retail will chase this
every day
they get caught up in it they want to
get short on a breakout they're using
some five minute 15 minute breakout rule
in London or New York or whatever you
know and that is a fake move it's
designed to do that very thing why would
it be interesting to do that because
those cell stops being triggered to get
Traders short chasing it they think it's
going lower
is the perfect counterparty the smart
money going in and buying it because
they're the SS to their Buy
every long has that a sell site
every short has to have a long side
so
the
the dance between liquidity and how it's
utilized in PD
you have to take a step back away from
thinking about things in terms of
overbought oversold and indicator
settings and things like that
and look at who's available right now
to take the other side of my trade
and utilize that as like a bus stop okay
or a mile marker between Where You Are
and where it's ultimately going
Terminus is your low hanging fruit
objective that is not the end of the
move
Terminus is just where you define
where the low hanging fruit objective is
if it just gets that far you've made
money if it reverses there great you've
already made honey
if it continues you have something there
that could potentially
pay more
but you don't need it to notice what
that would do for you if you haven't
considered what that would impact you in
terms of your psychology of the trader
you're not putting so much unrealistic
expectation on yourself
you're literally just placing a
realistic objective and what would that
be
if you're going long here
and it runs up and hits the low end of
that imbalance
that's profit
partial one
now if it doesn't go to
consequent quotient of that Wick what do
you think of that
that's a partial why
what I said earlier whenever there's a
high or a low that you're expecting to
be breached
traded to and through
if there is a wick or a tail consequent
encroachment that midpoint you must
always every single time without
deviation must take a partial always
it's in stone have it in your Journal
have it in your psyche expect it do it
always
then you have the BS
now we're expanding and I mentioned the
cable could trade up into this area here
because it's unfinished business
what levels above this BS can we
utilize
well I taught this and I think I don't
remember if it was in Twitter spaces
or if I
I think I did a live stream
I'm almost certain I did a live stream
at least
I might be having a senior moment here
I believe I did it I don't know I gotta
I'm second guessing myself now
but here is the gradient levels I'm
almost certain I did a live stream and
mentioned this but the
the low end of the gap which is all the
Shaded area here okay
Above This High we have the low quarter
percent the lower quarter
gradient level of this entire range then
we have consequential which is midpoint
we steam through that so the next
objective would be
127 754.
that's a finite number it's it's it's a
static number so if you were targeting
that for another partial you would
factor in spread so you would deduct
whatever your typical spread is for your
pound dollar
Forex pair and then you would have a
limit order sitting there and if it were
to expand up into that
you'd have a partial and there it is if
you're inclined to hold over the weekend
and you feel like this is going to open
up higher which it could do open up
above it and trade down and fill in the
gutless I'm playing devil's advocate for
a moment saying and I don't know this
because I'm
talking to you guys I'm watching it but
let's just say it makes the high today
already here and it's done we could Gap
open and higher on Sunday
and then trade down to this and fill the
Gap and that would be a scenario if
you're willing to hold over the weekend
I'm not trying to entice you if you're
in it to do that of this giving you
scenarios how I would think about it and
when I was using over the weekend holds
when I would trade that whole positions
from Friday's close into Sunday's
opening that this idea I would use in
this context here because this is still
exposed this is the other portion of
that inefficiency on the weekly chart
remember all this movement from high to
low that shaded area was one weekly
candle
where it only was going down so to
reprice efficiently we're seeing price
deliver on the upside so until it gets
up to this point here there's an
inefficiency in the form of a SS
and balance bias efficiency on that
Weekly chart
these are the parts where you get lost
and this advice important that you make
sure that you rewind the video and scrub
back to the parts where I actually show
the weekly charts you can remember what
I'm showing you here but it's important
by having these HTF
annotations on your weekly chart and
then showing them on every time frame
you won't be
you won't be surprised I mean the things
that
generally have happened to you in the
past probably won't be a issue for you
when you start doing this
trying to hit the delete button and I'll
set some page down
50 year old eyes all right so anyway
we're going to take a look at the 14th
how we traded in here
and then we'll drop into a 16 minute
chart
all right so here is
the 14th at two o'clock
that's the beginning of what
London open Killzone
So Below actually prior to that at one
o'clock that's a European open
running open Killzone two o'clock to
five o'clock in the morning in your
local time then
we Gap up in here
rip off into and then look at the bodies
here
that's the low of that Weekly imbalance
that fair value got
that's the signature I like to see when
you start seeing moves form and they
respect these HTF
inefficiencies or
areas where
a real Gap would be or we're not talking
about new week opening gaps today we're
not talking about New Day opening gas by
the way in case you're wondering
um
but we're working with HTF
weekly and daily inefficiencies and this
is the real support and resistance
you're looking for like one of the
things that I try to do
was determine a way of picking
what retail support resistance should be
and that always this is the one you use
I would always get them wrong sometimes
I'd be right but most of the time I'd
get them wrong so what I wanted to do
was determine how I could bridge the gap
between the expectancy of traders to see
what is a support what is a real system
what qualifies and quantifies a support
or resistance and I found out that the
largest degree of precision is around
these inefficiencies
and anybody can say oh everybody's known
about gaps everyone's known about you
know inefficiencies but once they close
in they're done with them I'm not
they're Treasures to me I'm holding on
to them for months
and the algorithm will refer back to it
which is why I keep a 60-day look back
on my charts I'll go back 60 days
in any old PD array whether it be a Fair
makeup a breaker anything like that I
will refer to it if it's in the proper
context of what I'm looking for what
does that mean I stated on the 13th of
June that I was bearish on dollar and we
would want to see the British pound
trade up into
all of this area here is that's the
inefficiency from the weekly chart it
has unfinished business
well we're seeing it expand up and it's
done it's done it energetically but
where did it start on the 14th right
here at London
and then rallied up we have a wick
what is the wick doing here
damage
damage it trades down outside of that
Gap
does it go to some random level
foreign
got
that's consequent encroachment
that's a signature when I see this when
I see that right there and it pulls back
up into it I'm still staying with the
narrative that this is going to go
higher this does not change my mind it
does not freak me out even this going
down outside of the Shaded area again
this is what I refer to as a mohawk a
little tiny little and the reason why I
mentioned it to the Mohawk is
um when you cut your grass
okay gentlemen
you got there cutting them on and you're
listening to the radio you're looking at
your next generator she's wearing a
bikini and your wife ain't looking and
you just move them over too far over and
you leave that little tiny little Mohawk
you got to come back and and get it well
that's kind of like what this is it's a
little tiny little Mohawk outside the
the range of where you had your Miller
we allow for that okay maybe your wife
doesn't allow you looking at your
neighbor in her bikini but we allow this
in PA this is you know
permissible for PD
but notice what's occurring the bodies
here
and the body's here
they're real close to proximity to that
shaded area so we treat this as okay
it's no problem even though it got real
close to that low the damage was done on
that Wick
it returned then to this FVG
it was consequent encroachment all of
this in here I would be watching it I
was not trading it I would be watching
it and saying okay in my mind
if we were looking at it live
you would have seen me type out
retail sees a Bear Flag drop their
flag and they would expect it to drop
down like this
and that's where I would be drawing in
or typing in excuse me
the fake Bear Flag
so whenever you see me doing examples
where I talk about what retail sees
it's in relationship to what I'm showing
you here
like this is this is real order flow and
notice I haven't done anything with a
ladder depth of Market level two data no
profile stuff it's just simply reading
inefficiencies and liquidity across the
HTF transposed to lower
time frame staying with that premise
that dollar goes lower it's risk on all
assets get to go higher
stock indices the Forex pairs all that
business they get to go they're free to
move up
so here's Thursday two o'clock in the
morning
it's trading where
at the low of that Weekly inefficiency
or Gap
and then we have the market takeoff
rally and let's go into a 15-minute time
frame
okay so we have more information in here
this week now has been refined to on a
15-minute time frame consequent
encroachments are right about there so
it's treating right at that point
consolidating just outside that range
and then we have a short-term High broke
so now we have a shift in Market
structure at the low
of that Weekly inefficiency that Fairway
got
so the shift in Market structure is
there a Gap
look in here is there a Gap
lowest down close candle
now the ICT you said you used all the
candles why don't you use them both
those candles that candle is outside of
that Gap isn't it outside that shaded
area
so what do you do you use the down close
last one
you thought you knew under older blocks
I don't know anything yet
pull a shorter block
down close candle trades into it you
want to see it repel price
does it repel price yes
so at this point
you you can take this entire range now
for entry you're going to use a down
close for support whether the
information is going to continue
offering institutional sponsorship that
the price is going to continuously work
off that level then you can take this
range and then apply it here but the
entry would be on that lowest down
closed candle
I already hear the people hissing as
I
it supports it here supports it here
look where the bodies are stopping
see that
why am I not using this down close cane
on this down close the ICT it's inside
the Shaded area right of the Gap we have
to use the out outside of the range
okay so we're inside of all this
external range liquidity
we have to use the PDA rate it's made
available inside of that and it's
separated by this down I'm sorry this up
close candle so that breaks the
continuity of down close down close up
close that's a change in estate delivery
then we go back into down close down
close
so the change in the state of delivery
is the open on this price there
but for entry purposes we use that last
down closed candle but for supporting
for a reclaimed order block
go back into month four of the ins the
mentorship these two down closed candles
it's being reclaimed here and here and
we can see that the opens and closes
here
that's supportive and then we have one
more little Wick through it because why
the Wix do the damage you don't rush
your stop loss don't rush it up
Market breaks above here
then takes off clears the BS and
then we get in expanding sense
so we have a little bit of range still
here but ultimately we're aiming for
this that's a that's a perfect delivery
if we can get up to that point will it
do so before the closer today I don't
know I don't need to see to do it
because I'm not trading it but you knew
about it on the 13th of June
all right so oh yeah
all right let's go to NASDAQ
one two three four we only have four
more markets to cover
I'll be blending in the FOMC setups and
and how to trade that stuff as we talk
about each so
get back to daily
NASDAQ
all right so there is the setup that you
saw me trade yesterday on my cell phone
so I apologize I know some of you are
like why don't you record the whole
thing looking because I had a guy here
trying to teach me how to use my pull
and use the setups and such and it's
something I'm not used to worrying with
and
as he's talking to me I told my wife
said pay attention to this part because
I'm looking at something
and I was trading the NASDAQ and I was
able to capture a little bit of it but
anyway
the
the NASDAQ
let's go back let's take output these
executions back on in a minute give me a
second
so on the 13th of June ahead of CPI I
mentioned that as I was meaning to
mention earlier they didn't do so but
I'm gonna do it here
CPI number I am generally not accurate
ahead of it meaning that it's only been
a few times publicly that I've expected
certain things to unfold in CPI and then
it happened most of the time I'm wrong
so does it surprise you when I tell you
as my students not to try to trade ahead
of CPI it shouldn't surprise you so
because I'm telling you not to trade in
advance of something I'm trying to
illustrate to you in no uncertain terms
that there's a great deal of risk in
doing so so if I'm not able to to do it
and I'm supposed to be teaching you why
would you want to trade it you're
gambling I am gambling if I try to
determine in advance what it's likely to
do so I set parameters up like I did on
the 13th I told you where the BS
and SS was and I'll give you the
FVG and then as each was
traded to I told you what would be
delivered to next so I wanted to
favorite how you got which we'll look at
in a minute
went down the SS real quick all
in one minute and it went for the buy
side and I told you it's going to pull
back into the middle the consequent
crochet of that range that defines both
the BS and SS and I'm
probably talking too much for not having
the chart in front of me but
the main takeaway was because of it of
it being ahead of a CPI number I was
making allowance for
the SS below here
which is right
there on this day
I was expecting it to be potentially a
Wipeout where it could come down Spike
into this
and still resume going higher I was
expecting that because it would be a
classic CPI it's a classic FMC type
thing it's a classic NFP
event where they use the smoke screen of
that high impact news driver
upset daily liquidity which would you
know clearly you can see these are
relatively equal
so there's a lot of cell stops resting
it's been trailed up through here so
that's why I mentioned the CPI could
potentially use that smoke screen or the
market rather couldn't use that as a
smoke screen and drop down air and clear
up all the cell side here just on a wick
and then we'd still be where we're at
here and maybe even higher you know it's
it's
it's a scenario I offered up as a reason
to be cautious
if you stick to that as what I expected
for Nasdaq ahead of CPI I was wrong and
that completely solidifies why I tell
you don't try to trade ahead of it
because there's so many variables that
could take place so many things can
happen
nobody really knows what it's going to
do when it happens and when it does
happen I showed you and you watched it
live it was over in there and if you
didn't see it live it's in the recording
it's moving and traversing so fast
that there's no way you're getting
filled and all Brokers pull liquidity
you're not allowed to trade that because
like I mentioned at the time in that
live stream it opens them up to
unnecessary risk
so they claim that there's a absence of
liquidity like Traders aren't willing to
trade it there's a lot of people out
there trying to gamble on it
but they don't want the likelihood of
some yahoo getting lucky with an over
leveraged trade that they're be booking
and B booking is when a broker trades
against you and yes it does go on but
you know if you learn how to trade ball
you don't need to worry about that
so here we have
um Thursday today and here's Wednesday
Tuesday the 13th as I was mentioning I
was expecting some
some wild whips or NCP I can can do
those types of things but it was kind of
muted to the downside and offered still
continuation you know up
so we're going to drop into a 60 Minute
chart
okay and you can see how this type of
move right here
FMC CPI NFP all those
things tend they tend to be a
characteristic of those types of new
drivers new drivers so a high impact
news driver for your notes
um
it can occur on a medium impact news
driver but most of the time the high
impact news driver is when I expect the
worst case scenario in terms of where
the safest
retail spot of anyone that's an open
profit meaning the Market's been going
higher this is a general rule of thumb
so we're not really talking about this
Market Per Se it's every Market if the
market has been going up for a while and
it's been
classically seen as a uptrend everybody
that's long should be in profit a high
impact news driver my mindset is always
it's going to run against that
either to reverse on them or to offset
any trailed stop losses so that way they
can be utilized to be a counterparty and
then resume that existing primary
uptrend
so I'm always looking at these high
impact news drivers to go after for the
purposes of unseeding profitable
positions and then it resumes but if it
reverses I'll know if it's a reversal at
the time of delivery so that's why I
have to wait I have to wait for CPI I
have to wait for FOMC I have to wait for
a NFP if I'm going to trade
them
MythBusters ICT Edition you know you see
people say ICT says never trade on
Mondays no I tell you as a new student
learning don't trade on Mondays let
Monday trade use the information that
you get once you know how to trade you
can trade Mondays all day long
okay that's the proper context of what I
said I teach my students don't try to
trade NFP
but you can trade after non-front
payroll about 30 minutes after non-front
payroll yeah you can trade the gas the
inefficiencies in the liquidity it's
easy to trade it after but it's next to
impossible for you as a new student or
new Trader to feel confident or
consistent trading non-trump payroll
when you don't have experience doesn't
that sound like a responsible person if
I'm trying to teach you if you're
learning something from someone
especially if you paid to learn this
wouldn't you want that person to guide
you away from where you're probably
going to hurt yourself
that's what I'm trying to be as a mentor
that's what I've always maintained
same way with CPI CPI can rip your head
off and shove it straight up your ass if
you're wrong that's the reality of that
it's so violent so quick if you're wrong
it's unforgiving the broker's not going
to say well I'm sorry no they're going
to give you the worst case Phil your
stop is not going to protect you it's
going to be the worst case scenario
and it's probably going to be a instance
where you wish this thought would have
worked and it's running even past your
stop
and by the time they remove all the
the
self-imposed lack of liquidity
you'll get filled at the most ill
position or or price
that's the way it works so because I've
seen this for so many years and I've had
my own experiences where getting smashed
around my face ripped off or my head
shot up my own ass that type of
experience doesn't need to be repeated
not in my students so I'm trying to
teach you how to avoid all that stuff
and it should be received with
gratitude because I wish I would have
had someone tell me this stuff and save
me all this pain because it was very
very painful and
troubling the the wreck myself
constantly not knowing that
at the time I felt like I was gonna be
right
and you're gonna have those instances
even learning with my Concepts you're
going to get overconfident
it's gonna happen it happens all the
time my students they get this sense of
invincibility
they're invulnerable they can't they
can't do it wrong now they figured it
out they cracked the algorithm
and then all of a sudden you get that
one simple stupid little losing trade
and it's always going to be on a high
impact or a medium impact news driver
where you thought you were going to do
better than the rules and I make that
same mistake when I lose it's me most of
the time always me
trying to outperform my own algorithm
because I've been here before this looks
like a time it's it's the human element
that Creeps in
so the more rigid you are about filing
rules that are not infinite in the list
simple little rules
simple little rules the things that I
outlined when I tell you look for this
level to act as a means for a premium to
then distribute price lower to this
discount okay that's pretty simple it's
giving you a framework then you simply
wait for time I've told you the times
they were waiting for it but now we're
in stock indices so it changes a little
bit okay it starts at 8 30.
and goes to 11. there's your morning
session then you have to worry about
trading the lunch are you a lunchtime
Trader yes you can trade lunch you've
watched me whip this out of these
markets trade in that lunch hour but as
a new Trader you shouldn't try to do
that yet stick to the morning session
then trade the afternoon session or one
or the other if you make money in the
morning don't trade the afternoon as a
new student that doesn't mean everybody
stops trading and don't trade the
afternoon session because they made
money ict's giving you
whatever because they want to cherry
pick things out of context I'm telling
the new students don't try to do a lot
try to find one good setup per week and
then build on that over time
you can see clearly there's a lot of
opportunity
lots of opportunity to find setups after
setup after setup but if you feel like a
kid in a candy store
you're gonna you're gonna try to do
everything
and that's not a good thing
you want to just pick your shots know
what you're trying to do and focus on
that only
and that's what these discussions help
you
be reminded of because it's very easy
once you start making money whether it
be in a demo or funded account or live
you get drunk
like you get drunk on winning and you
think that it's oh I can go on here
again right now it's still running let
me get in there again oh it's still got
some more juicing let me get it and then
that's it you give it all back and more
and then you're mad at yourself you get
mad at me because you think I caused
this you brought on yourself
if you didn't listen to the dry points
and the boring parts that's why you
wrecking yourself
and if you've wrecked yourself go back
and listen to those boring parts of the
lectures because that's the that
keeps you on the straight and narrow
so anyway here's NASDAQ hourly chart
and
where are we at here
8 am
so we have
this big wick here on the hourly chart
I figure out what this
is here
I'll bring it back up in a second
body to low and I had the gradients in
here okay so we can see to midpoint
which is consequent corrosion of a wick
or tail for your notes I failed to
mention this earlier I apologize for the
folks that don't know I treat every one
of these tails in wicks
I treat them the same way as I do with a
gap
okay the algorithm refers to that area
as a inefficiency or a gap so it's
treated the same way midpoint is
consequent encroachment
and if we are looking at this this Wick
here or tail
the low
for maintaining bullishness would be
consequent corrosion which was fifteen
thousand fifty four and a half
so as long as price does not close below
that
everything stays bullish
The best scenario for continuation on
the upside would be from the high of the
Wicks or the tail here down to
consequent encroachment
look at the bodies respecting the upper
quadrant
of this entirety of this of this Tale
there's the upper percentage of it or a
quarter of it look where the bodies are
stopping
the Wicks do the damage
so when I'm watching price I don't have
a fib
on the Wicks I'm looking at it okay and
I'm just eyeballing it roughing it like
this when you're watching me do
um
executions when I'm reading PA
live Kayla by Candle by candle and I may
not go into the details like this
I'm looking at that and saying okay
roughly that's about half
and then what's half of that to the
upside what about here and I'm watching
these candles as it happens in this
instance or anything similar to it
are the bodies stopping at or real close
to the upper quarter or half if we start
seeing a body going down into the 50 or
consequent encouragement and starts
going lower or a close rate on the
consequent encroachment that's a warning
sign to me I'm thinking okay this is
probably going to give up the goods and
go lower
but simply because these two lows here
are in close proximity that's not enough
to Warrant that this drop here is going
to keep on going
I'm looking at all these tails
and I'm measuring the willingness of the
bodies
to close and or open at their respective
either the quarter percent or half you
know it's consequent encroachment or the
upper quadrant not wanting to see the
lower quadrant even ever being Revisited
and we're not seeing that here
and the market does in fact tear up
higher so it's one of the things I'm
using and utilizing while I'm reading
price and tape reading with you all or
if I'm watching price on Twitter and I'm
calling things out I'm looking at all
these things and weighing it all out
okay so we have a bounce price range in
here
a balanced price range okay what is a
balanced price range it comes in many
forms I shouldn't say many it comes in a
couple forms but as I was mentioning
earlier in the workshop video today we
have talked about how markets stay in a
Range
and when they leave that range because
upside and downside has been delivered
on price
it makes it a balanced price range what
happens when it's done over the course
of a couple candles and not a multitude
of candles
think about it like this if I was in a
a live setting say if I was on a stadium
or not that's the main stadium if I was
on stage okay and I was in a room full
out of you okay I would right now ask by
a show of hands by raising your hand up
and you don't need to do it I can't see
you and there's something you're gonna
do it raise your hand if you have been
in trading long enough to remember what
a key reversal is
okay a key reversal would be a day where
it's like this
and
this right here all of this movement
here would be absent from the chart
and you would just see the market would
be here one day and then the next day
would be gap down here and then the next
day it would be gapped up here
all of this movement would be invisible
it would just be looking just like that
okay that is a key reversal or
a island reversal
very very classic old school dinosaur
type of trading and
that is essentially what I'm trying to
take your attention to because that
element of separation
that
once price goes to an extreme
which is what it's doing here because
see what we have here we have a low
we run through that low and we do it on
a very large candle and then we come
back all the way back over top of that
again
so these two candles right here
this represents a balanced price range
because it's reached down to a level and
it's offered on one single pass all this
move and the next candle over here one
single pass so the way I do this and I
Define it is this
which Which is higher
this candle's low
that moves back inside of this up move
of this candle excuse me
get this down close I'm sorry this down
movement on this candle
eats into this up close candle but only
to this point
this low or this low which one's higher
clearly this one
this is the only
candle that is defined
in the range that this candle goes lower
and this candle goes lower so what I'm
saying is the range is from here
to here extend it out okay so this makes
a balanced price range
all of this in here I don't care about
I could care less about that
what I'm looking at is this relationship
I'm not sure there must be the outline
yeah it is
so it's the bottom line
right
there we go so that's the balance price
range here
and what I'm what I'm trying to convey
to you
is that because we had single pass down
single pass up
this is balanced now once we leave it
here what that means is this range you
define it by what I just showed you here
the highest and the lowest extreme
between both of these up close and down
close candles this entirety of that
range
low
to high where are the bodies of the
candles over here stopping
kind of is some serious there ain't
it
that's algorithmic
all the bodies of these candles here are
respecting the midpoint of this balanced
price range how the can you go back
through any retail stuff and see this
being taught anywhere else it's not it's
not anywhere
these are things that you wouldn't learn
by any book none of that exists
anywhere this is stuff that's authorship
oh
so when I'm watching a balanced price
range or if I make mention of a balanced
price range what I'm suggesting to you
is that there is a definitive boundary
that at which I don't want to see
breached
on a
on a candle's body okay I don't want to
see it move Beyond this in this case we
were looking for what for
dollar move lower so a lower movement
dollar is what in other asset classes
risk on risk on is dollar lower so
dollar lower all foreign currency higher
and it gives the freedom for stock
indices to go higher knowing that the
dollar Index and index Futures are not
locked step you every Point higher is a
lower move in this or that it doesn't
move like that okay much like
um
when I taught bonds and the yields how
the yields will move
and they'll cause a long-term effect on
foreign currency
because they're going to chase that
yield but the yields can change
and the delay between all of that
shifting in the currency
it's not an immediate thing just like
commitment of Traders net Trader
Physicians just because the commercials
are net long doesn't necessarily mean
it's time for you to go long
so there's rules to all these things and
that's why it's important not just to
Simply watch one video or one lecture
and think you come away with
understanding it it doesn't work that
way
but
when I give a boundary to a Marketplace
and I code in a limitation of how far
the Market's going to go it's limited to
a degree of
this is how far you're allowed to go
but then the Wicks are permitted to do a
certain measure of of damage which is
what we're seeing right here
the halfway point of that range nobody's
going to look at this stuff here okay
and Define it like that
it isn't anywhere else okay
I I codified this so I want you to
understand that
these candlesticks are supporting the
idea of the principle I'm teaching to
you it's not limited to just this
it's happening every time I tell you
there's a balanced price range this is
the this is what's occurring the
Market's returning back to equilibrium
that's what this is here okay it's not
consequent encroachment it's not mean
threshold it's equilibrium a balanced
price range is going to go back to
equilibrium
the bodies in here are supporting that
as long as we don't get any close lower
there is no manual intervention if it
does there's manual intervention and you
abort it
this is just supporting the idea that
it's going to go higher so what you want
to see is you want to see the market one
two
move to the up move up and then create
more power three power three is
open down close rally close on the high
open drop rally close on the high
do we see it here drop small rally up
close
open drop down rally come back still
enough close
so much of a small little movement you
can barely see it but it up close we
open we drop down rally up close what is
order flow
what is the order flow at that time
is it bullish or is it bearish
bullish
at this time right here
right here okay on this candle's close
on the very next candle on a 15 minute
basis you can use power three on that
one fifty minute candle right there
as it opens it drops down
you can be buying anywhere in the upper
50 of this candle here and expect this
range here to stay open why
why would this be expected to stay open
you see this candle right here
this is the same thing occurring here
with more candles in between this is all
time distortion
I know this is too complicated this
give me a moving average I know I know
some of you were getting frustrated
because but you want to learn and I'm
willing to teach it to you but you don't
need everything but I'm teaching you how
I do these things how do I determine
when I'm doing live executions I say
this is going to stay open it's optimal
for this fair value you have to stay
open you're asking me to teach you so
I'm teaching you the same element of
delivery here and here
that one single candle right here
imagine this one candle if all these
candles from this candle here
to here we're compressed into one
interval it would be the same thing
happening right there just more candles
that's all it's happening so my eyes go
into this
to this so now let's use the same
criteria okay
Which is higher this low
or this love
This Love
so there's your we don't want to Anchor
to that okay
draw that down
come on
I use a it's not a mouse it's a
touch pad thing which is lower the high
of this candle
or the high of this candle
let me take this off you can see
the dog
this high
or this high
Which is higher this one
for this one
this one so this high in this
I'm sorry this low and this high is the
two reference points
but you want to expand it down you want
a full encapsulation like we did over
here for a balanced price range so this
is a lower FVG than this one
to what degree what measures the
distinction between this being lower
than that one it's this
candle here
in other words think of it like this
I know what I want to say I just can't
find the words to
they're escaping me
all right if we were looking at both
fear by gas like this
which one's higher
this one right
so to identify and map this out we use
this one
as the high and we drag it down to here
okay so all of this
is a balanced price range
it should never
it should never come back down and
through the midpoint of that meaning
there would be a small portion of this
Gap left open so let's play Devil's out
again for a moment say it went down into
this range I would not be concerned
about it doing a complete closure here
because we have this sphere value Gap In
this River you got that basically
overlap
in this range right there
so we have this portion here and over
here so this creates what
an island reversal
multiple candles that are segregated
from all the movement here and here
so how I internalize it is all of this
right here
was manipulation just like all of this
is manipulation
so the purpose was is to offset existing
liquidity
for the purposes of anyone that would be
profitable once we get above this high
it's all spending time down there to
allow offset longs to be taken out and
who would assume that position if
they're getting knocked out smart money
the market rallies
it admittedly balanced price ranges are
going to be requiring a lot of Education
a lot of teaching okay and I promise you
that
you don't need it but you asked me to
tell you how I know
certain FVG are going to
stay open and I'm not I'm not hiding it
from you I'm telling you these this is
it this is what I'm doing to do that
okay they're all principles and Concepts
that I'm using to implement to determine
when FVG are going to stay
up and I know I'm talking to you right
now over this chart it's after the fact
but I don't know how many of the
examples you've watched me trade where
I'm doing live examples I'm entering and
I'm managing the Stop and I'm taking
partials and hitting targets I don't
know how many of those examples I've
shown restore that you've seen but they
predominantly have been shared on
Twitter because I usually put music
behind them because you know I like to
do that but
I still show them on my YouTube channel
too but most of the time they're being
shared on Twitter because it allows you
to see a very small two-minute sometimes
less than two minutes and 20 seconds
compression of me executing
and every annotation I'm talking about
and showing if I'm talking about how a
fair value should be it would be optimal
for it to stay open and not close
I'm using that either as a breakaway Gap
these are the two primary functions okay
either I'm treating it as a breakaway
Gap and it should not close fully
meaning like this Gap here let me let me
draw it in
the charge Edition today
it's too good for the books
this Gap here
it should stay open
to be optimal that means it's the best
case scenario to see this stay open I
would say that about this one regardless
because it would be treated as a
breakaway Gap why because this over here
is a balanced price range and it's in
equilibrium and the body's supporting
that idea is seen here
then we see price moving here and then
we have this big extrapolation but yet
to take out this high
so this is the draw this is where price
would want to reach up to because
there's real liquidity above it what
kind of liquidity by side
this Gap is moving quickly away from all
this consolidation around equilibrium
based on that balanced price range
and I know some of your heads are
swirling right now like what the hell is
he talking about
example after example spend time with me
every time there's a balanced price
range I will bring your attention to it
okay I do it in live executions I talk
about it in advance I talk about it in
tweets I talk about it in reviews okay
the more time you see it
the more exposure you'll have to it but
for a breakaway Gap and some of you
thought I'd never get to this topic huh
a breakaway Gap is expected to form when
for instance say we're bullish on the
market
and you have identified a key level that
would support us
or be presented as support and that
is acting as a discount array
balanced price range at equilibrium
that's one of the PD arrays that is not
taught in the mentorship core content
where I show you the pdra Matrix and I
give you a spectrum of where they are
a balanced price range can exist in any
place in a discount or a premium so
there's no real definitive place where
they work in an hierarchy whereas the
hierarchy I show you in The pdre Matrix
the ones that are there that is a static
that is very finite they they nest in
that order but there are other PD arrays
like this one I'm showing you here and
like Event Horizon those things can
exist in any range of that Spectrum
which we Define as a discount or a
premium Okay so
and if you're brand new that just
completely win over your head but I
promise you dig into the the content and
it's there
don't try to think you're going to learn
how to do all this stuff right away and
you don't need to know everything you
don't need to know a FVG that
stays open you don't need that to be
profitable but I'm making it available
to folks that want to know everything
that I'm willing to share
so you asked I'm teaching you how to do
it so even if this didn't have this Gap
over here that creates a balanced price
range between these two favorite gaps
the fact that
it does this move here and creates the
Fairway Gap notice there is no Gap here
all through here until this candle forms
no Gap is there
everything is efficiently delivered
every previous high is touched every
previous high is touched
this one goes outside the range of it
and even goes deeper but then you have
this big extrapolation of The Upside
so this Gap here
even if this wasn't here as a fair value
got this Gap
that's shaded here
I'm being conscious of whether or not
this live stream is keeping up with
because I noticed the one on the 13th
when I was moving my cursor around what
I was talking about wasn't showing on my
cursor so I'm hoping that's not the case
here but the one that's shaded let's put
it that way I would treat that
regardless of the gap on the other side
here
whether that's there or not this is
classified to me as a breakaway cap
meaning that a breakaway Gap I don't
want to see it completely close in
it can come back down to half of it but
because there's a balanced price range
here I wouldn't want to see even half of
it traded to so then you would see me
say I want to see this trade
I'm sorry remain open it would be
optimal for this to remain open
but the very next candle here the same
thing you would expect it to do what you
can see it open
and then the previous candles High over
here overlapping this one that would be
otherwise a FVG if this would
make the low as low as it did here this
low completely returns back to debt the
candle's High
so any movement from here down into that
you could be a long entry or if you're
already long you can pyramid
so when you see me showing you a one
minute chart or a three minute chart
whatever time frame I'm utilizing I'm
showing you
I'm not trying to hide anything from you
but I've been very open and candid about
that I'm looking at other time frames
so this is a 15 minute Candlestick chart
if you were watching all this movement
from the open of this candle down to the
low of it and then we're watching it on
a one minute chart
it would be not so clear probably to
what it is it would be the factor for me
to trust that that drop down where some
of you might be freaking out thinking
you know it's hitting this area or this
area in that resistance or whatever
um
I don't I don't feel those problems or
fear because I'm trusting that the order
flow
is being supported by every candlestick
that's real order flow
all the candles are supporting each
other
there's no trend line required there's
no moving average required there's no
v-wop required nothing it's pure price
just pure price
and then we get one down closed candle
that happens after the high is taken out
here
where is it trade back down into
relative equal highs
all this overlapping in between this
area here
that is creating a very strong
balance price range in and itself all of
this movement in here is back and forth
back and forth so it's showing that it's
not willing to go below fifteen thousand
two sixteen
so was it what is it more likely to
explore
BS that's existing where would
that be
above here and keep pressing higher
so it's a matter of reading a lot of
things that if you're if you're really
not interested in becoming you know
versed in what it is I teach this is
where we depart where you're like okay
this is too much I'm not interested okay
it's just too much this can try this new
conjecture it's hindsight it's that but
I'm telling you everything that I'm
doing when i'm doing the executions and
the things I'm leaning on when I give
you the analysis like I did on the 13th
you know it's based on all these things
at the time when I'm looking at the
chart am I watching a a five second
chart a 15 second chart you know 30
second chart a five minute business a
five minute chart or an hourly chart all
these things I'm looking at
notice the things the same things that
I'm looking at are continuous
discount or premium
inefficiency or liquidity
the only the only separation from those
things for analysis purposes is the
relationship to the balance price range
or the lack of a balanced price range
did you pick that up
there there's there's no necessity for
you to understand the balance price
range just know that you will see things
that will
not present an opportunity for you
because you don't understand it
notice that you would not need this to
take any trades
it just gives you more clarity about how
to read PA and know where you
are in that PD Continuum
where are we at in relationship to where
price has been and where is it heading
what reference points is it using for a
new point of
buying where you can then break that
down in in the smaller fractals which is
what I've shown you here with each
individual candle power three
is essentially the the open if you're
bullish it's an open down move that you
want to go along in and that's the part
that Larry Williams was saying he didn't
understand how to do that and he made a
facetious comment saying that I don't
know maybe if you knew their
their zip code it will help which was
silly obviously but
um
it to me was like a personal challenge
like well if he can't do that I'm
going to spend my time trying to figure
that out so that's that's where I got
the idea of you know stripping down the
market and looking for discounted
premium
the opening price when it's bullish I
want to be looking at the open or less
the buy whereas at the time when I was
learning from his material he was
teaching and trading with real money
buying on strength so he would he would
buy
some measure of the previous day's range
usually 20 of the previous danger range
added to tomorrow's opening and if it
moved like that he would buy that and
consider that buying strength I tried
that and got my ass handed to me um I
just I could never make that work for
myself I'm not saying that
it doesn't work or that he didn't make
money with it because he clearly did
I couldn't make that work so I
understand when I teach a specific
concept and it might be the balanced
price range that you're probably looking
at this is too complicated
don't worry about it stick to the things
that make sense
I did the same thing I I had a love and
an adoration for Mr Williams when I was
learning all this stuff I've trusted
them with everything okay I was
literally throwing money in Brokers
accounts just to test a new thing I
learned that day okay so it was I
understand but it's like the the Fanfare
that comes around somebody that you have
a lot of affinity for but don't do that
with my Concepts you know and really
spend time with measuring what it is
that makes sense to you that you've done
the due diligence and back testing and
seeing what one of these PD arrays that
makes sense to you and the obvious ones
the easiest ones that you see that's the
one you spend the most time with and
you're most of you are going to
determine your model is linked to that
In Bloom where you're planted don't try
to Tinker with it too much all you're
trying to do is find something that
separates from where the market is right
now where it's likely to go and measure
risk that you can afford to take as a
loss and then you repeat that over and
over again and that's profitability
that's consistency that's continuity
which brings longevity you don't want to
be a one-hit wonder get a five figure
withdrawal from a funded account say
hell yeah I'm balling here that's not
that's not success
that's what everybody's treating it like
right now they want to get funded and
get a lottery win okay I'm not teaching
you how to be a lottery Trader I'm
teaching you how to be a long-term
consistently profitable Trader but that
doesn't happen overnight some of you
think you can make it happen like that
it doesn't work like that it doesn't
because you're going to bring in all
kinds of things that you have to wrestle
with then you're gonna you're gonna
swear up and down that you know
something I'm gonna teach or talk
or will teach is the replacement for
what you think is the the best thing for
you every time I bring something new
you're going to question the thing that
may be showing you evidence that this is
your model right now
don't let me sway you
with something new
it'll always be on the YouTube channel
whatever I'm teaching is going to stay
up but wherever you start seeing success
even in the early stages don't abandon
that you have to give yourself time and
you have to stick with something long
enough to know that you have a
foundation in it and you're going to see
that all these PD arrays lean and lean
on one another it's like a web
that all it's a whole entire structure
when I look at Price I'm seeing all of
it at one time
some of the things I want to see I have
to wait to see if they're going to
manifest and that's usually on the heel
end or backside of a high impact or
medium impact news driver
all right so
let's go into a five minute chart
excuse me
all right so we have
all the balance price range equilibrium
we have the Breakaway Gap we traded
above we have a down closed candle so
what is this
what's this down close candle
bull shoulder block does it have a fair
value Gap
right there
what time of day is that
1005 what time is that
that's your am session Silver-Bullet to
ICT Silver-Bullet you can trade this
Gap right here which would be
encapsulated here what time do you start
looking for and
an ICT Silver-Bullet trade
if you're trading in the one hour
spectrum of 10 a.m to 11 A.M you start
with your 15 minute down to five four
three two one if you don't see it in the
one minute or higher
drop down into the seconds charts if
you're adamant about finding one it will
be there it will absolutely be there let
me
let me tell you why okay here's the why
behind a solar bullet okay
there is always folks just like a
partial profit pays every time
it's a hundred percent profitable when
you take a partial profit it never fails
to pay you that's why I teach you to do
it you're always winning taking a
partial it never ever ever fails to put
more money in your account think about
that and there's dumbasses out there
that'll tell you taking partials is the
stupid they've ever heard because
you incur the initial risk and you take
less than you tried to make when you
first put the trade on you don't
know if that Market's gonna go there
Yahoo
and you as a new developing student you
have no idea is going to do that either
so when it gives you the opportunity to
take money out you do it any over time
doing that you learn more about yourself
you learn more to trust okay I've seen
this before let me let me expand outside
my comfort zone this is where I normally
take the majority of my trade-off let me
just take a small portion and move
myself to break even and graduate in my
experience and seeing what it feels like
to go into these scary moments but still
taking profits nobody no Buck
Rogers jumped out there and said I know
how to trade this is the model I'm going
to do and it's full bore full pool no
partials and I'm doing it all the time
that's an okay that's an
that tells you that and it's an
that's telling you to trade like that
you don't know when these markets are
going to have manual intervention you
have no idea when it's going to turn on
you nobody does that if I didn't if I
didn't
have the respect of the risk that's
available in these markets I wouldn't
use a stop loss
and I'm the guy teaching you I'm telling
you I get pissed off when I see students
sending me their screenshots of their
trades that are open the first thing I'm
looking for is where their stop loss is
and I usually bite my tongue because I
don't want to embarrass them but if
you're sending me tweets and you're
sending me your open profit trades
whether it be live or demo or funded
account if you don't have a stop loss on
here just know that I'm cringing
I'm cringing because you're not using a
stop loss that means you're
gambling you you assume that you're
absolutely right there's no way you can
be wrong and I don't even think that
I authored all this and I still
have to use a stop loss
because you don't know when chaos is
going to show up
you don't know when uncertainty enters
the chat
some unexpected event some bomb drops
somewhere someone declares w-a-r-u
paying attention
so
why do Silver-Bullets work
why will they form because there's
always going to be displacement
between 10 o'clock and 11 why
this is the part where you take notes
folks okay
in the hour of 10 o'clock and 11 o'clock
in the morning New York local time
what has happened already
The Market opens at 9 30. they're
opening bell I mean we've been trading
all night long but the opening bell
happens
ding ding ding everybody's now paying
attention everybody's clapping their
hands I've never understood what the
they're clapping for but the bottom
line is is that the Market's open
9 30 bills of ring now everybody's
rushing out there to buy and sell stocks
great
retail trader John Q public is watching
the ticker tape and he's saying okay my
stock opened up
two dollars more where it closed
yesterday this is amazing
I'm making money well that Gap is going
to close likely and then it drops down
then after that Gap fills if it fills at
all then there's new sentiment that
shifts okay it either overlaps that Gap
and breaks down then it treats the low
of the Gap as resistance and keeps going
lower or
it fills the Gap rallies up treats the
higher the Gap is support and then
continuously moves higher there's your
Gap Theory right there
use that with new week opening Gap new
day opening Gap any Gap any fair value
Gap any real liquidity void that's how
you treat it
now
what separates the support behind that
Gap is the consequent culture in the
midpoint how we trade there
at time of day
at 10 o'clock we have 30 minutes behind
us
which is why I tell you the 30 minute
opening range that's important
every every algorithm
uses that first 30 minutes
every one of them
they use that to refine a very specific
range to look for inefficiencies and
allow sometimes liquidity to form below
or above it and they'll do another path
go back below take stops out and then
run through
or don't return back into it at all
but just half of it
and then it runs higher or lower in
deference to whatever the bias would be
for that day
but the main takeaway is at 10 o'clock
you have 30 minutes of trading after the
opening bell so that initial flurry of
rush to do something
John Q public is doing their trading
then and they're usually apt to be wrong
so we allow for that to take place we
don't have any bias ahead of time okay
we don't care
and we wait and see where price delivers
from 9 30 to 10 o'clock
now at 10 o'clock
we refer to where we think price is
going to go anyway
where we've been calling price for
NASDAQ
I'm going to use the continuous
contractors to get a HTF
perspective
okay
BS liquidity here
[Music]
there and we have a order block
there why this one Michael
this one stretches down it's relatively
equal lows also I'm using that as a
reference point you wouldn't be wrong by
saying this one
okay I'm just using it because it's
lower so it's a lower hanging fruit
objective it doesn't mean it's going to
go there it just means that that's how I
would look at it like that
so if we have this
by side liquidity here as a potential
drawing liquidity
and then drop down into that with Tony
Green we're on
was it 15 minutes right
yes
we have this as a buy solid liquidity
and go back into what we're looking for
higher prices nonetheless
lower dollar
risk on
your dot higher pound dollar higher
and equities are permitted to trade
higher
our Focus was on ES
that's the one I've been teaching
through there was an on
filled or re
traded to
weekly imbalance of volume and balance
on the e-mini s p
NASDAQ has been the upside performer so
even though NASDAQ has already moved up
you could take trades in the ES
but if you're trying to take a trade
like if you want to use relative
strength analysis and you want to do
longs
the one you want to be trading is the
one that's showing the outperformance on
the upside which has been clearly the
leader in Tech so NASDAQ is in the
upside leader
BS will follow in suit by sympathy okay
so it's a sympathetic price rally it's
it's moving in concert with what has
been shown in NASDAQ and it has to catch
up to what es I'm sorry what NASDAQ has
done
for the purposes of making it clear I'm
going to use the
June contract because you'll remember
these inefficiencies
okay so here's the NASDAQ remember I
told you there's the inefficiency we've
already worked inside that one
if we look at it from the perspective of
the ES
we only went to this high and we have
yet to trade up into this inefficiency
so in my opinion you know we have much
more room to go up on the outside
now if you take that insight and you add
it to the new front month
based on the volume we have this
here
okay so that's the this is the month
that we're trading in for ES and then we
add it to NQ again
we can't pull that out because of the
the data is not being there so I'm
referring that to
the previous month that will be expiring
knowing that we're likely to continue
but I fall away from the analysis from
NASDAQ and we're like more so on the es
because es should move sympathetically
higher to try to catch up
that's the theory of Six Sisters Six
Sisters we have the leadership in NASDAQ
but in es es will try to move in concert
with so we may see in the future a a
consolidation or a lack of leadership on
NASDAQ and then
more upside offered on a bigger day move
on like ES
it might not happen but that's how I
treat the six sister so as long as the
leadership issue goes higher which is
NASDAQ that should pull up looking for
instance all boats rise in high tide
that's the that's the moniker I'm using
here this everything goes up when the
tie goes up so
but if you contrast that with with the
the Dow
is doing
this thing's lethargic it just doesn't
want to join the party at all
but we were able to see it in a while
our Run Tour
High here
on NASDAQ
I told you I was waiting for CPI on the
June 13th live stream
um I was aware that the CPI number could
potentially cause a big dive lower for
the person to SS but it would
just be the purpose of taking out stops
and then resume that was the whole
premise when I talked about NASDAQ you
can go and watch live stream that's
there in the commentary and it was a
similar idea with es it was probably
wait and see the only thing I was
definitive on on stock indices at the
time of that live stream at the 18
minute and 49 second time period I
pulled up this chart here and I said
that 39 628 would be the Drone liquidity
which is in the first High
and that's where we saw it draw up into
and it stopped pretty much right after
that
retrace lower
and now we're piercing it again
um
I don't trade the Dow I use it as a
barometer like I use the dollar Index so
I'm looking at the relationships between
the three averages so if this is
typically you understood as Dow Theory
which I think in
obviously using stock indices it works
it's a proven method and it's comparing
the averages they should confirm one
another and I'll show you what I mean by
that let's pull up the es chart
and we'll pull it up on a so this is
what I'm thinking we're going to reach
up to so that way we know if in case I
lose track of what I'm saying I think es
is going to pull up into 4500 or just
below it so there you go you have an
expectation of what I think
we're reaching for I know someone's
reached out and told me that Larry
Williams is calling for you know
retracement or moving lower I don't see
that happening until we get up to here
for at least yes
and I'm happy to be wrong to you know
against his analysis but you know I'm
sharing what what I think
all right here's a 60 Minute chart and I
still want a 15 minute chart I failed to
mention earlier a 15-minute chart is a
Bellwether chart
like it's to me like if I was forced to
do anything less than a
a daily chart
and I couldn't do anything below a daily
chart
and just use one time frame it would be
the 15 minute chart
like it gives you the best of the best
in terms of short-term entries and
targets because everything you can find
on The Daily you'll see it on this if
you compress enough you'll you'll have
better refinement of those level levels
too you can get short-term trades you
can day trade you can scalp you can
enter into long-term position trades
it's the the
it's the time frame it does all
I'm not limited or satisfied with that
because that's why like I go into lower
LTFs even sub one minute
like in the seconds charts I don't
advise the new people to do that because
you can read into
15 and 5 and 10 and 30 second charts
thinking you see something there that on
an hourly chart
is like Rocket Fuel and boom you know
these things can move like 40 handles on
something on a HTF basis
on a news driver and you're thinking
you're seeing a FVG on a 30
second 15 second you chart and get
roasted
all right so anyway
yes here on a 15 minute basis
you click on this little thing up here
for com compare
and you're going to type in or find it
in here but I'm going to show you how to
do because assuming you don't have it on
your chart yeah
NQ u2023
if you do it like that it's going to
plot it right over top of your chart I
don't like that okay what I do is I go
over here and I set it to and I know
some of you are going to say well if you
do this you do I know I know
foreign
candlesticks
you can do it on a line basis
but I'm going to show you the
Candlestick version okay
yeah I did it wrong
I have it set up as a template I've been
spoiling myself with it
you can create little templates over
here
and we'll set this on new pane
new pane puts it down below the price
and you want to do it with a dow also
and I don't see the Dow here so
now if you're going to use it as a as a
line chart
since we're looking at lows okay this is
how you back test you study it and get
your screenshots of it if we're bullish
and you're expecting it to see a
rotation higher in some Divergence which
would be smt diversion
you're plotting on the low
so you're comparing the relationship of
the low of es or whatever when you're
using this will be my trading instrument
and then for Nasdaq I'm plotting this
line chart on the basis of the close
I'm sorry on the low rather and same
thing with the
the down
you're going to do it on the well
and then squeeze it up a little bit
and you want to compare the low do we
see a lower low here on the NASDAQ we do
and it looks like we see a lower low on
the Dow so there's no smt diversions
there
same thing here
lower low respectively
lower low respectively so if we see a
time when there's a
lower low in your trading instrument
whether say you're trading es or you're
trading NASDAQ
when you compare the other averages
against it if you're long or wanting to
go long you want to plot this and if it
gives you a Divergence it acts as
a qualifier I can you can take and you
will take trades without smt but when
smt forms or Divergence against the
averages or if you're using it against
the
the dollar against the Euro or the pound
versus the URL which is a correlated
pair smt that versions when you're
looking at two closely correlated which
is essentially what we're doing here
it's this is a
uh
correlated pair smt but with index
features if they were considered payers
of correlated pair smt the versions
would be euro dollar
making a lower low while pound dollar
makes a higher low when Dollar is
bearish
that would mean dollar goes lower and
the one that makes the failed lower low
that's the relative strength leader that
was the one you would be going long in
in either Euro or pound whichever one
makes the the failed lower level
so there's a lot of measuring that goes
on when I'm watching PAs
if you
heard me many times mention I have a lot
of monitors okay you don't need a lot of
monitors but you need to be able to have
at least two charts open that could be
done on the laptop like I was showing
you here earlier or it could be a
secondary monitor you know in your
system
it's very very difficult to trade
on your cell phone
okay it's not impossible I mean I've
done it but
you are literally looking through
a very small window
of what is going on and it's very easy
to get
fixated on whatever you're seeing in
that small little four inch universe or
whatever your instrument is or tablet or
phone is
you're missing out on a lot of
information and the way I trade is I
look at all these other things I'm
showing you here today
each monitor has its own real estate
what it's responsible for What markets
to follow what time frames I have on
here all of those things I'm monitoring
I'm constantly getting a new refreshed
view of everything from the higher time
frame down
across a lot of markets that are closely
correlated so I'm using inter-market
relationships and
intra Market relationships so that way
there's a relationship between how
markets are either positive correlated
or inversely correlated and they should
agree on the most part I'm allowing for
this discrepancy or cracking correlation
where it's expected to form I do not
look at charts okay this is very
important I never look at charts for the
purposes of finding an smt diversions
look at the lows here
we have a higher low here
we have a higher low here but we have
the lower low on Dow see that okay here
that's a Divergence as SNT diversions
I used to when I was younger when I was
first dabbling into this I would only
look for it to form and trade based on
that
and I had my hands handed to me
it's only when you know where the
Market's likely to draw to it creates a
real measure of accumulation and
distribution
Larry Williams has a accumulation
distribution formula which when I first
learned about it I fell in love with it
and and for Commodities in you know
HTF price moves four hour
and daily I found that it was really
good but eventually you know it's just
didn't work as well as I wanted it to
and didn't form enough but I was using
it as a means of getting into some of my
trades when I would look for something
to go along the qualifying thing was the
50-day moving average would be bullish
in other words it's sloping up
and then I would look for an oversold
condition on an hourly chart with a
stochastic and the Williams percent are
being oversold than the very next day I
would look at the opening and as long as
it dropped from the opening price damn I
would chase that going into longs so I
would be on there buying it buying it I
would never want to go short I was
afraid to short I didn't know him I
didn't understand how to short so
everything I did was primarily gone long
so my model would be supercharged if I
saw a accumulation distribution bullish
Divergence
so I don't want you thinking that it's a
Magic Bullet okay where all you have to
do is look for a Divergence and that's
your entry because Divergence is as you
saw earlier when I was showing you the
euro dollar events against the dollar
Index
um there was a smt diversions at the
time that would have been a qualifying
thing for me to say I'm done and I
wouldn't hold for the trade anymore
but you watched the dollar rotate go
lower and the euro dollar make it even
higher high so I would have missed
whatever that movements and if it's even
going higher I don't know I haven't seen
it since we talked about it but the
just for the purpose of smt alone that
Divergence does not mean anything
coupled with profit taking when it meets
the time of day where you should be
trying to you know close up shop or at
least try to get the majority of your
trade in in real profit and not open
profit where you actually take partials
and now you're booking that profit that
to me is more meaningful in the sense of
using it or if it does form an entry
with the smt diversion at the time of
day and it fits the criteria and your
drawing liquidity hasn't been reached or
targeted has been reached for yet then
then it's more meaningful to use it but
being in and of itself it's useless
okay it has to be used at the proper
context and I see a lot of new folks
that have just recently gone through
some of my stuff they're like you know I
don't hear you or see you talking about
smt
it's not required you know it's really
not it's just one of those things that
if it's there wonderful you know
um I don't look at cot every single day
I take a trade you don't need it it's
just a qualifying thing that just adds
more support to it if you're a long-term
position Trader
and you want to trade that way
commitment of Traders and seasonal
Tendencies coupled together
with what I was showing you here
that is a that's a winning recipe like
that that is a really good model and
just use the entry models that I've
taught like with the 2022 model or even
the Silver-Bullet trades
and you thought I wasn't going to answer
the thing you started to talk about why
Silver-Bullets
form and how how the deforming why is it
there they're always going to be there
because of
the first 30 minutes of
PD you have 30 minutes now
in the marketplace
The Rush The Mad Dash to get in and do
something to buy and sell that's already
in the marketplace now
the initial the initial surge of
institutional orders being thrown out
there for their clients or their own
that's in the market now too
so now we have 30 minutes behind us the
initial impulsiveness that usually comes
into the marketplace is now behind us
and now we're in the First full hour
of trading after the bow
the first 30 minutes is done
that's like the Asian range okay
now we have the real move London
think about it in the 24-hour cycle kind
of probably confusing some of you but
the long-term students know what I'm
talking about I'm looking at that that
range of
the intraday movement on the morning
session as the same impulsiveness that
comes into London where there's a lot of
volume that comes in in Forex that same
thing occurs in that first full hour of
10 to 11.
they all want to make a Mad Dash to find
profitability
and a lot of the algorithms wait for
that first impulsiveness to run higher
or lower and that inefficiency that you
find on the time frames and the models
I'm showing you they all dog pile on it
they're all dog piling on that one there
so
it's not a measure of the selling or
buying pressure that's pushing it it's
the algorithm itself is offering it to
them
it's going to move from that fair value
Gap to wherever it's going to go
regardless of how many people buy or
sell into that guy
it's it doesn't make a difference
everything in price is scripted it's
completely manipulated it's absolutely
controlled and the only thing you're
trying to do is look for that small
little inefficiency when you know where
you're aiming for you're aiming for some
HTF Target
like we outlined for a euro dollar and
the dollar Index
if you have a HTF bias
and we know that that's a directional
bias that's looking for a reason to go
higher
it would make sense for us to expect
some kind of run higher from 9 30
going into 10 o'clock
in looking backwards in seeing in that
price run higher was there any
inefficiency or fair value you got
if there is then we can use that as an
entry that has to happen
at 10 o'clock
till 11 o'clock
the FVG doesn't have to form
in itself inside of that one hour period
it can refer back to some Fairway Gap
that formed you know in the run-up if
it's bullish between 9 30 and 10 o'clock
and if you're bearish and you're
expecting it to move lower the fair
value Gap could form in the move from 9
30's opening down to 10 o'clocks low so
that price leg wherever the fair value
would reside there it can return up into
that many times you're going to see a
lot of the trades that I've taken in the
past if you go I I was one of the things
I want to ask you as a community I know
some of you out here save everything I
do and I love you for that
has anybody got a full collection of
every single execution I've ever made
public
because I I don't know where they're at
once I put them out on Twitter like I
don't know how to find them there's a
lot of them I just don't know where
they're all at if someone could like
create a
I don't know maybe
a thread
and throw them on that that'll be
awesome I'll retweet it if you do it but
the I would like to see them all and
you can see a lot of things I'm teaching
you will make much more sense to you now
that I'm I'm teaching you like this
you'll go back and say oh there it
is I can see he just talked about that
there it is he's doing it but in the
early stages I wasn't trying to teach a
lot of that because you know I even told
my private mentorship groups I said look
you know I'm gonna demonstrate it but
I'm not gonna go into into detail about
what it all is until some jackasses want
us to go out there and start selling my
videos so now I killed that whole show
and put the core content videos up on my
YouTube channel that's known that's
another reason why it's not coming down
when I leave in November
so anyway
um
we talked about
gold too and when I do gold and I'll
I'll teach you the FMC setups and we're
done for today
let's go into gold let's go to a daily
chart
and
I always use forex.com I don't have an
account with them that's just the feed I
go with and I trust that one
I don't look at Orlando or pepperstone I
don't use any of these other ones it
helps provide
a consistent medium for everyone because
especially if we're using
Forex if you look at different Brokers
they're going to have a different
opinion about what the high and low was
right
all right so anyway gold
I at first when I opened it up I said
you know I wouldn't touch it I wouldn't
I don't know
but like I always do I say gun to my
head
I said I think we're gonna go below the
SS here these relative equal
loads
so again you can find that at the 20
minute and five second
marker of the June 13th 2023 video with
analysis okay so let's go into this and
we'll segue into the four oh not the
Forex but the FOMC how to trade it and
it's the same premise that I'm going to
teach you that it's the same application
whether you're trading non-profit
payroll or
um
FMC they're treated the same way FOMC
generally is a much more larger
magnitude of a move but there's they're
using the same macro they use the same
thing it always happens the same way
it's just a much more muted
event when it's NFP so
anyway I took your attention into these
relative equal lows I said okay I think
it's going to go there
so that's what I thought was going to be
the draw that's where I thought we would
reach for and I didn't say anything
beyond that okay I didn't say anything
lower I didn't say anything higher I
said you know this is we're going to
reach for
so that was said to you on the 13th of
June so let's go into a 15 minute chart
we'll get through this one pretty quick
[Music]
take a 10 minute break and then I'll
come back and teach you how to trade
FOMC and NFP
and then we'll bid each other farewell
[Music]
okay
all right so this line is that level
from the daily chart which is the
relative equal lows it's the
1938.20 level
okay and
we would be looking for a drop down when
you're going lower and I should have
dropped into a 60 Minute chart when I
drop into a 15.
okay so those are those relative equals
from the daily but now seen on an hourly
chart
and
you can see on the 13th we created
another low here so resting below here
was a large pool of what kind of stops
sell stops why would they be sell stops
down there because look at the movement
from here up
Traders are going to chase that it goes
down they see it doesn't go here and it
rips one more time so what are they what
are they trying to sell the idea of when
I say they it's the real market makers
it's the folks that are controlling
price and yes gold is one of the highest
manipulated instruments there is it's
literally a joke and that's why I don't
like trading it I know a lot of you like
to ask about all the time but this one
is extremely manipulated it's like the
Japanese Yen like I can't stand it okay
it's so absolutely ridiculous how
controlled it is I choose not to touch
it and just like the Swiss franc too
good grief he's leaving everything
the weather this low and this low their
cell stops below this low sells though
so they were selling the idea that this
is a trading range and buy everything
think about it there's so many people
out there on YouTube they're still
making videos like this today
I have a range here every time I get to
the low end of the range you got to buy
it and you can make money every time and
all of a sudden
I did that kind of stuff
at 20 years old I did all that
the indicators and the oscillators will
tell you every single one of these loads
at the perfect oversold condition and
that's what tricks you
so when I stopped looking at the market
like that and looked at it from
liquidity or inefficiency then I didn't
rely on the Uber oversold I could see a
robot oversold relative to the range
that we're trading in which is really
what mathematically is being done and
tortured in in indicators like you're
defining a look back period generally 14
period 10 period nine period and then
you're
basing that range as high as high and
low is low and where you're at in
relationship to that so you need an
oscillator to tell you that like this
right here we're above 50 of this High
to that low
below these lows is SS liquidity
the gun to my head I told you that's
where I think we're going to trade to so
is it higher
after the 13th when I told you that no
it only went up
to go to a short-term premium
the short-term premium is relative to
this high
down that low
at equilibrium
or higher as a premium
we're definitely in a premium okay so we
don't need to see an oscillator tell you
it's over bar oversold it's defined by
that
if you pulled up a Williams for sonar 10
period or a stochastic it's going to
show you overbought right there I don't
need to see that I already know it's
there once you understand how to read
price and read what range you're in
presently
it's easy to identify what is a robot or
result and you don't need any indicator
to tell you that you don't need to see a
moving average crossover or a macd to
tell you where Market flow or Market
momentum is pointing
look at what it's doing
it's building a narrative that this is
supposed to be trusted as support
and that's building
in engineering SS liquidity
so when that occurs
and I'm sure some of you watched it
rallying up here and thought you know on
the 14th ict's got it wrong
and the only thing I did is trade up
into a premium and then wipe out
they ran right for those cell stops what
was the reaction after it did that look
where we're at now
now I'm not suggesting that there isn't
opportunity in this market or there
wasn't an opportunity because there
really was
I don't want to trade in these Market
environments there was a time as a young
man in my 20s I wanted to capture these
moves from here to here and here to here
and here to here I wanted to be in
everything
and I discerned that
while it's possible I didn't have the
aptitude to be able to do that yet and I
lost money in blue accounts trying to do
that trying to learn how to do it with
real money
it does not work you have to know what
you're doing and be bored with the
things that you're doing in that process
over and over and over again before you
even think about putting real money in
there so anyway let's take a closer look
with the 15 minute time frame now we
have that context
at two o'clock yesterday
there was an event that took place
and what event was that
FOMC right
so at two o'clock
whenever there's an FOMC
event
it's to be treated
in two stages
okay
this is going to be a general rule of
thumb it will serve you more times than
not
you will lose money on it eventually if
you push it every single time I promise
you that but if you go back and study
old moves you'll be quickly convinced
that what I'm about to tell you my
long-term students know this and we
expect it all the time I had two folks
tweeted me yesterday who I unfor I I
can't I can't deal with people if you're
going to come in and you show me this
type of
perspective or mindset you are not ready
to learn from me so I I just block them
it's not because I don't want to take
heat from people because I'm my best
trolls my biggest trolls are not blocked
by me so it's not a thin-skinned type
thing I I don't have time or energy to
deal with people that are close-minded
and if you're brand new and you come to
me on Twitter
and I share an example of me executing
I hate seeing all after the fact again
or someone supporting that idea
immediately you're showing me that you
are not there to learn or you're not in
the proper mindset so I broom you quick
I get rid of you
um
if you think you know everything or if
you think I owe you an execution to put
you into a trade that you can copy me
you don't know who I am I'm not
promising you that and that's one of the
biggest things a pet peeve I don't want
anybody being able to copy me
I got people constantly asking me what's
the color of your candles I know why
because they want to take the videos
like this one that doesn't have a
watermark on it and anytime I do an
execution unless I have my watermark in
it you know they invariably find their
way on to tick tock they're on Instagram
they're on Facebook they're on YouTube
under somebody else's thing saying they
took the trade so I don't like that okay
I know I know my own trades I don't need
the like they can you can block out
everything I know who who's trading that
if I'm looking at I know it's me
and everybody else can recognize when
I'm trading because you know it is what
it is
but I don't want people copying me so if
you're new like this is the first time
you listen to me
I call things before it happens and
people will tell you it's easy to do
that anybody can do that but these same
people are all day long saying well we
gotta watch and see what's going on up
here oh well it could go down here you
got to be careful oh no it's getting
tight in here and all of a sudden after
the fact they'll say I did not call this
stuff no I say gun to my head this is
what the gonna happen and there
it is even if I'm not certain I will
tell you what side I'm on and I'm
comfortable being wrong in those
instances but when I don't say a gun to
my head and I say this is where I think
it's going to happen bet your
ass is going there okay that's what's
happening so I'm not in this business to
try to have an opportunity for all of
you to copycat me I am in this business
to tell you how to do this
I don't need to be doing this but I want
you to succeed but you will not succeed
by copying me or trying to get money
right now because you're short on change
and that'll inspire you to do if you
don't want to learn how to do this by
what I've already shown or taught or see
my students doing nothing's going to
convince you so that's why I I
distinguish the the grade of student
that comes to me the people that just
simply want to listen learn and practice
and put the time into it they're not
going to complain and they're not going
to ask for more than I've already given
and that's the people I'm teaching
that's the people that keeps me coming
back here
I broom entitlement I get rid of that
I don't want I don't have any
tolerance for it and you can have the
opinion of me whatever you want I don't
care but I'm the only out
here that's telling you where it's going
to go precisely every single week and
I'm asking nothing for it nothing
I'm I'm here all day today
so just know
that you're not obligated to be here and
not sure as and I'm going to
teach you any of this I love doing it
but I if if you come to me on social
media
and you talk that nonsense to me with an
entitlement mindset or oh it's after the
fact and you didn't go through the
process of hearing me explain how all
these things happen I've already taught
how this works and the reason why I'm
saying this because I'm about to teach
you how to trade FOMC and it's the same
thing with NFP
same macro that's being utilized okay
it's a two-stage macro that means it's a
first run and then reversal okay it
doesn't happen every single hundred
percent of time but most of the time
unless they intervene that's what the
macro will do
it will go to levels as you watch me
call out on the CPI
I told you where the FVG was
I told you where the two pools of
liquidity the very specific elements
that led to that delivery at CPI
it happened
you can't trade it it's happening too
fast and the broker will not let you get
filled anybody that shows you them
getting filled that is a white
label fake mt4 horseshit it's fake it's
fake it's fake I don't give a who
you are it's fake you are not getting
filled on those things it's not
happening period
but if you wait until these reports come
out
in that first initial Surge and they put
the the availability of the trade back
in place
all Brokers pull their they don't
they don't want to be getting caught on
the the wrong side of some goober that
got lucky
that's the reason why it happens folks
it's not because nobody wants to trade
it or they're scared they the broker
doesn't want to have that incurred risk
that's the reality that's it that's
what's going on okay but they caught
something else because think about when
you look at that perspective it's like
you you know I could be making
money right here and you're preventing
yeah that's exactly what they're doing
they're saving their own ass they're
protecting themselves and guess what I'd
be doing the same thing
because you can get lucky
I got lucky
I got lucky for months early on I did
and then found out I didn't know
so would it make sense for someone that
has millions of dollars available and
you
customer deposits and they are over
leveraging that
30 to 1.
and they get right on an over leverage
position on a big fast runner 100
Handles in NQ you know 50 Handles in the
ES
come on man like you wouldn't take that
risk on either so you can't fault them
but it's just the reality of this
business it is what it is
but you don't need that first initial
search it's better for you to wait
and they paint all these scenarios with
the first initial run
oh it's going to keep going lower or
what's going oh it's going to keep going
higher so think about it like this at
two o'clock
we see gold
do this run here rips lower
remember this is the low I told you it
was going to go to did it go to it at
two o'clock
it's a 15 minute Candlestick by the way
it drops down but falls short of the
objective and then leaves this low in
this low as relative equal lows and then
it rips up higher
What's Happening Here
what's occurring
it's setting the stage for
traders that suspect that this is
support we can go long it's going to
Rally
that's not what we want to see
go into
the the expectation I'll teach you where
the FVG or the imbalance
it drops leaves this inefficiency right
here
when it drops it comes back up into it
there
to offer an opportunity to go short and
then it delivers where I sit on the 13th
which is that relative equal lows on the
daily chart it digs into it here
lower lower one more good time and then
rips higher today
all of this PA in here I I'm
telling you I would not be in any of
that
I didn't at all if I was looking at Gold
real time I would have told you that
it's possibly going to go here but I
wouldn't touch it and that's the honest
God truth I ask any of my long-term
students I say this all the time about
gold
I don't know what it is this fascination
with trading gold but there are better
markers to trade than this
but that two stage or a second stage of
delivery after 2 30. see the first move
is like a
a red herring hey pay attention over
here look at all this okay and then at 2
30 that's the real move
that's the real one okay so it can it
can come in two forms it can go
rally up suck everybody in thinking it's
going go lower and then wipes them
completely out and goes lower a lot
or it can drop lower
get everybody thinking at two o'clock
that it's going lower and then at 2 30
it rips and takes out the height it was
formed prior to drop
okay that's the buy or sell in that way
the other thing is where it drops down a
lot leaves a fair Bay Gap and at 2 30
it'll go back to the FVG
then the real run comes
most times most times it does not do
this
usually it creates a run One Direction
and that direction is a complete Judas
swing where it runs creates a high it
doesn't come back to that high and just
makes a lower low in the day
ES
two o'clock I know I've got people
sending me messages saying that the
title is wrong
I know it'll be changed I mislabeled my
notes Friday and everything since then I
mentioned that earlier in the recording
of the two o'clock is the initial leg
of FOMC
we dropped
rallied higher FVG
drops down rips up higher and then
one more time drops lower
if you look at the first move going into
a clock
what is the first move
it's dropping down
so it's setting what what's the
expectation what's retail going to think
it's going to keep doing
lower
this FVG is utilized twice
two times
trades into here rallies they dig into
it again today one more time and then
they send it higher
on NQ
this will be much more impactful because
I actually executed on it
it's all I'm sorry
all right so we have
yeah um we started where should yeah so
this is the NQ and I want to take
everything off this
[Music]
strip it down to nothing
all right
so here we have NQ NASDAQ delivery
contract month is September
inside this drop
okay
think about what I've talked about here
think about what I've been talking about
for weeks in relationship to es even the
s p and the NASDAQ futures contract
which of those two has been the
leadership on the upside
which one has the strongest price
delivery for being bullish
and Q NASDAQ
so if we consider
trading FOMC doesn't it make more sense
if we want to go long why would we want
to go along
what was the move that took place on
the drop down into two o'clock it's
dropping at two o'clock
so here's your fake move
so this drop down here and then they
hold it here holding it holding holding
holding it and at 2 30
the macro begins
so when you're Trading FOMC
if you're not writing this down you're
completely wasting your time
you have to know which of the indices
that you're going to trade because of
relative strength which one's stronger
there's always going to be a leadership
issue whether it be NASDAQ or ES
Dao okay if it's Dao I just
go to ES
if it's NASDAQ I will trade NASDAQ over
ES
if it's anything leading to the weaker
or the stronger for the Dow
I always elect to use the Es as a
deferment I defer myself to trading only
yes not the the down
so if it's a matter of picking which
entity I'm trading it's either decision
of whether trading the NASDAQ and it has
to be the leadership on the upside that
means it's been going up longer Harder
Faster than ES
if es is going up longer Harder Faster
than NASDAQ if it was reversed in its
role I would have taken this trade in es
and not NASDAQ
so the first delivery at two o'clock was
seeing price do what drop down I want to
go into a five minute chart
when this Market dropped here what was
the where was the most energetic
price leg beginning from
here
at this big move here I'm not saying
that you can't see this one as a high or
this is a higher this is a high but this
is the most energetic so all of this
starts the Run going into FOMC
so anyone that's in this move wears
their stop loss
right about that short-term High
I'm aware
but remember I'm listening to this guy
tell me how to run my pool
and I'm not really paying attention to
him and I'm trying to get an example on
FOMC and I'm doing it with my phone
which is what you see on my Twitter feed
okay
tools playing in the background it's
what it is okay so
I think it's going to go up here but I
can't pretend to be listening to this
guy and watch all this watch all this
stuff happen as it's going on so I
picked a very easy target low hanging
fruit objective which is going to be the
buy stops resting Above This short-term
High
why was I going long in here what was I
looking at
this move here
I'm sorry this movie this down closed
candle here
all of this movement in here back and
forth
I'm treating that as like a very small
little bounce price range it's going
back and forth back and forth so I'm
trusting that there shouldn't be any
more meaningful run below that if we
take out that candle's High
we have it here
so we take it out High
that low now becomes that's it there's
no more need for any more risk going
lower the the stage is set because what
time is it
the first stage of that delivery in the
strongest of all the indices which is
the NASDAQ
I'm not looking at or caring about es
I'm not looking or caring about the Dow
I'm not looking at relationships between
the smt I don't care about that
it's time
the macro will run on time it's going to
favor
this Market because it's been
outperformed on the upside so it's
its sponsorship is heavily on this one
going up versus the es like it's been
doing for weeks
and the Dow has already proven it's
lethargic
it's not interested in performing like
the es and or not even close to NASDAQ
so all Focus would be on NASDAQ
so
buying going long
right here what am I keying off of
look at the arrow where I entered
and what I've already told you
this body of this candle the last down
closed candle
I'm using as Bella by the way
this movement down into here
I'm buying that right there right there
bought that then I'm using this right
here this opening price and inside this
little area here I want to use that as a
means of wanting to go long on a pyramid
so I went along with five contracts
which is not a lot
and I added another one which is I'm
pilloring
what am I aiming for here
just before we get to this High because
during FOMC it could do this wild whip
saw still and then deliver up I want to
get in or I'm sorry I want to get out of
my trade as it approaches this high low
hanging fruit I don't need it to go to
the high or higher to get a fill
there's my exit on this candle here all
this rundown is completely wiped out
ultimately taking out
that high here
over here
two stages
NFP is the same way
it either gives you a drop
come back to a fair bag Gap and continue
or it gives you a drop and completely
reverse and rip higher everything
reversed
the difference in knowing which one it
is is how it trades at the time which is
why I have to wait I have to see what
it's doing
how it delivers and compare it to the
other averages
that's what I'm looking for I'm looking
for that relationship between the other
it's not smt I'm looking at how who's
been leading the pack higher or lower
whenever these reports come out
and then I'm looking for where the
liquidity is
traders that were trying to chase this
they're trapped down here
they're hoping it's going to go lower
back up it goes
go back and look at your calendar
and every time there was a FOMC radio
announcement and NFP study
how that liquidity is taken
study that it's always a two-stage macro
it always does something initially
that gets people thinking it's going to
do something specific and then it rips
their face off
CPI is that macro on steroids
on crack on meth okay it's it's
literally like cocained up
the same macro
and you can't trade that
you can't okay you can't so
all these high impact news drivers and
or medium impact news drivers if you're
afraid of those
just wait 30 minutes minimum make wait
30 minutes after they form and then see
what liquidity resides in the
marketplace still in any inefficiency
and if it offers you a range that
presents
potential to see 10 handles then you
probably have a good chance of making
five out of it
or maybe even more so it's a there's a
lot of
waiting around to see what happens on
these big impact news drivers because
you don't know and I don't know before
it happens how they're going to use that
information to manipulate it
because they want people chasing this
idea at the moment
and they know that Brokers are pulling
liquidity
not that there is an absence of trading
or interest it just means that all the
Brokers are collectively saying the hell
with this we are not getting caught on
the wrong side
because
if they get a client or a large base of
their clients that are over leveraging
and everybody predominantly over
leverages you know you do it too
what happens if they're right on a big
move day
the Brokers are out
they're not trying to do that so
wait wait for that initial shock and
Trust the fact that you don't need that
first move to make money you don't need
it
wait for the the first move in two
o'clock at FOMC and then
230 then it's going to rip the other
direction
that's that's what it is that's exactly
what happens it's kind of like
well I don't want to say it in the live
stream because I think my channel might
get flagged but I've said the analogy
before on Twitter and stuff and I'll
talk about it this weekend in a shotgun
Saturday I'm sure you're all wondering
what it is it's not a big deal it's just
it's a analogy I use
that has something to do with making
individuals run to a specific area and
then attacking that once they get there
for a larger impactful you know event
that's that's what I mean by two stage
so it's designed to Corral Traders into
one big area
make them think it's going to do a
specific thing so that way there is a
pool of liquidity that's being
sacrificed and then that liquidity is
being used for a counterparty so it's
tricking traders to go in the wrong
direction and then breaking them across
the coals the other direction
that is going to be it for today we went
through my entire hit list of everything
and I was a little bit short on my time
two o'clock that's pretty good isn't it
you got some
got some value today
I talked about a lot of things that
hopefully will amplify
some of the misunderstandings or or
shortcomings in terms of your learning
and I amplify the own things that I know
I get a lot of requests for Breakaway
gaps and introduced more insight about a
balanced price range
and
preached that we focus on understanding
which one is the leadership and when
does it matter when does it really
matter to be in the the one that's a
leadership because you see ICT trading
the yes
even though I told you NASDAQ weeks ago
was a strong one so why aren't you
trading that one because I'm teaching
you how you can still find profitability
if you did it wrong if you found
something
as a setup and you didn't confer with
the relationships between the averages
okay or if you're a Forex repair Trader
you didn't do the relationships between
which is stronger the British pound
versus the US dollar or the euro versus
the US dollar
you want to be in the stronger one if
you're going long you want to be in the
weaker one if you're going short
well when it matters most is when we
have these high impact news drivers
because they're going to really
capitalize in Wind these markets out
when they are the leadership issue look
at the relationship between
the NASDAQ here
in es
you see it right away don't you
it was not able to climb as high look
look at here here to here okay
I'm going to take you back to the NASDAQ
see that higher that's why ICT was
buying this one and not ES
and you know funded account
traders that have you found their way
into
I guess the part where they can make
money and then take the money that
people pay in and call themselves you
know paid out whatever that is a trade
right here that they could do
it's not the maximum number of contracts
available that they can trade it's less
than and that run right there is
equivalent to twenty three thousand
dollars
so you you tell me is it worth the
gamble of trying to guess before the
fact
or waiting for the initial
you
impact crater to form and then you go
over there and find the people that you
can pick the pockets of that you know
they're dead already you don't know it
and you go there and you take their
money from their accounts and get out
and walk away
I'll leave you with the idea of that
being a good analysis or not but I'm
usually the action guy that you know
sees things from a Rambo perspective
that's just the way I look at things but
the if you want to look at it as
ballerinas dancing around yeah whatever
whoever whatever whatever suits you that
helps you understand you know what the
Market's doing it's wonderful but
yeah my audience predominantly is male
so and I'm a guy so I I kind of like
lean to that
but one more time you can see the
difference between the two
much much weaker on ES
okay
so it's two o'clock
and my stomach is growling
so the only thing I had today was bone
broth so
I'm somewhat hungry
I'm trying to think if there's anything
else I want to add before we close it
and I don't believe I do have anything
else in addition to what we've done here
real quick I just want to show you the
down
okay so we have a drop the Fairway Gap
it trades into here and they reclaim it
there today and then they sent it higher
so it's a little bit of a delay to take
out the relative equal highs we
mentioned this high
on the 13th of June and that's where it
hit it and just retraced lower and now
we're climbing above it here I'm not
really excited about the Dow still um if
even I was willing to trade it I still
wouldn't be interested in trading where
it's at you might be thinking well
wouldn't six sister apply to that
because it has a lot of ground to gain
to try to catch up with
NASDAQ or even es
maybe I just don't trade down it's it's
a a real spotty index and it's only 30
stocks that make it up so it's very
easily
manipulated okay and I want to say it in
the same way like I mentioned but gold
because it's nowhere near the degree of
manipulation and endowed that is in Gold
but Dow is very thin okay meaning there
isn't a lot of trading that takes place
in it versus the es in the NASDAQ and
NASDAQ is a fast Market because it's
thinner too so that's really what makes
the the es a little bit slower but
sometimes there's a little bit of a
inversion where es will outperformed the
NASDAQ but most of the time the
NASDAQ acts like the British pound
versus the Euro okay es will be
equivalent to like a Euro and NASDAQ is
equivalent to how
British penetrates British pound always
exaggerates the move that would be seen
in Europe which is why I always
predominantly like to trade the cable
which is pound dollar but there are
times when euro dollar will outperform
cable and you have to know the things
I'm teaching here the relationships of
measuring when to look at it and when
not to consider it and you can't learn
that in just one video you have to see
it experience it see analysis see things
called in advance watch how it performs
also back test all those things should
be included when you're looking at Price
moves like when you're looking at Forex
price runs and you're logging them for
your Journal you want to be looking at
other closely correlated pairs not just
the one that you see the setup in so
that way you're getting a a real clear
depiction of what everything else around
that pair was dealing at the same time
so that way it's not this in and of
itself an island of itself saying I'm
doing whatever I want to do no it's
being subordinate to the macro that's
under underway in all the markets so
anyway
I think I've given you enough today to
give myself a day off and a three-day
weekend and I understand yes it's not
Friday so I'll be changing the title of
this
and I will catch up with you I'm sure
somewhere on Twitter I don't know but if
I don't talk to you tomorrow on on
Twitter I will talk to you
Saturday morning at nine o'clock for a
Saturday shotgun with ICT
so I'll talk to you next time
be safe