in this section we're going to cover the
underlying nature of the mental skills
that you're going to be learning and
then at the end of the section I'm going
to put these skills within the context
of three developmental modes that you're
going to eventually learn to trade in
which would be first the mechanical mode
then the subjective mode and then the
intuitive everybody kind of have a good
idea where we're going today
maybe a little bit better of an idea
than when you kind of walked in here
yeah okay so anyway what I want to do is
let's just let's just go through and
take a little bit of an attitude survey
here kind of get an idea where you're at
there are no right or wrong answers here
it's just a matter of what you believe
about the nature of training so if we
get it's kind of money making money the
traders primarily a function of analysis
who would agree with that raise your
hands it's alright you raise your hands
so you're telling me that only a few
people would agree part of it okay okay
I often find myself thinking there must
be a way to trade without having to take
a loss come on be honest come on oh yeah
yeah
you know oh let's say I find myself
thinking that there must be a way at a
trade well taking a loss right okay okay
by the way the first one when one of the
things one I mean this is one this is a
primary one of the things we're going to
talk about a lot of making money as a
traders primarily functional analysis
that that really isn't the case at all
what you're going to learn in other
words trading is execution trading is
execution how what you decide to do of
course is analysis and the problem is
that it depends on what you're using
your analysis for if you're using your
analysis to avoid the risk then then
certainly making money is not a function
of that because you will you will
virtually consistently lose but we're
gonna talk about that more in a little
bit okay okay I have trouble getting out
of a losing trade who has anybody here
still have trouble getting out of a
losing trade okay that's fine you won't
have that trouble after today I got I'm
really my goal is that when you walk out
of here you will understand and no
uncertain terms that there was
absolutely absolutely no reason to hang
on
what you will define in advance as a
losing trade do you find yourself
planning trades you never execute an
executing trades you never planned
that's a pretty common things that
affect most traders there is always a
cost associated with finding out what
the market may do next it's good to
think that that means you're accepting
the risk that there's a certain amount
of cost meaning a certain amount of risk
involved to finding out what the market
one may do next if I were to thoroughly
analyze my trading results I would find
that my average losing trade is much
bigger than my average winning trade
well a few people in here that might
still be fall in that category it only
takes one trader somewhere in the world
to negate the positive outcome of any
particular trade who agrees with that
anybody raise your hand if you agree
with that place nobody raises their hand
oh this is big I love it thank you very
much thank you very much for not
agreeing with that because you couldn't
be further from the truth it couldn't be
more wrong this is one of the things
you're gonna learn it only takes one
trader somewhere in the world to negate
the positive outcome of your trade or
your edge that's all just one you're
gonna learn that today I wouldn't put on
a trade if I wasn't sure it was going to
be a winner who agrees with that
statement please raise your hand please
who agrees that say I'm good good good
I'm saying good because because what I'm
seeing is that yes there is a gap here
that we're gonna have to fill between
your particular attitudes about training
now and and where you're gonna end up
with hopefully by the end of the day I
would answer this question absolutely
not
I wouldn't put on this trade ever wasn't
sure I was going to be a winner
I've trade trade from the perspective of
I don't know if any trade is going to be
a winner and I said I don't have to know
as a matter of fact that is one of the
principle let's say principle concepts
that you will have to adapt to become a
consistently successful trader and what
the pros have adapted and the reason why
they can do what they do is because they
have learned not just learn but they
believe without a shred of doubt that
they do not have to know what's going to
happen next
make money and don't even think about it
in those terms they don't even think
about it in those terms it's not a
matter of what's going going to happen
next when you understand the nature of
how technical analysis how your
technical formulas and your mathematical
formulas interact with market behavior
and what they can and can't do and what
their inherent limitations are you will
also understand that I wouldn't put on a
trade if I wasn't sure it was going to
be a winner is absolutely one of the one
of the worst mistakes you can make to be
consistently successful trader it is a
fact it's probably the number one kind
of perplexing at this moment yes good ok
I always define my risk before I enter a
trade does everybody here in this room
at the point where they always
predefined their risk who doesn't raise
your hand please raise your hand I want
to know where everyone's at come on it's
all right ok sometimes I find myself
blaming the market for what went wrong
well let me ask you this is anybody
anybody feel betrayed by the market ever
and anybody ever feel betrayed by their
by their their their their signals their
technical signal or whatever methodology
that they use we're going to talk about
that in detail too
the more trader learns about the nature
of the markets the easier it will be for
him to execute his trades who thinks as
a correlation there that the more I
learn about the nature of markets and
price movement the easier will be to
execute your trades who think there's a
positive correlation there ok
again couldn't be further from the truth
there's a negative correlation there the
more you learn the harder is going to be
to execute your trades to be it depends
on why you're learning and of course but
we'll get into that to be a successful
technical trader you have to determine
what the market is going to do next I
already said that's not the case so so
you'll know how to answer that one but
but if I hadn't said it how would you
have answered it who would have said yes
if I hadn't have already told you guys a
couple of people and you came to Houston
oh come on
okay trading skills who are the
professionals we already talked about
that and why would it be beneficial to
think like a professional trader we
already talked about that what's the
answer
ah anybody can make money okay
we're kind of already established the
fact that anybody can make money as a
trader yeah we're talking about
consistency what we want to do is we
want to close that profit gap we want to
we want to make sure that our
bottom-line results reflect the
potential of our methodologies okay and
that's what the professional has learned
how to do the professional has learned
how to close that profit gap they have
learned the appropriate skills to do
that they're people just like you and me
okay they're no different they really
aren't they've evolved into a different
way of thinking about trading that's the
reason why they can do it and you can do
it too with understanding and awareness
that is really primarily what this
workshop is about anyway because because
when you think about if you've read
stories of people who have have aspired
to greatness in as a trader you'll
always find but almost all of them that
there's this underlying thread this
underlying theme that that virtually all
of them have lost one or more of what
they considered a fortune before they
started becoming consistently successful
why do you think that underlying thread
our theme exists in their lives what's
that why do you think that commonality
exists because at some point they lose
so often and then come back from losing
that one they gain the confidence that
they can do it and as a result the fear
dissipates and as soon as the fear is
gone they're trading from a carefree
state of mind and when you trade from
that carefree state of mind everything
about your trainings changes remember
that the primary skill that we're
talking about here is simply trading
without fear this is a trading skill it
is the primary skill that you will have
to acquire to create consistency
to trade without fear what does
consistency look like I've already went
through on the on the grease board here
and showed you a consistently rising
equity curve with the draw downs the
normal draw downs being a reflection of
what can you anybody remember what I
said about that what was that
normal losses that reflect any trading
methodology right okay what skills are
necessary to experience a winning trade
now think about now I'm gonna contrast
okay
I'm gonna do a little bit contrasting
here just just to show you one of the
reasons why it can be so difficult to
get even into a frame of mind where we
start asking the the appropriate
questions about what do I need to really
be consistently successful because what
does it really take to experience a
winning train what skills do you need
anybody got any idea what skills do you
need to experience a winning trade but
what's your name sir Maurice says a
click of the mouse who's with Maurice on
that come on who's with Maurice on a
click of the mouse got one two anybody
else three four he's absolutely right
that's all it takes
there are no other skills needed no
other skills needed other than the
actual physical ability to put your
finger on the mouse button and click in
the buyer of the cell and you can find
yourself in a winning trade you can find
yourself in a spectacularly winning
trade far beyond what you could have
ever imagined and what skill did it take
what what did it take there's just doing
it that's all
just doing it at that way at that moment
do you need an edge do you need to
happen to even even have to know even
know what an edge is is it possible to
just be to walk up to your computer and
the arrow happened to be on the Buy
button you click and then find yourself
on a winning trade if you didn't have an
ad you did you you just clicked it what
are it take it took nothing
do need a plan need no plan do you need
the discipline to execute the plan no
you don't need that either do you now
see you're gonna be the opposite of all
this of course is what we're gonna be
talking about in terms of creating
consistency but go ahead did you say a
squirrel I'm sorry squirrel you okay
squirrel okay go ahead that's good it's
all the things that lead up to me that's
the implementation but what about all
the things that lead up to that
implementation Oh understand I'm not I'm
not negating that at all I'm just saying
that that that that the reality is you
don't need anything that's all I'm
saying because I'm contrasting here I'm
just making a contrast between what you
need to be consistent and what you need
to win oh okay that's all I'm doing okay
you just sum that up of what I was about
to say there's all the difference in the
world between having the skills
necessary to experience a winning trade
as compared to having the skills
necessary to consistently experience a
winning absolutely that's what I'm
that's all I'm talking about here
because see there's because what this
does is this the non understanding this
contrast creates what I call is like a
huge psychological gap because if you
don't because it's very easy for us to
think that trading is easy and if you
believe that trading is easy even if
you're getting even if even if all your
experience is starting to tell you that
it's not it doesn't mean that that
experience is dropping down to a level
of realization where you change your
behavior or change the way that you
think about trading if your first
impression if your first experience was
that this couldn't be simpler and then
you spend you know how many X number of
years or half a lifetime finally coming
to the realization that you know what
yeah to win like what do you need like I
could I could be in a casino and and
plunk a hundred-dollar bill down you
know at a blackjack table and and end up
with a blackjack what did I need
nothing I just happen to win now if I
want to be a professional blackjack
player and make up make a consistent
income from playing blackjack well
that's that's a whole nother matter
isn't it and we're talking about the
same things here with trading there
would be a number of skills that I have
to acquire to be able to make a
consistent reliable income as a
blackjack player and there are people
who do it do you need a good reason to
put the trade on to win do you need a
good reason no not at all what
characteristics distinguished the pro
from the typical trader
well they plan their trades no they
execute their plan without error ah
we'll talk about trading errors in a
minute big difference okay they can move
in and out of their trades with an ease
and effortlessness that would boggle the
mind of the typical trader okay what do
you need to achieve consistent results
well you're gonna you're gonna need an
edge you're gonna be able to identify an
edge you're gonna have to have a trading
methodology are you not right okay and
you have to have a plan on how to
utilize that edge in other words you're
gonna have to determine risk parameters
how much does it cost me to find out if
this particular edge that my methodology
provides me how much there's gonna cost
them how much they're gonna cost me to
find out that this edge is working on
this particular trade or not that's your
risk parameter are you guys with me on
this okay
money management parameters in other
words how much you're in other words
contract size or number of shares that
you trade all these have to be tailed
this has to be taken in consideration
you could have a standard amount or you
could have an amount that fluctuates
based on you know based on other
criteria that you use you know to
determine you know the level of trade
that it is like it could be like a five
star trade or a 1 star trade with a 5
star trade you're going with a maximum
position with a 1 star trade you go in
with a minimum position and profit
objectives you have to be able to set
profit objectives see just having a
methodology
to get you into a trade is not enough
you have to be able to determine what
the risk is on a consistent basis you
have to know you have to know what your
money management parameters are and you
have to be able to determine where to
take profits these none of these are
easy things to do are they trade
execution the ability to execute trades
flawlessly so you can utilize your
trading plan to its maximum potential
this is this is the big one right here
this is the area because when you get
right down to it trading is about exit
trading is execution the act of trading
is executing trades and if you're going
to execute trades you're going to have
to be able to do them without errors
because it just it doesn't make any
sense to think that you will that you
will achieve a consistently rising
equity curve if you're constantly making
trading errors trading errors would be
defined as mistakes mistakes and detract
from your bottom-line results now the
interesting thing about mistakes is that
when you're when you're trading from the
let's say the perspective of you know it
doesn't really take anything to win then
there really aren't any mistakes that
you can make because anything that you
do could and could result in a winning
trade for any reason but when we're
talking about making consistent money or
an income that we can rely on then
everything changes about this everything
changes what I'm talking about here is
I'm talking about these like five or
four broad skill sets to be able to
create consistent results the kind of
results that you can rely on as an
income you're going to have to learn an
edge you're gonna have to acquire a
trading methodology that gives you an
edge I'm defining an edge is that
there's a higher probability of one
thing happening over another that's what
an edge is and you're good we're gonna
learn the nature of probabilities here
in a moment you're gonna have to have
you know you're gonna have to have a
plan on how do you you how you utilize
that edge meaning what the risk is
in size and profit objectives then
they're going to have to be able to
execute they're gonna have to get to the
point you can execute that edge without
making errors for you to be able to
execute that edge without making errors
you're gonna have to learn how to trade
from a carefree state of mind meaning
you're going to have to aspire to the
point where you can train without fear
and to trade without fear you're gonna
have to learn how to think in
probabilities that's basically where
we're going here and I said this primary
skill was learning how to trade without
fear learning how to trade without fear
as a function of learning how to think
in probabilities meaning we're going to
we're going to set aside or move from
thinking in a trade by trade mentality
in other words what this trade is going
to do for me right now am I right or
wrong on this trade and we're gonna move
to a series of trades perspective
because that's what your methodology
does anyway any trading methodology just
gives you a a win or loss ratio over a
percentage of trades in other words if I
take the same take the same criteria
that's in any kind of mathematical any
kind of technical formula it's
mathematical bait mathematically based
or a technical price pattern that you
would be able to see visually what we're
going to learn is that my edge meaning a
higher probability of one thing
happening over another is simply going
to give me a higher win rate over a
series of trades let's say the next 20
trades 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 9 10 11 12 13 14 15
16 17 18 19 20 and that the actual on a
trade by trade basis I don't know which
one's going to win or which one's gonna
lose in advance there is no way for me
to find out there's no way for me to
determine that then on a trade by trade
basis no matter what reason or rationale
that you come up with is that there's no
way to assure yourself that it's going
to be a winning trade there's nothing
that can tell you that
that training methodologies give you a
win percentage let's say 70% of the next
20 trades are gonna be winners there's
still way I'm gonna know which of the 70
you know which which twelve or thirteen
are going to be the winners or which six
or seven are going to be the losers what
you're going to learn this is what
traders what prep the professionals have
learned is that there's a random
distribution between wins and losses
over any given set of criteria that
define your edge there's a random
distribution I will get a higher
percentage of wins two losses but I just
don't know which trades are going to be
it requires a complete shift in the way
you think about training when you make
this complete shift everything about
your training will change now I expect
you to make it now because I'm just
still getting out still we're still in
the introduction we won't really get
into the meat of this until a little bit
but this is this is where we're going
okay that's not what yet this is where
we're going they're going to be going to
genuine and learn how to think in
probabilities because when you've
integrated when you have genuinely
integrated these concepts into your
mental system at a functional level your
fear will go away you do not need to
lose everything to get to the point
where you can figure out that well you
know I've got nothing to lose anymore so
I don't have anything to be afraid of
you don't have to do that okay you don't
have to do that all you have to do is
commit yourself to learn how to think
about trading in another way and your
fear will go away
because what we're gonna learn is the
correlation between what we believe and
what we feel there's a direct
correlation between if I'm going into a
situation with a certain belief that
let's say that my particular edge is
going to tell me what's going to happen
on this trade right here I wouldn't even
put this trade on unless I thought I was
going to win when you really understand
the nature of price movement listen what
we're gonna get into after we go through
this section on skills when you really
understand that you will never think
that way again when you really
understand the nature of price movement
you won't think that way again and that
is one of the biggest problems that most
the typical trader has let's say the
typical screen-based trader is that is
that they really don't understand the
nature of how prices move and the
underlying dynamics because if you
haven't had the exposure you're you
haven't had the exposure to the direct
markets you're only exposure has been
those blips on the screen and as a
result there's a real gap in in
understanding about what's really
happening when you understand what's
behind those blips what's behind those
photons that show up on your screen when
you really understand that you will
think about trading in another way and
in a completely different way it won't
even occur to you to do some of the
things that you're doing now won't even
occur to you
okay now so I've got so we've got I've
given you three so far the next broad
area that you're going to have to learn
it's like it's like you can you could be
an expert at defining an edge you could
even you can even be able to execute
your trades flawlessly and but run into
the next challenge and that's what I
just call self sabotaging beliefs in
other words all of us have a sense of
self evaluation all of us have this this
sense that were what we're worth as a
person you might say and if if you were
to take like an old Ben Franklin
accounting scale okay and this is
positive and this is negative meaning if
you were to list every experience in
your life if you had let's say conscious
access to every experience in your life
that contributed to a positive sense of
self evaluation that yes I am a worthy
person because what we're running into
like I kind of got ahead of myself what
we're running into is this is that when
you learn how to define an edge and
learn how to execute your traits
flawlessly what's your what you're now
exposed to is the possibilities for
unlimited wealth there's really there's
really not there's really nothing
holding you back well let's put it this
way there's nothing on the outside
that's holding you back but there might
be something on the inside that's
holding you back those things on the
inside could be self sabotaging beliefs
in the sense that if you listed all the
experience that contributed to a
positive sense of self evaluation and
all experiences that that that
contributed to a negative sense of self
evaluation that I'm not worthy as a
person I feel guilty about this this
this and this that you could end up you
know you could you go you can go pup
plus negative or you know net positive
or net negative what could end up
happening is that if you don't have the
let's say the skills or the awareness to
realize that as your equity curve
as you start making money these internal
forces if you have net negative these
internal forces start building up to the
point where they'll cause you to make
unconscious trading errors where you're
not even really aware that you hit the
sell button instead on the buy button
those kinds of things if you have to you
have to become aware of when these
forces are starting to build up inside
of you and either compensate for it by
not trading by the stop trading or to
find a way to neutralize them and there
are there are various techniques
available but all I'm saying is that is
that these kinds of these kinds of
errors that are the results of self
sabotaging beliefs don't really have
anything to do with your direct trading
skills in other words your ability to
identify an edge and your ability to
execute your trade but they can have an
enormous impact on your equity curve I
would assume too that you would be
monitoring your equity curve and you
would start seeing your curve go down in
an abnormal way and you would start
looking for your whatever's happening to
you let's say you're not feeling well or
whatever your wife just divorced you I'm
just or maybe something yes all good
things right things that you're bringing
up I mean these what I'm saying is
though the you show two extremes a
normal drawdown and then the boom or
bust drawdown there must be some way to
know at least I'm looking for to know
when you start looking at your self
sabotaging that's my question good
question as a matter of fact there are
software programs available now that
will tell you that there are software
programs available that will tell you
when in other words give you an example
there's the example when I was working
with traders with especially like hedge
funds managers and and and and and
larger traders there are people first of
all there are people that that they're
their sole job was if they were let's
say they were central here let me about
how important this is
they had let's say this is there in the
middle and they've got and they've got
let's say you know 10 or 12 money
managers these are guys that all have
their managing funds okay this guy's
sole responsibility was to shift money
from here to here to here to each
manager based on chart patterns of their
equity curves in other words they would
chart the equity of these particular
traders just like price patterns in the
market to determine their potential for
inordinate ly large draw downs because
of self-sabotaging beliefs that's how
sophisticated the market has become
that's how relevant these issues are so
that you can actually chart your equity
and then you start to go like this oh
well and then do another one like that
something's happening here okay I mean
it was just it was really kind of
amazing to me when I was working with
floor traders especially I mean this one
guy this pops into my brain just as just
as you as we're talking about this I
mean you know he came in for a
consultation and he had his worst day in
his life ever worst trading day lost
more money than what he's ever lost in
his life and I said well you know and
it's like normally almost virtually in
every case it's something catastrophic
is happening in that person's life well
it's always amazing to me is how much of
a disconnect that that the person would
have between the catastrophic event in
their life and what they ended up doing
is the trader in the market I said well
you know what's going on and then he
just I just said what's going on and you
just he's kind of yeah well yeah my wife
when I had this really bad argument last
night and you know and I when I left you
know when I left for them for the
exchange this morning you know he
slapped his kids around and he kicked
his dog and you know looks like they
came in and Hanna's worst day and didn't
make the connection between what you
know between what happened what happened
at home and what he did on the floor
and he might have felt completely
justified in with the argument that he
had with his wife in slapping his kid
around and kicking the dog but that's
that's what's going on consciously but
let's say subconsciously you know
everyone has real estate if the person
is relatively normal now a psychopath
you know they've got they've got some
sense of fairness and and he feels
guilty about what he did and he took
that guilt out in the way he traded that
day the market is not a good arena to be
doing this by the way okay this is this
is not a good area to be working these
kind of emotional issues out go ahead we
need the microphone you want me to you
want me to put it right here and I'll
just I'll just hand it to him the the
market also changes the patterns of the
are your edge may change in relation to
the market to distinguish between your
own troubled state let's say and market
behavior I can see that maybe one of
these fellows here in the PI there might
be using a system that is not as valid
as it used to be when the market changes
how would you know if you were the guy
in the center whether he was just having
a bad stay with with whatever's going on
in his personal life versus a change in
his system in relation to the market
another good question
you wouldn't know immediately but upon
investigation you could find out in
other words by just talking to the guy
or what you or what you do is that see
see what you do is you trade in sample
sizes - in other words when you have a
particular methodology that has that has
a defined criteria for when you get into
a trade what you do is you trade in a
limited sample size so that if you
traded 25 trade sample sizes or like 20
or whatever what you do is you analyze
your results at the end of that at the
end of a sample size and if your results
are satisfying then what you do is you
take another sample size if the results
are not satisfying then because you all
because you knew exactly what you didn't
under what circumstances you did it
you've limited your variables what you
do is then you can go back and tweak
your variables to see if you can improve
your improve your results because
because what's your name because
timed with time was really bringing up
is the fact that you're right because
we're taking a limited set of variables
mathematical formula to that that's a
being applied to a dynamic event and
that dynamic event are traders who are
acting on their own behalf
creating price movement and they
basically they create patterns that were
they're doing the same thing over and
over again but you've got new people
coming in with new ideas and old people
leaving and as a result these patterns
can change over time diminishing the
results of them think of their edge so
what you want to do is you want to make
sure that your sample size is large
enough to adequately test that edge but
small enough so that if the edge is
diminishing in its effectiveness
you're not losing an inordinate amount
of money before you find that out to the
answer question so that's how they find
out okay besides that there are because
of their software available that'll even
tell you now there's software yeah
there's software available that I'll
that will track your track your edges or
to track your equity in a way that can
indicate whether or not you're ready to
take a hit I don't know the name of it
but you know cuz I just found out about
it myself so what are some other ways
that you can address maybe a emotional
problem you might be going through or
other things outside of the trading area
besides stock trading well you said
there I mean there there are a number of
techniques a number of books available
there's there's counseling you know I
mean I'm gonna make I'm gonna make a
recommendation of a particular book
later on you know when we get into a
little bit more detail but but you know
it's it depends on the effect that it
has on your trading I mean you don't
necessarily have to stop trading but you
all but you have to make an objective
assessment as to what you as to your
state of mind in other words you know
you can actually say to yourself am I in
the best state of mind to be trading
today and you know and the kind of
answer that you get back from yourself
you know if it's relatively objective
it's like if you're really not in the
best state of mind because of things
that are going on in your life and some
troubling aspects that you haven't
reconciled then but you don't want to
stop trading well at least you're aware
of it by in another another technique
would be by keeping journals because
most really good traders keep pretty
extensive journals over
about you know what they're doing and
what they're thinking while they're
doing it and then you make this
assessment so that at least if you're
not you don't want to stop trading you
still want to put your put whatever
edges on your half of that day you scale
back in other words if your maximum
position size is let's say five thousand
shares you're not in the best state of
mind maybe you only want to trade a
thousand maybe you only want to trade
500 in other words to take these things
into consideration and you'd be
surprised by just being aware of it and
taking into consideration a lot of times
these these things will reconcile
themselves I don't does that help you
yes it does thank you okay okay in the
last area of these broad skill sets that
we're talking about is develop the
ability to recognize if you've crossed
the threshold from normal self
confidence into a state of euphoria you
guys are laughing okay finally I finally
got some giggles I yeah giggles out of
you guys here oh what's so funny about
this anybody want to anyone you want to
want to share what what's that no you're
right I mean being in a stadium for you
let's put it this way
the primary let's say the the the
primary characteristic of the state of
euphoria is that it's a state of mind of
complete and absolute risk lessness
you everybody get what I just said
you are in a state of risk less nests in
other words you have no ability
whatsoever to perceive risk so if for an
example
if this line right here
if below this line represents normal
self-confidence and above this line is
euphoria and and this threshold is
different for everybody by the way I
mean there are certain chemicals that
scientists have found that you know that
that flutter that flood our mind in our
body when we've processed this threshold
I have I've worked with traders who will
flip into a state of euphoria with one
winning trade okay usually for most
people it takes more than one winning
trade but I have worked with I have
worked with people that they'll flip
into a state of euphoria with one
winning trade now the problem with this
and it's a great state of mind to be and
I mean to be in a in virtually a
riskless state of mind I mean it's like
hey you know the it's really a cool
place to be but the problem is that when
were in a state of euphoria as a trader
we are I mean it's it's virtually
guaranteed that we're gonna make a
trading error and the kind of trading
error that will make in a state of
euphoria usually has to do with position
size so for example if you're normal if
you're if you normally only trade a
thousand shares in a state of euphoria
it's like okay let's let's mortgage the
house okay it's like you know let's go
to ten thousand twenty thirty whatever
thousand shares because you see you
absolutely know for a fact you wouldn't
be putting on putting this trade on if
it wasn't gonna work so you know for you
know for a fact see that because there's
no cuz you don't have any any ability to
perceive risk at all
now the problem even though it could
even end up being a winning trade it's
not that it's not that the trade might
not end up being a winner but here's
typically what's going to happen if
you're a normal 1000 share trader if you
go up to 10,000 shares if when you put a
thousand shares on and the market went
against you five cents a share wouldn't
be any big deal
you've got 10,000 shares on when you
absolutely knew for a fact that the
trade was a winner and it goes five or
ten cents against you it has the
potential to flip you into a state of
pure unadulterated terror
instantaneously you go from euphoria to
a state of terror in one instant because
your expectations about what was going
to happen
we're so resolute it creates a
psychological shock that puts you in a
state of mind
freeze mind freeze mind freeze is when
you are conscious of what is happening
but find yourself totally immobilized to
do anything about it and so if the
market happens to go ten cents against
you but keeps on going okay you just sit
there and watch completely immobilized
while the market takes your money away
until finally something flips you out of
that and you say hey you know you just
come back to your senses and you had
enough and you get out of the trade I
know this probably never happened
anybody in this group but but but I've
worked with many people so this is not
something unfamiliar to anybody here
[Laughter]
that's it's like going literally from
home state of minds like literally going
from heaven to hell instantaneously and
keep in mind the dynamics here it was
all based on your expectation it's all
based on your expectation
so you guys have got this okay there's
so we're talking about consistency see
what this is goes back to when I was
doing the contrast okay is that to
experience a winning trade you need
nothing I'm not saying that you don't
put something into it but the fact is
you need nothing
there's no skills that are required to
experience a winning trade but to
experience consistent results as a
trader
there was the kind of results that you
can rely on as an income there are there
are these are there are some pretty kind
of profound skills that we're talking
about are we not you've got to have an
edge you got to have a plan on how to
execute the edge you got to be able to
execute the plan flawlessly or at least
without you know without is minimum
number of errors or otherwise are gonna
detract from your results you got to be
able to recognize win you might have
some self sabotaging beliefs that are
that are rising to the surface to say
hey you know this is too much money why
you why do you think it is you have
probably read in the bud some of the
training books I know I'm sure you have
read at some point that someone gives
you the advice that when you have
windfall profits to stop trading and
take a vacation why do you think that
that advice exists why do you think
people have written that down I just
gave you the underlying dynamics for why
that's true it's not just the euphoria
no it's not just know it's not the
terror afterward it's it's the
possibility for self sabotaging beliefs
coming in and saying I am NOT worth this
much money even though it's what I want
it's what I desire it's what I've been
working for it doesn't mean that you
believe you really deserve it you have
to believe you really deserve it to keep
it
or at least recognize that you don't
necessarily believe it and don't do
anything to give it away in other words
take a vacation put it in the bank let
yourself get used to having it and and
at which point you'll say you know what
yeah you know I do deserve this money
and then you'd be less likely to give it
away the one of the best examples that I
give that good because I could give you
to illustrate this is a floor trader
that I work on again another bond trader
not as big as the other bond trader that
I was that I that I referred to earlier
he was a kind of trader who had this
reputation as being completely
consistent when when I met him he was he
would make anywhere from I'd say fifteen
to twenty thousand dollars a day that
was his daily his daily thing okay
day-in day-out
fifteen twenty thousand dollars a day
never had these catastrophic bad days
that was his reputation and it was true
so what do need me for well he he had
hired a bunch of guys to trade his money
thinking that he's gonna it'll live this
is very common you kind of have a funny
look but it's very common in Chicago
where once you become successful and
established what you want to do is is is
bring in you know as many let's say
bring in young talent that you can you
know teach your particular techniques
and just you know multiply what you make
based on their efforts I mean that's you
know but the problem is that the guys
that he brought into his group they were
you know I mean I don't know how to put
it I want to be I want to be nice I want
to they were just they were just
basically leeches I mean they a lot of
them when I you know talk to him it's
like I don't even there's some some of
them I don't even think wanted to be
traders they just they just saw the
opportunity to be able to get money from
him for the opportunity to do something
they hadn't done before and and it was
you know it was
these were not the kind of people that
that you would that you would hire and
under these circumstances they weren't
really suited for it many cases weren't
really suited for it at all especially
the trade down on the floor so he wanted
particularly you wanted ideas on how to
you know how to how to build this this
group up into you know a really
successful trading group and while we
were talking one day we had ordered
lunch in somebody a delivery person came
to with the lunch and he and he was a
devout Catholic by the way this is a
very important part of this he was a
devout Catholic and he it's so devout
that he carried a rosary with him all
the time he had a rosary in his pocket
and so when he he he paid you know took
his wall out of his pocket paid for the
lunch and he took the change and it just
sort of unconsciously started to put the
change in the same pocket with his
rosary and then we realized what he was
doing he took his hand out like that and
I said well you know say what's going on
yeah well you know I can't put money in
can't can't have money touch the rosary
and so we started exploring his beliefs
about money and his beliefs about
religion in relationship to money and
certainly his beliefs about the Catholic
Church and their beliefs about money and
you know once they ended something he
never really thought about but what he
thought about you know the Catholic
Church certainly doesn't believe that
money is dirty so why should he believe
that money is dirty in that respect in
other words it's not spiritual to have
money in a way that you know in a way
that it can another was a dichotomy in
his mind between his ability to his
ability to make money in the pit and yet
you would think that in a in this kind
of a situation he would be giving his
money away because he felt guilty about
having it well he didn't give it away as
a traitor because he was just too strong
of a traitor to do it but he was giving
it away in in with this organization the
kind of people that he had around him in
other words it wasn't going out the
front door the money was going out the
back door so he did find a way to to
extract that money in about his
about money religion the Catholic Church
their beliefs about money realized that
the you know the inconsistencies and and
so as we're coming to kind of
reconciliation about this
I gave him an exercise to see if if in
fact he'd really accepted what it is
that we were talking about and what do
you think the exercise was come on what
do you think exercise was it's not that
hard yes right put put put money in the
pocket with the rosary put the money in
the rosary together he couldn't do it he
literally his his arm he tried to put
the money in it was like it got it got
like he could not do it his beliefs that
we talked about were so strong that it
literally wouldn't consciously let him
do it but he worked on it see he he
wanted to get to the point where he
recognized the validity of the things
that we were talking about and so he did
want to do it so he kept on trying it
took him about a week and once it got
the money in with the rosary he had like
all these conflicting beliefs he had
about the nature of money in the guilt
that he that he felt over it it just
they just sort of all melted away and he
fired all these people he didn't even
try to make the traders because he
realized that they you know these were
not guys that you know that really
wanted to be traders and he realized
what he was doing he realized he was
just he's just giving his money away
what gives the professional trader the
ability to execute their trades out air
they are confident meaning there are no
longer encumbered by the same fears that
plagued the typical trader trading
without fears has learned mental skills
I've already given you examples of
mental skills remember what we say but
about the ability not to choke okay
under that would be an example of a
mental skill learning the trade without
fear hesitation or internal conflicts as
a function of believing that you don't
have to know what's going to happen next
on a trade by trade basis to win or make
consistent money this is a good this is
the heart of it right here everyone okay
this is the heart of it and again we're
still in the introduction believe
not okay so I'm gonna reinforce all this
but eventually what you're gonna do is
get to the point where you believe that
you do not have to know what is going to
happen next on a trade by trade basis
this trade and this particular trade in
this particular trade you don't have to
enter these trades thinking that you
know it's going to happen next to win to
make consistent money and that when you
stop believing that you will start
making consistent money because it's
there it's your expectations about this
trade winning that's that's gonna mess
you up go ahead what you really saying
is you have to have a belief in your
plan or your methodology and you're
looking for a probabilistic result
saying over a period of time I will
execute 60 70 80 % of my trades and one
I'm going into now could be a good one
could be a bad that's right I don't care
that's right exactly right perfect thank
you this is where we're going okay
thinking assuming or believing you know
what will happen next creates an
unrealistic expectation in a fascist in
a specific outcome
what's wrong with unrealistic
expectation we'll think about let's say
expectations in relationship to the the
characteristics of humanity you get this
cuts across all everybody and cuts
across all cultural all cultural lines
or barriers everyone it well first of
all if you even get to that point what
is an expectation an expectation is a
mental representation in other words a
belief an assumption or an opinion or
whatever thinking assuming or believing
a mental representation of what the next
moment meaning next moment next five
seconds or the next in ten seconds or
the next hour or whatever is either
going to in the environment in others
they have a mental representation and we
have an external environment that
expresses itself okay so my mental
representation meaning my expectation if
the if the environment shows up in a way
that is consistent with what I believe
then what it what will my state of mind
be this is a universal characteristic of
humanity this isn't any different with
anybody anywhere how will I feel what
will be my state of mind what will be my
experience I'll be in a state of
satisfaction a state of well-being
I could be joyous I could even end up in
unit a state of euphoria the degree to
which the environment does not express
itself in a way that's consistent what I
the way inconsistent with the way I
think it's either gonna look like sound
like taste like smell like or feel like
okay I will be in a state of
dissatisfaction the state of betrayal
disgust anger fear terror your ability
to create consistent results as a trader
is all about what you expect when you
change your expectations to be
consistent with the way the environment
the market environment exists the fear
will go away when you change your
expectations in a way that's consistent
with the way the actual market
environment exists your fear will go
away
and you'll be able to do exactly what
you need to do when you need to do it
without conflict without hesitation and
be able to close that profit gap between
what your methodology will give you in
what you end up with in your bottom line
unrealistic expectations cause us to
define and interpret and therefore
perceive market information as
threatening ultimately we could look at
we can break the market down to its
lowest definable component parts if we
break the market down to its lowest
definable component parts what we end up
with is up and down ticks okay an uptick
an uptick is one incremental price
change with a price move from one to two
from two to three four five six whatever
and then down ticks okay
when we're operating out of unrealistic
expectations we're going to tap into
four primary trading fears that will
cause all the errors that we make as
traitors those fears are the fear of
being wrong losing money missing out and
leaving money on the table
and those fears will actually cause us
to perceive these up and down ticks as
threatening and what we're going to
learn about the nature of fear a little
later is that fear will cause us to
focus on the object of our fear so that
we end up creating the very experience
we're trying to avoid therefore if I'm
trying if I'm afraid of being wrong I
will actually perceive this information
in a way that causes me to be wrong if
I'm afraid of losing I will perceive
these up-and-down ticks in a way that
will actually cause me to lose if I'm
afraid of missing out I'll actually
create the experience of missing out and
if I'm afraid of leaving money on the
table that's exactly what I'll end up
doing now when you think about the
nature of these up-and-down ticks and
the photons that appear on your computer
screens is is there is there an inherent
characteristic and that information
that's threatening in any way
in other words it is it is that
information is in other words when we
talk about the nature of emotional pain
which is which is the threat of pain
okay the fear not physical pain where if
we have all of us have a normal nervous
system and we come into contact with a
physical object object you know if I hit
this with my arm it's going to hurt if
you hit it with your arm is going to
hurt so so we've got some universal
commonality but with emotional pain it's
not that way at all although we think
that it is that's not because emotional
pain requires an interpretation and then
interpretation comes from what we
believe you guys with me on this on the
interpretation part because see the
information itself the up and down ticks
have no charge to them whatsoever
they're not positively or negatively
charged they're just up and down ticks
that based on your ability to read those
up-and-down ticks tell you what the what
the potential is for the market to move
in any particular direction
if you're perceiving them as threatening
in some way that's definitely going to
cause you problems when it comes to
creating consistent results in fact
you're going to find it impossible
okay let's talk about some typical
trading errors the typical trading is
the professional has evolved beyond
don't define the risk in advance of
putting on a trade why in the world of
all the trading books that you've ever
read out of all the workshops you've
probably been to I'm sure that you have
been exposed to this particular piece of
advice countless times and yet it is it
is the primary trading error that people
commit all the time they don't
predefined the risk in advance of
putting on a trade if you don't
predefined the risk in advance you're
operating out of the mindset that you
think you know what's going to happen
next and what I'm going to establish
from you when you establish for you when
we get into the next section is that
that is absolutely not the case
it doesn't mean we don't think that but
the reality is it isn't the case see
because when we have we predefined our
risk let's put it this way if if I'm a
typical trader operating out of the four
fundamental fears the fear of being
wrong the fear of missing out losing
money etc we got a real problem here
because our minds are naturally wired to
associate in other words they automatic
our minds will automatically make
connections meaning this that if I if
I'm I get into a trade and I end up
being wrong I expect it to win and I'm
wrong I have to admit that I'm wrong
it isn't just admitting that I'm wrong
on this one trade our minds because the
way our minds are wired it has the
potential to tap us into the accumulated
the accumulated the accumulated negative
energy of every time I've been wrong in
my life okay so if this circle
represents a huge ball of negative
energy you
inside of our mental environment about
what it means to be wrong
being wrong on just one trade could tap
us into that pain and it's going to work
differently for everybody everyone's
minds work so it works a little bit
differently but that's the potential if
you wonder why people seem to live and
die on the outcome of the next trade
this is one of the reasons why this is
why it's so important because it has the
potential to tap us into the accumulated
negative pain of every time we've been
wrong in our lives every time we've lost
something in our lives every time we've
missed out on an opportunity that we
didn't take advantage of every time
we've been in an opportunity and didn't
get the maximum amount that was
available those are the four fears so
the problem with pre defining our risk
as this is that if I'm afraid of being
wrong and I don't know how to think
about trading appropriately in a
probabilistic mindset I'm not going to
get into this trade unless I think I'm
right and the problem with pre defining
the risk is that it requires that I
gather evidence as the why it might not
work
pre defining your risk requires that you
gather evidence as to why it might not
work well I wouldn't even be getting it
into in the first place if that were the
case so I'm not gonna I'm going to
gather as much evidence as possible to
make sure that I'm doing the right thing
because if I start gathering evidence as
to why it might not work then I might
talk myself out of taking the trade and
then if I end up talking myself out of
taking the trade and it turns out to be
a winner I'll probably be in more
emotional pain than what I would have
been in had I taken the trade and it
turned out to be a loser so I just make
sure that I've got all my ducks in a row
and I don't take the trade unless they
do and therefore what I have done now
think about this what I have essentially
done is define the risk out of the trade
I've gone through a mental process in
which I have literally defined the risk
out of the trade why do I have to put a
stop in the market and predefined my
risk if I know I'm gonna win a
professional trader just doesn't think
that way they would not I'm not saying
that they never thought that way I'm not
saying that that they didn't experience
the exact same thought process that I
just took you through I'm saying they
have evolved beyond it they would never
allow themselves to get into a trade
without pre defining the risk and elbows
what does the market look like sound
like or feel like to tell me this trade
isn't working the next error to find the
risk but don't take the loss and it
turns out to be a bigger loss that's
probably again one of those things that
never happened anybody in this room but
just in case someone watches the DVD
where this sort of thing has happened I
included it same dynamics basically
hesitate get into late yr gonna hesitate
why you're gonna hesitate to get in if
you're if the criteria that used to
define an edge define an edge is present
in this moment why would you hesitate
because you don't think the trades gonna
work you have doubt in other words
you're either thinking believing or
assuming that you know what's going to
happen next think of the connection here
you couldn't hesitate unless you either
assumed think or believed that you know
what's going to happen next if you
operate out of the perspective that you
don't know what's going to happen next I
don't need to know what's going to
happen next egg money then there's no
point in hesitating jump the gun get
into soon where the signal never
actually develops coming off of a
winning trade you're gonna jump the
gunman to come off a winning trade or a
series of winning trades right and
you're just so excited about what you
see developing yeah
signal isn't quite there yet but you
know what let's get in before everyone
else and you never actually get a signal
that's a training error now see the
point that doesn't mean that you
couldn't win see what you're gonna find
is that when you trade on what I call a
trade by trade basis so we're gonna make
the we're gonna make the distinction
between trading trade by train and chair
trading over a series of trades when you
trade trade by trade it means that each
individual trade is like a life or death
thing in other words I I wouldn't be
putting this trade on if I didn't think
this trade was going to win not that not
the other the the the the opposite of
that was which is I'm going to put on
the next twenty trades because I think
that 70 or 75 percent of them or 50% of
them are going to win it was a huge
difference in perspective
so if you're coming off a winning trade
or a series of wins you're likely to
jump the gun but the interesting part
about all this is that each one of these
errors and I'm giving you could all
result in a winning trade you could do
every single one of these things and
still win
you could not free to find your risk and
still find yourself in a winning trade
you can hesitate and find out what
exactly exactly the right thing to do in
that moment you can jump the gun and
find out it is exactly the right thing
to do in that moment you could not take
your loss and the market comes back in
your favor all these airs that we're
talking about you can commit over and
over again and they could end up having
you can end up experiencing positive
results except one thing one thing is
that when you indulge yourself in
behaviors in these kinds of behaviors it
could lead to usually a no but then that
could it virtually every time leads to a
catastrophic loss catastrophic you put
on a train without predefined in your
wrist three or four times over in a row
and turns out to be a winner and then
the next one you don't do it that's the
one that's gonna be the catastrophic
loss see so on a trade by trade basis
you can do anything for any reason and
commit any error or what would be
considered an error in the perspective
of trying to create consistency and
still win and still have winning tarik
streaks and still have a lot of fun but
you're setting yourself up for
catastrophic losses
get out of a winning trade too sooner to
leave money on the table there's there
isn't a traitor alive who hasn't
experienced that let a winning trade
turn into a loser without having taking
any profits all these errors are the
result of thinking assuming or believing
that we know what's going to happen next
we will stop closer to an entry point
get stopped out and the market trades
back in your favour in other words what
would that tell you if you if you're
here if you buy at this price right here
and you put your stop here this is all
you're really saying is that this is
this is how far I'm going to let the
market trade against my position to tell
me that this trade is either not working
at all or that the potential for
twerking is so diminished that it's not
worth me staying in any longer and then
the market starts to drift down to your
stop and then you move your stop up and
begin to get stopped out and then the
market does this what would that tell
you about your attitude what yeah and
you hadn't accepted the risk of that
trade did you see do you see when people
can put stops in the market it doesn't
mean they've really accepted the risk
you could put a stop in the market but
it doesn't mean you've genuinely
accepted the risk this would tell me
someone came to me and said mark this is
what I did this is what I know I know
that you didn't accept the risk of that
trader you wouldn't move the stop what
yeah you can move the other way too you
know because well that's because y'all
want to meet you wrong the professional
trader is no longer susceptible these
typical trading errors because he's
learned to think in probabilities when
you understand the relationship between
how prices move and the mathematical
formulas and price patterns that make up
a trading methodology patterns that make
up a trading method it quantifies that
moving into tradable edges then why you
have to learn the skill of thinking
probabilities will become self-evident
in other words when we get through the
next section the way you need to think I
want you guys to be at a point where it
just becomes completely self-evident as
to why you need to think in
probabilities to make consistent money
it just makes sense it's just like oh
yeah okay this makes absolute sense
the three developmental modes of trading
now I gave you the broad skill sets that
you have to learn to create consistency
well then with those broad skill sets
are within the three what I call three
developmental modes of training there's
mechanical trading subjective training
and intuitive trading there's three
stages in other words in mechanical what
you want to do is you wanna you want to
trade with rigid a rigid criteria that
defines your edge all execution
decisions are made in advance of market
activity the market either confirms your
conforms your definition of an edge or
not and you execute your your executor
trades based on a plan in other words
what you're doing within the mechanical
mode of trading is you're limiting the
number of variables that you're dealing
with in the market because what you want
to find out is this you want to find out
what works and what doesn't this is
where to find out what works and what
doesn't you can pay per trade in other
words you can you can actually take a
particular trading strategy and
methodology and forward trade it with
paper trading or if you've got software
that does analysis for you can do it
that way too but it's better than
probably paper traded so that you're
actually interacting with your
particular variables that are defining
an edge so you're finding out what works
and what doesn't if you use an unlimited
number of variables and define an edge
we were trading randomly you never never
find out what works and what doesn't so
you have to learn that you have to have
confidence in that but the other part of
it too
is finding out whether or not your own
personal psychology is made up in a way
that you can actually execute that edge
and the problem with the execution part
of it is that paper trading doesn't cut
it you actually have to have money on
the line and so what you do in the
mechanical stage that you use the
mechanical stage as a means to learn
trading skills in other words your focus
is on skills and not necessarily on how
much money you're making or not making
because when you've acquired the
appropriate skills the money will simply
just be a byproduct of those skills and
then what you do is that if you find
that you cannot execute your plan
then you're gonna have to going to have
to get into a mode where you learn
exactly how to do that which is what
we're gonna get into later on but the
point is is that that that what I
recommend to people is that if they're
having problems executing their trades
in most cases is because they're
probably they're probably their position
size is too large in other words if
they're if once they once they will
learn that they that that there's a
specific regimen in which they can learn
to be consistent you know what they want
to do is they want they want they want
their cake and eat it to sort of know
they want to learn the techniques but
they don't want to cut themselves off
from still making a lot of money
when the reality is they don't have the
psychological skills to be able to
execute trades based on the way they're
trading before so there were 5000 share
trader before they'll set up these
exercises that we're going to talk about
later on the afternoon with 5,000 shares
and then and then completely blow it and
can't do it
the reality is their psychological
makeup is such that they may only be
able to trade do it and do it flawlessly
with 10 shares so I've worked with
people who had to go down to one to be
able to execute it flawlessly they had
to go down to one share and then they
work their way up and then they go to
two and then they go to five they go to
ten and they just work their way up I
mean is there any but in this room who
hasn't paper traded and who is there
anybody who has an experience being able
to execute your trades flawlessly on
paper but that when you when you try to
execute a plan with real money it
doesn't work see the plans the plans
work in your not working this is what
mechanical trading is all about okay
mechanical trading is finding out just
how big that gap is you cannot take for
granted that because you recognize an
opportunity to enrich yourself in some
way that you have the skills and be able
to take advantage of it appropriately
you can't take it for granted and most
everybody does
so mechanical trading gives you all this
information it gives you it tells you
what works and what doesn't in the
market and what works and what doesn't
with you so that you know what you need
to focus on to be able to make
consistent money you guys you guys with
me on this is it making sense okay then
you can evolve if you want to the
subjective stage of training because you
can make consistent money training
mechanically okay that's I mean it's but
most people like to be able to use their
their rational thinking in process and
try to figure things out and the
subjective stage of training is simply
this is a broader more flexible mode of
training where you use everything you've
ever learned about the price movement to
determine your edges in other words you
know all the different patterns you've
learned all the different nuances of
market behavior will determine you know
where you get in how much profit you
take where you set your stops you see in
the subjective mode of trading in the
subjective mode if someone said to me
okay
I'm buying here and my stop is here but
the mark is starting to come down to my
stop and I get out right here and I
don't let my stop get I don't let myself
get stopped out of my original spot in
the it truly for someone who's evolved
to the subjective mode of training
that's alright you can do that because
you're not doing out of fear and you're
not doing it out of the fact that you
haven't accepted the risk you're doing
it because you recognize the pattern
that the market is giving you is such
that there's a high probability you are
gonna get stopped out and so therefore
you must scratch a trader or get out
with it with a little bit of a loss it's
not because you're afraid there's a huge
difference you guys with me on this
and then the last stage is the intuitive
this is the most advanced mode of
trading it would be the equivalent to
getting a black belt in martial arts
it's when you find yourself in the zone
tapped into the collective consciousness
of the market giving you a sense of the
flow if you look at the market as being
you know a collection of individuals you
can tap into that you can find
yourselves not something you will
yourself into you just find yourself
into in this zone where you're just
seeing and doing things that you can't
necessarily explain at a rational level
and the problem is that there are people
everyone has intuitive capabilities
there are but but some people that's
completely shut off and with others you
know they don't trust it because you
know they they don't they can't make the
distinction between what's intuition and
what's just their mind hoping that
something's gonna happen or hoping that
you know what they see is really what's
going on and making it feel like
intuition the problem is until you
acquire these fundamental skills that
we're talking about you definitely don't
want to be trading based on intuitive
impulses you just want to make note of
them when you've got the skills then
find yourself in the zone then go ahead
and do whatever whatever comes to your
brain until you flip yourself out of
that meaning when you start thinking at
a rational level you mostly do flip
yourself right out of that right out of
the zone because your rational mind
wants to know wants reasons your
rational mind wants logical reasons and
these intuitive impulses don't come from
that part of your brain they come from
that creative part of your brain and by
definition creativity is bringing
something forth that didn't previously
exist they exist somewhere in the world
or in the universe somewhere but it
didn't exist in your mind and it's
outside the parameters of what you
already believe so there's going to be
an instant conflict between what you
think at a rational level and your
intuitive impulses until you train your
rational mind to accept your intuitive
impulses got that
[Laughter]