I'm good evening folks welcome back
well I was supposed to be doing a live
stream today but uh I guess the powers
that be
that uh
was unfortunate that I couldn't do it
today uh OBS wouldn't connect to my
YouTube channel
and I had all kinds of issues with it so
I elected to sit down and wait for the
close of the day and then come back in
here and do somewhat a little bit of a
review but also I want to teach a little
bit more about institutional overflow
Advanced ICT Gap Theory
so we're looking at the dollar Index
this is a weekly chart to just keep you
abreast as to where we are in that
Weekly range
reach it up into the weekly bearish
order block which is this candle right
here
which is the midpoint of that
pierced that last week so far this week
we're just Meandering around inside of
the range of the weekly order block
opening price
in that mean threshold
daily chart here
you can see
Fair shorter block again
working that level a few times more
over the last few days
we have a small little Fairway Gap there
and we trade it back down into the old
weekly inversion fair value Gap
and again
assume for a moment that
we move higher okay unless we break
below this low here I'm going to stay
with that narrative
and if it does we'll be looking for buy
side here
and then we have a
volume and balance there
and we have a
Wick so a consequent encouragement that
I don't have it on here because I don't
have too many lines
but I have that level in mind should we
go about this high midpoint of this Wick
and then the volume and balance
okay
that's also uh
the premium Wick console encouragement
on the weekly chart let's go back up one
more time
that's this one here okay
all right so let's move down into
an hourly chart for dollar Index usually
I don't do this with you but
we'll go into a little bit more detail
here
so inside this swing low
all this price action this is a
swing on a larger daily chart that we're
looking at through the lens of an hourly
chart see this Gap right here
notice there's an absence of one over
here but look at all the back and forth
price action so we have only sell side
here offered so that means the candle
went through between this candles low
and this candle is high it delivered on
the downside so it's sell side delivery
inefficient in the form of buy side
delivery so it's offered here on this
candle
to the next candle we open trade down
rally back up
and close right here next candle opens
trades down stops right inside that Gap
low
then sends it higher
this is a balanced price range
balanced price ranges
tend to either stop at their high or low
or midpoint or well she'll be consequent
encouragement midpoint of the gap
we can see that happening essentially
here
so this extended through and again this
is the reason why it's not supply and
demand folks we cut through candles to
get to a narrative
the algorithm is going right back to
this inefficiency
and the fact that we traded back and
forth here
by side sell side has been offered
it left that range right here
if it ever comes back down into it it's
highly unlikely that we'll trade to the
low of this Gap again and through it
so that's what makes a ICT balance price
range
we also have a imbalance here I wanted
to make sure I highlighted this Gap
but this candle is low and this candle
is high
that would be typically the Shaded area
here so don't be confused I'm not
drawing it to here to make up the 60
Minute Affair that you got which is in
the form of a buy side imbalance cell
certain efficiency so only by side was
offered Here Sell side was offered to it
there and then quickly after hitting the
balance price range consequent
encroachment price immediately erupted
to the upside working up into this very
magnet in the form of a city still sound
about to buy something efficiency
notice how many times it hits that daily
bearish order block here it's worked the
level here here and here
and that mean threshold weekly bear
shorter block here at 104.54
that also has a small little bit of a
inefficiency still remaining here so we
got as high as that candle here but
between this candle's high that candle
is low there's a small little Gap in
there
so
if you look at the high and the low and
the higher high here this down close
candle extend that through that's a ICT
bearish breaker so you can see it being
respected here respected here here and
even here
so it would be much more meaningful to
me
if we were to break that
low here otherwise I'm going to stick
with the likelihood that dollar Index
will either consolidate
or go higher either one
you know I could care less right now I'm
still neutral and I'll explain more
about that as we go
here's euro dollar this is its weekly
chart
and
all of this price action back and forth
in here
even at their sell side liquidity
resting below this
it's
being met with high resistance
so high resistance liquidity runs they
can still deliver and go below here but
High Resistance recording runs are very
frustrating sometimes for individuals
that don't know how to anticipate them
or
don't know what they are so I teach you
in my Concepts to identify what a high
resistance liquidity run is so that way
you can understand the distinctions
between that and a low resistance
liquidity run low resistance recording
runs
are high probability and they are
immediate gratification that this
immediately run to your objectives it's
very fun to trade them
it's almost immediate feedback once you
get into the trade whereas a high
resistance liquidity run
is a trade that's met with a lot of
resistance in getting to where your
objective may be now because I'm calling
it a high resistance or low resistance
doesn't mean that it's resistance in the
sense of support or resistance
from the perspective of a retail Theory
it's resistance in the form that it's
very hard for it to be one-way delivery
so it's going to be a lot of
consolidation move a little bit come
back retrace much more than you're
probably comfortable and then
consolidate more and then go a little
bit further in the direction you were
hoping for that's high resistance so
if a new Trader or a
Break Even Trader someone that makes a
little bit of money then loses it
when they are met with those kinds of
conditions in the marketplace it tends
to create very
sporadic emotional responses in their
psyche they become agitated they will
many times get stopped out because they
want to move their stop loss too
aggressively too soon
or they're afraid to get stopped out and
open their stop loss a little bit
further and it runs for that as well and
they regret having moved their stock to
a larger stop loss
understanding what a high resistance
liquidy run is
will help you to filter those types of
Trades out doesn't mean you can't trade
them or paper trade them or tape read it
just means that you don't want to be
putting a lot of emphasis on trading in
those environments but more specifically
waiting for low resistance liquidity
runs
all right here's the daily chart in here
you can see how we've hit that bearish
order block I mentioned the last time we
spoke
hit it now it is consolidating inside
of that Gap right there now look at all
the back and forth here up down up down
so it's being met with that
in the form of high resistance now can
this go higher with the dollar going
lower absolutely
can it work its way through this area
here and attack the cell side below it
absolutely
but because it's not one-sided because
it's not
so heavy-handed or
because I can justify both sides of the
marketplace right now
it's a neutral position for me
that means I want to only be Trading
when it's high probability and with low
resistance liquidity run signatures that
means that the market is more likely to
run quickly right to where I think it's
going to go
either it be a liquidity
or a inefficiency
so if I'm looking for lower prices and
if I was being honest with you gone to
my head I think the dollar is going to
go higher and I think eventually euro
dollar will attack these lows in here
will it meet it before running out this
high
that I don't know but because I don't
know that I'm sitting still with my
hands in my pocket not willing to do
anything
but every time I sit down with you I'm
always going to tell you what I believe
is likely to occur if I'm being forced
into a corner say Okay ICT what is it
you think is going to happen right now
regardless of whether you want to take a
trade in what do you think is going to
happen and that's what I do
I like giving commentary in the analysis
when the market is one-sided and it's in
low resistance the Kodi run signatures
because it's very pleasing for me to
share it and then you watch it happen in
your charts right now we don't have that
okay a lot of objectives have been met
recently both in dollar
and Euro and index futures
so we have to let the market consolidate
in month one of my mentorship core
content
on my YouTube channel I introduced the
idea of the four stages of price
delivery and
consolidation
expansion retracement and reversal those
four stages of price delivery
we are in now a consolidation so we have
to wait
you have to Simply wait
you don't want to push the envelope here
and try to
predict
what it's going to do when it's like
this it's easy to predict where price is
going to draw to when it's one-sided in
a low resistance liquidity run that
means it's very easy to see one side
either a buy or a cell and very very
difficult to justify the opposite side
of the marketplace so an example would
be let's assume that the market only had
one single low swing and not not the
back and forth trading range that we
have in this area here so prices spent a
lot of time working in this range here
so it's going to take a real significant
price move to get down below it
so if it were only a single
low and then reverse like a V bottom
type thing then it would be very easy to
assume that this would
continuously move lower and then it
would be a low resistance liquidity run
short
and then obviously the opposite should
be seen for a long in the dollar Index
but because we don't have that
we have to sit and wait for more
information
otherwise you're trading with low
probability can you make money possibly
but it's more likely that you'll be
wrong
and because I'm teaching you the
distinctions between High Resistance and
low resistance the quality runs
if you do engage it and you lose you'll
regret having done so because I've
already told you now it's lower
probability
all right here's the hourly chart on
euro dollar
so the last time we sat with each other
it was a live stream earlier
and I mentioned this area here how the
market ran up hit buy side traded into a
short-term premium relative this High to
that low and then once you hit the buy
side and that premium
very bad Gap in the form of a city sauce
on a balanced box on an efficiency it
worked lower to attack the sell side
here
there was South liquidity here and the
market was hanging right around this
area here and we'll look at that on a
15-minute time frame but eventually it
moved higher to the top end of that
daily fair value Gap
then went lower failed to make the lower
low here and then reversed higher to
trade into a deeper premium
further up in the upper portion of this
60 Minute fair value Gap in the form of
a sell-side imbalanced by certain
efficiency
then back into that daily fair value Gap
[Music]
so now in a 15-minute time frame here's
that hourly fair value guy
it ran up into it here
and notice what we were talking about in
the live stream I said while we were
hitting this area here I said if it were
going to go lower and it would be a high
probability scenario for it to go lower
I would prefer to see price stay below
this level here
if it was to go higher
I'm not interested in going lower
basically consequent encouragement
from the fear I got high and the fair
value Gap low and that shaded area here
is the daily fair value Gap
if we were to meet consequent
encroachment and then break down and
create another survey Gap that would be
viewed as
a premium array then I would look for
that low and that larger Celsius
to be taken but because if it were to go
higher remember I would prefer it to
stay around consequent encroachment
not go to the high because if it does
that
all that means to me is it goes back
down lower
it's likely to not go below that low
go back and listen to the live stream
where I was talking about it in here the
reason why I'm not interested in once it
gets up to here even though it did drop
notice it dropped handsomely from this
high of the fair value Gap but didn't
take out the sell side
because we are in that neutral zone for
me as a Trader where I don't want to
take a trade
if we're to tape read or study it
ideally we want to see consequent
encroachment which is the halfway point
of that Gap
which is in the iron shaded hue that
should be not traded back to the high
end but if it does
and it starts to sell off this is a trap
this low won't be taken in this cell
side and this cell side will be left
intact
they run higher
to take out the Asia high this is the
Asian kill Zoom
and this is the London Killzone
so the market trades down fails to go
lower
runs a short-term high so as a shift to
Market structure
Buys in a balance outside and efficiency
here trades down the consequent
encroachment which is the midpoint of
the gap between those candles low and
this candle is high there's your silver
bullet for Euro
rallies
find some support at that daily fair
value gaps yeah it's respecting that
runs up and consolidates in consequent
encroachment which is the midpoint of
the Gap High and the low consolidation
expansion
respects the high of it opens and runs
through it takes out age as high
swings all the way up into to take by
side and trade into a deeper premium on
that hourly fair value Gap in the form
of a city
this area up here that's shaded in pink
is this area here
on the hourly so this run
from here to here is this
on the 15 from that low up to that high
then we draw right back down into the
midpoint of that fair value Gap
so again it's reaching for liquidity I
like the idea
that we did come all the way back up
here to take out buy stops to me I think
that favors a continued move lower
because they left this low and they left
the larger pool of liquidity again I'll
take you right back up to the
that's this low here so there's sell
side here and there's a little bit of a
gap right there you can notice that
the little trading view icon things in
the way but
this candle's high and that candle's low
that's a buy side of balance outside of
efficiency and you have salsa
and you have relative equal lows here
so we came all the way back up to take
out the buy side
all of this is efficiently delivered
so if it was the trade up to the high
end of that that would have been perfect
but it left a small little portion in
there and broke down
I want to see it run for the sell side
here and here so I'm thinking want to
660 and maybe lower
but that's what I'm looking for going
into London to New York tomorrow that's
what I would favor that does not mean
I'm trading it it just means that that's
my gun to my head that's what I believe
based on what I'm looking at here if I'm
accurate about dollar going higher
that's what I would expect to see okay
so dump at the farm on it I'm just
telling you what I'm seeing in price
action
all right yes even the s p June contract
we'll be rolling over into the September
contract here shortly
but for around we're just looking at the
June contract
so
this Gap in here
is what I said we would draw up into we
obviously did that and we're looking at
the weekly chart and the Candlestick is
represented as such here so we hit the
high of that Gap and then we've been
banging around inside that which is
typical when price runs to a higher time
frame Target
lower time frame candlesticks and charts
will move into a consolidation profile
consolidation profile after multiple
markets have met their objectives as I
mentioned with the dollar Index hit
straight up into our premium objectives
Euros traded down into our discount
objectives and Es has traded into its
premium objectives so when that occurs
the market will tend to do what
consolidate which is why I'm saying I'm
neutral so you can see how there's a a
relationship between how I teach market
profiles not Market profile in the sense
that you think it is but profiles in the
sense of like schematics
a road map if you will okay uh
typical Behavior
or
performance
by Price something that looks familiar
that's generally what I'm trying to get
at and I taught and gave out specific
schematics for weekly profiles and daily
profiles so you can see what type of
performance price will behave like
because the algorithm will tend to
follow those types of profiles
and right now because the market has met
our objectives that we've been looking
for for a couple weeks now
it just sits still for a little while
and disconsolidates
it doesn't mean it's going to reverse it
doesn't mean it's going to explode and
continue it just means that we wait we
wait for more information now what I do
notice in here and I failed to mention
last time we were doing the live stream
there's a volume and balance in here
right there between this candle is
closed this candle is opening and we're
inside this Gap here it would be
fine for it to drop down into that area
there so around 4240 ish and that still
would not break the
structure that would it is going to go
higher and move like it did in NASDAQ
this High here where there's buy side
that would be the next draw on upside
but short term it may consolidate or
retrace down into this area right in
here that's a volume imbalance and I
don't want to have too many lines on the
chart but you want to have that on yours
in the event that we do retrace lower it
might want to draw into that area
as long as we stay
above this candle why am I picking that
candle we've already worked inside these
two down closed candles that's your
bullish order block consecutive down
closed candle it traded down into that
and repelled price higher
if it was the color outside the lines of
this volume imbalance which is that
white shaded area
it can trade down into consequent
encroachment of this candle's tail so
about right there which is essentially
the low of that volume balance
it can go a little bit past the little
you know somewhat but I don't want to go
below there
if it trades below it not doesn't
require a close if it trades down below
that then I would be more reluctant to
anticipate that high being the next run
on liquidity okay so in layman's terms
I'm expecting it to consolidate inside
this white shaded area
allowing up to a retracement into this
area here worst case scenario half of
this candle's tail
but not below that candle's low okay so
as long as we're remaining above that
candle's low right there I'm staying
with the idea that we could potentially
go higher like we've seen in NASDAQ
everything can change you know overnight
going into tomorrow but based on what
this chart's showing you right now
that's my opinion
[Music]
daily chart here for yes we have a fair
value Gap in here
shift in Market structure
drops into a fair value Gap rallies up
and into our Gap
so in the upper portion of that volume
of balance on the weekly chart which is
that white shaded area and that specific
area where there was no trading it's
worked its way up in there and now look
how it's just hanging around in there
see that
interesting isn't it watch what happens
when we drop into a lower time frame
here's the hourly chart
this blue line is the high of that
Weekly Gap
this blue line is the low of that Weekly
Gap
the white shaded area is the volume and
balance
I'm drawing your attention to this Wick
right here in its midpoint which is
consequent encroachment
so this is a discount array because it's
below market price
let's play devil's advocate for a moment
and let's assume for the sake of
discussion that the market does in fact
want to go higher
it could trade down into this area here
and then run for by side notice how he
left clean highs here
so that looks like perfect textbook
resistance I don't like that I never
like that
smooth edges like to be made Jagged okay
I have an expression I say it many times
and
I think this will be disrupted
now how and when it will occur
we have to watch and see what price does
at each Killzone okay or specific times
of the day where we like to trade
so I want to see do we respect price at
this
discount consequent encouragement of
that Wick
if it runs through it there is another
Wick right there so this midpoint of
that one you want to draw that out in
time too
it's also basically these highs
now
what I don't like about that is I don't
like it going back down to these
relative equal highs because that's
treated as what resistance turn
potential support right I don't like
that so take us back into that higher
time frame daily chart remember what I
said about 42.40
is in that volume and balance on the
daily chart so it could trade down into
and Below these highs here if it really
wants to be aggressive
trade down through that all the way to
the low of that volume and balance on
the weekly chart
which would take us into this area right
here
right there
okay so just be mindful I I don't have
like an affinity for like these levels
here draw that out in time and if it
comes down to it we'll treat this
support
and I don't see that as resistance okay
I think this is like knocking on
heaven's door so
um they may need to take it down deeper
just try to sell the idea that this is
resistance and then come back up later
on and you know break through this here
like
gunbusters uh this area here I don't
have a four hour chart tonight but I
added the notation that we showed this
in a live stream yeah the other day
yesterday
and it's based on the four hour
Tuesday May 23rd
10 A.M
inversion pair that you got so you can
watch the live stream you'll see it's it
was there and that's what we're seeing
the respect of there and this is the
daily fair value you got inside of that
[Music]
all right here's the 50-minute time
frame on ES today
hi
look how it's thought right at the High
of that volume and balance hooks that's
perfect it goes right to the tick
not in your textbooks just in the book
of ICT
brakes lower trades to the low of the
Gap now this line and that line are
the Gap levels on our weekly chart for
ES
the white shaded area is the volume of
balance this is that Wick
discount Council encouragement
level that I just showed you before we
drop down and go back up
that's this one here okay so Wick
discount consequent encroachment there
I can already hear some of the newer
students this is really complicated
everything's complicated when you first
start
so I'm thinking that we could draw down
into that and how we trade to it and if
through it
all the factors I just gave you for the
other hourly chart they are to be
weighed out that's why I'm I'm waiting
to see I don't have a very clear
definitive here's my next setup I'm
watching those levels to see how it
forms Market structure around them
so I'm not trying to guess I'm not
trying to be
predictive yet okay so I'm sitting
neutral we're not reacting the price we
never react to price but we're sitting
still waiting for more information so
that way we can predict the next outcome
right now it's uncertain but I do
I have the opinion if the gun is in my
head or I think it's going to go I think
it's going to go lower first to go
higher later
and the five minute chart you can see
here we had buy side resting above these
highs here in this short term high this
is your opening range due to swing so it
rallies up hits the high that Weekly Gap
High
and drops lower so now there's a buy
side resting below that
to the left over here
is the other relative equal high on
Monday that formed so over here
you can see how you hit it
broke lower Drew back into current new
week opening Gap
came back up to it anyways opening Gap
and then rejected traded down to the
weekly Gap low and then Consolidated
around it notice that this low to the
high in this range here it's essentially
hugging that Weekly get well
so it's kind of like a equilibrium price
point in this consolidation in here
and I would suspect it I want to trade
down into that 4264 4240 ish level
anything below 4240 then obviously we
have to keep our mind on seeing that
daily level I've told you about I didn't
want to see it Go below
[Music]
right below here
is sell side okay right below there so
all this run up
it ran for the sell side
the weekly Gap low
and all this area in here I'm going to
teach you
a little bit more about gaps but for now
here is the am session ICT Silver Bullet
trading up into that Gap High
swing low is right there so I hit our
higher time frame weekly objective
that's a key level it hits it breaks
lower shift in Market structure that's
bearish
small little imbalance here this right
here
that move right there that is the 2022
ICT mentorship model
so
buy side taken into a premium
shift in Market structure fair value Gap
trades up into it there's your show go
short
what do you aim for relative equal lows
and liquidity
if you want to be overzealous you can
aim for the weekly Gap low I personally
wouldn't have but for the sake of
argument you could have
now if you're trading the ICT Silver
Bullet which is the model that I've
taught you for 2023 for the YouTube I
teach mentorship
we have a shift in Market structure and
it's much more pronounced
so this swing low here is broken
we have a fair value gap between this
candle's high and that candle is low
this is a civi cells on imbalanced by
sound efficiency
price returns back up
there's your short
you'd have to endure one more time in a
small amount of draw down in here
it spends a little bit of time and then
finally gives up the ghost breaks one
more time below that low
digs into this sell side but notice that
that low is just barely below those
you know what it's reaching for new week
opening Gap they're like a magnet okay
the market drops comes back up another
fair value Gap so you could have taken
this one if you didn't take that one or
you could have traded this one short
pyramided more in here
drops down look where that low is on
that candle right there that's the new
week opening Gap below
bang perfect right to the tick
runs right back up in
returning back to the old Fairway Gap
dropping aggressive
small Gap in here around new week
opening Gap
Trace up into it here which is
institutional order flow integer drill
which is a partial
return into not a complete closure of
that Gap that candles high that candle
is low
just a little bit above the low and then
consolidates
and tears often goes lower and I'm going
to tell you how that love would be
significant
do you take the high here and add your
FIB to it here and draw it down to that
low
one standard deviation
would be 42.78.75
that's a pretty handsome objective if we
treat that high to that low this low
being a fulcrum point
that means if this move from high to
that low
s like a door okay and it swung this was
the hinge of the door this high if it
was allowed to swing completely all the
way around
it would come right down right below
that low here it would come to that
price point here so all I'm saying is
this range from that low to high
subtracted from that low takes us right
to this 4278.75
that's pretty good isn't it you know so
that's a pretty good run for a silver
bullet
getting short around the 4298 level
that's one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven twelve thirteen
fourteen fifteen sixteen Seventeen
eighteen nineteen handles that's a
pretty good day
even if you're trading with one contract
let's go a little bit further
now I'm going to teach you Advanced Gap
Theory
we're going to take a look at that same
price swing all of this is the the
initial runoff this is a Judah swing
okay
in the first 30 minutes of trading so at
9 30 opening bell we see the price run
higher
stops dead in its tracks at the weekly
Gap High the Gap high that I told you
about weeks ago
having that level on your chart and then
anticipating
price reacting there
swing low it breaks lower and that gives
us this small little Gap right there
this Gap right there is simply a fair
value Gap it's a common Gap they can be
traded though with the context I've
already taught you 2022 model buy side
higher time frame level
takes buy side does it go after the
short term low yes it does did it leave
a gap yes it did okay trade up into it
it does
go Short Stop Above This candle's high
right there if you're really scared and
you don't want to take a larger risk put
your stock right above here and trade
with less Leverage
the market breaks lower and we have this
Gap right here
this is a fair value Gap in the form of
a city just like this is but this is a
breakaway Gap what is it doing it's
breaking away from this important higher
time frame High
inside the model of the 2022
ICT mentorship model that I taught you
and it's moving aggressive so we have
one two two times there's a shift in
Market structure that's bearish
this is a breakaway Gap Breakaway gaps
must it must have some context as to why
price should see for instance this is a
bearish breakaway Gap it's breaking away
from a level that we would already
anticipate being some measure of a short
okay some context around this level we
would expect to see some kind of respect
of that level okay so it's a higher
timing weekly get high we've already
been there on Monday repelled lower
we created a short-term High prior to it
here and it ran up to it there and then
it took that low out there left the Gap
that in itself is the 2022 model
then it breaks again
returns back into it here with the leave
relative equal lows
so there's your fulcrum point from low
to high
you may have missed the 2022 model entry
here no problem
the return back into this Gap here
Breakaway gaps tend to leave a portion
of the Gap unfilled
from this candle is low to this candle
is high
it retraces all the way up into this
level so between these highs of these
candles and that candle is low there's a
small portion that's left open we would
expect to see that if this is going to
be a gap say you went short into it here
and you're seeing it watch it in here
your stop if you were shorting in here
would be above this candle's High
not fearing any return back into this
because we have two shifts in Market
structure
this
return in here you're anticipating while
entering the street you're expecting
this portion to stay open
if it does
you want to see that happen anyway for
your trade
but if it doesn't and it completely
fills it in that's not a breakaway cup
then it may need to come back up and tap
this one more time
so if you were to get stopped out
you have to wait for it to hit this Fair
bit you got and then break one more time
create another imbalance or a fair value
and then use that to go short
so what I just taught you is how you
navigate if you're wrong and it doesn't
become a breakaway Gap
you wait for it to trade to the higher
time frame if you're Vega and then break
lower again create another fair value
and treat that as a potential later
Breakaway Gap
but the context is it's running up here
that get Traders thinking it's going
higher bullish
okay from this low up to this high in
here this looks like a bull flag I
guarantee it the most retail Traders
and when it went above that high here
that validated everyone thinking that
it's a bull flag
then it broke lower
now if you didn't have that Weekly Gap
High
you would never understand what I'm
showing you here but you've known that
level for weeks
it broke down and then here is a
breakaway cap it's qualified as a
breakaway Gap because it leaves and goes
lower to another new low and leaves that
portion open at that time we get real
confident that it never will come back
up to this level here so we can drop our
spot right to that level there and let
it roll
then we have
these two candles here these are one
minute candles so this is essentially
two minutes
of a fair value Gap so this is a
standard typical ICT Fairbank Gap in the
form of a city
and you can see them come back and trade
back to them
they're like again a common Gap common
gaps can be retraded to multiple times
and they reclaim them sometimes as
supporter resistance
[Music]
and then we have this large gap here
these two down closed candles
that's one big theory about you got in
the form of a sibi if we were looking at
a two minute chart right now it's one
minute if you do this on your own charts
look at this area here on a two minute
chart
this one candle down
so it's only trading back up into
consequent correction of the two minute
range
of these two specific one minute candles
so in Easy language and layman's terms
from this candle is low and this candle
is high when a two minute chart this is
one down close candle midpoint of that
is where it's trading here that's
consequent encroachments
this is the fair value Gap in the form
of a civi cells on imbalanced bison
deficiency
and it's a measuring Gap
what's that mean
we can take this range and use it for
projection
the market breaks lower and then we have
another fair value Gap in the form of a
city you can look at this on a two
minute chart this will be one down
closed candle and again essentially
working into consequent encroachment
taking buy side here and then breaking
lower to a lower low below that Weekly
Gap low
standard fair value gaps which are
common gaps they can be reclaimed or
traded back to as resistance or support
trades back up to it here look at the
bodies of the candles here
that's telling you what the narrative if
you're reading my Gap Theory
in price if you see these signatures
like this see I'm going to tell you all
the time
the bodies tell you the story
the Wicks do the damage the Wix is what
everybody else gets messed up with
dojis and specific you know types of
Candlestick formations nonsense it's all
nonsense okay
reading price action naked with time
and looking for these types of
signatures here the open and close of
these two candles here are supporting
the idea that this low
of that inefficiency is being respected
and then price does what it trades lower
where does it trade too
below the sell side here but not some
random level
if we take the high of that price swing
and draw all that Fibonacci all the way
down to that candle's high right there
from high
to lower the Gap why this Gap because
this is the measuring Gap
it's approximately half
of a
implied dealing range implied meaning
we're looking for it to go lower but we
haven't seen price go there yet
we're not reacting remember we're
predicting price so the high here draw
that down to that candle's high right
there
right there okay
what that does is gives you a projection
to a standard deviation of negative one
and I showed you in the live stream
yesterday so if you want to watch the
video prior to this one in the ICT
mentorship 2023 playlist
go to the section where it shows the
Fibonacci settings and you'll get the
settings that I can
share with you there but the negative
one standard deviation comes in at 42
69.25 okay I screenshot this so that way
I have my cursor right underneath there
so that way the data that you see up in
the upper left hand corner here the low
comes in exactly at 42 69.25 folks that
is the daily low
to the tick
right there and it never went lower
today
even after our session didn't go lower
so
this is my ICT swing projection Theory
when I break the market down see gaps
are just like a pdra matrix
they have an hierarchy okay
you have a breakaway Gap you have common
gaps common gaps can be reclaimed that
means treated multiple times
measuring gaps tend to leave a portion
open just like a brake wake up so if
we're expecting it to go lower it stands
the reason that we expect it not to
trade all the way up here
and if we're expecting it to be a
measuring Gap guess what we want to see
it not go up there and that confirms and
qualifies it as a measuring Gap then we
can take the high project it down to the
low of the Gap if we're bearish and then
get our standard deviations but that's
standard deviation negative one has to
be in agreement with moving below an old
area
of liquidity
so that's between these two things makes
us have the Precision okay it's not
simply you take a fib put it over two
different price swings and then you're
going to get the same math that I have
but
understanding that gaps have an
hierarchy
okay and this is how I qualify my gaps
every time you watch me do a recorded
Trading
episode where I'm going in I'm trading
live data and I'm pyramiding and adding
and pyramiding and adding and I'm taking
partials off and I'm looking for a
specific level
I'm using this logic here when I'm
drawing out when I say I want to leave
this see this portion of the Gap stay
open I want to see this portion of the
Gap statement ideal if it leaves this
portion open unfilled
it's this Theory I'm teaching you right
here okay
common gaps
are a fair value Gap that can be
reclaimed treated as support and
resistance we see that here it comes
back up and bangs It And Trades lower
this Gap here
projected through all this mess here
it's not supply and demand folks Sam
seiden has no idea what this is
trade up into it here the bodies of the
candles respect that candles
high right there
perfect
don't take my word for it look at the
data
and then it trades lower and makes the
very low of the day here using my swing
projection Theory within the context of
my Advanced Gap Theory
so hopefully you enjoyed tonight and
hope you learned something else
um obviously if this is your first time
watching things with gaps or my theory
on gaps and or swing projections it may
feel a little bit uh complicated and you
have a thousand new questions and that's
wonderful that means you're trying to
learn and I'm here to teach you don't
think that you can just watch this video
and you understand it I want you to go
back and look at old price swings look
at all these old price swings and start
breaking down the gaps and use this
hierarchy I have more to teach you
that's deeper in that era because
there's other gaps that I'm going to
teach you that I haven't even taught my
charter members yet but that context
will be taught later on I'm going to do
it real time
for now use this as a benchmark to go
and look at your other old price swings
and start measuring them out and journal
them in your trading journal until I
talk to you next time
be safe