foreign
so I got tied up yesterday obviously I
wasn't able to get on YouTube with
anything but I did an execution shared
it on Twitter the link for that trade
example will be in the comment section
of this video
all right so let's go briefly through I
don't want to spend too much time on
this one because I have to hit the road
so a dollar Index is our weekly chart
obviously I mentioned in the commentary
on Wednesday that unless we take out
that low and trade into this
inefficiency one more time how it's
going to hold on to a bullish bias for a
dollar and bearish bias for Euro trying
not to pick tops and bottoms on a higher
time frame chart
so you can see the market did in fact
aggressively move toward that low no
problem I stated very plainly in
Wednesday's video that I'm not trading
Forex I'm not interested but a gun to my
head I always try to sit down and share
with the viewers and my students what my
opinion is on the market at the very
moment that the charts are being shared
with you okay it's a wonderful
illustration of
seeing me
outline something from an opinionated
position
and admitting up front that I wasn't
going to be doing anything with the
information regardless anyway but I want
to kind of
put some tent posts down so that way you
can
get comfortable warm up to the idea of
not having to be right okay uh
usually the septics I mean Skeptics of
me and my work they'll say well look see
he said that and it didn't do that look
at that we're gonna kind of like
make sure you understand in the proper
context because I do lots of video work
I do lots of audio clips and things that
people can listen to on Twitter and on
this YouTube channel
and it's very easy to take something I
say out of context and make a an idea or
an argument about okay set up straw man
arguments and I'm not here to try to
make myself look like I'm always right
in fact I was
kind of hoping that the dollar Index and
the euro dollar would do something
contrary so that way it sets the
Precedence going forward that you don't
have to be perfect and you can be right
sometimes
let's still be profitable
you can be incorrect
sometimes and still be profitable so
that means being profitable when you're
wrong
and I'm going to kind of teach that as I
go through this
so the dollar Index on Wednesday I
mentioned that I would hold on to a
bullish stance on dollar unless we take
out that low and trade into this
inefficiency now if we trade down below
it and come back up I would expect it to
be treated as resistance and then that
would set the stage for a run into these
lows but I have to see if we'll do that
obviously at the time of this recording
it's around 11 o'clock or so
in my local area here on the east coast
of the US and on Friday so this is
representing
not Friday's data but this is Thursdays
so I took the screenshot at this time on
Thursday
in the daily chart we'll be representing
that as well so all of this is
Thursday's
time it said this presentation will
encapsulate Thursday and then partial
Friday's action and I have to hit the
road so I won't be able to do anything
as a final review so we have a breaker
here on the daily chart we have high low
higher high down close canes on here
with the lowest close notice I'm not
using this one
I'm using the lowest close
the volume the narrative the storyline
is inside the bodies the Wicks do the
damage so you take that range expand it
to the right and that would be your
breaker
and I'm calling this a weekly breaker
but it's in inside of this range here so
I'm zeroing in on
the daily chart to get inside of what
this would be
over the course of
more than one week obviously but I'm
looking at that daily candle right there
so from a weekly perspective but not
leaning on the weekly chart
but that specific candle right there is
what I'm aiming at and drawing it out in
time and I mentioned how we worked
inside these levels here the weekly
mean threshold of the bearish order
block that's this level here 104.54 I
mentioned the daily order block
opening price here so it was lots of
work on that level
and then ultimately we did in fact trade
down here
I want you to think about
if you're hanging on every word and
syllable that I say
where I stated that I'm going to hold on
to a bullish bias for a dollar unless it
takes out that low
now what I'm suggesting if you listen to
that Wednesday analysis
I'm saying that I was not interested in
taking any trades I'm sitting still
I'm neutral I made a very clear
statement that I am neutral that means
I'm taking new trades I'm going to wait
and see what the market tells me
so
it was kind of like teaching
whenever I give something out in terms
of analysis or I call a move and it
happens there's a group of individuals
that follow me they're immediately
responding with Okay now what's it going
to do now what's next because they want
to see the next magic trick
and I'm trying to settle those
expectations down on all of you even for
the folks that don't reach out to me but
you're probably thinking okay you got
that right so now what's he going to
call next
so it's not that I'm trying to entertain
you I'm not trying to Dazzle you with uh
being correct I'm trying to teach you
how to manage yourself because come
November when I'm no longer doing this
with you all
it'll be up to you to stick to what
you've understood and learned as
rule-based ideas
so what I'm saying is I'm interested in
staying bullish on dollar
bearish on euro dollar as long as
we stay above this low
if I'm neutral I'm looking to take new
trades but if it does trade down here
then that opens the door for me
potentially
conceding and saying okay this is
probably much more meaningful and if we
come down below this
inefficiency
I'm going to see it be treated as
resistance and then any subsequent
premium array
that would set up a later like a fair
value Gap something that effect or a
very shorter block maybe a breaker that
could act as some premium array to send
us into this area here so it's kind of
like my inner musing the thing I'm
considering as a potential future setup
but I can't do anything now because
we're going into Friday and I won't be
in front of the charts on Monday either
so I'll be back in the sooner things
next Tuesday
so here is the hourly chart here we got
down
on Thursday when we saw trading begin
again and we ran quickly down into that
low and then into this low here so
clearing up all the sell side resting
here we
aimed into that and now we have in my
mind potentially shifted bearish not not
convinced entirely I want to see more
evidence on that daily chart and get
below this inefficiency and treat it as
resistance okay so I'm waiting I'm
predicting that as a future possibility
in price action
the outlook for setups if it does that
so it's an if then clause
okay in itself it's algorithmic if the
market will do this then I will do that
but I'm predicting
I'm not reacting I'm predicting that it
will use this inefficiency that's shaped
here as a potential area of resistance
and treat it as a premium array and then
look for that lower daily relative equal
low where cell side would be residing
so it's a condition for me to allow
myself to sit still and relax and not
rush to get into another new trade idea
which many of you need that skill set
all right you're a dollar again this is
representing where we were at the time
on Thursday at this screenshot
so we worked inside this order block
here and
it's a weekly chart so
there really isn't any inefficiency in
this until we get up to here
so if we see that further breakdown on
dollar this will be the point of
Interest I would have on a longer term
for euro dollar
unless this low is taken out if Euro
takes this low out then we resume
looking for these loads to be taken okay
so based on what we saw on dollar Index
on Wednesday's analysis I said that if
we saw that low taken out on the daily
for dollar Index
then I would push my near-term
bullishness on dollar to the back burner
waiting for more developing conditions
potentially setting up shorting ideas
for a dollar which would allow for
upside
on your own now let's just say for sake
of argument say it trades higher and we
get above this
entry says support that could be the
Catalyst to send us up into this volume
of balance that never got traded to
okay so we can see at one two three
dries pattern that would eventually much
later in the year become a factor okay
so I'm just giving you some forecasting
I'm not stating that that's the Ironclad
gospel that's going to actually unfold
it's just these are some of the ideas
when I look at this chart that's what I
think this is a weekly chart so it takes
some time for those things to develop
right here is the daily chart of Euro
and we were Meandering around in here I
said I would stick with the idea that
we'll see if it wants to go lower enough
higher dollar and the higher dollar did
not manifest itself and I said I wasn't
sure if we go lower
if it needs to take out this High first
I didn't know so I was neutral I was
waiting for more information it did in
fact do that now this is where
critics people that don't agree with
what I'm saying or just simply don't
like the fact that you all like
listening to it and trading and finding
profitability in it they'll say they'll
cherry pick the things I say and take
them out of context and say well he said
it was going to do this and it didn't do
that what I stated was I was neutral on
Wednesday it means I'm not taking any
trades in Forex
I'm not using the dollar to trade I
don't trade the dollar I use it as a
barometer for risk on risk off
but index Futures can sometimes fly in
the face of what the dollar Index is
doing
so I'm a little bit more flexible when
it comes to index trading but in Forex
it's
almost iron clad okay if the dollar is
going to decline harshly that decline
the dollar would open the doors for a
rally in Euro you know cable pound
dollar Aussie dollar those types of
currencies
so we didn't see
in fact the run up in here took out that
high but we're still inside this order
block so as I'm saying I'm reserving my
verdict
on what this is going to do until we get
into trading so when I get back from our
road trip here on the weekend
I'll see how we close on Monday's
trading and then I'll give you some kind
of commentary probably on Monday evening
on the YouTube channel
all right so here is where we take the
context
and apply it to the real mechanics of
trading there's nothing wrong with
having an expectation and Analysis like
before you sit down go to bed you look
at the charts and you think okay well
this looks like it may do this or that
so you're predicting you're doing your
analysis you're looking for a setup or a
condition in the marketplace if it meets
that condition
then you'll assume a trade position okay
or incur risk when I stated on Wednesday
that I was neutral that means that I
have no interest in taking the trades
and even if I didn't say that let's just
take that out of the expression
and say that it was you
or I'll just stay on the hot seat ICT
said that he wanted to see your dog go
lower okay take out the the
um the truth and the fact that I said I
wasn't doing anything with it if I'm
stating that I want to see
the euro dollar or any Market
to set up a situation where we can be
going short on it
if the market doesn't present the
conditions for that short to manifest
itself
there is no reason to be upset there's
no reason to point fingers and say ha ha
you got it wrong or me haha iced tea got
it wrong getting it wrong would be
getting into a trade that would be a
failure and stopped
and with the loss okay there is no
there is no setup in here
that gives the expectation with time so
that means the time of the day that we
will be taking a trade which would be
what your your dollar could be traded in
the long and open it can be traded in
the New York open and or running close
there it is that's the that's the times
I'd be interested in even
conferring with euro dollar
we had these relative equal lows here
that I was trying to aim for did this
Market show any displacement lower after
Wednesday's commentary did it displace
lower create a fair value got the trade
back up into and then go short for that
be honest now did it form no the only
hand did was roll right up out of that
came back down found some support inside
of this imbalance which I'm sleeping at
the time I'm not watching it and it
rallies up attacks this high
mean threshold of the 60 Minute fair
value Gap over here it consolidates
around that then expands up and attacks
the buy side here so
profitable in the sense that there was
no monetary loss
but wrong
in expectation and
no ego bruise no Pride harmed because
there was no setup
that failed no setup manifested itself
so that's what generally the Skeptics do
outside of our community they'll point
fingers and say ICT said this and it
didn't do that hoping because in your
ignorance and very limited understanding
of what it is that I'm teaching you'll
see that and say oh yeah you know it
doesn't work or he doesn't not a traitor
he can't read price or he doesn't have
to do anything right
it's someone that is trying to
capitalize on
the viewing section of our audience that
doesn't know enough to know better okay
so there is no setup in here that set up
a displacement trade back up into a fair
value Gap and then run the liquidity
here here and potentially over into this
low but I didn't I didn't call that low
I called this area of Interest right
below that low here at the time on
Wednesday's commentary this little logo
was just inside this area with the mm
data I had on the chart okay so uh
it didn't manifest any kind of losing
trade what we want to see form that
gives us the framework for the trade has
to be there in price if it doesn't
manifest or make itself present in price
action there's nothing to do
there was no losing trade there was no
missed opportunity for a short because
it just simply didn't manifest it went
the other direction no problem you're
going to have that okay you're going to
have that occur with you in your own
analysis your own trading and you can
sit around and beat yourself up and say
oh I should have did this I should have
did that or you can say okay well I'm
glad that my system My Method my
conceptual ideas about how I'm reading
an engaging price action kept me from
taking a loss even though it didn't give
me the opportunity I wanted to pursue
and participate in
I was not able to incur a loss
and there's no ego harm there there's no
Pride there it's flexibility you have to
be flexible as an analyst the Market's
going to do certain things sometimes
that you just don't anticipate
and you're going to get that part of it
wrong but the the beauty is of not
fearing that because if you understand
what I'm teaching you my Concepts my
setups when they form
they're actionable but if they're not
presenting the framework then chances
are the likelihood of you having a loss
is reduced whereas if you just go out
there and trade on indicators or if you
trade on some willy-nilly idea or some
black box idea where it just constantly
keeps throwing ideas that it's a buy SSL
it's from my perspective that's you know
complete Randomness and you're going to
be more prone to being victimized
through that Randomness whereas we rely
on price actions to show us something to
work with and at the time of that
Wednesday analysis and commentary we
didn't see any displacement lower
afterwards so there's nothing to engage
here there was no there's no short that
failed there's no short that manifests
itself so that way you understand the
proper context it's not me trying to
save face and look smart and say ha you
know I I got it wrong so let me get up
here and pretend to give you a narrative
so you don't pay attention to it now I
want you to pay attention to the fact
that I called that to go lower into
these levels because a gun to my head I
had to share my opinion
it's easy for someone to sit on the
sideline say he says buy and sell and
when one works he comes back and says
sometimes there isn't a very clear
expectation from the time I'm sitting in
from the charts and talking to you
and I made that very plain when I said I
was neutral but gone to my head that
means I have to give you my opinion
right then and there I would prefer
to see the market run these lows this
low and maybe get in this area here
okay that's wonderful but did it give us
anything to act on no
so there's no reason to be upset about
it there's no reason to point fingers
and say the concepts don't work or I
can't trade or it's a scam okay it just
means that you are learning how to
navigate
navigating price like this is what
you're gonna have to do every other
system every other educator every other
Trader
has these environments where they go and
they expect to see something they really
want to see something form in price and
if it does they will trade that they're
predicting price
but that setup might not manifest for
them
and they either have to adapt
in Reverse or do nothing well I was
sleeping where all this was going on
so it had already ran up into this area
here when I woke up
so Thursday it was like okay well there
it is I mean so it's already moved
I'm not ashamed of that my focus was and
it has been on index futures
so a 15 minute time frame you can see
here that gap on the hourly chart let me
kick back up into it before we
see that and it's this right here
okay that by setting balance cell signal
efficiency it's a fair value Gap
the market trades back down until here
and into that shaded area which is a
fair value cabin itself
and we'll look at
now the 15 minute time frame you can see
it treated down into it here that's the
London session that's the London open
Killzone so there's your trade it's a
Judas swing and it rallies up admittedly
if I had saw this like this prior to
London
um I still wouldn't have traded because
I'm not trying to trade Forex right now
but I would have anticipated it I'll run
into this area and how we traded at the
order block here
uh that would have been in my mind much
more impactful so we had a down close
handle there we rallied above it and
traded into that mean threshold of this
down close candle that you're seeing
here that right there that's a trade I
would have taken
I would have taken that but you know by
the time I sent and looked at the charts
it already moved too much and I'm not
interested but we have an immediate
rebalance there
and we have an immediate rebalance there
so when you see those
those are signatures that tell you that
the Market's going to want to quickly
get to some level of liquidity or
inefficiency in the old high on the
hourly chart was here to drove up into
debt rather hand ceiling
all right e-mini s p our weekly chart
you can see we did in fact trade higher
on that Weekly Gap and buy side resides
here and outside that we have this
volume of balance as well NASDAQ I
showed you on Wednesday I believe my
memory serves me correct
um NASDAQ has already traded up into its
secondary volume of balance but
the sap has yet to even take us High out
let alone get up into here so
s p unless it completely crashes we're
going to maintain an expectation that
we're going to look for this High to be
traded up into
[Music]
and on e-mini s p daily chart here you
can see that we had this box out of
balance outside and efficiency we traded
down into that I mentioned that it was
likely to do something to this effect
where we would trade down and then run
higher and we did in fact take out those
relative equal highs let's drop into a
hourly chart you'll remember this I at
the time of this recording I sent out a
tweet on my Twitter account taking you
to a
YouTube link that takes you to the 24
minute and five second Mark of
Wednesday's commentary where I go into
this hourly chart and I say okay
I'm taking your attention into this Wick
right here in the midpoint of that which
is consequent encroachment and I say
let's play Devil's Advocate let's assume
for the moment that the s p wants to go
higher if you hold that bias
remember I was saying on
Wednesday I was neutral so I was giving
you an actionable plan of study so we
can go forward okay not to say well you
know the market could go up here or the
market could go down here because if you
just listen to Wednesday's video and
commentary and you walk away thinking
that you didn't pay attention
you you have to listen to what I'm
suggesting to you because if you are
following this market and you're bias or
your
belief is that it's going to go higher I
told you how to engage that and it was
at that 24 minute and five second time
and it's this
Wick right here midpoint of that folks
this does not appear in textbooks okay
it will now because everybody's going to
start writing books on Amazon and
everything else and it's going to be in
mentorships now because you you watched
it panel
but there's still some things that you
need to know you just can't look at
every Wick the question is going to be
how do I pick that way right
well
below this consolidation this was that
Weekly Gap low and this is the weekly
Gap high and I mentioned that there was
buy side relative equal highs there's
buy stops resting right up here and I
stated that I don't like that retail
sees that as resistance I never liked
that that's what I said in Wednesday's
commentary I stated that smooth edges
like to be made jagged okay it's an
expression I've used in a number of
years and this smooth area will be made
Jagged and we've seen that today on
Friday this is where I took the
screenshot at 10 25 this morning Friday
and I mentioned that
let's assume for a moment and play
Devil's Advocate that the market does in
fact want to go higher
it can drop down into this Wick
that's this one here notice there is no
inefficiency there
there's no old high no support
resistance none of that garbage okay
it's algorithmic the Market's going to
return right back to that price point it
means something to the algorithm
it's a point of reference so the market
drops down clearing out
relative equal lows
how far can it go down below those
relatively cool those Michael to that
Wick is exactly what I said is a 24
minute and five second
in Wednesday's analysis it could go down
there and then run higher to take out
the buy side and go higher go back and
listen to that video and tell me if I
did not in fact say that if I lied and I
didn't say that in the video call me out
on Twitter everybody can see it you know
I don't let comments appear on YouTube
because people advertise you know crypto
stuff and make it look like I'm doing
that and I'm not doing anything with
crypto and I'm not selling you anything
I said this
this is what
analysis in 30 years experience and
authorship in these Concepts provide for
you
that right there it drops down just
enough for the spread to engage that
price
it rallies short-term High taken drops
back down in
rips higher
institutional overflow entry drill
into this bison efficiency
rallies fall short of this high in this
high
any retracement here is just going to
set up a run to take out the buy side
any drop here is going to further
increase the likelihood that retail
Traders are going to see that as strong
resistance so they will want to go short
here if they haven't already went short
there where they're going to place their
stop loss where they believe it's
protected in fortify behind this real
strong quote-unquote resistance well you
saw how that worked ripped right on
throughout like it's nothing this is a
nice hot knife right through butter
throw just knocking on heaven's door and
Hallelujah
and here is the five minute chart you're
going to see a link in the comments
section where you watch me engage go in
right into the market and trade the
Silver Bullet trade for Thursday's
Trading
there's a level uh 42.90 and a half that
I had in mind I wanted to see it trade
up into
but I want to use my limit order just
below that
and there's an inefficiency rate there
that I felt that was going to be
impactful
so you'll see me waiting for a
short-term High to form and then when
that short-term highs ran out I teach
this to my students which is running
down Equity when you're approaching
targets
and or get three quarters of the way to
a profit objective
and you're bullish anytime you make a
short-term high and you run above that
short-term High you want to be taking
partials there I don't care what Tom
Dick or Harry says in their dollar menu
mentorships partials always pay 100 of
time there's never been a partial profit
taken that did not pay it always pays so
while you're learning I teach that skill
set
to traders that are learning how to
find consistency and to encourage them
to keep studying if you go in with I'm
only going to enter on this trade here
put my stop loss here and I can only get
out if it goes to my target you're going
to be very frustrated learning how to
trade like that so I teach a graduated
understanding with liquidity and trade
management that works it works folks and
you see me doing it many times in my
trade executions when it was with Forex
you watch me do it now that I'm doing
index Futures you see it happening there
and when you click that link in the
comment section it'll take you to a link
on Twitter and you'll be able to watch
me do the trade that I did on Thursday
which was working in this price range
here
yeah
all right here is those executions and
again you'll watch this live I was using
a two minute chart to get this in
Balance right here
and you can see that up here to the
Chart I apologize the uh the other day I
had the the late was it the labels or
whatever the titles or not toggle them
trading View
so you know just if you listen to what
I'm talking about in the commentary I'm
telling what I'm looking at in terms of
the market but sometimes the time frames
are not very clear I don't always
remember to say what time frame it is
but I'm trying to do better in that area
this is a two minute chart the
inefficiency or Gap is on the two minute
basis
and as the market dropped down you watch
me draw this out before price drops as
it slams into it I'm going I buy and
once it trades higher it comes back down
in what am I trading on this five
contract Edition pyramiding
high low
or low so this is my ICD bullish breaker
if we trade Above This High which it
does here
in here
and he retracement down into this I'm
going to view that as a reason for the
algorithm to reprice to it and go higher
it spends multiple times in it because
once twice three times and then finally
rips
once it creates this short-term High
here and we drop down as soon as we
route above it I took five contracts off
above that high at 42.88 which is also
inside of what
that hourly imbalance the old one okay
so some of you would say well you know
that's oh why would you pick that one
because it's in order flow and it's in
close proximity to that 42 90.50 which
is the actual swing high on the hourly
chart where a buy side would reside
and ultimately I put my stop loss up
here
and it came down and hit it I let the
recording go so that we can see it does
in fact go to where I was looking for it
to trade to
which was 42.90 that was the level I had
on here which would be two ticks below
the
4290.50 60 Minute old high so I'm
looking for it to trade up here
I use the 4290 level and then I had
limit orders
right below and to allow for the spread
to allow me to get out
and ultimately like I said it stopped me
out so over ten thousand dollars in in
one trade which you know by anybody's
standards that should be a pretty good
you know month let alone one trade uh
somebody out there might be thinking you
know that that would be enough for me
for a couple months to live on the
independent where you live and it's not
meant to then instill a sense of it your
trade has to be that high to be viewed
as ICT you know acceptable any
profitability
is good you know that that's your goal
so aspiring to trading to these levels
you know a lot of you guys are out there
with funded accounts you could do this
type of trade here
give it enough time building up your
your equity
this type of trade would be rather easy
to put on
and
you know it's up to you whether or not
you want to get to that stage you don't
need to do this well
you don't need to trade this many
contracts if you just did one
and then bought one more here and
pillared it and then got out up here the
same way is there something wrong with
that no it's probably better than your
job paid for one day so that's what I'm
trying to encourage you to think like
that so with that I'm going to wish you
a very pleasant and safe weekend I'll be
quiet on Twitter I'll be with my family
and uh we'll touch base with you all
Lord willing on Monday and so I'll talk
to you then be safe
foreign
[Music]