foreign
folks I hope everybody's doing well
so tonight we're doing a little bit of a
lecture here on some important
information about finding setups
and I get a lot of questions
as a mentor teaching Forex and recently
index futures
and the things I'm going to talk about
tonight are not limited
to any one particular asset class so
it's kind of like remove all of the
uncertainty
of where you're supposed to be looking
in the charts when am I supposed to be
utilizing electronic trading hours what
am I going to be referring to regular
trading hours for what reason what type
of setups form when
and that way it allows you
to have a setup for life
now some of you may have thought this
was going to be a pattern
or a PD array lecture it's not
I'm teaching you how to find your own
setups but specifically
when and where they form that's the part
that is always a constant
that's the thing that
a lot of new Traders and those that are
struggling as a break even Trader lucida
it's a matter of knowing what to look
for and when
it incorporates Market profiling and
that is not Market profile in the sense
that we're using like v-wop and things
like that
we're talking about schematics
things that I've taught and have shared
publicly on this YouTube channel
you can find that information in the
core content where I'm dealing with
specific day profiles
the topic would be alerted day trading
and
I cover a lot of this stuff also when
I'm talking about
specific market reviews and
I understand it many of you you maybe
knew
okay and you wanna you wanna one two
three easy get me in get me out pattern
and I've already produced all that okay
it's on the YouTube channel
but
for the folks that really want to find a
lot more setups or not be limited to a
one-trick pony not that that's a bad
thing because the 2022 model is
excellent
the optimal trade entry pattern is
so when I talk about these areas in the
marketplace tonight
and I promise we will not be here very
long usually when I say this on Twitter
and I'll do a Twitter space we go for
hours and hours it doesn't feel like
hours to me but yeah I do have a time
limit tonight so I have to get through
this and because of that I presented it
in a PowerPoint
presentation so it helps me keep
my focus so I always have some kind of a
monologue coming in
so I want to kind of set
the expectations
for everyone that's going into this
study so that way you know what it is
you're going to be trying to glean from
it what's the purpose
and then we'll get down to the
nitty-gritty it'll be right to the point
and I'll show you some details in terms
of executions and such
SO algorithmic trading with ICT models
for all assets and again the premise is
one trade setup for life
now
what do you think that would entail
something that would repeat
over and over again
it's not ambiguous
it's very specific
now when you see me doing my trade
executions
sometimes they look too good to be true
and sometimes I'm question as to whether
or not I'm using something that's
delayed and whatnot and today I had a
little bit of a Clank today I've shared
some things that uh my wife wasn't
expecting me to spend any time online
today but uh
I felt like I wanted to share today
and I answered a couple things that came
up over the years
in terms of doubts or concerns
and
I really want you to think about the
lesson tonight that we're going to cover
and think about how your setup
your multiplier the PD array that you
gravitate to most it may be the fair
value Gap it may be a breaker pattern it
may be the optimal trade entry pattern
it could be a simple order block
it could be a turtle soup
it could be a number of things
whatever it could be the inversion fair
value Gap
whatever that PD array is that you
see easily in a chart the one that you
don't have to look too hard for or
strain your eye or
scour through the candlesticks to find
it the one it just simply makes sense to
you when you see price action your eye
goes right to it
that my friends is the One You're
supposed to be looking at that's the one
you start with it does not mean that
it's going to be your entire career
it just means that that's the one that
resonates with you right now it's a new
student of mine
and then you grow from that
I promise you
when you learn one PD array
and how to use the information I'm going
to share tonight
it'll be so much easier for you to see
all the things that form
in all the PD arrays that I've taught
and then we'll teach
but you have to have some kind of a
baseline to grow from
and if you're rushing through it or
trying to push too much on yourself
the the time limits that you place on
yourself are learning how to do it is
unrealistic something you're going to
learn sooner than others and other is
going to require more time
I can't speed that up for you you're
bringing in your own learning curve and
the things that you're going to worry
about
are going to find its way to the bin
as you learn how to focus on the things
I'm teaching you and not anything more
than that per lesson
so
let's get into it
all right so draw on liquidity okay it's
the sole purpose of price delivery and I
wish to thank Patrick Weiland
for getting this screenshot from his
live stream today I needed to make a
point about uh liquidity and the
resources that are available in the
market today and how I'm going to help
you
not lean On Tools like this now
admittedly
if this type of thing was in existence
when I first started in the 90s that's
the 1990s by the way not the 1900s as my
youngest son always says makes you sound
like I'm really really old
but uh this is a screenshot of the book
map okay I am not
a affiliate with them I'm not suggesting
you should subscribe to it and I'm not
trying to kick dirt in their face either
I'm just saying that
the primary function for that tool
can be made redundant with tonight's
lesson
now I don't want you to take my word for
it you're welcome to compare and
contrast and then see if there is any
validity to what I'm going to say
tonight but I promise you you're gonna
see that these things while useful to a
new student to a new Trader they're
absolutely wonderful crutches and that's
not to be demeaning or to talk down to
it because believe me if I but I had
access to this when I first started I
would have absolutely subscribe to it
because it would have helped me learn
faster
the whole premise of liquidity but the
problem is with a tool like this
it kind of like brings more attention to
levels of liquidity that are not so
pertinent to right now okay or what's
about to take place in terms of a
narrative and price action okay and when
I teach smart money Concepts
by the way when you hear SMC it's my
Concepts okay when I talked about it and
first started teaching it I referred to
them as smart money Concepts and when we
look at liquidity
there's a specific range in mind
when I'm looking at my charts and I hear
or see people in comments
um I I've watched other YouTubers and
their complaint is you never really
understand why ICT is picking this high
or that low he's hiding it from you
that's tonight I'm going to
show you that that has never been the
case I've always said these things but
it's always tucked in during the
discussion the boring parts
because you're not trying to listen it
goes over your head that's why when you
go back and look at old videos it's been
there the whole time but you're looking
for that one trick pony that magic trick
that sleight of hand thing is going to
let you go out on social media and look
like a rock star
if you want to be able to do that you
have to learn like tonight this is a
lesson that gets to the heart of the
matter where is it that you should be
framing your focus
and what liquidity what specific
liquidity does ICT refer to
yes we're going to cover that and you're
going to see by contrast if you look at
the things I'm going to cover tonight
and utilize it with this resource here
book map
I don't know if they offer a free trial
I don't know that at all but there's
YouTubers out there that stream and kind
of like share this at least their
Affiliates they want you to sign out
with them I'm not saying don't use it
I'm not saying you should use it I'm
just saying that for folks that are
trying to do this without having extra
things to pay for or look at
you can take the information tonight and
compare and contrast and see if it
doesn't really get to the heart of the
matter in terms of where liquidity it
should be focused on for any one given
period intraday
all right so when we first start talking
about
liquidity the assumption is is you're a
day trader whether you're a scalper
whether you are a session Trader
a intraday day trader where you're
trying to do the entire daily range
or if you're just a short-term Trader or
you're looking to time the market for
your longer term swing trade or position
trade all of that
is encapsulated in tonight's discussion
so it's not a just an intraday chart
concept
you can use these Concepts to really
narrow down the amount of risk reduce it
to
minuscule amounts it doesn't mean it's
without loss doesn't mean that you will
have winning trades all the time it just
means that if you understand the
concepts I'm covering tonight
you will have the ability to go in and
fine-tune your risk model
be able to reduce the amount of risk
that's associated with your trades and
also time the market
know where the Market's going to go to
next okay
first session we're going to talk about
is the PM session ranges
okay and this is always going to be
referred to in terms of previous day
okay so previous day we are going to be
referring to
the 1 30 pm to 4 pm time window and this
is always in New York local time
now I'm saying that because I want you
to set your trading view chart
to New York local time
I say this as much as I can in all my
lectures because
I get confused when I talk to people
around the world and you're in different
time zones and I have made mistakes in
turn in terms of telling them what their
conversion would be so to eliminate all
that confusion if you just simply set
your charts to New York local time
and look at the charts that way yeah all
the confusion goes away it's very simple
so PM session ranges you're looking for
the highest high in the lowest low
between 1 30 pm and 4 pm now
is there any ambiguity there
no
it's very simple it's succinct right to
the point
now what do you do with it
if you are bullish
okay and we are trading in close
proximity to that range as we see here
this example here
I'm using the June contract before
rollover took place at the time of this
recording and live stream we are looking
at the September contract for the
indices for 2023 but I'm showing you an
example because this is something I
utilized in commentary something I use
in terms of learning analysis and
executions and such but I want you to
understand that when we look at
PM session ranges it is always referred
to in regular trading hours
notice this down here in the lower right
hand corner
let's make the chart a little bit bigger
so down here in the right hand corner
the rth that's regular trading hours
now you can toggle this if your
membership permits you I don't
know what
I guess membership is required for
trading view
um
if you're absolutely against treating
you then I'm sorry you're gonna have to
have to find the equivalent and I don't
know what that would be for you okay I
chose treating you because my community
said go to trading view when I left mt4
so we're all here now and
I don't know what it's going to cost you
and I don't have an affiliate program
with trading view I get no money for it
if you subscribe to it and I don't know
what the
amount of membership would be to allow
to get that I don't know okay so give me
the liberty and latitude to be able to
talk freely and you're gonna have to
work that on your own
but this toggle from rth to electronic
trading hours eth okay one or the other
is going to be utilized if we're going
to be looking for PM session
ranges it's always going to be into
the previous day
the time window the amount of time that
you're looking inside of what price
range what high are you looking at ICT
what's low are you looking at ICT
regular trading hours
it cuts out all the overnight Trading
the algorithm once we start trading
regular trading session hours the next
day
it's going to refer back to these
specific times
and what liquidity exists above and
below it so if we're bullish and we're
trading near the opening in this little
orange line here that's going to be in
every slide
that denotes the 9 30 opening bell
you know when everybody's on CNBC
they clap their hands
that's when the opening valve occurs for
the stock indices and stock market now
obviously they're trading all night long
but that opening window
starts that opening range for the next
30 minutes
where will that usually run for the
higher level if you're bullish
and we take out the PM session low where
it's going to be sell side below that
that's wonderful because if it's bullish
and we have a higher time frame premises
expecting the market to go higher how do
we know that that's what I've been
teaching you when I do my reviews or I
do my commentary or if I'm pointing to
something on Twitter if you're not
following me on Twitter you're really
missing out because I'm doing a lot of
information there and like real short
succinct manner I'm taking your
attention to right then and there
today I did it and a lot of people
actually followed it and it's not to be
used as a signal service but I'm calling
things live there drawing your attention
to it so that way you can study it real
time
but if you're bullish
and the market drops down below PM
session lows
notice that this low here and this low
here
that's encapsulated inside of the
1 30 to 4 o'clock
New York local time
So Below those relative equal lows
there's cell sign liquidity
it's really simple it's it's simple
isn't it when when you go through the
process of listening to me and doing the
things I tell you to do and I justify
why you should do all these things
that's the boring part
the folks that have started making real
money
six figures
payouts okay Doctor salaries in a month
or less
that stuff comes by listening and
practicing and going into their charts
and not taking my word for but going in
and seeing if the things I'm saying are
in the true
this logic
if we're bullish we'd like to see cell
site taking why because that means that
smart money would accumulate those sell
side liquidity
and absorb it
for their buy side so they're going to
treat that sell side as counterparty to
their smart money buying so they're
accumulating
in the Judas swing the drop down here
just goes into this area here where the
liquidity is so we definitely want to be
looking at previous day's session
not just any old high and low
the high in the lows between 130 and 4
o'clock New York local time that's the
PM session
that range the highs and the lows
there's liquidity above and below it
if we're looking for higher prices we
definitely expect it to be running to
the buy side but at the opening we
expect not always but we expect we
anticipate a run lower that Judah swing
that every Tom Dick and Harry on social
media are going to chase that they're
gonna think it's breaking the new lows
it's going to keep going lower
no
no no no no it's only running down air
to take sellers in the marketplace and
they're going to buy them
and then the market runs to buy side now
you could be a Trader that simply takes
this order
here as along as a turtle suit now
admittedly
this takes a great deal of conviction
it probably won't be the first thing you
reach for learning from me
in fact it took a lot of time for me to
trust that idea of buying below old lows
and selling above old highs for entries
not targets it's easy to do it for a
Target
but it's entirely different it takes an
entire paradigm shift in your thinking
to go into the marketplace and
anticipate that as an entry
but it can be done and it takes time how
you get there is you study old moves
like this and you Journal them
but your model could simply be wait for
the sell side in the pre previous PM
session range if you're bullish that's
your buy if you're going in that means
that you're expecting the weekly rings
to expand higher the draw on liquidity
higher on the weekly time frame we cut
out all that stuff in the previous
discussions
but going down into liquidity like this
when we're bullish we would reasonably
expect it to run for what the buy side
where what buy side what high are you
looking at ICT
that one right there why because it's
inside the range between 1 30 and 4
o'clock Hal pray tell
is that complicated
it's not complicated and I've taught
this ad nauseum over and over and over
again
but you're not listening so I'm taking
you by the hands knowing right into the
charts that way everything is perfectly
laid out for you you have absolutely
zero excuses you have no excuses now to
know what I'm anticipating what range am
I looking at
I'm not hiding it from you folks I want
you to succeed I really really want you
to succeed
if you can't learn it from tonight's
lesson I don't know how to do it better
than this one
okay
going further into the day now we're
considering a a full 24 hour rotation
okay so over the course of 24 hours what
is the mind of ICT what are the inner
musings of inner circle Trader
I'm going through the process of going
through this very routine right here
I look at PM session range
if it's not a factor or it's not to be
considered because we're not in close
proximity to that range because we could
be significantly higher or lower around
9 30.
so what am I looking for then if I'm not
close to PM session previous PM session
130 P.M to 4 P.M range
at the time of 9 30 at the opening bell
and I'm watching that next 30 minutes
which is the opening range
what am I going to look for then next if
it's not that
I'm looking at the London session raid
that means I'm going to be looking at
the range between two o'clock in the
morning and five o'clock in the morning
New York local time now again
tell me is that complicated
no simple
so in your charts you want to be
annotating what those levels are now you
can do it like this here where I have
actual annotations that I hand draw I
don't have a indicator thing that plots
them for me I prefer the high touch over
high tech
it means I'm putting some thought into
it I get closer to the marketplace by
doing that and sharing it with you
I just don't trust an indicator to do it
okay so I'm an old guy I'm a dinosaur
I'm used to doing everything by hand
anyway and believe me it doesn't take
that long to tell me you have to have
because it saves time and it's a cop-out
you just are lazy ain't nothing wrong
with lazy I mean lazy people can do
things very efficiently if they're smart
but let's Zoom this in here
all right so London session Reigns
if we are not in close proximity to the
previous PM session at 9 30. remember
this orange line here denotes the 9 30
opening bell
of the stock market
so
where are we at in terms of proximity
so we're starting the trading here
so where are we are we in close
proximity to a PM session high or low
but we are in close proximity to what
London session by side we're digging
into that so all of this can be viewed
pre-930 as a Judas swing
now notice
am I showing you regular trading hours
or electronic trading hours
electronic trading hours so that way
you're gonna be able to see the
overnight trading if you have it toggled
to regular trading hours you won't see
this information folks it will be hidden
from you which is one of the conundrums
that retail Traders fall into they don't
know either how to toggle electronic
trading hours or regular trading hours
and even if they do they don't know what
to do with the information
it's hidden it's in plain sight but it's
hidden from them you don't have that
excuse anymore tonight so
London session buy side liquidity we're
seeing that read up into it here and
then
where's the low in it
remember two o'clock to five o'clock in
the morning New York local time
that's not ambiguous what is the range
the highest high and the lowest low
here and here
so if we raided the buy side and we did
it on a run
that's a Judas
we anticipate that as a false run higher
and then we're going to see does it
shift lower how can we use that
information well you can use the 2022
model
you can use
uh breaker a parish breaker you can use
the ICT optimal trade entry
in here from this low
to the high is a fair bag Gap
this is a shift in Market structure
below this low right there
that's your 2022 model or optimal trade
entry
what would you be aiming for
numbing session South Side liquidity
do you have to sit through a retracement
yes
but we'll cover that
because that in itself is also
a range that we utilize intraday
notice what I'm taking you through
the whole routine of 24 hours where are
we at open open is 9 30.
we have to wait for 30 minutes because
there's going to either be a run higher
or lower or it may consolidate and then
we'll have to wait for the 10 o'clock
displacement and then you can look for a
silver bullet between 10 o'clock and 11
or you could use a run into
the launch macro which we won't talk
about tonight but I promise you I will
be teaching those things I can't do
everything in one lesson
everything line upon line preset the
phone precept it'll be taught here and
there
but before November you'll have more
than you'll ever need
so we have two ranges we've identified
here for defining where liquidity is
let me go back to discussion of that
book map application or software
I want you
if you have availability to do this
look at what bookmap is saying
when we're Trading
like here
tools like that will start showing you
lots of liquidity if they're accurate
right below that low
if it matches
if it matches the premise that I'm
teaching here tonight then it's valid
and that's where the market will draw to
every little small little liquidity
above the marketplace or below the
marketplace is irrelevant
when I say I'm looking for a draw on
liquidity I'm looking predominantly
around the levels I'm teaching you today
so think about how many times I've
called things on Twitter live
and how many times they were wrong
what three times Maybe
everything's on Twitter it's not deleted
it's not edited I don't do any of that
stuff
but all of you 300 000 plus now have
watched me take your attention to a
specific price point and then the market
ran off
it went right to it
how was I doing it it's what I'm
teaching you tonight
you can do this folks
now
there are going to be times when you
look at the market and it's not going to
be clear to you
if you don't have a clear depiction of
what should be taking place where the
market should draw to because there's
going to be times when I'm either going
to be on vacation or I'm not going to
Tweet or I'm not going to talk about
something
I'm living a life
so if it's not clear to you what it's
reaching for
don't put a trade on study it and that
experience will grow over time and
you'll get better at doing it but when
you're journaling I want you to go in
your charts and journal like this
this should be part of your journaling
if you don't journal and you don't
record these types of things your brain
and your subconscious can't retain it it
needs to be trained and conditioned that
way it activates a reticular activating
system
so that way it allows your mind to see
it and when you're looking at Price
action live it'll be like oh I gotta
look oh there's that high I'm looking at
there's that low I'm looking at
notice we're cutting through candles
folks it's not supply and demand and
it's not Wyckoff I'm sorry
I wish it could be something I could
point to and say go every day and learn
that but it isn't anywhere else
all right opening range gaps
okay opening range gaps are a specific
event that takes place when you're
utilizing regular trading hours
so let's zoom in
so down here in trading view you want to
make sure you're toggled to regular
trading hours by doing that what it'll
do is it'll remove all the overnight
trading so you won't see anything like
London or anything like that
where we stop Trading
for the rate of trading hours
and when we start trading
again
at 9 30's opening bill that's what
you're seeing okay that separation that
is my opening range Gap so whenever you
hear me say an opening range Gap not to
be confused with opening range opening
range is the first 30 minutes I will
have a specific teaching in its entirety
all by itself on this video only on this
channel it'll be opening range lecture
but when I say opening range that is the
first 30 minutes after the opening belt
9 30. so specifically it's 9 30 a.m New
York local time to 10 a.m New York local
time not ambiguous as it folks very very
specific this opening range Gap is where
we stop trading using River Trading
hours
and when we open up at 9 30.
if there is a gap lower
at 9 30
you will see this Gap here it's being
shaded with this little Orange Box
it doesn't mean it wants to run up there
immediately
okay and this is what I watch a lot of
YouTubers that understand there are gaps
and I didn't invented the Gap but I did
codify some things around how to use
that Gap and I'll teach more about that
also in its own lesson
but tonight
I want you to think about how where the
market reaches for
liquidity
where it reaches for that liquidity and
where does it want to go to after it
goes there
this low over here
right in here
that low is occurring in the morning
session or the am session between 9 30
and noon
so we'll be residing below that
sell stops so we call that sell side
liquidity
so we Gap lower
and then run into that liquidity right
there
using regular trading hours
now if you're using electronic trading
hours
you may
have a lower low overnight and then in
other words between these two price
points here
where we close the registrating session
and open it regular trading session
between those two price points you have
all of the 6 pm to 9 30 in the morning
worth of trading that could have made a
lower low here
I don't care
what I don't care
if I'm going to refer to the opening
range Gap and we get a gap lower like
this I'm filtering out all of overnight
pricing that's it
now is that ambiguous
is that complicated
no
what low whatever you're looking at well
on regular trading hours on this chart
that's a pretty obvious low isn't it
that's the stuff I've been doing on
Twitter
I'm picking the right highs and lows
folks because there's a method behind
what I'm doing I'm not inventing it as I
go I'm not going off on a whim making up
as I go I've been doing this stuff for
30 years it's the same stuff all the
time it's a well-written well-read novel
to me
that's why I'm so consistent that's why
I'm accurate and if you stick to these
rules you will become this accurate too
it's transferable
you should be excited I know somebody
you're grinning like right now he's
like man if I would have had this stuff
just a couple months ago I could have
passed my funded account challenge I
could have done this I could have done
that I could have bought a boat
a jet ski a car
a down payment on a house
but you have to go one step at a time
now
the opening range Gap
if we run to a portal code like this
here
wouldn't it make sense since we're now
into a discount and inside of liquidity
below old lows or in sell side now
we've already moved a lot from the
previous session here
here
what would be reasonable
well
look at that on my calendar
today we had the Fed chair pal jaw
booning at 10 o'clock in the morning
do we trade around pal or fed share
testimonies
no
not if you're new not if you're trying
to keep your money
now if you don't want to be a gambler
you wait
and you wait for what
the PM session
exactly what I said this morning on
Twitter
I said in Twitter I said today and
tomorrow
Fed chair will be testifying
so you want to be what
trading the afternoon if you're going to
trade it all the probabilities are going
to be high
in your favor if you wait till the
afternoon that means 1 30 in the
afternoon New York local time
to four o'clocks close
is that ambiguous
is that complicated
no
wouldn't you know it there's a low here
it forms at one o'clock
and then at 1 30 or so it creates
another low here
it's pretty interesting
what happens after that low forms
it runs right on up into that opening
range Gap
so all this mess in here
every Instagram Trader every Twitter
hero every YouTube Trader live streamer
they're in here trying to look for
patterns when there is nothing to trust
it's going to be running around going
amok
just seeking liquidity and it'll
frustrate you
that's the reason why I tell you to
focus on the sweet spots in the
marketplace
I don't care about retail Rick that's
going to come after the fact because
he's not going to tell you on Twitter
when I'm tweeting and saying oh you said
don't do this I'm going to go now and
trade it they don't ever do that
they'll come back two hours later
and they'll say look what I did over
here
so stop listening to those neophytes
the logic that I'm sharing don't take my
word for it go into the charts and you
will be convinced of it
100 guarantee I guarantee you you will
see this logic there
so it runs up in the opening range Gap
after
the New York lunch after the morning
session
chop
and it runs to a logical level
based on the information I've shown you
here
see in the morning
a lot of folks that understand this Gap
exists we're looking for any reason to
run right up there then no
they're not going to see it why because
they don't understand time the algorithm
runs on time
it Engineers liquidity in the morning
session and then it Engineers it going
into lunch and then it runs on that
liquidity
why would they want to do that we'll
talk about that
New York lunch raid
now
in the old days
and I was trading when the old days were
the thing before electronic Trading
we had open out cry pits and when you
called into the broker
they would answer the phone he had to
wait for them to answer the phone by the
way and then get transferred to the
trading desk that you are
seeing the account managers for that
account you have and you got to go
through the process of giving them your
account number and then your pin and
then you got to give them your order
they repeat the order the whole time the
Market's Trading
then they ask you if you want to wait
for your fill
and if you say I'm going to wait for my
fill
you're put on hold for a minute or two
then you come back and they tell you
confirmation number and where you were
filled
and many times you're upset because you
have real slippage
because you're all spoiled you press a
button you're in there right
and
the open outcry and the pits
would have a lunch hour where it was
very
almost like a routine unless it was a
big trending day
the lunch hour between noon
and 1 pm New York local time would
generally be a consolidation now the way
we could use that back then and I'm
going to show you how I use it now but
for historical purposes I'm giving you a
reference on how I become ICT
the lunch hour
many times was a reversal
and whatever took place in the morning
was completely reversed on and then if
it was a trending day it would just keep
on going and it would repeat whatever
the morning low was up the lunch high
and then run into three o'clock four
o'clock and that would be their full
Daily range
other days if it was bullish it would go
up and then consolidate during the 12
o'clock and one o'clock in the afternoon
and then do the same move in the
afternoon between two o'clock and four
o'clock that it did in the morning
session but it would do it in half the
time
so it was a measured move ABCD type of
profile
and in other days you would see just a
morning move and then consolidating
launch and then stay Consolidated the
rest of the day
in the same thing if it was a bearish
day it would create the morning move
then consolidate in lunch and do nothing
extra
now it's pretty it that was pretty much
it that was that was the profiles that
existed back then
now
you might be thinking well that's all
well and good Michael but which one do
you use well which one would you expect
based on the economic calendar
the draw on liquidity for the weekly
range what is it trying to do where's it
reaching for
all those things have to be balanced
that still requires you and your study
to get to that degree of um
well understanding
and implementing the things I'm teaching
but you have no excuse when I'm pointing
to it in advance I'm taking you to the
higher time frame weekly charts I'm
telling you where the Market's going to
go and we watch it daily and weekly move
thousands of points
not five handles thousands
hundreds okay so it gives you time
an opportunity to get in sync with that
type of moon you don't have to have the
lowest low in the highest high
so a New York lunch raid between noon
New York local time to 1 30 pm
but ICT you just said
it's an hour long noon to 1 30. and
there's people out there say oh the
market doesn't care about nobody's going
to lunch
uh the algorithm
doesn't take lunch but it runs on that
liquidity
so everything that was utilized
since the dawn of Market manipulation
when the powers that be
figured out that they could just
run a numbers game and everybody thinks
it's a free market
and they think it's buying and selling
pressure that makes these markets go up
and down and where they go
they utilize that information that was
not efficient at all when it was used in
open outcry
and that price
that manipulation that engineering
of Market Direction
was made much more efficient when
electronic trading took over
so nothing has changed in regards to
Market manipulation and Market making
we're not talking about dealers folks
okay if somebody's out there saying I'm
a market maker I'm a former Market maker
you are not a market maker you are a
dealer
the folks that are in control of price
where it's going to go how high it's
going to go how low it's going to go
that's who I'm talking about and you
don't see them they don't have a face
all of that's been changed now in its
algorithmic it's highly efficient they
never get sick
they never mess up because it's 100
electronic
it's following code it's following
instructions
period
it's all delivered on time
so a
lunch
run on liquidity a raid if you will
you have to define the range
between 12 o'clock and 1 30.
but you said it's an hour long 130
starts the PM session
that's when the algorithm can start
doing its macro a macro is a short order
of instructions that will create an
event in
price delivery
your focus needs to be on the highest
high and the lowest low
I'm showing you
the highest high in
12 to 1 o'clock
because there's nothing higher than the
high here
the low formed here
between 12 o'clock
and 130 that's the lowest low here so we
see this low it drops down there
if we're expecting price to be bullish
and it's not done anything in the
morning
Pals talking there's a afternoon event
that's expected like fomc something to
that effect
you avoid the morning session let
everybody else
Chase everybody else's opinion
in ignorance on social media everybody's
looking for the the guy with the hot
hand
the guy that's doing all the trades the
guy that knows or the gal
indifference to the ladies that do
Trading
they're looking for the people that have
something to say about the market right
now and if they've been right in the
past
well damn it they're gonna be right
today let me follow what they're doing
no
you trailblaze your own path using this
information you will be confident that
you have no requirement to be in
anybody's membership or audience you'll
be able to do this make your bread and
then go live your life and do whatever
you want to do not be chained to these
charts not looking at what I'm doing on
Twitter
because in November and 2023 that's
stops
you have to do all these things on your
own
and that should not be scary it should
be exciting
I'm excited for you
but the session hind session low for
lunch hour
well I guess it's really technically 90
minutes isn't it
do you said nine minutes oops
laughs
below here we can see it running down
taking that when we're expected to go
higher
what do you think exists up here that's
not being noted on the chart
hmm
we'll get back to that
the market starts it's running 1 30.
completely random now you're probably
watching this video and you've never
seen anything else by me or never listen
to Twitter spaces that I've done
and you don't know that I've said that
time at 1 30. you don't know that I've
said this many many times
referring about the New York lunch
and how there's an algorithm that
controls price and there's a macro that
begins at 130 that sets the tone and
pace for the two o'clock to three
o'clock Silver Bullet baby
hmm
the dots are starting to connect aren't
they
starting to see a little bit more
of the tapestry
that's a bit that's eluded you and
everybody else out there that doesn't
believe there's an algorithm doesn't
believe that these markets are
absolutely controlled by AI
I promise you that's exactly what's
going on
we want to see when we're bullish the
market dropped down and take out
the New York lunch lows
even if it's going to reverse
you can trade that
here
how can you trade that
wait for a shift in Market structure
fair value Gap
don't trust the five minute chart I've
already shown you today using a 15
second chart and we'll get to that too
what do you say a 15 second chart yes
yes friends and neighbors price is price
and you have to look where the
inefficiencies are and every retail
Trader is using a 15-minute chart an
hourly chart a four hour chart
and there's this taboo around five
minute charts or less because they're
not informed they're not initiated
they think it's noise
they're probably the Goldman Sachs cult
sorry boys but price is price and
whatever you see in terms of measuring
it using a time-based chart you have
every advantage using a Time based chart
in fact that's the only way you're going
to see it
so don't listen to people that say don't
look at the time based chart it's
nonsense wrong right away that tells you
they have no idea
algorithmic delivery it escapes them
sorry
it runs on time time is the first Factor
what am i showing you here tonight
very specific Windows of time and what
to reference it in terms of liquidity go
back and look at my examples folks your
draw is going to hit the floor
it's always been there
and it's always been explained to you in
this long-winded rants
these stuff that you say I'm boring
now I'm teaching you I'm trying to teach
you everything that would bring you as
close as I can bring you without having
the third years experience I have so I'm
I'm taking you fast track through three
decades of understanding
if you don't have the patience to sit
through whatever the duration is for the
lecture
that's a little bit myopic
and unrealistic you're selling yourself
short I don't care if you learn it
really and if you're going to be lazy I
don't care
but if you really want to learn it I'm
telling you what to do
I'm telling you what to avoid where your
focus should be
if you're bearish
you can wait for
a run up into the opening range Gap
take out a lunch box out liquidity pool
and then watch and see how it trades
back below the New York lunch High
if there's a displacement what does that
mean
see that low right here
displacement
what does it leave this candle is high
and that candle's low what is that
that's random look at that it's like
it's this you know
it has no Rhyme or Reason right wrong
that's your 2022 model
boom
sell short
aim for what ICT
the New York lunch hello
well it made this one here at one
o'clock but you can use this one while
you're long or bullish
I know it looks cherry-picked and talked
about I I promise I got something for
you they're thinking that right now I
promise you just sit tight but in the
afternoon session you can see how that
lunch hour plus 30 minutes that 90
minute window
that low right here is where sell side
resides and in the PM session it reads
that liquidity
TT look man there's some relative equal
lows down there and you teach relative
equal O's right
but before you get there where's the
next logical
rain to look for for in terms of
liquidity that lunch hour or 90 minute
period
now
I said a lot of talking about things
that some of you get pissed off about
because you think I'm some of my news
that you're talking down to you but no
I'm talking to you like a friend
if you were friends with me from
childhood this is exactly how I talk to
you
I know what I'm talking about
I know how to make crazy ass profitable
Traders
but I also have students that are
lazy they're not going to do
what I tell them to do and they're going
to make excuses why they failed because
they didn't listen and they rushed too
fast to get into live Trading
that's your mistake that's not my
mistake in hiding things from you I
didn't do that I'm not doing it here
tonight either
you have every Advantage after tonight
going in looking at what I'm looking for
where am I focusing
I promise you after tonight your shit's
gonna be different
yes it's gonna have nuts
am session ranges
9 30 in the morning to noon
so right away
we are considering this in the afternoon
so we can always refer to it in the same
trading day
so we could be anticipating a market
reversal profile something to that
effect
if
we have an elongated Market
where say the New York session
morning session rather of the current
trading day
is consolidation and then we have a
directional lunch hour or during the
lunch hour it's con in consolidation as
well
we can refer to and if we're bearish we
look at the previous sessions trading
now if you look at the previous session
you're using electronic Trading
what specific low am I looking for I'm
looking at the 9 30 in the morning to
noon
if I'm not going to look at the PM
session range remember I'm taking you
through very specific pools of liquidity
I'm going to look past
the PM session
well why would I do that because we're
already trading below it over here
so what I refer to it for sell side no
we're already below it so if I'm bearish
what am I looking for what low am I
looking for what's drawn liquidity am I
looking for
in this regard I'm using the am session
South Side liquidity
if I was bullish it would be everything
I just said here in reverse and opposite
I would be looking for the buy side but
if we're bearish
I'm looking for a very specific pools of
liquidity if I showed this on regular
trading hours it would still get that
low
very important
even though I'm showing you down here
[Music]
the electronic trading hours I'm doing
this for the sake of under showing you
and understanding that
whether your chart is on regular trading
hours or electronic trading hours and
I'm looking at previous daily range or
if I want to trade below yesterday's
lows what low am I looking at
the PM session low
or
the am session low
very very specific not ambiguous not
well I don't know which one he's looking
at he's always changing around no
I'm not it's always the same stuff
always the same logic always the same
logic
what's changing is
the profile that I'm operating in
because the Market's delivering a
specific way and I have to adapt to that
and then I anticipate I'm not reacting
to price I'm anticipating where it's
going to run to
what does that mean everything I'm
teaching you tonight
now I don't expect you to watch this
tonight and walk away feeling like you
know everything about what I just said
you're gonna need to watch it a few
times
and if it's something you don't want to
do you won't learn it
I promise you you won't learn it one
time watching it ain't gonna work you
need to listen to what I'm saying in
here and then go into your charts
spend weeks and months going back
through it
that's what will convince you that this
is Sound Logic it's not contrived it's
not conjecture it's not made up
it's absolutely what the market does
every week
every day
and it will not stop
so you can see the previous am session
low over here south side liquidity this
dotted line here the notes we're looking
at the 20th of June 2023.
so I can't use the afternoon session
high and low because we've already
starting at 9 30 we're already below
that
so what am I looking for ICT what am I
supposed to be looking for
that low
it doesn't matter if it was a lower low
okay
listen
if there was electronic trading hours
showing and it had a lower low and it
went below that low here I would still
listen I would still
refer to the PM session range as I
mentioned a little bit ago in this
presentation tonight
and before that one I would go to this
specific range here
it's a Civic time
I don't care about overnight highs and
lows I'm looking at very specific
regular trading hours
regular trading hours is going to be
referred to in the next trading session
they're either going to be respected or
blown out
it's simple
it's not hard
all right so let's blend some things
here okay
so as you can see we have several things
here in this chart and this is today's
trading the 21st of June 2023 and it's
the email s p
and I photoshopped some things in here
obviously being facetious by saying that
the opening range as I taught you here
tonight that was one of the factors I
utilized today in the if you're
following me on Twitter
I showed my PM session trade which is
what you're seeing here using everything
that I talk to you tonight
let's go through it okay
this morning we are watching Fed chair
pal
give us testimony at 10 o'clock
and I had my favorite Usual Suspects
that I like following on Twitter not
Twitter on YouTube rather
and those that were live streaming I'll
listen to them and
no disrespect gentlemen and meme
uh they had really no idea what was
going on
which is exactly what one would expect
because the Market's gyrating and going
sideways
churning up accounts going sideways
beating up everybody
you have to wait
until we get through lunch if that chair
pal is going to talk
and it's a 10 o'clock testimony or
whatever
wait wait for lunch
wait for lunch
if you do that
you will get the cleanest setup for the
day
the easy what does that mean cleanest
setup like what do you mean when you say
that
where everything just simply jumps off
the chart it just it makes itself very
obvious you want setups that are very
obvious that's clean okay I don't want
you as my student going into the
marketplace and trying to just be an
action hound and try to trade everything
I don't teach my students to do that
the ones that blow their accounts or
fail their funded account challenges
that's a characteristic that they have
that is not a
a derivative of learning from me
that's a personal character flaw
and you can correct it you can fix it
but you can't place that blame on me
if you wait and you listen I counsel all
of you real real time live on Twitter
don't touch this right now
all right focus on this time of the day
and when it's appropriate I'll point to
where the Mark's going to go to next I
did that today
the opening range Gap here
was utilized to get what would otherwise
be done if you had
done these same entries and managed at
the same position would have resulted in
a 9
362.50 before commissions
now I don't know about you where you are
in the world and you know you're walking
life but the almost ten thousand dollars
is a pretty respectable amount of money
I mean you can go on a nice vacation
with that
can get your spouse something really
nice you probably do some really good
Christmas shopping with that so that's
not chump change
and I want to think about the logic
that's shown here
pal
10 o'clock
trash Market okay just ignore it
just ignore it just don't even worry
about it oh but it's gonna run it's
gonna move that is you that's a neophyte
Trader
and an action Hound you feel like you
have to be able to do something in that
I'm telling you I'm telling you with 30
years of experience you don't need to
you don't need to it's liberating when
you just relax and say you know what
this is the highest degree of
manipulation right now and you don't I
don't know what they're gonna do because
they can manually intervene and send
price careening higher or lower and you
won't be able to
see it coming
so don't torture yourself do something
else sleep in
go have breakfast with your spouse work
out longer
take your boat out Roger jet skis
cut the grass whatever don't do don't do
anything in the marketplace just wait
and then what time does your shift start
at 1 30.
that's when the macro will start running
at 1 30 the market creates a a low here
Market trades down below
the New York lunch South Side liquidity
again
they can sweep it again but notice it
doesn't take that lower here I don't
require it to
the logic is it's going down there once
more
just in case
rallies
comes back down into this down closed
candle which is a bowl of shoulder block
I'm not teaching order blocks in this
lecture
the market rallies we have displacement
again
fair value gaps and whatnot I promise
you I'm going to take you into a 15
second
chart where I utilize the information
I'm going to show you here what I saw
was the market drop down below
the initial New York lunch sell side
liquidity
it's dropping down below here and then
I'm anticipating it to go up into the
opening range Gap that's this shaded
area up here
I don't need to show you an example
where it goes all the way up there I'm
teaching you low hanging fruit that's
the first threshold for you to learn
under my wing
you can and you can see it tonight the
logic is leave a partial on for that
but I'm trying to encourage you while
you're learning to learn how to do this
modularly step by step you're not going
to go out there and do you know a lot of
contracts in one time you won't know how
to do the pyramiding that you're going
to watch me do here in a moment
you're not going to know all that stuff
okay and to remove all of the oh man I
wish I would have had a
partial on I wish I would have held it
longer
you don't know where your growth is
going to be and how long it's going to
take you to get to a point where you can
trust doing that so I allow for and I
build into my teaching room for you to
develop independent from my
personal timing
see what I think a student should
require in terms of learning may be more
or less than what it's going to require
for you
so I'm trying to be a realistic Mentor
not just someone that says go through my
workshop go through my training in this
many days months weeks or whatever
you're going to come out knowing what it
is you're going to do and if you can't
then you suck that's just not practical
so what I do is I teach you where the
Market's going to go what is your
terminus
Terminus while you're first learning is
the easiest low-hanging fruit objective
so if we're buying
down here
on the basis that that sell side
liquidity pool for lunch
has been swept here and we see this
returning but not respecting
a run into and below that low it's
denying that and it showed a willingness
to repel back above this low that's what
I was looking through all of this lows
here I'm looking past all that going
right to that low right there remember
this low here doesn't get taken out
until the PM session
look at your chart yeah I mentioned it
earlier
this low I trusted it but Michael what
happens if it went down there then I
would have got stopped out
what yeah sometimes I get it wrong
sometimes I mess it up sometimes I bring
the baggage okay the scar tissue or my
ego into it and I try to outperform my
own algorithm
and I get my ass handed to me I get
stopped out if the trade's still valid
I'll go back in and re-enter you've
watched me do that I've recorded myself
doing that
go on Twitter it's there
it's there
if I get it wrong you see it if I get
stopped out you see it if I get stopped
out and it's still a good trade I'll get
back in if I get stopped out and I'm
done I'm done
I don't hide that from you
so I'm buying Under the premise that
we're returning into that South Side
liquidity here one more time
what is it doing here though if it's not
taking out that low what is it doing
it's trading below the rejection block
which is the lowest closing price in
this swing
I don't need that low to be taken out I
don't want to see it taken out
so all the understanding of price action
over here I'm anticipating this
accumulation
and smart money jumping on board like I
was to run to
relative equal highs and more
specifically inside the opening range
from record trading hours where we stop
Trading
and where we started Trading
42 22 and a half
that's this high in here
I could have very easily had a runner
run up in here and try to get one tick
below the high of the opening range Gap
but if I do those types of things you
already some of you already
get pissed off at your own performance
because you think you should have 30
years of experience and performance and
results too because you've watched my
videos or you spent enough time which
isn't realistic because none of you
spend enough time to do what I'm doing
it's not ego it's not it's not arrogance
it's it's real
practicality I mean think about it folks
I may have 30 years of experience but I
can't Pour That Into You in a short
period of time and you have 30 years
experience too
it's unrealistic
and some of you are very hard on
yourselves and you think that you should
be able to do what I do
so I try to teach with that in mind and
I teach low hanging for those terms are
my way of saying okay
to go higher
where is it going to go to logically
well if it's taken sell side out here
that means the sell stocks have been
rated there and we swept down into the
rejection block and preserve that low
in the afternoon should see a run up
into
that Gap and for those that are on you
know wondering why should that happen
and not take out the relative equal lows
is because we've already worked below
that am session low remember before we
trade into the well not trade the
transitions into this slide here we
traded into the previous session am
loves so we are really in a deep
discount
in that opening range Gap has not been
traded into from the open it opened and
ran away from it quickly it's never came
up to it until here
and it left what relative equal highs
what time of the day did it do it
between 12 o'clock and 1 30.
so that's your lunch buy side liquidity
everybody that's short thinks it's going
to keep going down that's where their
stop loss is who's doing that funds
not retail Rick
large funds Deep Pockets
buying and every time the market gave me
a buying opportunity very specific PD
arrays
on a 15 second chart
I was entering this is a one minute
chart by the way if you're looking at it
here it's one minute every one of these
entries were based on a 15 second candle
I recorded it I've already shared it on
Twitter but for the folks that don't
have
Twitter or refuse to watch it because
they don't want to be on the Bird app or
whatever I got you covered tonight
but every time it reached above relative
equal highs I'm taking a partial profit
up in here another partial profit
Above This High here partial profit and
above the high here partial profit
so I don't require
it to trade above this high
and I'm teaching you that you don't need
to do that either I mean if you got out
just with this 44 22 and a half that's
below
the actual liquidity above this high
and if you mimic this same trade in your
own account whether it be funded or in
life funds and you profited 9 362.50 are
you going to beat yourself up because
you didn't have that run up um to the
opening range Gap High
some of you might and that would be
unfortunate that's not what I want you
to think that would be really a toxic
mindset about your performance and what
you're trying to do you try very very
hard to filter out negative thinking
that's why social media is the worst
social media is like cancer
okay for a developing student because
everybody's got an ego they're all
pulling their dicks out for a measuring
competition okay and the point is you're
trying to learn how to make money and
all I'm trying to do is teach you how to
stay in the game long enough
so you can keep your money learn the
skills that's on showing you so that way
you can leave your job and then
live your life and do whatever you want
to do okay and you don't need to listen
to me the rest of your life I don't I
don't want to be doing these videos I'm
going to be doing it so I'm leaving you
a legacy so that way you can come back
to this information take your kids to
this information whatever and build
Legacy wealth you don't need you don't
need to entertain these people's egos
you don't need to come back and keep me
feeling good about myself either
this stuff works
but you have to graduate in your
understanding about where is it going to
go and be realistic
and then over time when you start seeing
this unfold
reasons for it to go higher
you leave a runner on
that's the only way if you're in there
trading and you're thinking to yourself
man I don't know I should probably leave
a runner on there I know if I leave a
runner on you know it's probably gonna
you know stop me out and if I don't put
one on it's going to run oh put one on
what's the worst thing gonna happen it's
going to stop you out in profit
see you're wrestling with being right
and many of you are trying to do that if
you're doing it in front of an audience
that is hard
because not only are you wrestling with
your internal dialogue about what you
should do and how you're managing the
trade but you're inviting everybody
else's feedback to your trade and guess
what
guess what girl boy that's not your
trade anymore you've invited the entire
Community that's watching you and your
audience to manage your trade for you
and that means you brought in a level of
uncertainty fear Pride
and pain that would otherwise not be
there if you were disquietied about what
the you're doing
that's what this is all about folks it's
not about getting out there and Showboat
Showboat and show what you can do
improve this improve that
is it going to matter
when you're paying off a house
how many people believe you did it
how many are going to have to come back
here on social media when you hit seven
figures and you're a millionaire how
many of you have to come back to social
media and go to the usual suspect and
say haha ICT made me a millionaire
if you think that you're doing this
for the wrong reasons
the people that are really killing it
they don't come on Twitter
they don't leave comments in my section
of my videos
they don't do any of that stuff they're
out there living a life
they've already thanked me they've
already shared their testimony and
they're doing big wheel
grow like that
all right so uh
this is a
15 second chart
and
I have to make sure that I don't play
sound on this and I gotta make sure
I do this correctly here
I recorded a song as I typically do on
Twitter I love Twitter for that reason
it's like a like a a text message to you
like if you had my personal phone number
and yeah so there's a lot of people that
have it and yes they abuse it
and yes I'm changing my phone number in
November
a lot of you
that listen to me or follow me on
Twitter when I'm tweeting that's the
same thing if you were like my best
friend and I'll say hey look at the look
at this Market here that's that's real
time right now right from my mind right
into Twitter
and I can't put the music on
in the in a presentation format that I
love doing over the years I used to be
on Twitter uh before leaving it they
started censoring me and I left it and I
came back
and one of the things I was looking
forward to was going back and doing
vignettes where I record myself
executing putting on trade putting a
stop loss on managing it for you know
putting on a pyramid position building
it up taking profits and watching the
position go from beginning to end and I
usually put a song on there it may not
be the type of song that you like it may
have foul language in it it may be a
genre that you don't like I don't give a
because it's what I like okay I
like doing that because it's what I like
doing
it's usually received well in the
community but I can't play that here
because I'll get a copyright strike and
I I don't need all that here so
I'll leave a link so you can look at it
in the format that I gave on Twitter but
you don't need it's gonna be the same
thing here
as a reminder every Candlestick you're
seeing here is a 15 second duration now
think about that lunch sell side
liquidity pool and where the market was
going to go up to now right now you're
looking at the dollar Index
it's going to change over to index
features but I want you to think about
what I showed you before we got to this
slide here
because when the when the video starts
playing it's like two minutes long and
I'll walk you through as much as I can
but everything that has already been
told to you tonight that's what I was
using
okay I promise you I didn't have
something secret okay everything that I
taught you tonight is exactly what I
implemented here and everything I'm
commenting and annotating in the chart
real time as I'm recording it
that's what I was seeing so I try to do
as much as I can in terms of annotating
the chart showing the reference points
where I think the Mark's going to be
respecting
certain levels why it should behave a
certain way
keeping in mind that I'm doing this
with 15 second candlesticks so I have to
know what the I'm talking about to
be able to do this
to be able to annotate it show you where
the rivals are going to be respected and
I was going to reach out to this and do
it think about seriously seriously folks
think about what would be necessary to
be able to know what's going on if
you're just simply looking at the 15
second chart like everybody else on
Twitter was doing today
and they watched it and look at the
comment section like what the heck what
the hell's going on how what 15 seconds
forget the time frame
forget the time frame think about what
I've told you tonight with the lunch
macro
it's running down to the sell side and
it's going back up into that opening
range Gap to take the buy side on the
New York lunch High where the buy side
is
that's all that I'm doing and I'm gonna
use every PD array that is discount
I'm gonna put in every every one of
these things could have been your
individual entry
based on the things I've taught just
using a 15 second chart
now there's other things if you were
looking at a one minute chart
the far less entries obviously but you
could see certain entry patterns or PD
arrays to get into the trades
based on a one minute chart two minute
three minute four or five
or
a 15-minute chart
but you have less entry opportunities
the higher time frame get you go
so this to add insult to injury for the
people that say this is and
it's fake and all this other stuff I go
into these Ultra short-term time frames
just to Overkill
just to rub their nose in it to show you
that this stuff works and it will work
for you it ain't gonna work for you the
first time you watch the video it ain't
gonna be working for you because you've
watched a couple videos and you wrote a
couple sentences down you think that's
journaling you're gonna have to really
roll your sleeves up and dig into this
stuff and study it it's a lifestyle if
you don't make it a lifestyle forget
about it it's it's not going to work for
you you have to be passionate about it
all right so I'm going long here on the
S P here's that uh
run that didn't take out the low at one
o'clock
and I'm adding a pyramiding and I've
already annotated that fair value Gap
and told you that it's an inversion for
everybody you got that means it's going
to go above it
treated as support and then rally up
into the buy sides that I'm going to
show you here
so you can already see that 4422 even
level is highlighted as a bicycle
liquidity notice it's below that high
I'll show you when we're covering the
lunch
liquidity so that's the order Block it's
reclaimed and it dug into the uh
inversion fair value Gap and for the
folks that thinking all the order block
doesn't work see here that entire range
is the order block
and I'm adding into it here inside the
fair value Gap that is already
identified as an inversion for your
value Gap
so this is going to be dynamic support
here watch how it respects it
I'm already showing you here it's going
to go up
and just like magic on a 15 second chart
look at that
it's unbelievable isn't it now my stop
loss is below the inversion favorite you
got and I'm showing you where the
executions are so everything matches now
folks this is not replay none of that
here's another partial here
and my stop is below the low at 44.16. I
don't want to chase it up there because
that's inefficient
it can trade down inside that so I don't
want to put a stop loss at 44.17 in half
it can come back in there deeper I'm
making allowance for that so my stop is
staying below that
I'm not in a hurry to guarantee higher
profits I'm more concerned about my
limit orders filling my stop is not
being concerned about
and here comes another
run up into a
10 lot limit order
that would put me at 5 remaining
see that retracement down in there
I'm not worried about that you might be
freaking out because you put your stop
loss higher or you maybe even stopped
out
but this is proper stop loss management
now here's the limit order and then now
we're going to run for that buy side
here
and then once it runs that high I'm
holding the trail my stop loss up then
this is exactly what I shared on Twitter
today
everything was recorded this is not
Market replay this is not uh the trading
view replay none of that stuff
okay the logic that I showed here
doesn't
show everything that I taught tonight
but what I was utilizing because you
don't hear me talking in in the trade
but the things that I'm doing to trade
this
everything I'm doing is what I was
teaching you tonight
it's not conjecture I didn't form fit it
I do this stuff every single week with
you all on Twitter
over and over and over again and when
time permits it I'll give an example
every single day today I gave several
examples
this one today I told you to wait for
the PM session that was the morning
advice
and I went in there and murdered it
so every single one of these individual
entries
that could be your model
some are better in terms of where their
entry was but I'm using them as
pyramiding opportunities
none of the things in here that I showed
violated any of the bullish order flow
this is real order flow notice there's
no Dom depth of Market level two data
required no book map required everything
that I've outlined here is shown to you
on a time-based chart my partials are
based on liquidity look at my exits on
the partials they're at the highs
my entries are in very key levels that
would be a discount array for what I've
taught you and I've done so on a 15
second chart that's not even a minute it
takes four of these individual handles
to make one minute
does it look like noise to you look at
how the market reacted
right there I time traveled folks I time
traveled when we were down here I drew
this out and labeled it in version
Fairbank app for the folks that have
been following me for the last couple
weeks of the month or so probably two
months I introduced the inversion
Fairbank account
okay so every one of my PD arrays can be
utilized as a contrain entry
but unless you have the narrative in
mind knowing where is it going to reach
for where's the liquidity it's going to
be drawing price next
how do you know how do you know that ICT
well you started with the weekly candle
where is it going to gravitate to I
don't care if you use another way of
trading folks I don't care if you do
trade with harmonic patterns okay if you
use what I'm teaching here tonight it's
going to make your start working
the times that it fails it's going
against what I'm teaching you tonight I
promise you that is not arrogance or
Pride or ego speaking your ain't
working when it goes against this
if you trade retail concepts with this
stuff your retail ship will start
working
you don't have to like me
okay you don't have to tell everybody
that you trade SMC or ICT or whatever
you want to call me okay I don't
care I really don't care
but I really want to see you succeed
even if you hate my guts and you
troll me you make videos about me and
all about I don't care I'm not
losing any sleep okay I can
still do this stuff whether you love me
or hate me
and I really want you to listen
and you never ever ever have to tell me
that it improved your Trading
I don't need it
I know it works
I want you to think about
everything I talked about tonight
and how it gives you a plethora
of opportunities that will always be
there
folks these intervals they happen every
day
and guess what
they can't hide it
they cannot hide this information from
you it doesn't require any kind of
subscription to any thing it
doesn't require you to do anything extra
it's simply just looking at the time
intervals where is that pool of
liquidity above and below and where does
it fit in a narrative I'm guiding you
I'm teaching you but teach me bias ICT
this is all part of it
it's all part of it
go back and look at the tweets I've told
you the focus on the PM session what is
that 1 30 to 4 o'clock
think
how many opportunities
are going to be much more Within Reach
for you now
because you have this understanding in
price
it doesn't mean you're going to be able
to go out and do it tomorrow remember I
said in this lecture tonight that you
have to go through weeks and months of
back testing studying what it's done
logging it journaling it and encouraging
yourself in the commentary in the chart
that you screenshot that you put into
your journal and you talk to yourself
like you knew it was going to happen in
advance and you're tricking your
subconscious into believing that is
experience and because you're
sugarcoating it with everything positive
and you're never saying anything
negative when you watch real-time price
it won't feel scary subconsciously if
you've always looked at Price action or
looked at people like me or other people
that you think are fraud scammers or
they don't really know how to trade or
whatever you are literally
flooding your brain with toxicity
and I guarantee you probably can't make
a penetrating because you've
done that
this game is 90 psychological
it's easy to talk yourself out of it
and it's easy program your mind to keep
you in the game before you really know
the skill set you have to cheerlead
yourself
nobody's gonna be able to do it for you
just watching my videos is not enough
I promise you I have paid members that
have paid me
and they still can't do it because they
have not done what I've told them to do
or they think they've done enough but
they haven't
the fruits and the results will come
because of what they've done and they
gotta lead the at the door when
they come in they can't bring in Wyckoff
Theory and harmonics and other stuff and
try to blend it together you have to
learn this first forget all that stuff
learn this and then once you understand
this it's easy to go into a John Murphy
Financial uh what's it technical
analysis of the financial markets that's
the retail Trader's Bible everything in
that book
everything in that book can be contrary
if you understand this but
same side of the coin
if you flip it over you can make those
retail Concepts work if you understand
this premise tonight
see the problem with retail Traders is
they don't look at the market like this
they're looking for patterns for
pattern's sake they're looking for
indicator confirmation they're looking
for things that cuts through all the
they think noise or uncertainty or
randomness of price action if you're
believing that price is random what the
are you thinking the indicator is
going to do it's not changing the
randomness it's just adding something
else to believe in
so that's not the right way the right
way is understanding why price delivers
the way it does and it does
own a basis of time
and price there's a time that it
operates and it's reaching for us very
specific price
I've already taught you the time
elements and today I've already taught
you the price elements time and price
between those two you will always have a
setup for life
you can have a breaker you can have a
institutional order flow entry drill you
can have a fair value gap an inversion
fair value cap I did this trade today
the rub the nose of the guy that was in
my comment section and you know you
don't see him but he's in
the videos where I uh it looks like my
comment section open is open rather like
It's usually the pre-recorded videos I
think it's what it does I think I don't
think it lets you do a comment or it
doesn't look like there's going to be
comments open for a live stream
but whenever I do a pre-recorded video
this section underneath the video it
looks like you can leave a comment and I
have so many people saying first first
first comment whatever that's silly but
invariably I get some goober that comes
in there and will say like you know this
is never done in advance and you you're
making this stuff up it doesn't work it
only works sometimes well that's true
for you because you don't know what the
you're doing but I know what I'm
doing and in inversion fear value gaps I
know which fair value Gap is going to be
inverted here it is folks and I've shown
it to you on a 15 second chart
like you can't get any planer than that
it's real
it's absolutely a real phenomenon it's
really there
but you know what makes it valid and how
to predict it
understanding liquidity
understanding time and price
that lunch hour
that nobody goes to lunch
the algorithm runs on that liquidity
and then it starts repricing and
spooling to the next pool liquidity so
since it took sell side okay what did I
teach you
price only goes up to take buy side or
buy stops or it goes up to an
inefficiency above market price that's
the only two reasons that price
goes up period and the story I don't
care how many years you've been trading
you can call yourself a market maker I
don't care what institution you work for
you banked that this one you did this
trading for that when you managed funds
and I don't give a
price only goes up for one of two
reasons to go up to inefficiency above
market price where it runs up for buy
side liquidity buy stops that's it folks
that is it it's not going up against
buying pressure and it's not going down
because of selling pressure
it's going down for inefficiency
below market price or it's going down
for South Side liquidity period and the
story that is it if it's not doing one
of those two things
it's going sideways
I already teach you and taught you the
economic calendar tells you when it's
going to consolidate
so what does that leave up or down okay
how do you know if it's going to go up
or down look at the weekly chart
what is it going to reach for on that
Weekly candlestick
something above the price or below the
price
which is the most obvious
there's going to be a fair bag Gap or
liquidity
which is the most easiest closest
proximity PD array
it's probably going to go to that one
but what if you're wrong then you
lose
You're Gonna Lose sometimes you're gonna
lose folks you're gonna get it wrong
sometimes why are you afraid
look at how many new opportunities are
made available to you now you have
information that is not found anywhere
else
I have laughed at all these
clowns
for 30 years on an internet pretending
they had some kind of Holy Grail
and they're Clueless
absolutely Clueless
and they perpetuate and regurgitate all
the stuff that I've bought in books
over 2 000 books and it's all horseshit
and I just can't bring it
throw I can't bring myself to the point
of throwing them away because number one
I spend a lot of good money on it I
worked hard for that money
and it just reminds me
of what I had to Wade through
and all the horseshit and lies and
garbage that people believe that makes
these markets move up and down
and it's all horseshit it's a waste of
time all the things that you think is
going to make the price go up and down
if it's in a book unless I wrote it it's
all horseshit and yes I just let pride
and ego speak right there because I can
do it I have the authority I have the
authority to do so
you have a setup for life if you use
this information
I have given you the freedom
to be able to pick what your entry model
is going to be
which one are you going to use
is it going to be an overblock a fair
value Gap optimal trade entry inversion
fair value Gap
turtle soup
uh consequent encroachment of a wick
hmm
all these things
are left into your hands and I'm making
allowance for that because I don't know
where you started in my videos
and if you're wondering where to start
the 2022 model or 2022 mentorship it's
41 videos I promise you if you start
there you will get the shortest route to
going into the charts and finding
something that works every day
every day works every day now here's
here's the caveat it may not work in the
market that you're looking at right now
but it's in every single one of these
markets it's in there
so what does that mean if you're an
index Trader
it will be in one index
it may be in multiple index
but it might only be M1 and that's why I
teach you to look at all three of the
averages the Dow the NASDAQ and the s p
it may not be in the pound but it is in
the euro
you see the difference that's why I
teach at least
a Triad when I talk predominantly only
Forex I was teaching dollar euro dollar
and pound dollar
you can't miss it then it's there
you have to have intermarket
relationships and study like that with a
closely correlated Market Euro and cable
or euro dollar and pound dollar are
closely correlated
they're inversely correlated
with the dollar
so when the dog goes up they go down
but just because the dollar is going
down doesn't mean it's a good buy to be
in Euro sometimes it's a better buy-in
cable most times it's better than cable
better in cable rather but there's going
to be times when the dollar is going
sideways in the Euro or cable May
outperform one or the other
what does that mean
it just means that the real trade is not
in that one it's in the Exotic meaning
that you can use the pound dollar if
it's really running or it's predisposed
to go up more if the dollar is
consolidating
that means you probably have a really
good trade short I'm sorry long and
pound yen
don't take my word for it just consider
it I've done lessons and core content
about that stuff too
those videos are not coming down in
November everything on this YouTube
channel will stay
I won't be here updating it after
November
but I promise I will leave you with more
than you will ever need
and you study at your own pace don't
rush
if you rush you just make it just makes
your learning curve longer
you can't you can't speed learn this
you can't learn I I saw a guy
I watched all of ICT videos and I've
condensed it
into 15 videos
and now you can do it quicker and sooner
and faster more efficiently Porsche
that's you hear that that's me
laughing at your ass you are
clown if you think you can take
everything I've done and condense it
into the smallest little time frame of
presentation you're going to miss so
much information
there's so much information in the stuff
I've given
and you don't even appreciate what it is
because you just went through it one
time and you haven't even started
trading with real money
and when you start trading real money
you come back and you watch those same
videos again you're like oh he said
that I didn't hear that the first time
you're gonna swear up and down and I
made an edit to the video and I haven't
it just doesn't mean anything to you
right now because you're not even a demo
Trader yet with consistency
when you start trading with real money
the lessons and all those droning
discussions
jaw burning by ICT all that's that's
going to be much more meaningful to you
it's going to be rich understanding
because it'll be
you that's prepared to hear it you're
not prepared to hear it most times
you're not
and to be honest with you I'm not
talking to you
I'm talking to my children
that's what all this is for
that movie with Michael Keaton my life
that's what I'm doing right here
When I'm Gone
they'll have all this they'll have all
this to listen to and compare and
contrast with notes that I have for
enigma which I am not teaching and none
of these presentations ever had Enigma
in them and no joker has cracked it and
figured it out either
they may call what the they're
doing Enigma that anything close
I promise you it's not even close
I am enigma
[Music]
appreciate you hanging out with me
tonight hopefully this was insightful
and helpful to you in your learning and
if you could
give me a thumbs up on the video it
doesn't cost you anything it's an
encouragement for me to want to come
back and do more like this until talk to
you next time
be safe