welcome back folks this is lesson eight
of the January 2017 ICT mentorship
this tutorial is going to be
specifically dealing with the possession
trade management
okay for bullish market conditions we
like to anticipate potential bullish
seasonal tendencies
and again like I preface in every one of
the seasonal teachings it's not a Beyond
though it's not a Panacea it's just a
rule of thumb a road map if you will
about what may unfold in price action
just because it's done it for the last
40 plus years doesn't mean this year or
next year or the three years from now
when you sit down in front of the charts
doesn't mean that's going to be the
outcome you see in price but we start
there because seasonal Tendencies are
just that there's a tendency for price
to do certain things
since we're looking for bullish market
conditions we're going to be focusing on
the bullish seasonal tendencies that are
most likely to occur in the next three
to four months we went through some of
my ideal seasonal Tendencies which ones
I like and how it go in to the
marketplace and look for them
what we do after we identify what most
likely will unfold for a bullish
seasonal tendency is we have to look at
inter-market analysis confirmations is
there something to suggest there really
is a bullish technical picture for that
seasonal tendency to come to fruition if
there isn't any technicals to align with
that seasonal tendency this season it's
a seasonal isn't going to drive price
but technical is in alignment with the
seasonal tendency are a very powerful
couple
what is the interest rate markets
telling you okay are are yields
increasing because if the yields are
increasing it's going to be good for the
currency that you're trading if we see
Divergence between the yields that may
suggest there's going to be a shift or a
pause in the underlying direction of the
marketplace at the current moment
when we look at inter-market analysis we
are blending the two of interest rate
yields and we're also blending the four
major asset classes the stock market
interest rates Commodities and
currencies
all four of them together should be
confirming your general outlook on the
marketplace now you may not get clear
pictures from all four but if you're
getting three to indicate that your
directional bias for your asset you're
going to be trading is in fact what
they're suggesting as well or confirming
then you probably got a pretty good
trade idea lined up
once this occurs
we go into a higher time frame monthly
and weekly chart for PDA now PDA is
premium discount array or PD array I'm
going to be abbreviating that for the
remainder of this mentorship so that way
when you receive PDA it's the premium
discount arrays that means the order
blocks all the things I look for for
institutional reference points
we're looking for a higher time frame
weekly and monthly charts to indicate
where institutional overflow on those
particular time frames will look to seek
to trade to
when we understand there's two higher
time frames then we'll know what the
daily chart is going to do and we're
going to be focusing on the daily chart
for a quarterly shift or intermediate
price swing every three or four months
we're going to be looking for this new
price Wing to occur and we're going to
be looking at inter-market analysis
interest rate yields to suggest that is
in fact unfolding we're not trying to
pick the absolute low and we're not
trying to pick the absolute High we are
trying to get in sync with that
quarterly shift to get the meat in
between in other words the biggest
portion of the move that's what we're
focusing on
we use the daily pdas to frame our
bullish setups in other words we're
looking for ore blocks voids gaps
rejection blocks you know old highs hold
lows we're looking for those things to
to frame our buy setup
we're waiting for that to occur
based on what we see on the higher time
frames and with intermarket analysis and
hopefully a seasonal tendency is also
suggesting a bullish move as well when
we have these things in alignment we
have a great deal of confluences in our
camp we're looking for a high
probability scenario in that case
once you get to this stage what you're
going to have to do is to you're going
to have to determine whether you're
going to be a buyer on a stop or a buyer
on a limit it doesn't matter which one
you'll elect to go with but just
understand that if you are going to be
trading with limit orders there's a
probability of you missing moves or
missing your fills because you're
demanding a specific price level
when you go on a buy stop generally
you're going to end up getting filled
more times using that order but
unfortunately that creates a little bit
more Gap in between where you're
entering and where your stop loss is
going to be if as long as you're not
over leveraging your account
which brings us to how much money should
you be risking no more than one percent
and again keeping the idea that you're
taking big positions in terms of the
time that you're in there but not big
positions in the terms of how much
you're allocating to the to the trades
so you're looking for big moves with a
little bit of your account
by having that your risk is going to be
reduced but your maximum payout is going
to be massive in terms of how many Pips
you draw but still it's going to be
relative in terms of the percentage
because it's just the nature of this
time frame
once you determine you're going to be
buying on a stop or a limit and you
enter the position you're going to be
trailing your stop loss below the lowest
low in the last 40 trading days
now this brings us back to the ifta data
range why are we looking for the lowest
level last 40 trading days because
if we're looking for a bullish move the
market will most likely not want to go
back
40 trading days to find the low it's
going to be looking for the highs in the
last 40 trading days so that means we
are going to have a trailing stop loss
order that's very handsomely behind the
current market price and it's going to
take a very significant price move to
stop you out it avoids getting knocked
out of the marketplace prematurely and
when you're trading long-term trends or
long-term quarterly shifts the worst
thing it can happen is get knocked out
prematurely and then the market moves
take place and you miss out on that move
in this time frame you are not looking
to Trail your stop-loss Ultra tight you
have to have some freedom in the market
you can't just let it you know you can't
demand really Ultra tight stops in
long-term trading you gotta allow it to
move a little bit gyrate pool back
against you sometimes and initially when
you first get in the trade you just
gotta have to weather that and
unfortunately it may not be your cup of
tea but that's again the nature of the
Beast once the trend starts underway and
it starts moving in your favor if it
moves 50 percent of the range that you
expect to see unfold on the monthly and
or weekly chart because that's what
you're actually trading off of you're
executing on a daily chart
once that range moves to 50 of what you
expect to see in terms of profitability
say say it's a 500 pit range or a
thousand pip range If It Moves if it's a
thousand foot range we're referring to
If It Moves 500 Pips in your favor you
need to still
consider what the lowest low was in the
last 40 days your stop loss is going to
be below that
but when we get above 50 percent then
we're going to be looking for the lowest
low in the last 20 days once we get
about three quarters of the way
of the entire weekly monthly range you
want to start trailing your stop loss
below the most recent
low in the last 20 trading days okay and
I'll talk about that in examples in a
moment but your permitting price to seek
out the liquidity on the upside and
giving it a lot of room to consolidate
if it needs to before it goes another
leg higher
if you keep your stop loss below the
lowest loan the last 40 trading days
you're going to have a better chance of
staying in the move
and not being stopped out prematurely
okay for bearish market conditions I
could probably just save this slide and
decide everything I just said for the
bullets just reverse it but for
completeness sake we are being paid to
do this now so I want to give you both
sides uh the bearish market conditions
again we're anticipating a potential
bear seasonal tendency so we're focusing
on the Bears tendencies that have the
most ideal conditions what times of the
year are they expected we already know
what they are we went through those in
three teachings and once we understand
what is most likely to occur seasonally
again we're just looking for it first
there then we're looking for
inter-market analysis confirmations is
there a suggestion across all four major
asset classes currency markets interest
rates Commodities and the stock market
are they all in agreement with the
expectation you have for the next three
to four months
and if interest rate yields are
confirming that direction as well
interest rates rising or increasing or
decreasing is that
Salient to your expectation for the
bearish move that you're trying to to
take on for next quarterly shift
if this does align then we go to the
higher time frame monthly and weekly and
we start looking for the ranges and we
look for the PDA for monthly and weekly
objectives institutionally
where are we looking to go how far are
we looking to go down where are the old
loads where are the bullish order blocks
where are the liquidity voids on the
downside where are the fair value gaps
below us where are the mitigation blocks
and potential Breakers we have to be
valueful of okay all those ideas we have
to start mapping those out because
they're either going to be speed bumps
or they're going to be rocket fuel for
our next price leg in our bearish
expectations so we have to be mindful of
them going forward we'll have them
already in our charts we won't be
surprised by them
and once we have all these ideas then we
can expect that quarterly shift to take
place and then therefore have an
intermediate term price swing moving
over the course of two to three
potentially four months at maximum where
we see a bearish move take place
once we have the scenario outlined okay
and we expect the monthly and or weekly
ranks or
swing to
take effect what we're going to be doing
is focusing on the daily chart and we're
going to be utilizing the daily pdas
that means the daily premium discount
arrays or basically we're looking for
bearish order blocks we're looking for
bearish liquidity voids to fill in we're
looking for old highs to sell above
we're looking for rejection blocks above
and old highs handles body and we're
looking for uh bearish Breakers to trade
into we're looking for mitigation blocks
to trade against and sell off of all
those ideas we're looking for that on a
daily time frame to get in sync with the
move we expect to see unfold on the
monthly and weekly charts so we're using
the daily PDA to frame our bearish
setups
once we have our setup what we're
looking for is
the determination are we going to be
selling on a stop or are we selling on a
limit order and that's going to be a
matter of personal preference again like
I said with the bullish market
conditions if you're going to be selling
on a limit chances are you may not get
your fill so just take that into
consideration and if you're 100 certain
you have to have the entry selling on a
stop is almost a guarantee you're going
to get that fill because you're going to
be selling on weakness and once that
price is triggered you'll be short and
again but it opens a little bit more
risk from where you enter and where your
stop loss needs to be which brings us to
once you're in the move you're going to
be using a trailing stop loss above the
highest high in the last 40 trading days
and what that's going to keep you from
having happen is a premature stopout you
don't want to get knocked out of the
market before you actually see the move
transpire you don't want to have any
opportunity for the market to have a
move against you
and see it take off once it knocks you
out that's enough it's very frustrating
to see that happen and if you wait a
long time for these long-term setups to
get set up just to get knocked out
prematurely you exercise so much
patience to get to that stage than to
Once get in it and then it knocks you
out worse thing can happen is you get
fearful or never get another opportunity
to get back in and it takes off and runs
away from you then you have to wait for
another higher level objective to get in
to uh and then you obviously lose some
of the potential profit but nonetheless
you can still get in the positions but
it's nothing worse than that and having
all the analysis done the homework the
patience factor and get in in the market
talk you know knocks you out prematurely
because you're trying to have too much
of a tight stop loss you don't need to
do that on a higher time frame trading
in fact it's better if you keep a wider
stop and you try not to rush to move it
up to break even because break even on
long-term trading is just the worst
thing they possibly ever consider you
don't want to do that so we're going to
be trailing your stop loss above the
highest high in the last 40 trading days
and by doing so what you're doing is
actually giving the market room to
breathe and move around
when you identify the range at which
you're trying to see unfold on the
monthly and or weekly chart when the
price moves 50 percent of that range in
your favor okay in other words it's
moved half the distance you thought it
was going to even at that moment okay
you're still going to be using the
highest high and last 40 trading days
your stop is going to be above that okay
because you're not trying to get knocked
out once it moves to about three
quarters of the the range that you
anticipate seeing
then what you're going to be doing is
you're going to be looking for the
highest high in the last 20 trading days
because you're getting really close to
that ultimate objective and it may not
really get there so you want to lock in
as much profit as possible if you use
the highest high in the last 40 trading
days and you've seen three quarters of
the move you may see a deep retracement
that maybe end up becoming the actual
reversal that you didn't expect to see
think like Optimal trade entry it could
go 79 of the total move you expect to
see but then fail and go the other
direction and you would just be knocked
out with a great deal of more larger
loss by using that trailing 40-day stop
loss above the highest high and last 40
trading Days by reducing it to only 20
trading days we're using ipta procedures
for data ranges but we're using
measuring the ranges okay and grading
the scale of how far that move has
already happened when we start getting
mature in our move we want to start
locking in more aggressively that that
position but we're only going to drop
down to
a 20-day look back once we get to three
quarters of the move that we expect to
see
then we have to start dropping back in
terms of how far we go back in terms of
using a stop loss basis you know we're
not going to use 40 trading days the
entire duration of the trade we only get
three quarters of the move under our
belt you know obviously we're going to
be looking to lock in some of that
profit and keeping it from moving a
great deal against us so by using a
20-day look back every single day while
we're in the trade once three quarters
of the move has been seen what you're
doing is you're ultimately bringing that
stop loss closer to the market price but
not so close that knocks you out if it
does knock you out and goes to the below
a 20-day low chances are you probably
May really handsome profit or you
probably saved yourself a complete
reversal and watch it erode more profits
if you would have stepped just kept that
that 40 trading Day High
so let's take a look at a couple
examples real quick and then we'll
put in this January teaching up
okay we're looking at the Japanese
Genesis the weekly chart
and we have the high up here and we have
these equal lows we talked about during
the live uh teachings of the mentorship
and then below these equal lows we have
these two panels which makes the bullish
order block
and what we're going to do is we're
going to add a Fibonacci just to grade
the scale of this entire range
so we have this high
all the way down to this low
I'm sorry this is high rather of this
candle
and that gives us our range low and this
is our Range High okay and here's
equilibrium right in here okay so we're
looking at this move here after market
structure has been broken we have this
swing low here
it's violated here and then we have a
rally so we're going to be looking at
this high in here
only daily
looking for an ultimate move down to
this level here
so we're going to go to a daily chart
now dropping down into it and we're
going to be looking at the sell side
first
okay here's that move
we'll refer to this in a minute when we
get to the um the buy side objectives
but here we have this High here
price has the um
a break in Market structure here and we
have a rally up it goes into this last
up candle which is a PDA on a weekly
basis
and it's also a PDA for the daily and
it's a bearish order block for us here
trades right up into the body of this
candle which is the open comes in at
121.69 the high on this candle
comes in at 21.72 so only three Pips
higher than this opening price
at that candle here we have the up
candle so we're going to be doing what
we're going to be deciding if we're
going to
sell short
on a limit we're gonna be selling short
either on a limit above this close or
we're going to be selling on a stop
down here
which one are you going to do but what
we're doing is once we get in we have to
use the high in the last 40 trading days
I have here a range that's already been
created with 40.
right here so there's 40 trading days
from this day here which is the trade
day here because you have the up candle
this is the day you would trade Look
Back 40 days your stop loss has to be
above here
so your range of risk is framed out for
you by doing this
and let's just say you're going to sell
a limit
if you have a stop loss of 250 Pips you
got to be above that say 260 Pips
that's your stop okay some of you are
probably cringing with that 260 Pips
good grief it's long-term trading folks
and I mean you really gotta change your
uh way of thinking about it because
it's not going to be the same as it was
when we were discussing complete uh
intraday action
and then you can do things like this you
can go
here is
one
two
three
four
five
six
seven
eight
and we won't get nine
it just falls short of that
okay so we have
basically eight
r on this trade
that's falling short even at the
objective so
we can have uh
that one off here and here's AR
right there okay so selling short up
here
we have 8 times 260 Pips
the thing about that that's a massive
move okay it's huge move okay and as you
trade this
what you're doing is you're you're
continuously every single time you look
at the trading day you're in you're
going to be looking back
and again I have another Ranger here 40
pip uh 40 trading days range or
approximation let's say like that
okay every trading day you're going to
keep looking back what was the highest
high
in the last 40 trading days
okay each trading day
you're looking at the right end of this
here okay every single trading day
you're looking at the highest high and
you're keeping your uh stop loss
above that high
whatever that whatever that high is okay
like right in here looking back in the
last 40 trading days your stop is above
this high
at this point here we have that real
deep trading retracement your stock has
got to be above these highs
okay this is where we actually hit the
objective so anything past that doesn't
mean anything but at this moment here
your stop has to be above this hot here
so it keeps you from getting locked
knocked out prematurely
and again eight times 260 Pips that's
this huge huge move
so we're going to focus now on the buy
side
and we saw that Weekly bullish order
block down here
and we expected it to trade back up to
the weekly bearish order block
in here here's the buy Looking Back 40
trading days your buy uh buy position
has a protective sell stop below these
lows in here okay if you bought in here
before the election and we had that big
wild whipsaw even with this wild whip
saw if you would have bought this day
here on a limit below the close here on
the limit on this candle if you bought
here on this candle on a limit on this
day here
yeah you would have saw profits and then
on the election day you would have rode
through all this probably would have
been scary for you but even then 40
trading days back your stop has to be
below here so you're not knocked out
long term you're in there and again the
same thing you're looking for
the lowest low when you buy it
in the last 40 trading days
like for instance if you bought here
your stop has to be below this low
let's see which one's lower this one
the low is 109.19
and then you have this candle here
yeah one and 9 19 so it's got to be
below this low here
and then you have another buying
opportunity on this day here again your
stop still stays below here
on this day again your stop still stays
below here
on this day here
the lowest low in the last 40 trading
days is here still
but we have to change gears now once we
get half the range
I'm going to add a
fib
to this
we have our low
foreign
here and once price trades through this
here we start looking back 20 trading
days and we start trailing our stop loss
below the lowest low in the last 20
trading days
so we get 20.
from here stop loss has to be below here
on this buying day here the last 20
trading days your stop loss still below
here
this day here the last 20 trading days
is still below here
stock loss has to be below here
and on this trading day your stop loss
has to be below this trading day slow
and after that it just hits the
objective the weekly bear shorter block
so again above halfway point you want to
start trailing your stop loss tighter
below the low the last 20 trading days
but prior to equilibrium or halfway move
you want to be 40 trading days back
using if the data ranges because it's
not likely it's going to seek that
liquidity it's going to be seeking the
liquidity above the 40-day
ties in above the 20 highs and it's
going to be looking for the 60-day high
now you can see how that if the data
range comes into play using these higher
time frames
so until we talk again I wish you good
luck and good Trading