welcome back folks going to do a quick
little review here and I'll squeeze in
another approach to using some PD arrays
I've already taught and how we can kind
of like build a model around it that'll
come at the end of the video here for
now let's take a quick look at the
higher time frame on the US dollar
Index last time we talked I mentioned
that we would be looking
for potential run up into
here this was the bide liquidity pool I
mentioned we were driving up into that
we've seen that and then the later time
we might see this actually happen it did
we stayed bullish we haven't been
looking for lower prices on dollar uh
there's a small little volume imbalance
right in there watch that going into
next week and then obviously the buy
side resides here so a really strong run
below these relative equal
lows sell side liquidity taken fair
value Gap traded up and continuously
moved into the B that we had here here
and here longer term we have this so
dollar showing its underlying strength
and it's still going to put interterm
long-term pressure on euro dollar
wanting
to go lower and pound dollar wanting to
go
lower speaking of Euro here is the daily
chart for euro dollar and I mentioned
the inversion fair value
Gap we trade up into that look at the
bodies again again respecting consequent
inion which is the midpoint of any
Gap Market broke lower taking the cell
side out here then we moved aggressively
in this direction towards the cell side
throughout the entirety of this week it
would have been nice to see this trade
up into this small little Gap here I was
kind of looking for that
today but the failure to get up there is
you know it's indicative of heaviness
heaviness meaning that the Market's
likely to
lower and again attack that cell sign so
with higher dollar prices we're going to
stick with the idea of looking for lower
prices for fiber and fiber is just the
nickname for euro
dollar okay cable or pound dollar see we
have
a inversion fair value Gap here the
Market's been breaking
lower next draw liquidity Still Remains
at the sell side liquidity here
this one we traded up into this small
little fair value Gap there you can look
at your lower time frames we trade up
into that this is institutional Oro
entry drill where it goes into a
partial but less than half of a fair
value Gap there and then sells off so
we'll be looking for near term we
have sell side resting below here and we
have the cell side below here so we're
maintaining a bearish stands still for
British pound so if you guys appreciate
or like these longer term you know bias
based ideas for Forex I'm not going to
be drawing your attention to the smaller
time frames because I don't think that
it is something that we should be doing
right now it's something for you to do
or your own analysis but from the higher
time frame I'm just lending my
experience to give you the bias and you
can see pretty much it's been delivering
like Gang Busters so uh if you like that
kind of stuff you want me continue just
give this video a thumbs
up em Min S&P futures contract September
delivery daily
chart and we just fell short yesterday
going into this discount fair value Gap
to just got really really close but not
quite getting into it we have this buy
side and balance sell sign efficiency
between this candle's low and this
candle's High that's the blue lines here
that's denoting that buy side balance s
sign efficiency and this red line is
consequent encouragement or midpoint
between this candle's low this candle's
high so all this big movement up here
it's buy side and
balance sell side inefficiency so it
needs to see what lower price is
delivered we seen that happen here and
this price movement here is is in my
opinion what we're having to deal with
on the lower time frame so if you
watched how we traded on Wednesday
Thursday and Friday of this week for
index
Futures unless you were Ultra shortterm
like one minute scalping five minute
scalping um You probably experience a
lot of difficulty in terms of navigating
you know the EB and flow of intraday
price action so whenever we have these
kind of
like bookends think of it like that okay
we have strong opinion ated reasons that
we can make the case for higher prices
and for lower prices and when we have
that everything
makes trading with a great deal of
precision that would otherwise be
apparent in all time
frames it kind of reduces it down to a
very
infrequent well at least you may observe
that it will be
infrequent we've seen that Wednesday
Thursday and Friday not the latter part
of Wednesday not the first part of
Wednesday but the afternoon of Wednesday
Thursday and then Friday's
trading we're seeing all that in here
so it's going to have to move outside of
this
range definitively for me so in other
words it's got to either trade above the
buy side B sell sign efficiency is high
or it's got a trade below the buy side
and balance sell sign efficienc is low
why while we're in here I will not be
interested in taking any trades for em
mini
S&P this area here is a fair value Gap
from this candle's low this candle's
High the Shaded area is denoting
that on the hourly chart you can see how
we had Fairway Gap here institutional
entry drill which is a partial entry but
just falling short of half the Gap
breaks down one more in time does the
same thing here look at all this range
bound trading right in there see that
then we break lower small little range
break lower small little range and this
placement to the downside trading to the
low of the inefficiency or the bide Bal
sside efficiency on the daily chart
remember the blue lines denote
that big singular up Clos candle and
then the red level is the midpoint of
that and that shaded area is the fair
value gap on the daily chart we Tri up
to consequent encroachment here roll
over and just fell short of trading into
that inefficiency on the daily chart and
sweeping below this low so it fell
just short of reaching into that and
then we had this gnarly Thursday and
Friday a trading range for E Min S&P
returning back to consequent
encroachment 15 minut time frame again
you can see how we had Friday's trading
Thursday's trading in the afternoon
retracing back up into consequent
encouragement so a really nice sell off
here in the morning which was really
easy to see
that follow this price action here this
right here you have to be extremely
Nimble and know exactly what you're
looking for if you can get it take it
and stop otherwise you can get chopped
up in here over trade or do a lot of
things so otherwise undermine your
growth or create draw down for your
account so these are problematic areas
until we leave this range I'm not
interested in touching it so if we stay
within this when we open on Sunday and
trade into it on Monday my hands will be
away from all asset classes because my
only interest right now in trading is
the index Futures S&P and
NASDAQ NASDAQ daily chart similar vein
we have depos balance sell efficiency
defined by this candle's high this
candle's low midpoint is consequent
encouragement
and price will have to
leave this buy B sell efficiency either
higher or lower before I'm interested in
trading because we had this run
up I like the idea of potentially
trading down to
15126 and a half I mean that that's what
I'm interested in seeing I want to see
that happen because we've seen it happen
for
ES the run up we seen imp partial uh
decline which we'll look at that and I
called that level real time before it
actually is delivered on Thursday on
Twitter or we could rally higher and
come back out of this buy side and bance
out efficiency and then resume going
higher and reach for the buy side here
and completely close in this
inefficiency over here in the form of a
CBI so because the analysis is
conflicted meaning that we could range
Bound in here for a little while and
still deliver to that 15,26 A5
that's what I'm kind of expecting to
happen but I'm not excited about taking
any trades in here until we definitively
leave this buy sign balance sell sign
efficiency the reason why is because
even though I like the idea of going
short I could be wrong and it may be
just accumulating in here to go higher
because this Market stock market is
absolutely rigged okay I mean more more
than it really is okay and other time uh
they're propping this market up for
political reasons uh there's no reason
for and there's no justification for the
shares being at the levels they are for
stocks right now it's just it's not
warranted at all so because we're seeing
conflicted both sides of the narrative
on the higher time frame that forces
your hand to be a intraday scalper you
know short-term trading swing trading
you have to be very very precise you you
get really one entry and that's it so in
a very small one minute time frame
you'll have a little bit more
opportunities to navigate but you have
to have experience and be nimble so I'm
just showing you my cards I'm not
terribly excited about going into next
week until we leave this B B cell
efficiency on the hourly chart you can
see we ran buy side here into a bearish
order block we broke
down bearish order block here
displacement to the downside swept the
cell side here entered the buy side and
balance cell
efficiency rolled over after
institutional order entry drill here
which is just a partial entry into this
Cy I try to keep the charts clean that
way I have less to talk about get
through this chart discussion quicker
for you this
evening we rolled through went through
half of the daily buy sign and bance
cell side efficiency which is the
consequent encouragement level that blue
line which is just midpoint between the
lower level and the higher level of the
daily buy sign and balance sell sign
efficiency that One Singular big green
Candle on the daily chart that's the
reference points here for it on the
hourly chart so we rolled over and I
gave on
Twitter on Thursday I said to have 15,1
85.2 and
15,17 noted on your chart and we went
down the bodies respected both of those
levels we Wicked through both of
them 15175 is this candle here so
there's a buy sign B sell sign
efficiency between this candle's low
this candle's high with this one big
candle so that's where that
15, 175 level came from the 15, 1885 and
a quarter level which is here is the
daily buy s balance sell s efficiency
25% quadrant okay so in other words if
you take this level here and this level
here and divide it in equal parts four
equal parts half is here here so halfway
between this level and here is this so
it's the lower quadrant 25% level of
here this is that's not quarters Theory
by the way right away I know some think
oh he's teaching quarters Theory it's
not quarters Theory I'm looking at an
inefficiency and I'm grading that just
like I teach how to grade a price swing
in my core content so these are all
algorithmic signatures that price will
respect and adhere to so it's important
to know what they are and how apply it
to your charts and then anticipate these
types of responses Market rallies off of
that on Thursday comes back in and ret
trades back to the consequent
encroachment midpoint and then sends us
back up to the high end of the daily b
side of Mel so efficiency
high on the 15-minute time frame you can
see how again on Friday and on Thursday
just a really gnarly trading range I
mean you
can grow very frustrated trying to trade
this if you're 10 trying to anticipate a
follow through either higher or lower
you have to be very very Nimble and look
at the lower time frames pick your shots
if you get a winter stop for the day or
the session and be done and try not to
force your hand too
much all right see here's the one minute
Candlestick chart for the NASDAQ and I'm
going to teach you something that
employs my inversion fair value got now
before I get into this there's a a
couple points I want to make because
there are a couple Romper Room mentors
out there that will tell you that a fair
value Gap is something that is simply a
support or resistance level on a lower
time frame that's not true that's not
what it is it's an actual
inefficiency this little area in here
where one single candle pass up to the
upside that's a bide and B cide
efficiency so it's not had any
overlapping with any other candles after
it formed on the downside so it's
lacking what sells side delivery
so it's part of this swing
low part of an expected
redelivery between the high of the daily
buy sign cell sign efficiency which is
this level up here and the low of that
same daily B Bal and cell efficiency
okay so if we are up in the upper
portion of that range because here's the
consequent cment between this level and
this level and we're seeing the market
start to break down it's doing here this
inversion fair value got this is part of
what many of you ask how do you know
which fair value Gap is going to be an
inversion fair value Gap how do you know
which fair value Gap to use I'm
employing a lot of different things time
and price I'm using institutional Market
structure not your classic higher high
lower low crap because that's that's
infancy that's it's to myopic you need
to know what you're looking
for in the grand scheme of things price
was already working its way down into
and towards this redelivery on the buy
side and balance s sign efficiency low
that's this price level down here so if
we are looking at this price leg running
higher with the expectation that we're
going to see it roll over this becoming
a fulc chome Point high to low project
it down that gives us a reasonable
expectation to see it reach into a
discount range which would be half of
the range between this high and that low
which makes the daily buy side and
balance soide efficiency if your first
time watching this I already said enough
to completely confuse you but I promise
you if you take a few times to watch
this video the only thing I'm stating is
all of this price run here going down is
just simply trying to get down to this
level here because it was One Singular
Candle on the daily chart that went up
so the market will efficiently deliver
sside delivery which is not sell-side
liquidity sside delivery is just the
market goes lower it books price on the
downside in other words it's offering
price between the Range High of the
daily buy sign B sell sign efficiency at
15361 A5 and the low of that daily
Candle by balance efficiency at 15,26 A5
so the only thing I'm stating here is if
we were to take that range which is the
daily candle and I I'll explain again
what what I'm showing you here on the
daily chart but for now conceptually
just imagine if half of the range from
that price level here and that price
level here half of that range is here
anything at that price level or higher
is a premium if we're bearish we really
want to be selling short up here with
the expectation that it's going to aim
for something down in the lower half and
ultimately perfectly delivered to this
lower level 15,26 A5 it need not do that
so what levels are we looking for
because we're not dealing with zones
well what's the the lower quadrant lower
quadrant price level is here 15,1 185
and a
qu half of the range on the buyid B sell
sign efficiency on the daily chart which
is this high and that low that's in
purple half of it's here half of the
half point and the low is the lower
quadrant point so that's why I was
saying on Thursday to have these levels
noted and then you have the Tuesday
August 29th 2023 10: a.m. 1 hour High
sign balance C sign efficiency low and I
already mentioned that before we drop
down the lower time frames so everything
I'm saying here I've literally pointed
to and referred to what it is in this
very video so you don't have to go
anywhere else searching for anything
it's just a matter of listening to what
I'm saying here and then finding it in
the chart and also following along in
the narrative as why am interested in
this very fair value Gap at all because
we're in a premium I'm expected this to
see this price leg roll over it already
broke below it
here so it rolls through I'm not
interested in selling short
there because I know that time is a
bigger Factor so when price is running
up like this I'm not trying to chase
that I'm not trying to be a um an
early participant I want to see price
get to
8:00 8 clock is here so the market
trades back down through it again we're
not supply and demand so every time you
see a little rectangle here the nefy the
first the first- time viewer or someone
just has a a super superiority complex
they'll say that I'm teaching supply and
demand it's absolutely not because I'm
looking through all of this to go right
back to that specific candle right there
and its specific price
levels it trades up to a here now
because of time I'm expecting it to have
a better influence over price does it
send price lower yes one more time it
comes back up and hits it again does it
go through it again no it's stopping
because it's referring right back to
that price point right there so if this
is a fair value Gap and I was bullish
I'd be interested in buying it when it
was going down into it here or if it
went down through it and it came back
above it now I would treat it as you
know a reclaimed discount
array I'm looking through these
candlesticks
to a specific PD array but I'm applying
narrative which is a very hard thing to
teach because it's learned conceptually
by experience seeing over and over and
over again that's why I'm trying to tell
you that what some of you are asking for
is a one shot one kill video where it
literally answers all your questions in
one visit one sitting one View and it's
it nothing is like that okay but uh this
approach to using an inversion fair
value Gap because otherwise it would be
bullish here it's not because we're in a
premium
I want to be short I want to be looking
for shorts because I expect that daily
chart that big bullish green candle is
going to be redelivered to the downside
and the first level I'm looking for is
the halfway
point and the quadrant the lower
25% which is here and then dug into the
hourly chart by CB cell sign efficiency
which is what I mentioned earlier before
we got into this part of this video
that's where those two levels came from
and I quoted on Twitter before we got
down to
it the way that this inversion fair
valap is being
implemented is my
model madus madus is a slang or nickname
used for the M2 machine gun okay so
that's just the way my mind works and
the way I kind of like classify things I
have 81 different PD arrays and there's
several things that I can do with each
one of those PD arrays this is simply an
inversion fair value Gap how I use that
fair value Gap is a model and if we have
a inefficiency as outlined here between
the
daily buy B cell efficiency high and low
we're bearish we're looking for lower
prices we get this Market structure in
agreement and then time of
price we're expecting an 8:30 delivery
we can get in here and use this and get
ahead of yes get ahead of and enter
before the news it's like an x-ray view
tips your hand or tips its hand to you
and tells you this is what it's likeing
to do and you have the inefficiency here
trades up into it and at the delivery of
8:30 news and then we see it run away on
the employment
numbers trading down
into the lower 25% quadrant between
between this low and this High lower
quarter or quadrant level is here Trad
still here and then trades to the 15 175
level and then ultimately we seen it go
higher from
there I'm going to zoom in a little
bit there's that
Gap so that inversion fair value Gap
within the context of expecting it to
trade
lower best case scenario you know being
the low of the daily B so icy for Nasdaq
but needing it not to do that to
profitability which is first partial
would be here at consequent encroachment
and you let it run some more to get down
to the lower quadrant and they that
level you want to take a partial and
then if you can get down to another
discount array which was in close
proximity which is only 10 handles away
which was that hourly B Bell and cell
deficiencies
low on this date and time on on your
hourly chart so that's why it's
annotated that way you can go back and
look at on your own charts I want to
take you back up again just know that
this is what I'm showing you
here this range how I'm employing the
inversion fair value Gap there here for
myu Mau is a model that you can use a
inversion fair value Gap when you are
expecting price to run right back down a
inefficiency that was buy side and
balance sell side in efficiency this can
be reversed when you have a sell sign
and balance buy side efficiency and
you're expecting price to go higher the
inversion fair value Gap here would be
something after a low and then would you
know trade back down to it and then send
it higher so everything here is just
completely
reversed and I know if you're brand new
to my stuff I'm sure I'm quite certain
you're you're probably confused right
now and you have to study but really
what I'm saying here
is this level here and this level here
on the hourly chart is
this this One Singular candle and what
I'm saying is on Thursday I was
anticipating the run down into at least
the lower
quadrant the lower 25% between
this and this which are these levels
here respectively this candle's low this
candle's high so we have One Singular
pass
higher we expect lower prices to be
delivered the same way just going back
down to
redeliver over the inefficiency here it
was buy side delivery but now it needs
sell-side delivery because it's
inefficient in that regard because
there's no other candle between this
candle's low and that candle's High only
one candle went higher and that range
defined by that candle here this low and
that high needs to have efficient
delivery that can only happen by having
price go back down inside this entire
range lower quadrant halfway point if
you have a inversion Fair value Gap and
you're bearish and you're expecting a
news report and it's tipped its hand to
you saying okay we are likely to break
lower in Market structure and a lower
time frames we can anticipate this
drop that's occurring in
here
drop and that's
occurring in
here
drop and zoomed in inside that
premium to
Discount that's the inversion per you
got
M second opportunity to get into it
again it breaks aggressively
inefficiency once more at 8:30
employment numbers runs aggressively
partial
here
partial best case scenario would be if
it would deliver to the low of the
hourly but I mentioned real time I said
take your profits don't be greedy and
then we seen it
go a little bit lower than my objective
on that particular day but never got to
the low of the daily B cell efficiency
being this level
here it never got to that level
so I'm certain it's a lot for you to
digest but every one of my PD arrays you
can apply it to specific elements of
Market structure and how you anticipate
price delivering and you can plug and
play each one of these pdas with the
expectation that the model will deliver
under a
specific premise we're
expecting this level here to this level
here be delivered with downside delivery
in our sells side delivery as price was
going
lower it's not random it's not going to
some random level it's going to very
specific price levels and if I'm going
to use this inversion fair value Gap I
can use it in the context of myu modu is
simply a model utilizing an inversion
fair value Gap so that PD array it's an
advanced version or application of
inversion fair value Gap but it takes
you right back to the core context of
where are you in price what's it likely
to go to next and are you in a shortterm
premium or short-term discount if we're
bearish and we're in premium we can
anticipate price reaching down into a
discount but not some random level very
specific levels and it need not go to
the best case scenario which would be
the low which I still hold true that I I
suspect at some point maybe next week
that we'll try to reach down here until
I'm proven wrong and I'm I'm okay with
being proven wrong I'm going to be
trading it but the idea is I expect it
to trade down here because the E many
S&P has already traded it to its
respective bid and bell and cellid
efficiency for its daily
chart
all right folks that's it for this one
enjoy your weekend thanks for watching
until I'll talk to you next time be safe