welcome back folks this is Lesson Four
short-term Trading
blending Gupta data ranges and PD arrays
for liquidity runs
okay when we're looking at if the data
ranges
we're referring to specifically time
and PD arrays are dealing specifically
with price
so blending the two elements together
you're blending time and price
theoretically
if the data ranges provide you a context
to look back
the last 20 days the last 40 days in the
last 60 days
As you move forward
you're casting forward for a new set of
20 40 and 60 each new day you shift that
range forward
the look back period gives you the
context of frame
the PD arrays with a reference point in
time
the enter Bank price delivery algorithm
will reach back in to data arrays
between the last 20 days the last 40
days and the last 60 days
which
data array they use or refer to is
respective to the PD array in reference
to price
if price is in a premium Market
obviously working for the market price
up
we would be looking for a bearish
mitigation block
a bearish breaker
liquidity void
fair value Gap
a bearish order block
a rejection block
an old high or an old low
for the market price and below for a
discount Market
we would be looking for a bullish
mitigation block
a bullish breaker liquidity void
fair value Gap
bullish order block
rejection block
old low or old High
moving from the market price up in the
order that's listed in the premium data
arrays that's the
order in which the algorithm will seek
those respective price reference points
they're not in any different order this
is the order for the hierarchy in the
way that they're set up
there is not always a void or Gap or
mitigation block it may just simply need
to go all the way up to a bearish order
block or a rejection block and the same
thing is said in opposite terms for when
the Market's in a discount
it's not ambiguous when we look at price
in the form of the PD array Matrix
a good practice this is always to Simply
go through your price charts and just
look for where price is right now at the
market price and above you
okay looking back last
20 days and 40 days and 60 days
which PD arrays in the form of a premium
Market exist again not all of these
bearish or premium arrays will exist in
your price
there may be a selection of three or
four or maybe as little as two
rarely we have all of them
to choose from
so what you're doing is you're looking
back over the last 20 days
and you're looking to see above us in
terms of the market price what would be
deemed as a premium Market
the last 20 days which PD array exists
in price action
looking back 20 days
which discount PD array exists below us
there may be a PD array above and or
below us that's already been used by
Price action for instance you know maybe
a bullish order block
price is already traded down into and
responded and reacted accordingly and
had higher prices
that PD array has now been exhausted so
you'd have to look for another discount
PD array
when we refer to time and price what
we're doing is we're blending both the
components just like the algorithm does
the algorithm has to go back a specific
number of time
so what we do is we break it into 20
trading days which is essentially one
month
40 trading days which is essentially two
months and 60 trading days which is
essentially three trading months
by combining both time and price we get
the closest thing we can arrive at in
terms of what the algorithm will seek to
do in terms of trading to the next level
liquidity
when the markets are bearish
we work from a premium Market down to a
discount
based on whatever premium PD array
discount PD array exist in your current
market action
when it's bearish those premium PD
arrays will be your resistance points or
where cell signals or sell-offs will
occur
or new cell setups
the objective for price to reach down
into will be the discount PD arrays that
exist in your price action
we don't force the idea of any of these
PD arrays
they're either in the chart or they're
not
if there's an absence of any one of them
it doesn't negate or increase or lessen
the validity of a ideal setup
it just means that you have far less to
choose from in terms of targets
or setups
all right let's take a look at an
example we're going to use the
Australian dollar this is the daily
chart
and the first thing you want to do is
you want to break your market up in
reference to time
so now we have the look back of 20
trading days
40 trading days and 60 trading days
we can go back all the way to the 60
trading days
and you can see that the lowest point
with the old load noted
and the highest high formed in the last
20 trading days that is our total 60-day
trading range
splitting that market in half in
reference to its old High
and it's old low we can see where the
premium and discount Market ranges exist
if this old Woe Is violated
we would have to go back
and look at the old low
formed in the 60-day look back period
the arrow delineating the the lowest low
in the last 20 trading days if that is
violated and traded below
we would go back not to the 40 trading
days because there's no lower low
the next lower low or discount PD array
exists in the 60-day look back
and those levels are noted respectively
the last 40 trading days you can see the
range is defined by the highest high and
the lowest low in the last 20 trading
days
so when we look at the last 20 trading
what we do is we think in terms of the
PD array Matrix
now what I've done here is I've overlaid
the actual
Matrix
now you don't need to have this much
information or try to have this in your
price action but I'm giving you a
graphic depiction on how I internalize
and I interpret price action
so if we see where price is right now at
Friday's close of the week of this
recording
market price is defined as Friday's
close and we would be looking at the
highest high and the lowest low in the
last 20 trading days
that's our first look back period of 20
trading days
we start looking for bearish mitigation
blocks in the premium range a bearish
breaker liquidity void fair value Gap
bearish order block rejection blocks and
or on Old high or old low
the low market price we identify any
bullish mitigation blocks
a bullish breaker
liquidity void
a fair value Gap bullish order block
rejection block
or an old low and or high
with that in mind
what I've noted is in the last 20
trading days these are the respective
premium and discount PD arrays in the
last 20 trading days
working our way from the top down we
have an old High
a rejection block
a bearish order block mean threshold
that's the three of candles the ranges
of their bodies highs high and lowest
low in terms of the bodies not the wicks
that's the mean threshold or Midway
point
then we have the bearish order block
and then we trade down into the discount
area we see a bullish order block
bullish order box mean threshold
the rejection block and then finally the
old blow
if we move down into a four hour chart
you can see how these PD arrays give you
much more detail you can start to see
how price moves from one PD array to the
next
the market for the Australian dollar
made a higher high on Tuesday
failed to make a higher high and trade
higher into a monthly range as I had
expected in my analysis
you're going to learn that having these
understandings of short-term Trading
it's not required for you to know all
the time exactly where the Market's
going to go if you fail in your analysis
it'll give you an immediate reason to
maybe reverse your analysis and take the
trades in the opposite direction
this was the case this week in our
mentorship
originally I was long or bullish on the
Australian dollar but the expectation of
a larger price move
it failed to do so on Tuesday
once Tuesday broke down
as you'll see in the later slides in
this presentation we have a lot more
analysis to suggest the price was going
to trade down and close the liquidity
void
now again this is a four hour chart so
if we saw price fail on Tuesday
and break down lower during Tuesday
we start looking for bearish ideas
inside of the premium range so we look
for all the premium PD arrays to start
keying off all potential cell scenarios
when we sell short
on The Daily PD arrays in the premium
range we would be looking for a lesser
time frame to Target our exit
that would be in the form of a four hour
or one hour chart
the four hour here shows a clear
liquidity void as outlined here
price also trades back up into a
mitigation and breaker
trades up to an Institutional price
level 76.80
and while we're not necessarily needing
the actual high of the week we can still
take participation in the market move
because we understand that the shift in
order flow has now been moved to bearish
so we were looking for
discount PD arrays
the low Market action
at 76.80 we were in the premium range
the void closes and takes us into the
discount range notice that in the Shaded
green area
if we further refine this into the days
of the week on a four hour chart you can
see how this clearly came down and
closed in the liquidity void
right to the PIP
if we add our Market maker manipulation
template forming the high of the week on
Tuesday trading at an old monthly weekly
and or daily High liquidity pool
that's what we saw on Tuesday it traded
slightly above Monday's high
rejected it once Tuesday broke down
the likelihood that we would see lower
prices was in effect why I said we could
start looking for shorts at 76.80 with
the objective of 7605 as our downside
objective
that was framed as we see on our Market
maker
manipulation template the discount
Market PD array is going to be used on a
time frame lesser than the premium
liquidity pool that was used so the
daily
high on Monday was violated on Tuesday
that's a liquidity pool raid
on a daily High
if that's the context we're going to
drop down to a four hour and or a one
hour chart
to look for a discount PD array
it comes in the form of liquidity void
taking us down into 7605 was our
objective
everything tied together we get a
combination of
elements of time and price
blending
and using the market maker manipulation
templates in accordance to our market
profiles that we used and learned in
lesson two
we get a symmetry in the marketplace
that would otherwise probably Escape
everyone else
so hopefully this is
an example
and understanding and using an example
we used
in live analysis this week
while we were initially wrong and our
expectation of a higher breakout on
Aussie dollar
that failure swing on Tuesday
gave us Insight on how we can change
gears and get short on Aussie dollar
even while it traded in sympathy with
the weaker dollar which isn't typical
blending the two time and price it gives
us the ability to work within the same
parameters that the algorithm will at
the interbank level
hopefully this has been insightful to
you we'll build more on these ideas as
we go through and trade with more
insights using the ifta data ranges and
PD array Matrix