foreign
welcome back this is lesson 1.4 defining
open float liquidity pools
okay we're gonna be looking at the
Canadian dollar for this teaching
okay we should look at here's a chart of
the Canadian dollar Futures chart
this is the March delivery contract for
Canadian dollar
foreign
CAD pair daily chart
when we're looking at price
what we like to do is identify on a
higher time frame where are the
liquidity pools for the large funds
because the liquidity pools for the
large funds is largely where markets
will want to reach for apart from
long-term fundamentals on a intermediate
term basis that means about three or
four months the large funds open float
the liquidity that's above old highs or
below old lows that will be generally
targeted every quarter
how do we go about identifying which
ones that we should be focusing on right
now we have to incorporate a technique
called open float
now open float is simply just taking the
last three months
or taking the last month and a half to
the next month and a half in the future
encapsulating that time
and basically you're looking at
three months of data
and by doing that what I'll do is give
you a range to look for the highest high
and the lowest low on the daily chart
which will lead you to where the large
funds liquidity pools are above and
below the market price
for example let's assume for a moment
it's August 1st
and we can look back and see where the
highest high was in the last 60 days
over the last 40 days and over the last
20 days prior to August 1st
we can identify also the
lowest low and the highest high
in the first 20 trading days to the
right of August 1st
then 40 days out what's the high and low
of that range
and what's the high and low the range 60
days out from August 1st
when you have that range 60 days look
back in 60 days cast forward that is
open float you want to find the highest
high and the lowest low in between those
two reference points and time
on a near-term basis you can look back
and see what the last 60 days trading
days range was high and low in this case
we can see the lowest here
and the high is here
going forward because we're looking at
the look back period here casting
forward those levels we can see that
eventually during the month of September
those highs that were formed in the
latter portion of July 2016 they were in
fact rated
so the market was drawn to the buy stops
on the fund level at those July highs
extending it out so that we have 60 days
look back and then 60 days cast forward
we can see what the total open float is
with the low end seen here
in the high end seen here
you can see the market did in fact
eventually still dry forward reaching
for the buy stops above
the October highs in 2016.
so if we're looking at the market like
this we can also identify where
significant short term and intermediate
term highs and lows are
if we look at the last range of 20 days
behind us and 20 days casting forward
expecting a new high or a new low to
form
because no one can accurately depict the
future and forecast the future we have
ideal times to look for in terms of
intervals 20 40 and 60 days intervals
looking back for the most obvious buy
stops and sell stops
don't just look for the highest high in
the last 60 days and the lowest low in
the last 60 days behind us or in the
look back phase what we're doing is
we're looking for where's the near-term
high and low in the last 20 days
whereas the short-term high and low in
the last 40 days
and where's the intermediate term high
and low in the last 60 days
that same thing can be done casting
forward
for looking at August 1st 2016
we can cast forward 20 trading days and
expect a range of high and low to form
noting what that high and low is on that
particular range will give us the
liquidity pulls that are on a near-term
basis the easiest ones from the market
to reach for
when we're looking at short-term trades
and day trades that range is going to be
easy and helpful for you for intraday
scalps and day trading
when we look out 40 days
it gives us a little bit more of a
short-term basis for defining the
liquidity pools on the daily chart
looking for the last High and the last
low in the last 40 days that made the
highest high and lowest low buy stocks
would be above that high
and sales tax would be below that low
in LTC 60 days cast forward from the
first of August would give us the
boundary point at which open float ends
in terms of time not in terms of price
but in terms of time so we are
bracketing the market if you will 60
days forward in time
and we're looking at back in the past 60
days so we have 120 trading days
of what would be called open float
we're looking for the highest high and
the lowest low in that range but every
20 days
there's a high and a low form now you're
about to experience a growth spurt one
of the most powerful patterns I like to
trade is the turtle soup which is a
false break above old high and a false
break below an old well
the pattern that I learned about that
was taught in Street smarts book while
I'm not teaching that pattern here out
of respect for the the authors of that
book the idea of a false break above or
below
based on
the turtles trading pattern which is a
long-term trading pattern or system if
you will
that allow long-term trends to pay out
the turtle Traders and turtle Traders if
you know what they are Richard Dennis
put together a hodgepodge of different
walks of life people all from different
walks of life for the purpose of
teaching them
the concept of trading and he used a
long-term trading model
and he taught that buying a breakout
above a 20-day High holding for
long-term trends or selling short a
20-day low holding for long-term trends
while they had a lot of losing trades
their winners were monstrous it's a
trend following system which is what I
teach that the large funds are in the
Foreign Exchange Market they're
long-term Trend following because these
markets are highly linked to
interest rate markets which are under
underlying fundamental drivers for the
marketplace
long-term trends are in fact
fundamentally driven in currencies but
because
the system was based on buying on a
breakout of the 20 period or selling
below 20 period low
that breakout many times was false and
in itself it gives us an edge so if we
look at every interval of 20 trading
days
which is what we have here 20 40 60. you
can encapsulate where the next high and
the next low is on price
and where the highest and lowest low on
each 20-day interval going forward and
looking back you'll know where device
thoughts and sell stops are so that we
can take respective trades based on that
also if you notice that the buy stops
keep getting hit and rarely do the sell
stops keep getting hit by default it
teaches you to institutional order flow
is what
bullish it's looking for higher prices
it keeps drawing on the buy stops above
the marketplace
and conversely if we notice that the
cell stops keep getting ran out and very
rarely do the buy stops keep getting hit
that tells us what for institution order
flow it tells us that the institutional
overflow is bearish so therefore the
banks are making a move on the large
funds liquidity below the lows or
running their sell stops
okay moving forward one month this is
September 2016.
the same thing is done here we've
identified where the ranges in terms of
the look back 60 trading days from the
beginning of September and we have 60
trading Days cast forward we're going to
look for the lowest low in the last 60
trading days
prior to September 1st
and that's this one here
and the highest high
in the last 60 days is here
and again we can keep noticing that the
buy stops above old highs keep getting
taken out you can see that high is
violated also in the month of September
moving forward we have
October 2016.
look back period of 60 days and cast
forward of 60 days we have identified
our range or open float
the highest high in the last 60 trading
days prior to October 1st 2016 is this
High here and the lowest low in our look
back period of 60 days is here so open
float on a large fund level are
referenced by these two price points the
higher it's where the buy stops are and
the lowers where the sell stops are
so they're looking for the buy stops
above the marketplace and they keep
taking those buy stops out notice also
in the first 20 trading days to the
right or the future from October
2012 there's a low that forms in the
Canadian dollar
it takes the lows out in the form of the
bodies of the candles made in the last
portion of September then there's a
rejection that trades higher so we had
one attempt here to clear out the sell
side liquidity
moving forward delineating our
open float range for November 2016. you
can see the look back period
60 trading days maximum 40 trading days
and 20 trading days the highest high and
the lowest low formed in the last 20 and
40 and 60 trading days
the lowest lowest seen here
highest high seen here and again going
forward into November we can see that
that high was in fact taken out on the
upside so they keep taking the buy stops
out and institutional order flow is
indicated as bullish
casting forward one more time into
December 2016.
looking back last 60 trading days prior
to December 1st the lowest low is seen
here sales tax will be resting below
that in a large fund level
and buy stocks will be resting just
above
the high scene here notice also in the
first 20 trading days after December 1st
2016 We Made It Low
and then price ran eventually up into
creating another higher high but blowing
out the buy stops above the November
High
and then ultimately making a run down
into
a lower low
for January
and it forms in the first 40 trading
days after December 1st 2016.
and going forward in time
at the time of this recording
look back period last 60 trading days
you see as low as low as seen here
highest highs seen here we have already
violated the lowest low so we've taken
out the cell stops on a large funds
level and
we can look forward in time for a new
price like that retrace higher and then
see if they want to take it lower
because it's all indicating that they
want to take out the sell side liquidity
now
okay let's take a look at the dollar CAD
pair this is the daily chart and let's
apply some of these ideas on the daily
chart
okay you can see the bodies of the
candles over here
we did Wick down below
130 50 level and retrace a little bit
that's where the cell stops will be
resting oh no
intermediate term basis because we're
looking at a daily time frame
price advancing does trade down there
and takes those sell stops out of the
marketplace and quickly runs away
next area up here the bodies of the
candles you can see that Wicks through
it
five stops will be resting just above
that
large funds
have their buy stops taken out here and
then quickly rejected
and we have a low down here with the
bodies of the candles
sales thoughts will be rested just below
that and we can see the market does in
fact sweep down there and take the sell
side liquidity out
so what makes these false breaks and and
false breaks higher and lower so
lucrative is the fact that we understand
that large traders in the form of a fund
Trader they have their buy stops above
these levels and they have their sell
stops below these levels
every 20 trading days there's going to
be a new liquidity pool formed
it's going to be on the buy side and on
the sell side you just have to identify
where those ranges are in respective
terms to where the most obvious swing
high and swing low is formed and then
frame that going forward whereas the
next 20 days high and low whereas the
next 20 days high and low keep going out
but looking back in the last 60 days and
looking forward into the future 60 days
gives us the range for open float the
highest high and the lowest low in that
range of 120 days that's what the large
fund macro is in other words we're there
aiming for the large fund buy stops or
sell stops they're going to be derived
at looking at where the range high and
low is on the last 120 days 60 days
backwards
in time and with the next high and low
if it makes a higher high in the next
new 60 trading days
we don't know where that high is going
to be in in the future we don't know if
it's going to create a higher high or if
it's going to make a lower low
we just monitor as price creates new
price swings on highs and lows
where are we in relative terms to the
last 60 trading days are we making a
higher high
then the the highest high or are we
making a lower low in the lowest low in
the last 60 days
and we look forward 60 trading days into
the future and we keep moving that basis
forward each new month we're looking for
and we're we'll eventually arrive at the
institution order Flow by default you
can see where they're running the market
they're taking out buy stops
continuously rarely if ever taking out
cell stops what's telling you do they
want to press the market higher they
keep grinding against those large funds
so
if it's seen as an opposite where we
keep seeing the sell stops keep getting
ran out and very real the buy stocks get
taken out institutional order flow is
bearish so therefore as long as we
continuously see the market making new
lows
we keep watching that range of the last
60 days and where are we in relationship
to that are we above it or below it if
we're above it we have to continuously
keep seeing buy stops get taken out if
you start seeing cell stops get taken
out we're probably making a quarterly
shift and the reverse is said if we're
below the last 60 days low
and if we're below that last 60 days low
we're really oversold we're in a deep
discount market and if we start seeing
buy stops getting hit and very rarely
new we now see cell stops getting hit
we're probably performing a market
structure shift or quarterly shift for
a new Direction in the marketplace
and you can see that in fact is what
happens here with the Canadian dollar
so let's take this information and go
back to the Futures Market
and take a look at some things
now obviously this is going to be the
price action of the Futures Contract
which is going to be inverted from what
we see when we're studying the dollar
Index versus the Canadian dollar because
that pair starts with the US dollar
first that means when that market is
going higher as a pair that means the
dollar strong in Canadian dollars weak
if the dollar cad's going
lower that means the dollar Index is
weak and the Canadian dollar is
strengthening
well in this case
we are looking at the Futures Contract
of Canadian dollar and I want you to
look at the same reference points we
just showed in the previous slide
we're just going to do the opposite in
the Futures Market
you see the bodies of the candles being
ran out here in December
and then quickly rejected
we can see the bodies of the candle
made in November gets rated in December
and quickly Rejects and it runs for what
the bodies of the candles here we're
running the old high out where buy
stocks will be resting
and that's where we're at presently but
prior to that big run up
off of that 73
50 73 65 level
take a look at this right here
I gave you a teaching with the
Australian dollar and I showed you how
we can use these quarterly shifts to
take place
and open interest
off of support resistance ideas on a
higher time frame basis
when we're looking at higher time frame
charts we are identifying Clues and
seeking
evidences that we can see that they are
about to make a move on one side of the
marketplace we understand what's making
that short-term fluctuation could be
largely attributed to just running the
stops on funds
large fund traders buy stops and sell
stops but it's not always that the
markets are moving based on very very
long-term fundamentals and as it relates
to higher time frame charts but every
three months there can be a manipulative
phase in the marketplace that still can
be a catalyst for us to be a Trader
taking high probability entries
and looking for high probability exit
points and by looking at where the
logical fund level traders buy stocks
and sell stocks would be and looking for
evidence is that the market is showing
participation by smart money
I.E the banks if the Market's trading
down to a support level at 73.80 to 7360
in that range
we have a clue here that once the market
start trading lower from the 7 500 to
74.60 74 40 level to 7400 and then once
we got below 73.80 level by that point
open interest had already tanked you can
see clearly here that's a huge drop it's
a massive drop
you only need a 15 the decrease to have
a massive uh indication that there's big
huge
institutional sponsorship behind the
move that you're expecting if open
interest is declining what they're
saying to us is they are not willing to
be
offering sell side liquidity to buyers
they don't want that so they're scaring
those individuals by dropping the market
really quickly and open interest
declines rapidly open interest only
declines as an Evidence
that the smart money are not wanting to
be heavily short high open interest is a
indication that there's a big massive
liquidity uh program that's been offered
for buyers the bank is offering that as
risk they're holding the risk on that
but if open interest declines while the
market drops off precipitously and it
goes into a support level because look
at what's happening in November 2016.
the Canadian dollars Futures Contract it
rallied from around 73.80 up to 76.40
which is a very respectable range
price comes back down runs the bodies of
the candles that was formed as a low in
November 2016.
price comes down again looking for
another shift in the marketplace
it runs out the sell stops below the
7380 level with an old low remember we
look back in
higher time frame institution order flow
reference points
liquidity pools water blocks fair value
gaps equilibrium
all those price points we used and
learned in September we look for those
in our higher time frame charts
we're seeing a liquidity pool in the
form of a cell stop
resting around 73.80 they make that run
and on low open interest at a support
level they are indicating that it's
going to go up higher if the Futures
Contract for the Canadian dollar marks
contract delivery is indicating that
there is very low open interest at a
support level at a time when the stops
have been running out below the
marketplace
that's indicating what potential
strength and you can see the price
action that transpired after that rather
explosive price move
looking for a move from 73.80 all the
way up to 76.80
so 300 Pips move up
from one specific level that could be
easily derived by looking at the
evidences that we've shown here in this
teaching
using open float
casting forward 60 days casting forward
40 days casting forward 20 days notice
also every 20 trading days
the high and the low becomes very
obvious you can start circling these as
you create new highs every time there's
a new higher high
note that and then wait for the price to
come back down to an old 20-day low
study that every 20-day High every
20-day low is going to have buy stocks
and sell sauce resting above the highs
and below the lows if you do this as an
exercise going forward you'll see
clearly what side of the marketplace
it's seeking if it keeps taking out the
buy stops or the highs the market is
doing what it's moving higher it means
institutional overflow is on the buy
side you don't want to be selling short
in those conditions
if the market is taking out the sell
side liquidity continuously and rarely
ever taking out the highs of the uh
price action that means that
institutional overflow is indicated
lower and you want to focus primarily on
being short
until we get an obvious change in
Direction how would that happen well if
you go and you start trading to the
lowest low in the last 60 days
well we're probably going to be very
very deeply uh oversold and we're going
to be in deep discount even if the price
only bounces a little bit on a higher
time frame like this it can bounce
you know a great deal it could be over
150 200 Pips sometimes and then
eventually roll over and continuous uh
fashion keep going lower you don't want
to be caught on the wrong side of the
marketplace trading on a hard time frame
chart and not see the evidences that
it's given you and trade accordingly you
have to have all these things in mind
looking for where the liquidity is and
the easiest way to do it
and to make all this very simple because
it could be very easily complicated and
I'm sure probably complicated in many of
your minds
what you're looking for is a revolving
continuous range of 120 days
and you whatever day you're looking at
you look back 60 and you look forward
60. so there's 120 days there and you're
constantly monitoring where's the
highest high and the lowest low in those
in that range
and that's where the buy stops and the
sell stocks are going to be on a large
fund level
the
look back phase is where the hard stops
are going to be
that means where the actual buys and
sell stops are going to be aboggan oil
high and Below an old low
but if we are looking forward studying
new price action as it occurs
you need to be mindful of where you are
in the last 60 days range are we near a
high or are we near a low
and that's also going to be indicative
of where we see the next quarterly shift
if it's going to be continuously moving
higher and higher and higher it keeps
taking out buy stops eventually
unless you're in a one-sided parabolic
price move which we'll teach about
uh generally you don't see too many of
those uh the market generally moves from
range to range and using this concept it
will be very beneficial to you because
you can see where the near turn that
means to 20 period high and low in terms
of trading days and I'll say that again
the next near-term move is going to run
on the near-term buy stops or sell stops
that means the last 20 days range what's
the highest high and the lowest low
that's the near term open float
the short-term open float is what's the
highest high and the lowest loan will
last 40 trading days
and the intermediate term open float is
going to be the highest high and lowest
low in the last 60 days
knowing where you are in that range and
what side of the marketplace keeps
getting taken out will give you Clues as
to what the next shift in price is going
to be once it starts to break down you
know you're going to have a significant
price move and you can trade that
accordingly even on a daily time frame
where you don't have to go down to a
lower time frame for entry you can
execute purely off of the daily chart
so we're going to build on these ideas
as we go through the rest of January
until next time this concludes this
teaching wish good luck in good Trading