welcome back folks this is lesson 1.5
defining institutional swing points
okay we're going to be talking about
institutional swing points now
you've heard me teach
in many instances where the
swing high swing low forms in the price
action swing high being a high with a
lower high to the left of it and a lower
high to the right of it just a three
consecutive three candle or three bar
pattern
one with a high with
two lower highs to the
either side of it
and then obviously the same thing would
be said just in opposite terms for a
swing low one candle with a higher
candle to the left of it and a higher
candle to the right of it
that's a swing low that's what i learned
from my mentor larry williams pretty
simple easy pattern
there's been a lot of patterns i've come
across through my development as a
trader some of them
rather elaborate they really didn't mean
too much in terms of future
prognostication but nonetheless they
were fun to read about initially got my
hopes up but didn't really deliver
anything
i'm not talking about swing points in
that
degree here
i want you to think about institutional
swing points
in terms of
concept in other words what's going on
behind the scenes i don't want to draw
any charts up i don't want to pull any
examples up i want you to think about it
conceptually because we're going to be
building on these ideas
i want you to understand that there's
really only two forms of
swing points in the marketplace as it
relates to institutional trading
it's in the form of a stop run or a
failure swing
that's it there's nothing else
so we're going to talk about the two
forms of swing points and we're going to
talk about the contrasting differences
between
the two and what makes them
opportunities for us as traders and how
we can see the characteristics of both
the first one we're looking at here
is
essentially the breaker
okay this is a breaker where the market
will generally make a higher high
fail then break down and have a
rejection at the highs
many times this is a very surprising and
deflating pattern for some traders and
everyone's experienced at some time in
their development where they've bought
a specific price point with the
expectation it's going to go higher
initially does and then once it makes
that new higher high it breaks lower
aggressively and you probably experience
it as well where you market you sell a
low
and it starts to break lower you feel
good about the trade now sudden just by
moving below a previous low a little bit
explodes on the upside and now you're
trapped or stopped out
this pattern in my opinion is the most
powerful the most dynamic the most
significant price pattern you need to
learn conceptually
and you understand some of the
characteristics about where it forms
but
what generally happens is
when you have a selling
scenario the market will generally make
a rally up
to an area of old resistance now that
resistance can come in the form of how
we interpret resistance as a bare
shoulder block it could be a breaker
or mitigation block
it could be an old low it's returning to
or it could be you know high it's
returning to
and it may fall short just by a few pips
or points initially and start to trade
lower
and retail traders and like myself when
i first started i thought that this was
most likely going to be when the market
would break down aggressively and start
trading lower and i could be
expecting lower prices well
the market makes one more pass higher
driving out that short term high it
creates and it spooks the marketplace
and it upsets those traders that are
already short
and ultimately goes to the level at
which you would have expected it to
trade to the first time which is that a
resistance level or in this case it
could be a bearish order block for us or
could close in a gap
but when we see price hovering just
below a key institutional reference
point like we learned in september which
are the bearish order blocks bullshore
blocks liquidity voids fair value gaps
when we see these things in our charts
we anticipate price trading to them
to the pip or
into them a little bit like as it were
for a order block
the
the idea is once you see
the level and these levels are going to
be delineated with the blue lines
uh the diagram on the left represents a
selling opportunity or where we expect
some measure of resistance
that could be a bearish order block uh
the short-term high that forms prior to
that
higher high
that's what gets many traders caught
and if you understand order blocks
many times the bearish order block is
just above that it didn't it didn't
trade to it or it leaves a little bit of
a fair value gap
and price comes up and just falls short
of filling it in
and then finally drives up and closes
that little bit of a range in that's
when you get this
breaker
swing point
now why is it a breaker
the fact that it creates that little
short term low in between the higher
high and the previous high
for the sell side diagram on the left
when the market breaks down and takes
out that short term low
prior to the new high
that is indicating that the market has
broke
those individuals that were initially
short
and now they're trapped
so when that move takes place what
you're seeing is
the opportunity for the marketplace to
move aggressively away from the level
it was an initial fake out
and then the buy stop sometimes also are
what's targeted so it could be a order
block it could be a
fair value gap it could be a liquidity
void getting closed in it didn't get
closed the initial time and then
searched up the second leg up
many instances
by looking at your charts you'll have a
plethora of examples and
gaining experience by looking at
hindsight examples of how that occurs
the one of the benefits of looking at
intraday charts not that we're going to
be talking about intraday in this
month but when we practice with intraday
charts it gives us a lot of
examples of where these types of events
take place because this very pattern
here
this materializes every single day it
materializes every single day and in
every single pair it's there you have to
study every single time frame and see
how this pattern manifests itself
when the bias of being bullish
the market diagram here that we have on
the right hand side where the cell stops
are ran out below a short-term low once
it hits the level or short falls short
of a support level the market many times
will drive lower and go right into that
level
to me i love this pattern because number
one i can see when it's forming okay i
can see when it's just falling short of
a level and where we're going to
anticipate one more drive lower or in
this case it could be a drive higher on
the bullish side but when we look at
price
it's important to have the key levels or
the institutional reference points that
we taught in september
those ideas
have to already be on your chart if you
don't see them
already outlined
you're not going to be able to
capitalize on the opportunities that
these patterns present themselves with
so if we see cell stops being ran out or
if we see a fair value gap below the
marketplace or a liquidity void that
didn't initially fill in the first pass
lower and then dries lower then closes
it in
all those
scenarios can lend well to this pattern
by itself
conceptually it doesn't do you any good
just hearing me talk about it so you
have to go into the charts and literally
pull out examples where a short-term
high was passed through just a little
short period time right after that and
then it creates that re rejection or
reversal high
same thing is said for the
buy side of the uh the breaker pattern
these swing points if you look at them
they many times offer
outstanding entry points what makes them
scary is the fact that
the number one question i get about them
is how do you know
if you're going to see it reverse if you
sell above the previous high
and that comes by experience with
trusting the institutional reference
points that we taught in september and
throughout all the free tutorials order
blocks
breakers mitigation blocks liquidity
voids and now you've learned
fair value gaps
so
having these ideas in your chart you'll
be able to anticipate
these patterns unfolding before they
actually do
if you don't have the levels on your
chart
you're going to be surprised by these
things but that's okay i already know
that most of you aren't going to be able
to see this pattern readily before that
happens so what can you do with it once
you see the pattern break down
in the example on the left-hand side for
our
bearish swing point in the form of a
bearish breaker
when that high is broken and it takes
out that short-term loan between
that market structure shift breaking
point
that becomes your trigger
if price ever comes back up to that
level you can be a seller
now the beautiful thing is
we already have a stop run
on this pattern
now think institutionally
there was a short-term high
right here
the market comes down creates a
short-term low and it rallies up taking
out this short-term high
blowing out the buy stops closing in a
liquidity void that didn't get filled in
completely when this first pass came up
or it came into a bearish order block
maybe it fell short of the various order
block here or maybe this is just a
simply an old
high
and price comes right back above the old
high and then rejects and trades lower
you don't have to fear this pattern here
if you can't if you don't have the
confidence to get in here and sell that
idea
like an institutional trader would go
right in there and sell it rate as it
trades through it
wait for it to break down if it takes
out that short term low when market
trades back up to that trigger point
right here
that's when you would be looking to be a
seller
the wonderful thing again is about this
pattern is we already have the stop run
so if it's already
stopped out those individuals here
there's no reason for it to want to come
back up and trade back in there because
these traders are already knocked out
so we can be a seller here with a great
deal of confidence that our stop loss
could actually be
above this high
or rate at that high the likelihood of
coming back up there after an aggressive
breakdown
once a level has already been arrived at
discerning that there has been an
expectation of the market being bearish
if we see evidence is that we've already
seen a stop run here
if we've seen a move start to break
lower at or just below that that
resistance level
this is going to lull traders into
believing and let you know what it feels
like as well you want to see price
action moving in your favor many times
as a new trader so this dropping off
will get traders short where's their buy
stock going to be placed right above
this high so this pass through clears
out that buy side liquidity that they
can engineer new shorts on
so when we see it return back up to this
level here it gives a great deal of
confidence even on a daily time frame
that we're most likely not going to see
price trade back up to this level here
because it's already done its job of
knocking out those players that are
already short they don't want to give
them an opportunity to get a good price
in a short they've already done that
themselves by knocking out the initial
bears
this breaking point here we want to be
selling at that point right there
so when we look at price we're looking
for this pattern for ourselves
this is the highest most probable
condition to be a short seller in the
marketplace because it has a built-in
advantage even though it's the most
fearful thing for you right now you
don't want to sell above an old high
because you haven't practiced enough you
haven't seen the effects of looking at
institutional order flow on a higher
time frame or any other time frame for
that matter that frames the support
ideas around these particular
reads on stops
the same thing is said just in opposite
terms for when you're looking to be a
buyer you want to see a short term low
form at or just above a key support
level it could be a bullish order block
it could be a liquidity void that hadn't
filled in on this pass here that does
here
it could be an old load it just simply
runs down below
if it's an old low there is no limit to
time between this low and the new load
it forms
okay and that re in that regards there's
no there's no time limit like you can
look at an old low here and it could be
six months and then finally it trades
down below that low and then it runs
that's still the same pattern here okay
ideally you want to see something that
has just recently created a low came
back a little bit a few days maybe a
week and then it dries one more time
through it and hits your bullish
institutional reference point it could
be again
trading down to an old high or it could
be a lower low it trades down but the
main thing is you want to see a low
that makes no real sense stopping there
and giving a little tiny little bounce
and then expect that drive lower closing
in on that real level you're having on
your chart which constitutes support
just like we mentioned over here the
opposites said here
any buyers over here on this little pop
is going to have their protective cell
stop just below that low
we want to think institutionally about
accumulating those sell stops
so if they're going to sell it to us
we're going to be a buyer and we're
going to be buying a deep discount with
the expectation now here's the thing you
want to see an immediate response away
from that level you don't want to see it
trade down below this low
and hang around for a while okay you
don't want to see that
the problem you're going to encounter is
because we're trading on a daily time
frame as position traders we're gonna
have to wait a long time sometimes
for
that confirmation it may it may require
the whole entire daily range before the
daily candle creates the wick
here so this many times will become the
wick
the market will trade down
make that low here and then wick away
from that low and then you'll see what
many people get excited about as a
hammer or
some kind of a doji okay and i'm not
teaching classical if you want to call
it that candlestick patterns but the
idea is
candlestick traders trade the
candlesticks that have formed
institutional traders we trade it when
it's a bold face candle before it
becomes that that wick or that hammer or
doji
it takes a great deal of confidence to
be buying down here below an old low
whereas retail traders they all have
reasons to justify why something should
be done after some form of confirmation
if you're demanding confirmation you're
not going to get this entry down here
but you can get a favorable entry point
by waiting for a market structure shift
here
so when the market structure shifts on
the bullish side here all eyes go back
to this reference point here
we're not worried about coming back down
here again we don't care about that
we're worried just simply for a return
to this level here
so again the same mindset we said about
the sell side or bearish breaker on
swing point
this
we know this has already been arrayed on
cell stops
there's no expectation or reason to
believe that the market needs to come
back down into this level again because
it's already done its work it's cleared
out the sell stops and the market is
quickly rejected
the market if it does give you an
opportunity to come back down into
this
breaking point
we can be a buyer here
with the exception
that there may be a bullish order block
over here it doesn't have to come back
down to this level just like it doesn't
have to come all the way back up to this
level it could just come right back up
to an area over here where there would
be another order block to trade off of
depending on how aggressive
the selling was away from this high or
where the buying was in terms of
magnitude you may never get that return
back down to this price point it may
just keep on screaming higher and that's
sometimes going to happen and that's
going to be a missed opportunity but i
want you to think about the marketplace
in two
conceptual ways as it relates to swing
points
you have a breaker swing point
which is what we're describing here and
i'm giving you the classification of it
and i'm teaching this one first because
this is the one i trade predominantly
because it's based around
the pattern i like to trade which is the
turtle suit
a false break above an old high
rejection and quickly it moves away and
if i don't get the entry off like i want
to
it i always give it an opportunity to
get back in here so it's like a
two-chance setup
and many times you don't get two second
chances in trading you know you either
miss it and you never get it again or
you take it you lose money and here
this pattern is in my opinion the best
pattern in in market structure when
you're looking for uh
institutional evidences to what should
be taking place in price when you see
this pattern unfold and you learn to
anticipate it you're going to have the
highest probable entries for all your
setups because you're actually entering
at the lowest possible point for buys
and you're selling at the highest
possible point for sales
and yes it takes a great deal of
conviction to do that but it also
doesn't demand it
you can wait for this pattern to give it
to you
by waiting for the break above the
market structure here
which
is ironic because
you don't
get that same forgivingness
with the next pattern we're going to
talk about which is the failure swing
all right this is the failure swings is
the second
form of institutional swing points again
i understand
that you know
you probably understand this a little
bit but i'm giving you some additional
points because if we're going to start
breaking the market down into modular
form where we can go in and start
utilizing these things not just speak
about them in broad terms
i want you to narrow your focus to only
two ways of viewing the marketplace when
it turns
we already mentioned the breaker swing
point and now we're talking about the
failure swing
the failure swing is when you identify
when there is a
resistance level and it trades through
it
breaks down
and comes back and retests it
it can't make another pass through
now this level could be up here it could
have been just touching it here
and then failed to make another pass to
it it's the same thing in same
conditions but we're focusing primarily
on is the ability for the market to get
back to this high and make a higher high
or the fact that it makes a failure
swing
we don't ever know with great deal of
conviction if we're gonna get the
breaker set up
so while this may be unfolding we could
be anticipating this high being taken
out to be a seller up here
but many times what will happen is the
market will come up and fall short
and then break lower
and that's a missed opportunity we can't
be a seller at a high price
we may have may have even second guessed
this entry as a short but we are
demanding a breaker to occur
which would be selling above this old
high but it doesn't give it to you here
that would be a missed opportunity but
it doesn't mean there's no trading
opportunity
same thing can be said for the buy side
we have a support level down here the
market trades down into it may trade
through it or the blue line representing
our support level could be down here
right at the low it's not important as
it relates to
where the actual level is what we're
anticipating is is the market's gonna
probably make another pass through and
retest this low
again we're aiming for and trying to get
breaker swing points if we don't get the
breaker swing point that's not a problem
we have an opportunity to trade off of
this pattern as well
if we get the buy
set up like this and it retraces off of
the the level that we are anticipating
seeing support at
and it comes back and starts to come
back down and fails and makes one more
pass up if it takes out this short term
high
or on the sell side takes out this short
term low
we have another
opportunity
because what we have here is the
market's already shown a willingness to
do what it's run an area of liquidity
out
it's trap traders above here
and traders below here so sellers are
stuck down here
and buyers are stuck up here
they're not giving them an opportunity
to get out
they're quickly repricing here
so now when we understand that think
like an institutional trader
if you know
you have
a guy on the hook or a fund on the hook
up here
he's he's long now
if you can
reprice the market and go lower with it
leave them holding the bag up here
or vice versa they sold on some weakness
down here because again think like those
turtle traders long-term position
traders they're selling on a breakout
they're selling below 20 period lows and
buying above 20 period highs
so if we can see this phenomenon taking
place where they've moved away from a
low aggressively came down but failed to
make a low and then broke through a
short-term high
in an area where we anticipate
bullishness on an institutional basis
we have to sit back and simply just wait
because we'll understand that this
movement could have been moved into a
order block that's bullish this could be
a bearish order block this could be a
move that goes into a old high to run
out buy stops here
it could be an older hot you know height
is not being shown in this diagram just
like this could be an older low
you know to the left of the truck that
wouldn't be shown in this diagram but
we're seeing the evidences that they've
already did the manipulation down here
we don't know that for certain until
we see the retracement back up
here so all this retracement here
this is a gray area we don't know for
certain if this is going to stop here or
if it's going to continue up
and give us a break or swing point
just like we don't know that there's
going to be a continuation to go lower
to have a
breaker swing point for buys here we
don't know if it's going to go down
below that low i never know that for
certain i never know that i anticipated
the most optimal entry i'm looking for
that scenario but it may not give it to
me so if it doesn't
and it starts to run the other way i'm
just simply going to put my eye sight
right here for the buy and here for the
cell
if i can't get a retracement back here
or on an idea for a short
if i don't see anything to justify a
short here and sometimes that occurs
sometimes i just you know i don't get it
right and i'm human just like anybody
else will if i can't get a short off
there and i don't have strong
convictions to sell there it's no
problem i'm going to just simply wait
for that
swing point right here to be violated
and then i'm going to be aiming for this
level right there that's where i'll sell
now
if i'm going to sell at this level here
i can have great confidence that myself
can be protected with a buy stop right
above this short-term high because it's
in inside this area at which they had
already ran the stops out on the form of
buy stops so if my buy stop is here now
they're not going to come back up here
and give these opportunity to get off
they're not going to let them out
so i can be a seller here with my stop
here and look for lower prices
same way can the same thing can be said
here
if i don't know with great deal of
conviction that this is a good buy
or i miss it and it takes off it's no
problem i'm waiting for this little
swing point here to be broken
once that high is broken
i can wait for price to come back down
to this level right here
when this level is retreated to down
here
i can be a buyer with a great deal of
confidence that my stop loss can be
placed just below this low because it's
going to be in an area where they had
already ran the cell stops
now
this is probably very 101 ict okay but i
want you to come away with this idea
that the institutions
go into the marketplace to trap
or they go into knock off that's what
they do
they are in the business of knocking the
funds out when they're going to be
correct
and they'd like to put them in on the
wrong side when they have pending orders
that are allow them to be offside for
instance in this case here
funds could have buy stops here with the
expectation if it goes out they're
thinking this could be a long-term trend
filing buy program where they can hold
on to it for many months
the institutions will drive the price up
there
take those buy stops in but when those
buy stocks become market orders to buy
they're selling
with the expectation they're going to
reprice aggressively and then go short
i may read it wrong just like you're
going to read it wrong i may be looking
for a breaker scenario up here where it
makes a pass above this old high i may
be looking to sell
this old high on turtle suit it may
never give it to me
and i may not be astute enough watching
price to see this is the scenario to
really be selling at
so if i miss it
just like you're going to miss it too
and you see this breakdown in here no
problem wait for it to trade back up to
this level here and that's where your
shorts going to be and your your
position is going to be protected with a
stop loss right above this high it's
going to be in an area where it's
already been traded to
with manipulation
buy stops have already been violated
here they're not going to come back up
to take those out if it does you're
probably wrong anyway you want to be out
same thing is said over here just in
opposite terms
when the market comes down here and
rejects you you may not see that
initially as a rejection you may
anticipate one more pass lower to get
that ideal buy
and it doesn't do it and if you can't
get this off as a long
and it starts to take off no problem you
go right back to this price point here
and wait for it to come back down you
can be a trader that takes a long
position there with your stop-loss right
here
again with the expectation that if your
stop loss is already below this low
you're in an area where they already ran
out sell stops so there's no reason for
them to come back down there again
especially if they have a very dynamic
price response here
the the magnitude of which they move
away here
and the magnitude at which they move
away here indicates that they have
already trapped a sizable
number of orders net long here
and seismo orders that are net short
here they're not going to want to let
them off
and if they are short
how can they get out of their short
position if they aggressively reprice
higher
they're going to collapse their trade by
doing what buying it back they're going
to reprice quickly so that way they
force them to buy back at a higher price
where they can now start scaling off
their position that they bought down
here and down here
at a net profit
and the opposites being said here where
they could quickly reprice here
smart money sells here and sells here so
if price aggressively moves lower
those that are
along in this point here they're going
to want to collapse their trade and they
have to sell it so they're not going to
sell it down here
where smart money can buy it back after
being short from this point here
so when we look at price
i want you to think again in two
institutional swing point theories
you have a breaker which is the ideal
most optimal trade entry pattern there
is in the marketplace because it's
absolutely the deepest discount buy
and the absolute most premium to sell
it's scary to do it it's absolutely
uncomfortable when you first start doing
it and i i know what that feels like
it's scary but that's the whole purpose
of getting into a demo account where you
learn to do those types of things you
cannot learn it doing with live money
that's all part of this mentorship you
have to be practicing in a demo where
you can literally go in there and step
in front of the marketplace once it
rolls into a new high
sell it
get that responsiveness of seeing what
happens in price sometimes it'll keep on
going okay no problem you're gonna be
wrong but you're gonna know right away
that you're wrong and you don't have a
hundred pip stop on you can have a
relatively
modest stop one
point is
when you're right you get immediate
feedback and it's very encouraging it's
confidence building and usually if you
enter on the right side and you're
selling an old high
it's amazing because you'll see how fast
the market tanks
if you buy an old low and you're doing
it on a breaker setup and it's a swing
point in the form of a breaker you're
going to be able to see dynamic rallies
just like that take off and it would
they'll be explosive
so
don't think in terms of classical char
patterns like head and shoulders or
think in terms of uh
bear flags and bull flags things like
that
only try to convince yourself that
there's only two real ways the market's
going to turn around it's going to be on
a breaker where they run stops or it's
going to be a failure swing both of them
are indicating a manipulation but they
both have to be used slightly different
the first one being the breaker swing
point that is the ideal one you want to
be looking for that scenario all the
time on any time frame not just a daily
chart but any time frame
but if you can't get the breaker
don't fear
or be upset about missing that move
because it still gives you the
opportunity to get in there because
they're only going to turn the market
one of these ways that's it and nothing
else happens in price
i challenge you to go in and show me
something where that doesn't do this
because i can tell you it's either a
breaker or it's a fair swing every
single time it's never anything else so
you're you're limited it's really just
two conditions in the marketplace if
you're going to be a seller how are you
going to be a seller you're going to be
selling it at ohi or you're going to be
selling it on a retracement back to a
break in market structure that's it
if you're going to be a buyer are you
going to be buying an old low
or are you going to be buying on a
return or retracement back to a market
structure break to be a buyer at support
there
it's just that simple nothing else can
happen there's no there's not 50 000
patterns to be looking for there's not
all these different candlestick patterns
to memorize okay new dark clouds
covering this and no inverted hammer
that it's just simply understanding
where are the orders
relative to old institutional order flow
reference points key support resistance
on high time frames
how is the market behaving at that level
did was it able to pass through it and
did it reject
if it went up to it fell short it's
probably going to make one more pass
higher and it might give you that
breaker entry
if it doesn't give you a breaker inch
and it gives you a fair swing this is
how you trade them
but there's nothing you need to worry
about
in a demo account while you're teaching
yourself if you're if you're worrying
about rushing to get in with live money
if you don't know the characteristics
between these two swing point theories
you're going to hurt yourself you're
going to be frustrated you're not going
to be able to focus and you're going to
end up chasing price or blowing your
account and then you're gonna be
frustrated you know or taking taken
completely out of the marketplace where
you can't fulfill your dreams as a
trader
so hopefully this has been insightful to
you guys i'm gonna wish you a good luck
and good trading i'll talk to you again
in the next lesson