okay folks we are looking at
lesson 1.2 of the long-term analysis
implementing macro analysis quarterly
shifts and open float
okay we're going to be talking about
open float on this teaching
okay
the quarterly shift
with open float
and let's first start by defining what
is
open
float the open float is the current open
interest above and below current market
price
now this is going to be in the form of
pending buy orders in other words buy
stops that are resting above old highs
or it could be just resting above market
price doesn't have to be old highs
and
sell orders
it could be
below the market price by very little
bit in terms of pips or could be below
significant lows
there are
open interest in the form of
sell stops for entry orders
and sell stops for collapsing long
positions
and there are buy stops to get along and
then buy stops to protect short
positions
all of those
are equating to
open float
it's the total open interest of the
players that are in
the market now or hope to be
depending on where price goes relative
to those standing orders
okay when open float is used
to determine buy side liquidity
shorts use protective buy stops above
the last bearish shift
buy stops above short-term highs that
could be in the form of
a weekly high or a monthly high
five stops above the highest high in the
last three months
buy stops above the current six-month
high
and buy stops above the current 12-month
now don't be discouraged by hearing
these numbers because
you can be
really close to
the 12-month high for a long period of
time and never really get to it
um
when i first remember reading about this
type of idea the range for the 12-month
high and low
i thought to myself you know it takes 12
months to get back to that level and
that just shows how myopic my viewpoint
was when i first started trading
the 12 month high and low you can be
inside that range for a long time near
the high or the low it doesn't take that
long to get to it so some of the new
traders that usually
send me emails they ask me how often
do i trade 12-month highs and lows well
you could see a 12-month high or low
pretty quickly yeah it depends on what
the range is in your market
the same thing is said for a six-month
high
the one we're going to focus on here
primarily is the buy stops above the
highest high in the last three months
because we're looking at the quarterly
shift
that's going to be a very
significant price level
where buy stops will be resting
so every three months you want to be
noting where that high is
and there's going to be buy stops
definitely most likely getting targeted
if we have a market structure shift
bush and they're going to be aiming for
those buy stops above the three-month
highs any run buy stops above a
short-term high which is a monthly high
or a weekly high
that's going to give us a strong
prognostication for short-term
volatility as well
when we're looking at the sell side of
the liquidity
long to use protective cell stops under
the last bullish shift
cell stops below short-term lows
that can be in the form of a
weekly low or a monthly low
sell slots below the lowest low in the
last three months
sell slots below the current six-month
low
and finally sell stops below the current
12-month low
now one of the questions i get a lot and
i get it actually sent to me by
email even in the free
members area from my website and on
youtube
when i talk about running stops or if i
talk about turtle soup
false breaks above old highs or false
breaks below no low
the question always comes up is how do i
know
if
the market's going to
stop just right above old high or below
and low and then reverse or
keep on going
and i'm going to teach you
the ideas that i use to get to that
conclusion uh what what gives me the
conviction that builds the confidence
on believing that it's just going to
punch above an old high and probably not
continue going higher not by much in
other words
and then retrace and probably offer a
shorting opportunity the same thing is
re reverse for
buying an old low once it's been
violated
okay
this chart is basically outlining the
same
levels that we had for the quarterly
shifts and every three months the
intervals are shown here
i kept the majority of the vertical
lines off i just use those segments to
delineate what those
reference points would still be relative
to date
and i want you to take a look at this
chart for a minute focus and study on it
and if you can pause the video for a
couple minutes
and note significant price highs and
lows
obviously you can see the one that's
here
and the low down here
so we have two
pretty significant runs above an old
high
and below an old low
i want you to draw your attention to
this
short-term low here
when price traded below that low
that was a break in market structure
okay so we had a
market shift
below that low
and the market continued trading all the
way down until it got to the 105
30 level whenever we see the bearish
shift lower
in price
your eyes need to go right to
the high it just came from
because on a daily chart
that's going to have a lot of liquidity
above it
that liquidity is in the form of
a liquidity pool
for buy stops
the folks that were fortunate enough to
be short
from that old high trading down into 105
their position would have
a run on the buy stops that's residing
holding on to a long term position now
you're probably asking yourself
what retail trader in their right mind
would have a buy stop on a short held on
that long
just to see it kamali back up there and
get knocked out
well
again the market's not trading against
the retail traders it's trading against
the large
liquidity offered by the big funds
because funds are traditionally
long-term trend following traders
these reference points on the daily time
frame are going to be salient to
understanding how open float has a big
impact
on where future price movements are
going to take you
as you can see here after creating a low
of 1.0534
market does in fact have one more market
structure shift
and sends price higher pay attention to
the
quarterly shift markers that we have
here
every three months
there is a significant run on liquidity
the move off of the 105 34 level has a
break in market structure
then you can see the
subsequent retracement back to the short
term high
and then price rallies away
fills in the liquidity void
from october
retraces back down
into the 108 60 level
then rallies again
then ultimately making a run
up for the buy stops above the 1
big figure
that market structure break there
bullishly
is the catalyst that sends the market
higher to make the stops
above 115 big figure
targeted
below that low
there's going to be a large liquidity
pool on the daily time frame again it's
not for retail traders it's going to be
for the large funds
because there was a significant
displacement among many months
about six months or so
the market rallied from
105 34
to 1 115 70s or thereabout
so it's a pretty significant move for
the euro dollar
there's going to be sell side liquidity
or
sell stops in the form of a liquidity
pool
below that low
you see price did in fact sweep down
there and grab that liquidity
neutralizing all the cell stops
so let's take a look at what takes place
and how we can use open float
and help answer some of the confusion
you have about why
the market should be expected to go a
certain level and then retrace or
reverse
and how we can look forward to one side
of the market being predominantly
controlled and staving off any
continuation after the move blows
through an old high or below an old well
as you see here we have a short-term
high here rate before
the market runs through that that
retracement back down into
the 107 50s
the buy stops that would be resting
above that high they're targeted and the
market runs right through that and also
fills in a liquidity void to the left
from october
then the market retraces
deeper and then we have a short-term
height that was created by that rally
above taking the buy stops
out that short-term high eventually gets
ran out as well
making a run on the buy stops that will
be resting above that now what buy
stocks will be wrestling about that
people that want to sell short
every time price makes a
impulse price swing
there's always invariably going to be
orders that want to be selling there and
they're going to be sometimes short
positions
funds will go in and start working their
positions in early
and sometimes they get knocked out and
that's what's happening here many times
you're seeing that same
phenomenon you end up going through it's
just going through
a larger scope in terms of
order size
and finally making a run on that 115 big
figure
clearing out the buy stops above the
previous october high
now i'm going to draw your attention to
how do you know when the market's going
to reach for one side of the liquidity
or the other
notice while the market was trading from
the low
at
105.34
all the way up to 115 big figure
there wasn't any significant move on
sell stops at all
they were driving price up to take the
liquidity out at 115.
once that liquidity was taken out in the
form of the buy stop raid at 115 big
figure
the market broke down and created a
violation of a short-term low that
short-term low had trailing cell stops
resting below it
those cell stops would now would be
violated
and canceled so any longs would be
knocked out at this point
now you need to be paying close
attention because this is where the
rubber meets the road
this
short-term low
and that run on the cell stops
right below that low here you want to
draw special attention to that right now
because this is your first clue
that we are probably going to work
the sell side of the liquidity
we don't know it at the time when it
first forms we have to start watching
what price does we already know we have
a strong rejection above the 115 big
figure and we've came a long way from
105 34
with none of the cell stocks taken
except for this one here
now we have a short term height that's
violated just briefly
but my question is is that short-term
little violation above an old high
is that making new ground for new highs
no it didn't even challenge the old high
but look at the strong rejection right
above that high
it creates another
lower low
so this short term low
right here
also
sees its liquidity in the form of the
cell stops
ran out as well
my question to you is this at this
moment
right now
it's at the midway point or equilibrium
between the 105 34 and the 115 big
figure
the chances of this creating a higher
high
where we're at right now relative to the
115 big figure
is not likely not because it's hindsight
and it's right in front of me but
because it's showing indications that it
can't create new ground once the buy
stop side of the liquidity is taken
but it's creating new lower ground every
single time a short-term low is violated
it gathers up more momentum and gathers
more
distance between the range of 115 big
figure and 105 34. so every time it
drops it drops a little bit more but
every time it rallies it fails to make a
new high even if it takes a short-term
high out
it's not gaining any more ground on the
upside
every rally is being distributed
we have a short-term high here as well
and those buy stops are ran out as well
same question does this rally above a
short-term high create a new high
no
it can't even get above the previous
failed attempt to make another higher
high
at the 114 big figure
then once again we have a rally through
an old high
does it gain new ground no but it's
quickly rejected and trades lower and
then
violates
two times
it goes below
the 109 10 level
once briefly before running up and
taking that run on 112
and then rejecting that level after
taking the buy stops out
and making a run for another pass
through the 108 50s
this
short
from this high at 1 12 95
was on the heels of the u s elections we
saw a strong dollar and the market
quickly rejected all of the rallies in
foreign currencies
the movement below
every short-term low
and gaining more ground
on the downside
that's the indication you look for
regardless of whatever time frame you're
trading but on the daily chart
you're looking for clues that it wants
to gain more momentum
on one side of the market or the other
you're going to reference where the buy
stops are available highs and where the
sell stops are below old lows but what
you're watching for is the tug of war
that takes place between each new run on
stops below the market
and above the market
if you notice where the intermediate
term highs are
if intermediate term highs keep creating
lower intermediate term highs
and enemy term lows and short-term lows
keep going lower each time
it's telling you that it wants the open
float below the marketplace in other
words it wants to seek to sell side
liquidity
it's going to draw lower so now think
about what this has done for you
it gives you a directional bias on the
daily chart
and it takes a long time for these moves
to take place
but
once you're studying price and you look
for these clues across many pairs and
many asset classes
you'll see that this is in fact what
leads you
to
daily chart
directional bias which also will
serve you very well in other disciplines
of trading whether it be day trading
scalping short-term trading or swing
this will give you
what you're looking for in terms of how
do i know what side of the market it's
going to make the run on is it going to
run the buy stops or it's going to run
the cell stops
think about what time frame you're
looking at here this is a daily chart
if the daily chart is indicating that it
wants to run
lower because it has no problem getting
down below short term lows
but every rally
has a failure to make new ground and
can't make a higher high
when it does make a higher high it's
punished immediately
but the high that it makes is always
just above a short-term
insignificant high
every time it does this it solidifies a
intermediate term high
that is now lower than the previous
an intermediate term high is any high
that has a short term high to the left
of it and to the right of it
think of it like a head and shoulders
top formation
every time you see
a
enemy term high that has a lower enemy
term high to the left of it and enemy
term high to the right of it that's
actually a long term high in the middle
again think like a head and shoulders
pattern now invert that
and you'll have the same thing that
would be said for an immediate term low
or a long term low
once you see that in price you'll
actually see the
market structure that i actually learned
from studying larry williams as a new
trader
you can see the market structure in this
entire
sample size of data
it's multiple
intermediate term highs
and long term highs that are
significantly
signaling that the market in fact wanted
to go lower
there was a liquidity void
around the
106.80 level
to
106.35
it filled that in when all the way down
to the short-term low at 105.34
bounce a little bit there and then
ultimately
once breaking that low
at 107 big figure
it reached down below
to take this outside liquidity out
now when you study the daily charts like
this you can look at
a lot of examples
but they require time
and unfortunately
they don't give you a lot of turnaround
time for study but in hindsight you can
go back and look at a plethora of
really nice trading examples where you
can see where liquidity was ran on one
side the market was drawn up for three
to six months
okay look at the move from
the
december low of 2015
up to the high made in may of 2016.
it's about six
months
then the move from that high
in the spring of 2016
it traded all the way down to a low
made in
december of 2016.
again
about six months or so a little bit more
in six months
but you're seeing
the effects of
how the quarterly shift
takes place
also how the runs on liquidity and the
implementation of open float open float
is the study of how the market reaches
for
the buys and the cells that are above
market price
knowing where orders will be building
and stacking above old highs and below
old lows
that will give you the framework to map
out which side of the marketplace
the market makers and smart money are
seeking to
make a run on
if you can determine that on a daily
chart like this it will give you
trend
daily bias
long-term bias
and it'll give you prognostication for
having smart money perspectives an
institutional vantage point with all of
your trades until next time i wish good
luck and good trading