all right guys
we're going to be looking at a ipta data
range example
and we'll be focusing on the australian
dollar now if you've noticed we've had a
little bit of a run up on aussie
and we're gonna break this down a little
bit in context why i was expecting the
the levels that we're looking at now
to be hit
looking at the charts that we share on
the forum so if you're not paying
attention to those charts or if you're
not saving them
it might be a good idea while we're
doing
this month not that i'm encouraging you
to do this throughout the mentorship
but when we do
daily reviews
i'm taking you basically to the points
at which i'm drawing my attention to on
my own journal how i have reference
points on my own charts
what you see
me noting on those daily entries on the
forum there are the points at which i'm
keeping focus
in my own journal and any salient points
that would be
in addition to those levels i will make
in terms of commentary
but the
the month of january when we do these
daily entries where i do the dollar
index euro dollar british pound us
dollar
dollar cad and aussie dollar
when i share them with you
don't just click on them and wait for
some kind of a neon sign and say buy
here sell here i want you to be focusing
on what i'm drawing your attention to
and then watching how price
moves to these levels
regardless of what type of trader you're
going to be you're going to need to be
focusing on how that happens from
beginning or from foresight to when now
we can talk about it in hindsight
because all these things
are going to help
you prepare yourself for when you
anticipate something and then waiting
throughout that process because it's not
is quickly learned by simply looking at
a hindsight example where i can say okay
this is what we said the market was
going to do this is where we thought the
market was going to happen and here it
is bang
when you see it
in the charts and draw your attention is
drawn to it beforehand
there's a submission to time that's
required and unfortunately we gloss over
that many times even as educators like
myself
it's hard to communicate what's required
in terms of having to wait for that
thing to unfold or develop in the chart
just simply because we have a level or
an order block or a target even for
price to get to
when you show a hindsight example it
that part of the lesson which in my
opinion is the
that's the main that's the main point
you have to learn you have to learn to
wait for these things to unfold the
impatience that
the market presents us an opportunity to
experience is overwhelming sometimes and
while i'm many times accredited for
being very patient i am not really a
patient person at all i'm very impatient
uh that's the reason why i don't do long
term position trading but
i'm going to counsel you to go in every
single day when we do our daily entries
for
the content whether it be a video
review or whether it be a a teaching or
if it's something along the lines of
just simply
providing the charts
you want to be
really
copying those charts printing them out
make you hold me hold me to
the standard of if i know what i'm doing
then it should be evidenced in this okay
for you for the most part we've seen
many times that occurring but for your
learning you need to say okay this is
when this was noted this is when the
observation was made so how long did it
take
for this to occur
now since january is focused primarily
on the daily chart
obviously each daily candle when it
paints and closes for the day it
obviously takes 24 hours to do that so
yes
we can glibly say
it takes 24 hours for this candle to
form and this is what it takes in terms
of uh the setup or level being reached
over this period of time it could took
three days or four days or two weeks
you need to experience that you need to
be being mindful of how long those
things take
especially on these higher time frame
charts if you don't do this
and you're new or you're just a
relatively
inexperienced trader
some of you that are in my group that
have been trading for a long time
know exactly what i'm referring to
there's a big
gap in between learning something with
examples in hindsight and textbook and
even being taught something in a webinar
or a workshop live where people say this
is what happened in the marketplace it's
missing that element of having to endure
what needs to be weighted upon to come
into your chart you can't just simply
say okay well this is the outcome i'm
expecting and therefore you know it
needs to happen on my time that's the
part that kills traders it was very
influential in my early
days as a trader because i i needed it
to happen right away because i first
started trading things were moving quick
there were fast markets and then when i
realized that it wasn't like that always
it was a very big struggling point for
me
so
just go in every day gather those charts
up print them out keep a running log of
them in fact it's probably a good idea
just to print them out every day and
just get yourself a three ring binder
punch some holes in it date them okay
and then keep track it's a good
reference point to go back on saturdays
and sundays on the weekend when we're
not really doing anything
go back and look at what was observed
before the fact and then how long it
took for these things to develop and
those levels to be reached and what was
the response after it got to those
levels
okay so it's important you go through
the mentorship with that in mind i'm not
just showing you
trophies or you know just
things in passing i'm really trying to
draw your attention to something that i
want you to focus on and study how long
it takes for these things to come to
fruition
okay so get it let's get into the
australian dollar example where the if
the data range all right so we have here
a futures chart
okay this is the march contract the
underlying daily chart of the futures
contract of the australian dollar
and by looking at
the futures contract if we're going to
be trading forex okay it's it's really
important that you know that you can get
a lot of insight just by studying
the underlying futures
price so since if we're looking at the
australian usd pair as our case study
we're going to be looking at how
influential the study of just the
futures contract alone
how that's paramount and understanding
how that moves right into and segways
beautifully into trading in the foreign
exchange market if i were to do a poll
right now if we were all in the same
room together okay and we simply said
hey look um
i've never traded forex or i've never
changed futures
if you were
studying one or the other i guarantee
you a large percent of you probably 80
or more
never really refer to the opposite in
terms of the analysis so what i mean by
that is if you're a futurist trader
you've never considered what the foreign
exchange markets doing or if you're a
futurist trader i'm sorry a forex trader
you've never considered what the
underlying futures contract is doing
vice versa
it's imperative that you understand what
they're both doing
to get a complete picture you want to be
looking at both
now obviously right away one's going to
assume well it should be obvious it
should be the same thing because the
australian is leading the payer all of
you versus the dollar so therefore the
australian underlying futures contract
should be in fact the same thing we see
in the foreign exchange market and by
far and large it that's true but there
are certain data points that you cannot
get by looking at the foreign exchange
market there's simply no way of getting
that because foreign exchange doesn't
give you volume it doesn't give you
accurate volume like you can get volume
from the underlying futures contract
and we'll talk more about that as we go
but i want you to take a look at this
chart here okay and i'm looking at a
little bit less than six months i wanted
to show just this data range because
outside of this the chart becomes spotty
because it is a futures contract and
it's march delivery that means
prior to march we had december's
contract and that's already uh expired
and now we're trading in the nearby
contract which is march 2017 australian
dollar
when we taught or rather when i taught
the ipta data ranges okay obviously i i
asked everyone to hold off sending me
emails but some of you were just
overzealous and want to know it right
now and these are things that are going
to be building on your understanding as
we go through the mentorship especially
through january
but i want you to focus when you look at
your daily chart just simply go through
and look at the last three months okay
start whatever whatever time point
you're looking at like right now let's
assume we sat down with charts right now
and this would be the first day we're
looking at australian dollar we're a
brand new trader brand new to the
concept we're sitting down
how will we how would we go about
looking at where
the ifta data ranges are
and if we're looking at australian
dollar
you want to go from today's
uh candle which is what's being painted
here
that
and it's not a can i know it's open high
low close but you have to suffer through
that okay because i
had to get these slides together and i
promise there will be candlesticks shown
but for now i want you to focus on this
because the open high loan closes
important
the
most recent market shift okay in the
last three months occurred back in
november
now i know some of you that are hardline
critics are saying well here we go again
this is the hindsight thing
this is where hindsight is gold
you need to know what i'm going to show
you in this teaching because it will
clarify what the if the data ranges are
actually supposed to be doing for you
some of you are thinking that it's going
to call the high and low 20 days 40 days
and 60 days away that's not what happens
sometimes it can hurt sometimes it can
occur
but that's not what its job is okay
the the question that comes up a lot is
when i'm looking for a order block to
buy one or if i'm looking at an order
block to sell into or if i'm looking for
an area of buy stops or sell stops
which one should i expect them to go
after which one are they going to
respect how do i know if it's not going
to keep on going through an old high and
not be a turtle soup cell all those
scenarios and those ideas while i told
everyone in the beginning if you were
just patient and waited and
all those questions would be answered
but some of you are just really really
impatient and i get it you're excited
and you think that you're not going to
learn all this stuff in the remaining
time of the mentorship but trust me i'm
committed you will learn it there's tons
of information coming to you but you
have to let me go through the process of
teaching it this isn't the first time i
taught this stuff to trust me i've been
successful in the past doing it okay so
just go along with the process
but if we look at back in november we
can clearly see that there was a major
market shift in november 2016.
now what that does it gives us a great
deal of insight we can't take a time
capsule travel back in time okay and be
back in november and go short there but
we can use the information that our
daily charts are telling us there that
means there was a great deal of
displacement
by the large players or smart money
when we see that
in november what we're seeing here is
the underlying futures contract of the
australian dollar has a market shift
right there that's a quarterly market
shift
over the last three to six months that's
the most
obvious one you can clearly see it if i
was to ask everyone if you're all in the
same room raise your hand if you can
clearly see that that is the most
obvious market shift in the last three
to six months everybody invariably would
raise their hand they would click
obviously if you can see it you can't
deny it
that's what you're looking for every
three months there's going to be
something like this occurring it could
be a sell-off creating a high or it
could be a a low where it starts to
rally but every three months i want you
to look at your charts
and anticipate
finding that in hindsight
now great that's wonderful you can see
it in hindsight what do you do with that
information see this is what
i have an issue with like with elliott
wave and all these other
very
they're just very highly subjective
if the market really is
influenced or controlled by smart money
or if there is what i'm telling you
there's an algorithm that controls what
price is going to do it's absolutely not
random it's predetermined it's it's
running on a script
that refers to specific data points that
it will go back to over and over and
over again
the ipta
data range okay
you have a 20 day
look back and cast forward
range you have a 40 day look back and
cast forward range
and then you have a 60 day look back and
what i'm suggesting to you is
if you are looking at price and you see
a for instance they have a market
structure shift here and the quarterly
shift occurs in november
that means that now the market is in a
cell profile from that point until it
gets to a level of significant counter
direction what would cause it to change
direction or consolidate that's the
other thing that's the vague green uh
not green but gray area in the analysis
sometimes you won't see a clear
retracement or correction opposite
direction for instance it's been going
down november it could have very easily
been consolidating here going into
january
okay
into february it doesn't need to be a
counter trend move like we're seeing
unfold here since the last week of
december it can be a consolidation
and as we go further into the content
for the january uh delivery of the
information we'll talk about when it
does or when to anticipate when it's
going to go into consolidation and not
have a
a counter swing
so back in november we see that there's
a high made
what's what's really going on that low
here is broken so we have a shift in
market structure and it breaks lower
we know that we can see it because it's
taken out an area of equal highs and we
pierced above that
taking out the buy stop liquidity pool
and that's seen here
that was the that was the basis and the
framework around what caused the market
structure shift
that quarterly effect comes in
uh to operation at that moment okay
where our eyes go immediately back to
november because you can clearly see it
when you see that and you delineate that
in your chart what you're doing is
you're now identifying the beginning of
november
so you have to have a basis point where
where is it where did it all begin
because if you don't get yourself in
sync with what ipda most recently did
and ipta is the interbank price delivery
algorithm that's for your notes again
you're going to delineate where the most
obvious one in the last three months has
been
then you're going to cast out
20 days
go forward
from the beginning of the the month that
that market structure shift or quarterly
shift takes place you're going to count
out 20 days now it may not even be
20 days you may look at the chart and
say hey this is an obvious one right
here something's really going on
if you do that you're really
doing too much anticipation
you got to go back to the most obvious
one and it may require you going back
three months
but find the most recent one where the
market structure has shifted and there
was a move that took place that was
obvious bullish or bearish okay
and it's really easy if you just divide
your your daily chart into
uh quarters like put one put a line on
march put a line on uh june and
september december and just keep doing
that your your eye will go right to
where
these uh quarterly shifts are happening
they're not going to always occur on
those months there's a little bit of
gray area which is the reason why we
have a look back and cast forward
the ipta data range okay what it's
really doing is it's highlighting
you as the trader you're going to try to
mimic what this algorithm is doing
it's looking for
the liquidity
in the range of 60 days in the past
where is the sell stops in the last 60
days
where are the buy stops in the last 60
where are the fair value gaps where's
the price gaps that price has not been
efficiently delivered in the last 60
days
where are the
the liquidity voids where price has only
been delivered on the upside where it
has to come back down to efficiently
deliver price and balance it out
by going back down and closing in that
range
optimal trade entries that's where that
comes from
where are
the equilibrium price points
does it have to return back to
equilibrium did we get too far ahead of
ourselves do we extend too far do we
have to come back and retrace minor
retracement before we see the next leg
lower by looking at the
market structure shift that takes place
in this november time period we are in
instance saying that this is a quarterly
shift
therefore because of the daily chart
this is going to give us insight about
what the market should do on a
three-month timeline as much as six
months
but i like to just remind you that i'm
only really looking for
about three months horizon time horizon
that far out i don't like to look beyond
that there's many many times i can show
you in journals where i had it right but
i really just because i had it right
doesn't mean i was executing on every
trade
but many times i'm really accurate in
about four to six weeks time horizon and
it's about the half-life of a
three-month cycle
so if i think that the time horizon is
consistently derived at by looking at
three months out by using the daily
chart like this
that's my belief i'm firm in my belief
that i believe i can teach you how to do
that and have a three-month horizon by
having that that is a great deal of
opportunities for all
disciplines of trading long-term
positions swing short term intraday
scalping all that stuff can be done
effectively by having this time horizon
but when we find the
clear market structure
shift that happens every quarterly
every three to four months or so we find
it we identified the beginning of that
month you gotta roll back to that first
month why are we doing that why does it
have to go back to the first month
first of the month rather because if an
algorithm and i'm not sure if any of you
are aware of
how computer programs are made or
designed but
when a systems analyst
sits down with a company and they say
okay look this is what i want
the output to be or i need a a report
generator that's it's going to give me
this outcome or i need this information
or i need this computation made i need
this process done
okay the system that's a system analyst
is going to say okay
what
what data points are
you making available to me so i can sit
down with my team of computer
programmers okay and the analyst will
make a documentation stage where he sits
down and outlines the overall macro
process
now
because of what they're dealing with
they are taught and learn computer
programming to some degree but they are
not doing the programming
they put all of the
context around what is supposed to
happen what processes are there
if this is done then this should be done
as well what checks and balances and
it's basically the documentation stage
of
the process of a computer program then
the computer programmers take that
information and they actually code it
out now
a
computer program and a computer
programmer is completely utterly blind
and useless if he doesn't have data
points to use
you can't have a computer program do
anything of any value unless it knows
where to draw
data points from there has to be an
array of information coming to it to
process and do calculations so my here's
my
this was my epiphany okay when i was
sitting down with
the folks that were introducing these
ideas to me
and know they're not in the teaching
circuits you're never going to meet
these people okay but
when i was introduced on how
the markets actually work and operate
the the fast thing i the fastest and
most obvious thing i learned was
there was no
ambiguity to how price moves around
randomness
because they were talking about things
that had a finite
or origination where it wasn't like it
could have been this day it could have
been that year it could have been this
month no no no no it's absolutely
nothing like that
if you understand that we're going to be
referring to things that are
numerical
they are price related
they are value based that means that we
have to look at a specific level and
price
but
how does the algorithm go just to end
the old price how does the algorithm
know that yet that that's where the
large fund stops are
see this is what's taught and permeated
in the teaching uh circuits in in
education for trading they teach and
i've said these things before but i used
it to communicate to you the idea
because most people don't understand
fund level trading they don't understand
institutional trading they don't they
don't know those types of things they
just think i got an account with my
broker so therefore i'm trading and if i
get stopped out it's my broker that did
it to me and many times that's true
but
the delivery of price from the central
bank level
that movement that repricing is really
not always but on the short term it's
being repriced
to take into account for large liquidity
pools that are available on the large
fund trading
realm not
your little mom and pop fxem
not your owanda none of those none of
those things okay are obvious or on the
radar screen for what i'm teaching you
here but they are in close
uh
they're basically in alignment with the
same thing okay but they're this these
movements for these runs on stops
they're not looking at oh here's michael
stop okay here's uh john jones from uh
allentown pennsylvania stops okay
they don't have that type of information
they don't see you they don't have any
identification of you they don't have
any identification to retail at all
but because these ideas are taught
across the board the same way because
it's been put out there to be done this
way because eventually if you're
if you are an accurate trader that's a
retail based trader okay
eventually if you're profitable to some
degree what eventually happens to some
of these people
they get
very high-minded of themselves they
think then they're great at what they're
doing so therefore they're profitable
and the first thing they want to do is
prove it to the world by having everyone
else give them their money and they're
going to be a trader that manages funds
no one wakes up and is born a large fund
trader
they come up through the ranks of being
a profitable retail trader so are they
going to come into that realm and change
the way they've been doing things
absolutely not
it's the same thing they're going to do
there then the difference is they have a
process on the fund level that they have
to go through specific parameters and
guidelines and stay within these to be
compliant with whoever is running that
uh that operation behind the scenes in
other words just because you're a large
fund manager unless you're operating
alone and independent if you go to work
for an agency and you are a fund trader
and you're managing under
their umbrella then
you have guidelines you have to work
within there's there's rules and things
that you can't do outside of these or
you're you're you know you basically get
canned you're out the door you're gone
you can't manage anything don't you know
they'll expel you
but
these ideas are the same so how can an
algorithm or a computer will just say it
like this how can a computer program
know where everyone's stop is
it has to have a range of data
now just because we have the the numbers
of price the value of price okay they
have to have a look back period
the look pack period is 20 days 40 days
and 60 days
and what you're doing is and this is
what i want you to do with your your
time after today's teaching while you're
waiting for today's daily recap video
because there'll be two bits go up this
is the teaching video for today and then
we'll have a daily review where i do
like 10 15 minutes talking about what's
already happened
and i'll give you the charts and stuff
to study
i want you to spend your time this
evening okay
and even tomorrow while we're not doing
any live session go back through your
charts and don't just look at the
australian dollar look at every currency
pair look at every commodity look at
individual stocks look at indices and
you'll see quickly by studying this
it will become quickly clear that
there's no randomness to it there's a
specific pattern that this thing does
all the time now it used to be
a manual thing where the market maker
was a real person they sat there and
they worked with a team of individuals
that manipulated price to do these very
things but because everything has become
so streamlined and efficient by
artificial intelligence ai the uh the
effectiveness of algorithms okay
that's been implemented now it's much
more efficient to do that and there's no
emotion it just does what it needs to do
so if it's a computer program or i'm
quoting with my fingers now the
interbank price delivery algorithm that
computer program we're going to call it
from this point on
for this teaching
for it to be
effective it has to know where to look
at
to find stops
they don't see orders
that's not what's going on they don't
see orders
the orders are executed on by the
traders at the bank level
the algorithm just permits the price to
move to that level which gives the
opportunity for the traders to execute
on that run
that's the real story that's what really
goes on everybody else out there in this
industry will tell you well it's this
happening and this this guy here he's
he's pushing a button and it's doing
this to have no it's not it's not that's
not what's happening at all
the algorithm will look back 60 days
and it'll find it's very easy if you if
you know anything about computer
programming
and you don't even have to do that but
just look at this
first of november
if you look back 60 days in the past
what was the highest high in the last 60
days
there's going to be buy stops above that
high what's the lowest low in the last
60 days
there's going to be cell stops below
that low
in the last 40 days what was the last
highest high and what was the last
lowest low
looking back in the range to the left
from that november red line that we're
dealing in november where are the stops
below and above those highs inside of
the range of 20 days
40 days and 60 days
now i already know what some of you are
thinking
what happens if there's a low
that's really really obvious that's just
outside the range of 60 days that's the
farthest extreme
that's when the open float will move
aggressively and go outside that normal
parameter of 60 days and you'll see that
big run
the market will jump
and skip right down into that old low
that's just outside that 60 day range
how do you know when it's going to be an
explosive move michael
when you have that scenario
if the last 60 days if they've already
ran out the the stops below and low in
the last 60 days
or above an old high in the last 60 days
and there is a larger higher high
or lower low where the stocks will be
resting above or below respectively
then you know there's going to be a big
run on price and they're going to run
for that liquidity
because that's the only other thing
that's left the large funds have their
orders above and below these old highs
and lows
you work just like the algorithm will in
a 60-day range look back the last 60
days
and then you watch going forward you
cast forward 60 days and you can
literally have this on your chart you go
forward count forward 60 days you can
literally go on your daily chart in mt4
and
change your date 60 days forward to make
a vertical line and that way as price
starts to paint you'll know you're
approaching that 60 day that means it's
going to be forming some measurable
intermediate term high or low before
that time
and it's going to create a liquidity
pool
above an old high or below no low that's
going to be influential for future
trades the same thing occurs by looking
back on the last 40 days
to the left of that november 1st
look back 40 days what was the lowest
low what was the highest low i'm sorry
what was the highest high rather and the
lowest low your buy stops above the old
high and the sell stops below that old
low inside of that range of 40 days
that's where ipta will look for that
liquidity now
it's not giving you directional bias yet
i'm telling you it needs to use these
reference points to find where the stops
would logically be see the ai cannot
it can't think
for a human
it can't do that but because human
nature says that we will as traders put
our sell stop below a low
and we will put a buy stop above an old
high
that's all the algorithms doing it's
seeking to take price to that level
when it gets to that level then
your broker
then the central bank can do a wild
spike
and send it above 10 to 20 pips
think about it now 10 to 20 pips then
becomes logical why they do those big
spikes okay intraday
20 and 10 and 20 pips above and over
high then it stops rate many times rate
at 20 pips or 10 pips and then rejects
it goes the other way
it first has to get to those levels
based on a daily chart in the realm of a
20 pip
40 i'm sorry 20 day 40 day or 60 day
look back and then cast forward so
really what you're doing is you have 120
days of range from the past and going
forward there's going to be a
significant move now some of your press
of course there's going to be a move
michael come on i mean a lot can happen
in 120 days yeah you're right
but there's things that you have to look
for that the algorithm is going to be
doing
to engineer these types of moves
you have to have these data points to
know why the market's going to go at an
old low what old low well where's the
lowest low in the last 20 days
where's the last 40 days where's the
lowest low in that range where's the
highest high in that last range and you
need to be noting those because that's
the one that they're going to run
they're going to run rate for those
if there isn't anything that hasn't been
traded to in the last 60 days if
everything's been wiped out above and
below the marketplace in other words the
open float all the buy stops above old
highs and all the sell stocks below all
those in the last 68 darn your look back
in other words everything to the left of
that november vertical line at red line
if everything's been cleaned out
above and below the highs and lows
there's no more buy stops there's no
more cell stops it has to create a new
expansion
so you have to identify what the next
high
and low outside that range of 60 days
looking back where that is
and that's going to tell you where
they're going to draw a price on this
daily time frame
it's more it's more confirmed when you
start applying it to the weekly chart in
the monthly chart because you'll start
seeing things align where that old low
that's just outside of the last 60 days
looking back
there's an old low that may not be on
this chart here i don't know i'm just
giving you a hypothetical
example
if there's an old load it's just outside
the realm of september in this example
here say maybe there's august there's a
significant lower low
the market's going to reach for that
there may be a high that's just outside
the september boundary in august
they may have
turned around here
and they make a run for that maybe it
may be in the 78th uh price range for uh
for aussie
that's what you would be noting and
you're going to look for price to be
drawn to one of those two price points
and you look for evidences that that
institutional order flow is going that
direction then you know where it's going
it gives you directional bias because of
the higher time frame nature of this
daily chart and weekly and monthly
so
what we have here this is the
look forward okay or cast forward of
november
this is 20 days out
from the 1st of november so we have 20
days here
inside of that 20 day range there's
going to be a significant setup that you
can use for your trading it's moving up
into the old load that was formed in
october
it goes into consolidation well here we
have a condition where the market didn't
create
any significant shift
but it starts to move in consolidation
then you count forward okay from here
that's the 20th
so you can go from the beginning of
november to the 20th yes there was a
price swing
but using the information next stage
would be 40 days out from that price
point of november beginning we have here
that is your 40-day lookout
or cast forward
and you're looking for
again a potential major
shift quarterly it can happen at that
point now it didn't give you the lowest
low because if you go back to the left
two two daily candles or bars the last
down
right here
this down candle that was the actual low
we had a small little range in here and
then we came down and hit this level
here 71.50
that's the 40 days out
from the beginning of november
framed on the
quarterly shift that took place here
so we're anticipating a potential change
in in the direction okay
20 40 or 60 days out
but that's the range it's not always
going to do like what you're seeing here
where it's almost calling the very day
it moves and makes the change
it's you're allowing your study to say
okay the price is going to move about 20
days and then we could see something if
it doesn't happen in 20 days okay well
in the next 20 days up to 40 days from
where the market structure
last shifted here quarterly then we're
going to anticipate
in the realm of the next 20 days it may
happen
so you have to be looking for signs that
it's going to happen if you don't do
these things
you're going to marry the idea that the
market's going to keep on going lower
and never turn around
it doesn't it doesn't do that mark is
not trading straight lines
so if we see here
on this day here this is 40 days out
from the beginning of november
very significant price move occurred
from that price
71.50
i mean i would think everyone if we were
all in the same room if we raised our
hand if we were in agreement i think the
majority of us if not all of us would
raise our hand say that's a pretty
significant move off that level
one of the things i learned when i was
an indicator based trader i'd like to
stochastic i like
larry williams accumulation distribution
formula where it plotted an accumulative
line based on the relationship to open
the close and closed open and measuring
that as some smart money buying and
selling well
sometimes that's true
not always and it didn't always give you
a divergence
i liked his william percent art and the
reason why i liked his william percent
are is because it has an uncanny ability
to be one day before
like if you look at stochastic you have
to wait for the the candle to close and
go to a new candle to see if the k line
crossed the d line or d line across the
uh the k line or whatever it is i don't
even remember what it was anymore but
the the trigger line that uses uh the
idea behind a crossover for stats for a
stochastic
that has to happen after the fact well
the market's already moved
when i looked at the percent r
what that did it gave me many times the
day before the real oversold condition
would happen for instance if the
oversold condition existed in williams
percent r
today that means tomorrow it's probably
still likely to go down just a little
bit more but that's going to be the buy
day that's a very low low
well
that same phenomenon sometimes occurs
with these ranges 20 days out you may
get
the if it doesn't turn it may happen on
the 21st day
or it may occur on the 19th
day
when the when it does occur but that's
not what you're relying on so it's
important that while that may have magic
in your chart sometimes you may see it
happen it might do the very thing of
turning on the 20th day or the 40th day
or the 60th day and you saw that in my
first teaching for the month i wish i
probably would have stressed it more
because everyone seems to think that
that's what's going to happen i i'm not
telling you the market turns every 20
days every 40 days and every 60 days but
it can and will sometimes do that what
we're looking for is these quarterly
shifts that take place once we identify
one
there's our beginning point okay but you
have to roll back to the beginning of
that month it occurs in it occurred in
the second week of uh of the month of
november so we're now we're calibrated
now we can start going forward until we
see a equal
or counterparty
uh to that move going lower it has to be
a significant um
you know retracement or correction or
reversal it's indicating that here the
last week of december why is it doing
that because we've taken out december's
high
see that
we're trading at a level where if this
was continuously bearish
it shouldn't be where it's at right now
today
okay
but my point in drawing your attention
to the 40 day is
it was not the 40th uh i'm sorry it
wasn't the fact that it made the lowest
low and turned on that day but look at
the low in proximity to the lowest low
that was formed here inside to see this
day here was inside the range of 40 days
back to this point price point here so
from this level of looking at the first
day of november casting forward 40 days
this whole turning point right here
could have happened any time in the last
40 days
now again that for the summers that are
cynical of course obviously this this is
of no value it's a great deal of value
because inside that 40 days just like
when we look back for 40 days and look
for the low for sell stops and we look
for the high for the buy stops
in this range here
what is this
that's a low
below that low is going to be what
cell stops
yes we moved
about 150 pips or so
below that
but we came to a level of 71.50 that's
not
random
7150 is a significant level it's a mid
figure level
and it's happening at a time
when inside of 40 days
the if the data range is going to be
looking to do something it has it has to
do something every three months
price is going to be
pushed around it's going to be drawn to
a level or it's going to repel from a
level
and it's based on what i'm telling you
here it's seeking large fund liquidity
now longer term where we're talking
about monthly and yearly moves they are
all driven by real fundamental things
like interest rates
but every quarter there's going to be a
ebb and flow that takes place a rally
and a decline when this occurs that's
all short-term in nature when you look
at long-term trends that
go for five years or 10 years
three months is nothing that's like a
five minute chart on the scheme of a
weekly chart it doesn't mean anything
there's no significance to it at all
long-term macro fundamentals okay are
not
impacted by three-month
cycles they're not
they can be used to get in sync with
long-term macro fundamentals
but
the only fundamentals you're going to
get from me is interest rates which is
going to talk to you this month as well
so again in summary the 40 days and i'm
not done teaching but for 40 days
this range we're looking back because
you know here we have a new 40-day look
we're casting forward 40 days so that at
that moment we're gonna have that
in our charts from this point here we
know 40 days from then this is where we
would have our expectation of a shift
but we also because we can do that in
advance we can now look back 20 days
from there
we can look 40 days back from there
where's the lows and where's the highs
think about that
if we know at this point here casting 40
days forward we can have a vertical line
right here
on our on our charts
now to someone looking over your
shoulder they'd be like why is that line
even there why do you have a vertical
line there
i don't know
i ain't telling you you weren't part of
the mentorship
but from this point here counting back
that's good here's here's gotta count
this day as day one one
two three four five six seven eight nine
10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20. okay
to 20 is basically the the last day
before you get to december so the second
to the last day of november is 20 days
back
what was the highest high
formed in that range
it's going to be mid july uh mid
december where it made those equal highs
so there's going to be what's resting
above that
buy stops so what is the ipta algorithm
going to do
it's going to seek that liquidity it's
going to go up there and take that
which high should i look for michael
that one
looking back from this point here
because we know it from this point here
casting forward
40 days okay going back 40 days well
that's going to be in the range that's
delineated here with this line that
we've already shown this is the low
is there any significance about that low
well i'll count you to go into your
4 hour 1 hour and 15 minute time frame
and put up 7300 on your aussie dollar
and see what you see
there's nothing random about this stuff
folks
that low is 40 days inside the 40 day
range okay that is a
significant turning point it's not the
very lowest low
but you can see that the low forms two
days before that and then we have a
market structure shift
and the market starts to go opposite to
what has been put in place in november
you can now also from that price point
there by having a vertical line on the
arrowed
daily range you can now start counting
forward 20 days 40 days
60 days
until you see an obvious
shift quarterly
there's a major structure shift okay it
could be bullish or bearish whatever one
it happens it doesn't make it that
you're not trying to forecast that
all you're doing is anticipating another
significant move in price on a daily
chart and it happens every three months
but the point is the
the if the data ranges
give you a means of looking back
20 40 and 60 days from specific
days and specific price points
because then you'll know what stops
they're going to be reaching for
above the old high and below an old low
it's not just well i'm looking for the
most recent obvious high and low no no
no no it's not like that at all it's not
like that at all you got to look back in
a range of 20 40 and 60
and then if all those levels have been
cleared out then you gotta look outside
that range then you know you're getting
may see a big move
and if it has these
characteristics then you know you're
going to see a larger move higher or
lower based on what those
uh highs and lows would be outside the
most recent 60-day look back
all right so this is the australian
dollar
candlestick you can
uh rest your eyes a little bit and then
we're straining your eyes on the open
high-low enclosed bar
here's that 70-50 level okay and why is
that significant here we have a old
low back in
february of 2016 we have a last down
candle but that last down candle
has a range in it okay let me show you
again this is what it looks like that
wick
right in here
right here look at that price movement
up
right before
the last it was the last week of
february the big green candle right
there
we know that prior to that we saw
the down close
and that explosive range higher
that high is going to be significant
it's going to be sensitive okay but all
the way down into the opening of that
weekly
range also notice that this last down
candle here
right before this big move up in the
last week of may of 2016 that last red
candle
that was the bullish order block as well
so we have a big range to work within
then going into the latter portions of
the
last down candle in december
that would be a bullish order block as
well
looking at the the high and the open on
that candle would give you significant
price points to go forward as well but
look what happens when price hits this
70 150 level it's been down here before
and they repelled aggressively away from
that
fundamentally must be something to it i
don't know what it is but on a weekly
chart we're going to be using old highs
and old lows
and if those old highs and old lows had
significant buying and selling pressures
it's evidence and you can see it here we
have to be mindful of that
and you can see that they have in fact
traded down there we tapped it two times
on a weekly basis
and then moved out
once we moved out away from that level
you'd see that they're going to be
looking to do what they're going to be
trading
above
these candles bodies
and the wicks are next
and we could potentially trade up into
this last up candle
in the last week of october of 2016.
that's where the bearish order block is
so we have a range that potentially
could take us up into 75 70 to 75.80
still
for australian dollar
let's go back into
the daily
or australian dollar and i want you to
take a look at this chart for a moment
stare at this for a second tell me what
you see
okay this is again this is the
march contract for the australian
futures market
it's going to basically do the same
thing our australian dollar pair does in
forex
but what you're seeing here cannot be
seen
in trading forex and er all these guys
that get on facebook and on the internet
and twitter and they know everything
about forex and they know the insides
and then and everything that's secret
okay the buzzword smart money and now
it's institutional trading everything is
making its way in everybody else's
curriculum now
but
none of them talk about this
okay and this is where i learned the
things that larry williams taught in his
book
how i made a million dollars trading
commodities last year wrote that book in
the 70s folks you know we're in 2017 now
very very few things have the longevity
of what has been taught in his book i
mean for
less than it costs for a pair of shoes
today
you literally can buy a book that if you
have no understanding about how
commodities move and how they're priced
and all that business uh to me i think
that is an essential part of every
trader's library again the title is how
i made a million dollars trading
commodities last year by larry williams
in his book
he talks about how he was taught he
didn't discover it he was taught this by
his friend
and i think if i'm not mistaken i think
he names his friend in that book but the
uh
if not you can find it on youtube you do
a search on larry williams and open
interest but the
the fact that open interest is the most
misunderstood
data point in trading is
a wonderful opportunity for you as a
trader
if there is now thing think just for a
second
if there is
100 control over price
there has to be someone controlling it
we're going to globally call that smart
money
if they are controlling it
why would they want to control it
greed
they want to make money just like
anybody else does banks are not in the
business to go out of business they're
in business to buy and sell money
or
provide means for you to borrow money to
pay them interest on the usage of that
money
that's just one facet of it there's also
speculation
that is the mis
most misunderstood realm because it's
not widely talked about you have to be
in that
arena you have to be there to know
anything about it and you are forced to
not talk about anything
so
i had to create a
language if you will okay to be able to
talk
where the things i understood
are effectively communicated
but also doesn't put me out there where
i'm in trouble
that's why we are in
this teachings uh this this medium
the things that i
quickly learned that were apparent in
the marketplace is that yes
there is a entity out there that is 100
interested in offsetting large funds
because they have real huge orders in
the marketplace and if they can upset
them or take them out of the marketplace
they know that their viewpoint will
eventually get back in line because
they're trend filing in nature they can
take them out of the move and take their
seat in that position or they can take
them in the wrong side of the move
and then reprice aggressively the other
way and they can profit from that
they're not looking at owenda or fxcm's
books and saying okay well you know
we're going to really punish retail
today retail is just following the you
know the blind
leader of all these textbooks
all that stuff
you know that leads you to losses that's
a
derivative of you doing what you've been
told to do
and it doesn't have any basis in how the
markets actually work
once in a while they will work
but you're not it's not because that it
didn't happen because the divergence
isn't stochastic it didn't happen
because your wolf wave or your harmonic
crab riding on the back of an eagle's
wings pattern doesn't that doesn't
happen okay price is moving based on
where the large funds orders are where
that open float is
on these higher time frame charts that's
what's drawing price but because
the price is going to allow
the bank level traders to get in and
build positions in otherwise
if it was really just the central banks
repricing
it would be like all the time big moves
moving up to an old high then down to an
old low
the traders have to have a opportunity
to work inside that position to
capitalize on the move that ifta is
engineering for them
how do we know when the banks
smart money are actually going in and
buying if we know that there's a
likelihood that 71.50 when aussie dollar
is potentially bullish
what evidence is there that there is in
fact smart money buying it
well inside that blue shaded area in
here i have a great
deal of insight to share with you and
some of you already know some about
something about this but i want you to
think about this
every
three months this occurs
write this down your notepad
if you're busy changing diapers okay
doing dishes
hiding from your boss write this down
every
three months
this pattern occurs
where you're at a support level
a major higher time frame support level
if you see an expectation that price
should be bullish
we have been trading lower
and
we hit the level like we're seeing here
at 71.50 as we just let me go back one
more time to show you the weekly chart
there's that 7150 level down here we've
been there before in
may okay so look at that level here you
can see that
that level
has been hit perfectly his nails it okay
and it runs away as price hit it
as price hit this level here
this purple line in here i want you to
look at what was going on as price was
dropping down
okay
all through this market structure shift
in november okay
what's happening here
yes prices repricing going lower it's
allowing bank level traders to be short
and capitalize on that move
but also open interest is also
declining why why is that happening
why is open interest declining
when this moves dropping down
what what significance is that
because if you read larry williams book
he says
his buddy told him if the market is in
consolidation
all through here all between 77
and
74.50 for august september and october
price was in a big trading range it's in
consolidation
then in november
it creates a false breakout above 77 big
figure and rejects and trades lower
open interest is taught that as long as
a trend is going up or down and you see
open interest increasing as the trend
goes that's a healthy trend that works
for bull markets doesn't work for down
markets
that's a misnomer that's misinformation
larry williams says when open interest
drops while you're in consolidation
we're in consolidation all through
august september and october
price drops down in here we have a big
drop in open interest
open interest
is the total open longs and shorts that
are in the marketplace right now
if the central bank
is the storehouse for price it's their
currency it's their commodity
if you are trying to buy
currency it has to be made available to
you
and it's going to come from a bank
if this would have been gold okay uh the
commodity is gold is there's a a
provider or a liquidity provider of gold
okay you have to buy up this position or
assume a position in gold well for
australian dollar if you're buying that
currency it has to come from somewhere
it comes from the bank so if they are
the liquidity provider for the price of
australian dollar the central bank of
australia if that bank is providing you
the basis of the valuation on australian
dollars
they are essentially doing what
they're the counterparty to all the
large funds
not always not 100 percent because you
have all kinds of smaller entities and
institutions that could take the other
side of other positions but from for the
most part
view open interest as
every trade that the central bank is
providing counterparty to basically what
a small brokerage firm would do with
their own clients they are the liquidity
provider well the central bank is the
liquidity provider for australian dollar
so if we see open interest increasing
what does that mean that means the
central bank is it's taking on risk
it's providing liquidity
for buyers of australian dollar
if open interest has a
15 or more
drop
or change lower like it does here this
is extended this is a very significant
drop
while price is sideways this is bullish
because what this is doing is
every every time open interest increases
it's indicating that they have now
provided liquidity for a buyer
if they're not trying to provide
liquidity for a buyer and they're trying
to reduce their holding or exposure that
means that they're not doing what to
offer liquidity to a buyer they have to
be a seller
open interest reflects the selling side
of a provider of liquidity
if this open interest declines
aggressively like this that's indicating
they do not want to hold the heavy
short position they would be having by
being a provider for those that want to
buy australian dollar
you see it rally then
but look carefully the extended trading
range is months long what's going on
that whole time from this point here
they start building in positions
they're selling this thing as it's
creating higher highs it's coming back
it's they're selling more of it here
and they're selling more over here
every peak
in the open interest from the low it
creates here
every peak in it is a high
they sold more here
they sold more here right at this high
they sold the most
right there
they're selling into that rally you
don't get that from leah williams book
you do get him saying open interest
increases when we're in bearish markets
and then for the consolidation it tells
you if we see open interest increasing
in a consolidation that means that the
open interest is reflecting heavy net
selling on the central bank level that's
how i'm viewing it for currency trading
but what he taught in his book was the
commercial traders the large commercial
users and producers of a commodity
they're actually building in heavy short
positions what i learned was by looking
at open interest and matching up the
highs to the peaks and open interest you
can actually see where they did their
cell programs that's a sell
they're selling it here and in the very
highest peak they sold it there now
think about it if they sold it there and
then we do have a market structure shift
here are they gonna hold on to their
short positions
if they're naturally a hedger
open interest is going to by natural
order of things reduce as it's going
lower because what are they doing
they're covering those short positions
they built in here that's what's
happening all through this process of
going lower
open interest is declining you don't get
taught in textbooks
it's showing you that they are in fact
in a cell program and they're profit
taking as it's going lower lower lower
lower lower open interest is going to
decline
then we hit a level like this
major support are they going to want to
hold on to a heavy
net short position by offering liquidity
to the buyers no way
how do they upset that they do rapid
price declines that knocks the desire
for buyers that want to move away and
get out of their way
because they don't want to be a provider
and by by providing the sell side to
buyers
they don't want that risk and that's why
they do these massive sell-offs in price
you see these big moves that jump down
to specific levels and they just keep
going lower and lower lower
they do that to take away and control
sentiment on the near term you may have
been bullish back here
well that goes away real quick when they
do this
and they would keep driving lower all of
a sudden there's no support levels until
you get down to 71.50
they know buyers are going to come in
so they have to reset and drop down
quick boom they reset they take all
their interest on being a sell side
liquidity provider and drop it down to
its lowest point
why are they doing that
because now their exposure
is not here
their exposure starts down here
and they go back to that same cycle now
everybody's signing a buy buy buy buy
and they will provide that liquidity
because they've already profited
down here from back here
back here and back here all in the last
week of september the midpoint of
october and the second week of november
where they sold and built in their
bearish positions
the telltale sign is inside that support
level at 71.50
dovetailing this with if the data ranges
and quarterly shifts we know that this
is most likely going to occur and move
all z dollar up
and go back into the charts and go back
into what i was talking about for
australian dollar i told you that it was
going to go higher this is not hindsight
cherry picking i'm telling you why i
said these things and what was behind
the scenes that i can't go through i
mean look how much we're talking about
it now if i did this kind of talk on
everything and every setup every single
day i'd never get done i'd never see my
wife
and probably be divorced really quick
but
these are the things that you're going
to do in your analysis it won't take
this long obviously you'll know what
you're looking for because of the
teachings but the mechanics behind it
all is that 7150 is support
price on the weekly charts bounced there
before
we're in the low end of
the the range for the weekly
um
um well
the lowest point which has been in a
long period of time going back to go
back to your weekly chart that i showed
here
in your notes
and you'll see that that's the lowest
it's been in recent time in the weekly
chart so therefore it would be
reasonable expect to see some bounce at
71.50 but i'm drawing your attention to
that little area in december
that little
massive really it's a massive decline in
open interest
right there that purple line when it
tanked went low real quick like that
that's the central bank
getting rid of any of their remaining
short position so now they're they're
done they completed their cell program
first week of november
mid part of december so now the they're
ready they're prepared for buyers to
come in
they have reset their self there's no
exposure on the upside
okay against them by holding heavy heavy
shorts so now they can start offering
that liquidity from the low end because
they made their book
from 77.50 all the way down to 71.50
600 pips
and believe me they're moving size on
all that
so from that point on okay we had that
delineation
on this
candle or bar remember earlier and
looking back 20 trading days we put you
right about in here that means the high
is here
that's where they're going to run
liquidity
that's where they're going to be seeking
to take price
now what does this mean for forex
trading
all right so this is what we've seen
price do
here's that
40 day
cast forward day
that's the very day and this is that
down candle or down open high low close
candle that small little one and then
here's the the last one or the 40 day
look forward from the first of november
price goes higher from there creates a
down candle
price moves above that candle
here this becomes a bullish order block
so if price was to ever come back down
we could be a buyer there
i said we'd like to see some bullishness
on this candle here because we're on the
left side of the curve this is all the
cell side now if you're going to be
bullish you're going to go look over
here at every down candle
there should be some bullishness in here
we saw some of that
they have a down candle here
if we had a retracement i would like to
see it price come back down here i would
be a buyer that was a potential scenario
that could have unfolded if it didn't
and we blew out the high of this candle
this down candle is going to be the new
bullish order block
so it's high comes in at 70 350 price
comes down hits it here yesterday finds
some sensitivity there and expands up
and closes in the range the context of
the move for australian dollar was i was
not bearish australian dollar
i did not have you set up to expect
lower prices on the australian dollar we
were looking for this thing to come up
here and close in this range and
potentially up into this bearish order
block and it's now confirmed that it
wants to go higher
relative to the things we just said
based on that weekly chart
and we described on the futures contract
on its own daily chart we had a mean
threshold of the range from this candles
open to this candles close that's what
this range is here we've moved through
that so now what is it indicating it
wants to go higher what's it going to
reach for it's going to look for a clear
run above this high here
because that's where the buy stops are
resting
they're not going to take it just to
this level here and be satisfied if
they're going to allow this move to take
place they're going to punch it through
equal highs now i know you're saying if
you if you're new and you haven't really
paid too much attention to
and equal those and you're only looking
for
like a perfect equal candle height this
is in my opinion this is an equal level
it's so close to
one another in terms of proximity
if you look at the buys of the cam
they're almost the same
i mean look at that i mean we have the
open on this candle and the clothes on
this candle since it's the same thing we
only have this one little wick so the
liquidity really is
above here
and in my opinion it's going to go above
this level here so that puts us around
that 75 70 to 75 80 level like we talked
about relative to that weekly chart
so by taking this information and
applying it to your charts
it helps you map out while you have
areas where yes this could happen we
could trade down here but if it did we
were buying we would be expecting to be
a buyer down there it may not happen
they may allow price to keep on going
and give you no real retracement but you
still had reference points to be
watching and monitoring going forward
this was the new down candle okay it's
going to be a bullish order block so
therefore we should not see this candle
give way if it trades through it it did
it traded above its high so now this has
become the support level this level is
where the banks are going to look to
defend it on the downside so any
movement into it like we see here
this candle trades into the body and
quickly rejects the next day it opens
trades down it hits the bodies i'm sorry
the candle
it's high it's 73 55 goes a little bit
below look at the low
73 52 it only went three pips below the
level we would be watching for and then
look at the aggressive move through it
trading in delivering price with a
bullish side of price buy side delivery
we had all down movement here between
74 34 and 73.80
prices moved
from
738-7434 yesterday
so having that
having that move from 7380 to 7434
it closed in that fair value gap that
we've we've been monitoring that
occurred in december 2016 and then
prices move through the mean threshold
it's obvious that we'll see
a move above that 75 25 level how much
further
like i said 75 80 looks likely
and if we do that we could really make a
run all the way up into uh
i'd say 76.50 so 76.50 is likely upside
objective if we get really rolling
higher but apart from that
uh that that was the uh the dna or
anatomy if you will of why the
australian dollar moved up why we were
expecting bullishness on it uh behind
the scenes
these higher time frame ideas that
you're learning you have to learn to
trust them on these monthly weekly and
daily in applying open interest to
levels that you would expect to see
bullishness in
every three months
okay and this is the last point and
we're going to close today's teaching
the point at which
these three month to four month moves
that take place every quarter there's a
major
shift in market structure
and while that may not undo the
long-term bullish or bearish moves
they are executable in a way where you
can make great deal of money you can
take a lot of money out of positions if
you're properly aligned
if you are not aware of these they will
take you by surprise and you're like
where'd this come from you know there's
you know
there's no worse feeling than
expecting a move to go
hard one direction and then see it do
something like this like for instance if
you're looking at this move here
and say you were a
fibonacci trader
not necessarily optimal trade entry but
say you were a fibonacci trader and you
saw the 50 level here there's a guy on
baby pips that makes a name for himself
on trading at 50 level
fibs and
i i use that as equilibrium but
you could be looking at that say okay
yeah and this day you would have
probably felt good about the whole idea
of being bearish on australian dollar
not
by what we've been talking about and we
mapped out very specific we even talked
about that very day being bullish
but in the retail mind
this whole day right here that would
look like okay well we have a double top
now
it's at a 50 level in the fib it's going
to go down and trade down below here or
i'll do i'll do an abcd type move and
i'll be looking for
70s on
the australian dollar that's retail
thinking we were not thinking that at
all we're mapping that candle out as a
reason to be a buyer
so the things you're learning is
completely diametrically opposed to
those things that you learn in the
retail world
and it's like that because we have to
capitalize on those ideas because those
things permeate large fund trading where
the buy stops where the cell stops it's
the same way human nature is going to
repeat itself every large fun trader
starts as a low end trader just like you
are right now just like i started
grassroots we all start from the same
place the beginning
no one becomes a large fun trader
managing billions and millions of
dollars
because you just felt like you want to
do it today try it try today if you're
successful today try to get a large fund
traders position by the end of the month
you can do that i'll send you one
million dollars through paypal
you have to do some things you got to
prove
you know you can trade okay and you have
to go through a lot of uh rick morrow if
you will if my if i can quote my
grandmother to get
to that that position
you have to prove yourself it doesn't
happen by accident so
if they are doing the very things they
did as a regular trader but they still
have to do things with guidelines okay
then
it's common sense that their stops are
going to be rate where everyone else is
going to be placing their stops but they
have a lot more money at risk
they have exposure that you don't have
you're trading micro lots and mini lots
and all these other things and i'm not
trying to disparage you or or you talk
down to you because i started the same
way i started with small stuff
but they don't see you you're not even a
blip on the radar screen but they do see
these large pending orders above old
highs and below lows in the last 60 days
in the last 40 days
in the last 20 days and once you find a
time marker where you can delineate when
there's a shift that has taken place or
when you cast forward 60 days at that
moment you know in the future 60 days
from that last market structure shift
quarterly you know that's a delineation
in the in the future so you can already
anticipate a significant move 20 days
from that one back from it which would
be
not 40 days
it would be
20 days back from that new
market uh delineation so for what i'm
saying is
by having these things on your chart
you'll be able to look backwards and
forwards and looking for the ranges just
like the ipta
algorithm will look for where the most
recent 20 day 40 day and 60 day stops
are
if they have been cleared out on both
sides of the marketplace
once they have been wiped out and we're
in equilibrium you have to look at where
the next range high and low is outside
of the last 20 i'm sorry last 60 days
that will tell you where the next big
significant move is going to be
and if you combine that with weekly and
monthly charts
it's almost like a no-brainer you just
have to wait for it to happen it takes
time for that to unfold and most of us
by human nature are not patient we're
impatient some of the folks that have
left this mentorship are classic
scenarios of that they're just impatient
they want to know it right away they
wanted to learn it all in one month you
know they stuck it out for the second
month the third month the fourth month
it was too much
i can't wait for it i gotta go okay i
gotta just gotta toss it in
and they'll be they'll regret the rest
of their life trust me they're gonna
regret it when they
look back they're going to feel like
they've missed the opportunity of a
lifetime and they have
what you're learning you're not going to
get that from anywhere else but it's
going to require you to work for it i'm
going to put your nose right where you
need to be focusing
but i cannot take away the lessons that
by studying it will give you that has to
happen by you doing it and if you can't
be here in the live sessions they're
recorded it's the same thing there's
nothing different by watching the
recording
when we leave january's content
we're gonna be applying all these things
so that way when you start looking at me
doing short term trading and weekly one
shot one kill setups and we go deeper
into the mentorship when we start going
back into intraday trading you'll see
all these things are the reasons why i'm
being a buyer or a seller in london open
or a buyer and seller in new york
session and why these levels i'm keying
off of and telling you everything that
you saw us doing in the september month
where we were nailing highs and lows
what the market was doing almost daily
all that was was me applying what i just
showed you in this teaching
i just didn't go through all the the
mechanics behind it all i just knew it
and applied it and just talked about it
just you know whatever this is what's
going on and it gives you a great deal
of confidence and for some of you it
will create an air of
arrogance don't let that become
don't let it define you but you
definitely will have a
level of confidence this goes through
the roof because you're going to know
with a great deal of
trust that the market is trying to get
to a level for a real reason
and it's being manipulated it's being
controlled it's being driven there it
has no
other way of
operating except for over time
price will
agree on a level that's arrived at what
ipda is seeking
last 60 days where's the high and the
low
last 40 days where's the high and the
last 20 days where's the high in the low
that's where your liquidity pools are
okay last 20 days where is the gaps
where are the gaps in the last 40 days
where is the gaps in the last 60 days
that's where all your fair value levels
are
think about it what's where's the
consolidations in the last 20 days the
last 40 days in the last 60 days that's
where your equilibrium price points are
going to be
when the market isn't going to move it's
going to gravitate and hang at those
levels
when you see me say i'm not doing it
today the market's going to be sideways
and you're all like well how did you
know that
this
what i just taught you today how to use
the data ranges house tells you what you
should be doing should you be expecting
range expansion on the upside
should you be expecting range expansion
on the downside that is directional bias
that's are you bullish today or are you
bearish today
if you are not in a range where it's
going to expand and you're hanging
around equilibrium in the last 20 days
the last 40 days and last 60 days in
other words what's that look like if you
go back 60 days and you see where price
has made a small little trading range
divide that range in half that's
equilibrium if your price right now
today is just hanging around and dollar
index is not trying to move it's
probably going to be a z day that means
it's going to go up a little bit down a
little bit and hang around the middle of
range
until it gets some kind of manipulation
what's going to cause that high impact
news which is the reason why i started
you in september looking at the high
impact and medium impact news events for
the week
draw those things together everything
that you've been exposed to so far for
the mentorship draw all those things
together
and apply the if the data ranges now
all of you are trying to over complicate
it and it's probably my fault because of
the way i taught it and believe me it's
a lot of things to digest
it's not simply 60 40 and 20 and
therefore everything unlocks you have to
use those ranges looking back and see
where the highs and lows are where the
gaps are where the fair value gaps are
where equilibrium is
and it'll tell you where the
institutional reference points are
it's up to you to execute on them when
they get to those levels based on what a
weekly chart and daily chart is
indicating bullishness for variousness
just because it goes above an old high
doesn't mean
it's a cell it could be
the confirmation is going to go to the
next buy stop level above it
that's the next stage of january's
content where we start building the
ideas of okay using a monthly and the
weekly and a daily chart nothing less
than that
what do we do what do we look for what's
the process what sets up the trades on
these time frames because if we can
identify and prove that this is what
goes on in price it does these types of
things that are repeating phenomenon
going back to our
algorithm idea and computer program
analogy
if the nose
simply by going back what's today's date
everybody knows what today's date is
it's january 12 2017.
the computer programmer can can gather
that information okay so what's 60 days
from that backwards in time okay then
the algorithm will simply say okay
what's the highest value of that asset
that it traded to okay right there so
now i need to go back up to that level
that's what it's going to do it's going
to go up there to allow
the bank traders to position themselves
once it gets close to that level then
the bank level and broker level
interventions and manipulations can come
in but the the broker is not going to
jump your spread 50 to 100 pips
the central bank has to get it in close
proximity to these levels then the lower
level manipulation that takes place in
broker level that's when that happens
but your broker is not killing you and
wiping you out with 50 pip swings that
doesn't happen it has to allow price to
be driven there and that's all central
bank level
so i threw a lot at you today children
uh hopefully uh i haven't confused any
of you hopefully uh i've given more
clarity um you're gonna see examples of
me actually using this information um
but i have to give it to you
conceptually first so that way i won't
be uh
inundated with a million questions about
why did you put a line here watch out
you'll know why i'm doing it because i
when i explain it
based on what i've talked about here and
what i've shown in the
lesson 101.1
for january it'll it'll start making
sense because we're not just going to do
this one time and never come back to it
we're going to be doing this throughout
the mentorship and
if you
i'm not saying you should but when i
start the signal service in the winter
of 2017
um
you'll know why i'm dealing with certain
signals then if you if you're able to
watch it some of you will probably
want just to see what you know what i'm
doing just to see how it lines up with
what you learn but the
the signals are all going to be based on
what you're seeing here
and it's
why they're going to be so good that's
why september was so powerful i had to
show you that yes we can read price it's
very predictable and if it's that
predictable on the short term then it
has to be that predictable in the higher
time frame
and you see now that it can be it's all
time and price
time
and price
time is
date on the higher time frame it's not
time of day it's date
calendar days
and they're calendar days that the
markets trade
so if we know there's a range of 20 40
and 60 days that the algorithm will look
back
then you know what high and loading
you'd be focusing on
if market structure is bearish
what does that tell you where's the loan
the last 20 days where's the loan last
40 days where's the loan last 60 days
that's where it's going to be reaching
for it's looking for that sell side
liquidity below those lows
what happens
if it has
two
lower lows that haven't been traded to
and it trades down below the one
in the last 20 days it takes that low
out and as a lower low
60 days in that range 60 days back
there's a low and you know that it's
possibly going to go down there but say
it doesn't go down there and it rejects
and it breaks market structure bullish
what does that tell you
you have a quarterly shift now it's
bullish [__] start finding the highs in
the last 20 days last 40 days and last
60 days and you'll know what if there's
dealing it's going to draw a price up to
them everyone else is going to be
looking at retail thinking okay this is
a trend it's downtrend they're going to
look for that old low 60 days out not
because they're doing what we're doing
but they're going to see classic support
resistance ideas and they hold on to it
they marry the idea it's getting going
down it's been going down so therefore
it must continuously keep going down and
they just watch the market grind against
them and all of a sudden we see what
we're seeing in the chart right now
australian dollar what happened
what happened
look look at the forums just for fun
today what happened with an australian
dollar
i haven't been there yet i'm just
prophesying
they're probably saying what happened
australian dollar
well you all know what's happened in the
australian dollar we talked about this
before the fact why it's trading here
why it went there
and now you know the mechanics behind
the scene what what led me to believe
that this 7434 was likely the mean
threshold was uh um
upside objective and
why this currency's a leadership
currency why'd i focus on this one why
why was i talking about this one and not
the new zealand dollar that's a study
for you this week as well
share that with me on
the forum show me what you discovered by
contrasting the price action just like
we just did here for aussie dollar do
the same thing with new zealand
do the same thing with euro
do it with the cable
you have to practice folks if you only
do the things i'm only showing you
you're cheating yourself of all kinds of
learning opportunity the time that you
have together
believe me you want to maximize it i
know some of you have businesses some of
you have family obligations and this is
a long-winded session but
you know we only have two of them a week
so suck it up
the uh
there's so much information i i
literally have 20 years of information
i'm trying to share with you and
it's a lot of information but this
information still has to be practiced
you have to implement it in your charts
you have to look for it you have to see
it in your charts if you're not going to
do that
this is going to be
it's not going to be enchanting for you
to be here
you're if you're wanting me to tell you
this is how it is and it's always going
to be this way and it doesn't require
you to look for it and study it
ain't going to work it's not going to
work
but you do have to do a little bit of
rolling up your sleeves get your nose in
the charts but i promise you
this is a guarantee
if you do the things i'm telling you to
do in this teaching and everything in
this month of january
it will give you every possible scenario
for any type of trader you want to be
and it will put you in the high odds
category you'll be in the upper five
percent you'll you will most likely be
on the right side and far less time be
offside on your trade
and that's what the higher time frame
whole idea is about because you're
trying to align yourself with smart
money everyone that's on youtube is
teaching smart money this is the market
maker i'm on a one-minute chart teaching
this by by the way they're not on a
one-minute chart
they're not even down there they don't
they don't even they're not looking at
that
they're looking at the orders on a daily
chart that's what they're looking at
that's what's driving price
and outside of that
it's a 15-minute time frame they're
looking for liquidity pools and and
ideas around a 15-minute time frame five
minute again they're not looking at that
but you can use a five-minute chart
to find where there's a most likely uh a
small little gap that would not appear
readily on a 15 or an hourly chart
so all these things dovetail nicely
but you won't appreciate that
dovetailing
until you start getting in there and
spending some time looking at price
that's already happened
some of you a large group of you are so
worried about that right edge tell me
what that right edge is telling you
michael
when that won't make sense to you
and you'll leave the mentorship
if i just gave you trades every day yeah
you'd make money
but when i'm done teaching and it's and
that's happening i'm done when i walk
away
you've made money but you didn't learn
how to trade
and that's a waste of time and money
you want to be focusing on what's
happened on that left side of that chart
because once you understand all that
it's going to repeat itself
because if in fact there is a smart
money entity and they are manipulating
and they are controlling things because
they're motivated by money and greed
they're not going to change their mo
their motive is going to be the same
thing going forward it's the same
business model every single day
it doesn't change
it's not going to stop working
the only thing is is
if you share it with people
number one
you're just making it common knowledge
and just you just don't want to do it
you don't want to do it not because it's
going to stop working
but because you just want to be a part
of that small group that is profitable
that is an elite that you know what
you're doing with your money you're not
gambling this is not
gambling
you're not rolling the dice you're
waiting for a scenario where those
individuals that control price
are in play their moving price and
you're on the same side as them by
default you have no other way except for
seeing positive
results
does that mean profitability maybe
if you're in a demo account you can't
make money on that
but you learn a positive response and
then therefore it teaches you this
worked let me try it again
wow this worked let me try it again why
do you think i tell you guys that it
takes a minimum of six months because if
you look at the things i teach you will
see at least one market structure shift
in that time period
you need to see one because once you
understand when it happens and you see
it unfolding
oh man the confidence level sends you
through the roof you're like oh man i
i'm never doing this again i'm never
working for somebody else again i'm
going to learn this business and i'm out
of here i'm done i need to do this the
rest of my life and your passion level
will go crazy
and you'll know what you're doing you
won't be just excited like a football
game fan you'll know what you're excited
about and why it's exciting because it's
consistent
it's over and over reoccurring it's
never deviating it's there all the time
very rarely do you hear these terms
taught and spoke about in textbooks you
know
there's always a risk there's always
this and it's always that the risk is
you reading it wrong but this is always
there in price
the problem is is that you're going to
let you as the trader steer you wrong
because you're going to look at
something you're going to get so
opinionated about something
higher time frame it's hard to change
directions a lot on that daily and
weekly chart
it's it's usually one direction for a
while
that's why you have to start there
because if you start on a lower time
frame you're changing your mind 20 times
inside of the day and i talked to some
people outside of our group they're
still in a free membership area to just
go on my tutorials and follow my youtube
channel
they send me charts all day long i can't
get to them i can't i can't keep up with
the emails coming in but they send me
their changed mind
you know here's here's what i'm doing
today in in cable i'm buying this and
then okay here's 20 minutes later today
okay i changed why i'm selling it they
change their mind again this is all
happening in two hours
that's somebody that has no idea what's
going on
no idea what's going on by having the
higher time frame premise by looking at
monthly weekly and daily charts focusing
on the daily chart this is what we're
doing with a daily chart we're framing
it like a bank does
no one's teaching you this they don't
give you the perspective okay from an
institutional vantage point where how
and why they're going to go to a
specific higher level
yes you can go back in time and look at
a chart and say okay here's an old logo
there's going to be sell side liquidity
here or sell stops here
all kinds of people on youtube that are
doing that now
and yeah it's great
but i'm telling you which low
and which high to go to
there's a specific phenomenon that
repeats itself over and over and over
again
and by having that as your
routine
every day you sit down your daily charts
okay where are we at in the current
range
where are we at with
respect to the lowest low and highest
high in the last 20 days the last 60
days in the last i'm sorry last 20 40
and 60 days
have we cleared both sides of the board
have we taken all the buy stops
in the last 60 days in the most highest
high have we rejected all that and
cleared out and back in the middle of
the range because what does that mean
you have to study are we at a large
larger longer term equilibrium where we
could stay sideways for a while or now
are we going to the sell side
looking for the lows outside the last 60
days range
having that and then start implementing
inter market analysis
that means you're going to start having
ideas from the commodity market
the equities market
bonds
all those things will start giving you
more information and it'll tell you
where the opportunities really are
that way even though we can be
specific and specialist about i'm a euro
trader
i'm like i'm a crude oil trader i'm a
gold trader
you do want to have some diversity by
having some exposure in other asset
classes because it gives you a great
deal of context about why you think your
market's going to go up or down or
doesn't move at all
canadian dollar is a
good example if if the crude oil markets
um
you know acting and behaving a certain
way the canadian dollar is going to have
a direct uh response to that
and when crude oil is not of any effect
in the canadian dollar you know will
move just like the other currencies will
but crude oil
has a great deal of influence over that
particular uh
currency canadian dollar
having inter market analysis and
relative strength analysis
together
and implying smt studies like the dollar
index
and
the interest rate stuff that i'm
teaching this month you'll have
very very little opinions
about what the higher time frames are
telling you and when you do that
you are in line with what the
institutions are doing because you're
not changing your mind every day this is
what's going to do i don't care if i see
two down days on a daily chart nothing's
changed it just means it's retracing
they're coming back for some more orders
to buy more
and that's when we go into discussions
about building in larger positions with
an underlying bullish move that's
already there we've already put in a
position that's bullish we're retracing
how do you add more to that where do you
add more to it and how do you protect
that position as well
and and
what do you do to scale out
do we ever hold for whole full positions
yeah
but you need to know all these things
you know by the end of this this month
to fully appreciate what we start
teaching in february march and april
because
they're going to repeat themselves and
as long as you have a general idea
of what is being taught in january
i mean if you're completely lost then
obviously you're gonna need to reach out
to me after the last lesson in january
but for the most part if you have a
general idea what i'm talking about when
we start applying it every single day we
sit down you'll see the data points i'm
looking at
you'll know exactly why i'm calling this
high being significant or this low being
significant or this gap
you know that that will make perfect
sense to you then
what order block am i looking at why why
this order block and that not that one
michael why'd you pick this swing high
michael not that swing hi michael
you just learned it today
there's a range i'm looking for
it's 20 days back 40 days back 60 days
back then i'm casting forward
and i know from that point on i know i
can have a nude look back point where i
can go 20 days 4 days 60 days back and
wait for those new highs and lows to
form that have not made its way into
price yet
when they form liquidity will build
above it or below it
based on what i see on the hard time
frame
i know what side the market's going to
reach for
when you do that same thing you're not
going to send me emails and text
messages and direct messages
do you think the um australian dollar is
going to go down today
i i think that the canadian dollar is
going to go down today what do you think
don't ask me what i think
if you're watching my videos and you're
in here don't ask me what i think the
whole point is
learn from what i'm teaching you and you
arrive at your own opinion and then when
you're wrong would you what did you do
wrong
don't avoid that that's a learning
opportunity
take that as a big opportunity center
stage make me a better trader what can i
do what did i what did i do wrong and
what did i see wrong there so i don't
repeat that same thing that's the
benefit of being in here
you need to go through the lab
experience go through the exercise okay
and make the mistakes now you want to do
those things right now when it won't
hurt you it won't hurt your development
it won't hurt your money it won't take
anything from you it will build you up
the folks that have left us they have
they have no concept of that they don't
want they don't want to wait around they
don't want to learn anything they want
to be spoon-fed
you are here to learn how to do what i
do
analyze the markets call the markets
from where they are right now and where
they're going to be at next
in between those two price points
there's opportunities and i'm going to
teach you how to take those
opportunities and manifest that in the
form of trades
keeping risk low
equity curves going higher and managing
risk all throughout the whole process
but you cannot get to that level
without some interaction on your part
and it may require you
to do things by watching videos like
this is a live session
you may be forced to do these things by
studying the recordings do not think
that this is not of any value because
it's a recording has no it has no basis
on that had no effect on it
staying committed
to the development process is hard it's
very very hard but i'm trusting that
what i'm showing you here
proves number one there is a
real routine on how why price goes to a
specific level
why it repeats why i tell you that it's
not going to stop working why i tell you
there's absolutely an algorithm that
controls price because it does things
that a computer program would naturally
do
because i learned to be a computer
programmer i went to school i have a
degree in computer science specializing
in information systems i know computer
programming
i know it so if
i look at this stuff and i wanted to
become a systems analyst when i was
going to school that was my job i wanted
to build the documentation stage so i
can sit down with the programmers and go
through them and if they had issues with
the coding i would help them
you know make this uh this process work
but i wasn't going to be the coder i
don't have the patience to do the coding
but when i started learning the
mechanics of what their
what the
price delivery does
i didn't think about it it just jumped
on my head
this is the computer program
this could be automated and by curiosity
i went home and looked in the charts and
said okay
if this is
possible i should see it in price
and here you go
it was right there
and i got nervous
and excited at the same time i was
laughing and crying at the same time
because i thought i literally hit the
lottery
like i had the winning lottery numbers
for the lotto every week going forward i
had it
every tumbler clicked it made perfect
sense i knew right away why i was wrong
on everything i lost money on
and i knew now going forward where's the
next setup going to be
why do i have to wait for it and when
will
what how much time will it take for it
to happen
when is it most likely to occur
where is that signal going to format
before it even gets to that price level
that's what this gives you
it gives you every bit of clarity that
you don't have right now
once you understand what you're doing
with it you'll have every bit of
understanding about why you're waiting
and sitting on your hands
see some of you say oh there's no set up
right now oh michael i don't hear that
because i want you to focus on what's
going on the price has to be
driven to a specific level then i can
tell you why this is what happened
we said it was going up we told you the
level is going to go up but why did it
go there you learned that today
going forward you want to be using these
tools to vapor frame the ideas that lead
to a trade setup
as you go through more of the material
small little pieces will start coming
clear things that you have questions
right now you need to not send them to
me in an email
be surprised by finding the answers in
the future lessons and in your own study
that's how you practice that's how you
develop as a trader
me giving you an answer
isn't going to always satisfy because
you're going to still come with 50 more
questions
i know that because it's the same thing
i encountered
when i think i needed to do something
about something and i scoured the
internet for it it created 50 more
questions well wait a minute now if i
came in with one
one little thing that i was unsure about
i go in i start looking for it and i get
the response and the answer to that but
then it created 20 000 different
scenarios that would create
a what if scenario well what if this and
what if that and that's the problem
every one of you are in that stage and
it's because you're overzealous and i i
appreciate that believe me i've been
there
but you also have to just take a little
bit of faith and trust the fact that
i've taught this before
you are not a guinea pig scenario i've
done this with groups of people and
individual bases as well
trust me i will get you where you want
to be at but you have to allow it to
happen but you also have to be a part of
it by practicing and looking for it
not looking for trades
looking for the things i'm telling you
the evidence that there is control
if they evidence control and price that
means that there's no reason for you not
to trust the things i'm telling you in
the future
if there's something i'm going to teach
you in the future and i'll say okay
refer to the if the data ranges this is
why this turtle soup false break below
or low is going to happen and we can be
a buyer down here
because if i start saying okay look
we're going to buy
tomorrow's
tomorrow we're going to buy today's low
oh i don't know about that because if we
sit in london and it starts diving 50
pips all in one candle
i guarantee you
85 or more not buying that day you're
not buying that low you're going to wait
for a bullish order block or an optimal
trade entry or you're going to wait for
it to move up 60 pips before you think
it's going to go up
you won't trust it and you've missed the
whole learning experience
you've got to go through the things i'm
putting you in front of to do those very
things pay attention what's being done
right now
i'm getting a thousand questions about
why they can't get to october content
right now i can't watch anything october
i can't i can't look at what's going on
in november why are you there
that stuff's there forever you have
access to that
focus right now on what's being taught
in january
i'm telling you it's a lot of stuff and
if you are wasting your time on things
that's already been taught to you and
it's already in recordings you can go
watch it any other time
pay attention more than any other month
closely to this one because i guarantee
you if there's any month you're gonna
have to come back to and study it's this
one
there's so much stuff in it it's dense
it's very very
vast you have no
easy way through this you've got to
grind through a lot of this material and
you're going to have to refer back to it
many times
and believe me you'll be back through
this whole month content multiple times
even when you complete the mentorship
and you're going to find stuff that you
didn't get the first time the 20th time
the 30th time
it's a lot of information it's two
decades worth of stuff
you want to be a big big time trader you
want to be consistently profitable it's
in this month you want to know when not
to trade and lose money it's in this
month you want to know how to frame a
trade before price ever gets there it's
in this month
you want to be a day trader it's in this
month short term trader this month too
you want a swing trader here
your options trader it's here
you want you want to be a trend trader
you want to be a breakout artist you
want to be a trader that sells options
rights options it's in here
you won't appreciate it until we get to
the supplementary teachings but
everything that leads to you being
effective doing those other things
stems from what you understand and being
taught in january here all the content
is being delivered
it's going to be a lot more than eight
lessons folks it's more it's sub
teachings inside of these major eight
topics
lots of it that's the reason why we're
not doing these live sessions and i'm
throwing an extra one in here today
by time because i want to encourage you
that what you're waiting for is exactly
what you're looking for
and believe me it's a lot of stuff and
you're probably gonna your head's gonna
hurt you're gonna have you're gonna feel
like man this is information overload
and i'm already pre-warning you this
month and i told you this of all the
other months in this mentorship this is
the one
it's a monster
it's tons of stuff and you're gonna have
to study you're going to have to study
in february we'll resume back to a very
standardized teaching model eight
lessons supportive
in nature and we'll be back to doing
more live sessions you know throughout
the week and then in march we'll be
obviously in live session on a daily
basis every monday through friday we'll
be back in live session but you got to
give me the time to give you this
information and still operate as the
mentor and answering emails and also
running it too i mean there's a lot of
stuff i have and i have a family
so permitting me the time to build the
lessons for you and change some of the
things because i all my notes are all
based on
like commodities and
indices so i have to change some things
and create some slides that relate to
foreign exchange because i'm
predominantly teaching to a crowd that's
come to me by way of fx
but and when it's um
it's necessary you'll hear me talk about
it where um
this is unique to a specific asset class
you know like we talked about today with
commodities the idea of having
the open interest in your study that is
only going to come by way of looking at
the futures market
so since we're forex traders it it
is important that you avail yourself
that information that's available to
everyone it's common knowledge it's free
you can go in and get it okay and
it's valuable it's a gold mine and
people that think they understand it
while they may have a little bit a
myopic view of of what one facet of it
does for you
what you learned today was the real
mechanics of what open interest does
it gives you the x-ray view of what the
real smart money activity is are they
really buying because if they're really
buying they're going to dump open
interest and it's going to drop 15 or
more and it's going to happen at a t
support level
if it's going to sell off and start
going lower and if that was a real
turtle soup cell
then that means prior to that turtle
soup cell they should have been a
massive increase over time with that
open interest going up and you saw that
in australian dollar
because open interest
high open interest indicates
them offering the sell side
they're only going to take part of that
if they know eventually they're going to
be able to sell that position off with
price being going lower
that's the only time open interest is
going to go up and they can do this on
long term trends
but it will shift every quarter they
have to fund themselves for allowing the
holding of that risk
now you're probably thinking okay well
michael if they're in control of price
what real what real risk is there
well
what happens when a rogue nation nukes
another nation
you're not thinking that are you but
that can happen
what would that do
what would that do if a nuclear bomb
gets dropped in any nation it's going to
freak everybody out uh oh we're in world
war iii bombs are dropping
when september 11th happened
boom markets are all over the place
anything can happen look at the brexit
look at donald trump
look what that did
there's risk okay but they take these
risky and uh opportunities and they
manipulate but they don't want to hold
on to something and not make money
so yeah why they will provide liquidity
and sell to the buyers that see price
trade higher for a period of time
every three months look at your charts
and see if they don't reset themselves
every three months it's there
it happens in s p
it happens in stocks it happens in
commodities it happens in bonds it
happens in forex it's there every three
to four months you'll see it it's there
and that's how they pay themselves
for holding on that risk offering the
liquidity for the sell side of it
providing the means for buyers to buy
currency
they will do
what we're discussing here quarterly
shifts
and you'll see evidence is that in open
interest
it will happen at points at which by
looking back 20 40 and 60 days where
those highs and lows are where those
gaps are where equilibrium is those
reference points in that time field okay
of 60 days is the maximum look back
it's simple and here's another study to
make it easy for you
just go back 60 days from every month
beginning
start every month it was an exercise
every single month a calendar month
put put a vertical line on at every new
month
go back 60 days find the highest high
and lowest low and you see if they don't
wipe that out you can take any pair
you can be the dollar index it could be
the
well look at the australian dollar
put a vertical line on every single
first trading day of every month
okay
don't do them all at one time so that
way your charts nice and crisp and clean
but put a vertical line at the beginning
of every month the first trading day of
every month okay and draw out a line
okay 60 days 60 trading days okay and
delineate that and then find the highest
high and the lowest low and then go
forward from the from to the right of
that and you see if they don't run those
uh buy stops and sell stops above above
that and do the same thing for 40 days
and do the same thing for 20 days
doing that study
that's exactly what i did the night that
i've seen how this works
that's all i did
i said okay
if i'm a data if i'm a computer
programmer i need to be able to
reference something how can they know
what the orders are
like how because in my mind how could
they see
lynne waldock's orders
because that's how i looked at it my my
perspective was
if what i'm learning
to do in the marketplace
to be a market maker i have to know
certain things
and what i was learning
if this is true
then i should see evidences of it in
price
and i couldn't wait to get home
i went home pulled out my charts and it
was a swiss franc chart
that was that was the actual chart i
opened up my
commodity price charts from
commodity trend service and i literally
turned the page and i literally
in seconds seen it
i said okay if i'm if i'm the computer
program and i'm going to be able to
reach up into aerial orders it can't i
can't know what every brokerage firm's
orders are
there's no way it's dynamic
think about it
you might have a trade on right now and
you might have a stop on
it may be there but something might
change and you collapse that trade
your order's not there anymore
every one of us are dynamic thinking
we may have an order there think about
what you did with your last trade how
many times did you meet your stop-loss
think about it you were long you you
moved your chair you shared your
stop-loss up okay and then you started
seeing a little retracement you're like
oh let me move that back and some of you
probably moved back further than it
first originated at you're dynamic so
your orders are always moving around and
that's why i say hey this is too much of
a variable
there's no way for them
to know every single book that's out
there
so how can you standardize it
the epiphany i had was
go back and go back to the same number
of days that i'm being taught to look
for
and just look for the high and low
that's where the buy stops are and
that's where the cell stops are
and there it was
it was like
solomon's mind just opened up all the
fort knox opened up everything happened
that moment a flood of emotions flood of
euphoria and fear like oh no did i just
do something i wasn't supposed to do did
i just learn something and see something
i wasn't supposed to that's how i felt
i had this big old textbook okay of
information i had to digest and i
literally didn't want to touch it
anymore because in my mind i had already
cracked it
i didn't want to go back
i did not want to sit with these people
and learn anything more than i had
already learned there
i went from that to the corn market in
commodities
it was there
soybeans live cattle pork bellies they
don't trade anymore
a silver
all the metals palladium platinum high
grade copper
cotton
lumber
orange juice
it's all there
once you see it you're never going to
forget it and you can't unsee it and
when you see these things that repeat
over and over again and they are they're
finite
you'll prove it to yourself in a in the
short little exercise like that
pull up a chart i don't care what asset
class it is define it look back the last
20 days last four days in the last 60
days where's the high and low where's
the liquidity voids where's the
fair value gaps and where's equilibrium
and you'll know exactly what price is
going to do on that right hand side of
your chart
it's going to move to those levels
now think in terms of overbought and
oversold
you will be able to define a range by
doing that
you don't need an indicator to tell you
if your overbought oversold look at the
highest level of liquidity
in the form of a high in the last 60
days and the lowest low last 60 days
that's your real overbought never sold
you don't need to you don't need an
indicator for that i've made fun of that
stuff in my free tutorials and on
youtube you know these guys talking
about diversity i don't need a
divergence i need to know where's the
range where am i in terms of
institutional overflow the real
institutional overflow the what i'm
talking about you don't hear this talk
chris lori is not teaching this stuff
okay online trading isn't teaching it
youtube guys on there they're not
teaching this
these are finite things unless you came
from where i came from you're not seeing
or learning or even knowing about this
stuff
it gets deeper than this
it gets more specific than
this this was just the beginning stages
of what i i'm taking you whether you
realize i'm taking you through the whole
process of how i became ict
the things i learned the way i learned
it the the process of how i got to it
it's what you're seeing here
one stage at a time
and how do i know it's like this because
i journal i've kept a journal for years
and i remember certain things because i
journal
i go back in time and look at certain
things i get to relive that moment
that's why i'm so passionate about
teaching you
even before i started charging
look how passionate i've always been
i've always been passionate because i
know what it was like for me to
experience it to go through the process
in that euphoric moment when i finally
got to what you're all aspiring to be
knowledgeable knowing exactly what
you're going to do with these candles on
your chart
what's this telling you what are you
going to do with this information
i'm making money with this
i'm building a business i'm building a
future for my family i'm building a
means of being able to build a legacy
for my family do they never have to be
supported to a employer
you're going to make your own way with
this information
and i'm interested in that i'm i'm
passionate about that
and when you do these things and you go
through the processes of things i'm
telling you to do with this month's
content doing these exercises
beyond the shadow of doubt it's going to
blow your mind
you're already here it's not a sales
pitch i don't need to sell anything to
you you're seeing it but you're not
really seeing it yet you haven't done
that yet
when you do
as soon as you do it i'm telling you the
form is going to light up you're going
to be oh you're going to be all over the
place you're going to be throwing up
char son sunday look at this it did it
here it did it here this is it then then
you are not gonna be able to sleep it's
gonna be like no doze forget about it
caffeine you won't need it you're gonna
be jumping around hopped up on goofballs
because you literally won't be able to
contain yourself because you know
exactly what you're looking for going
forward
that's exactly what traders want
you're asking for setups give me signals
no that's not what you want really break
it down you want to know what i know
you want to know when you are going to
take a trade because think about that's
ultimate control because if you know
where to find the next 20 30 50 60
trading opportunities
you don't have to trade today do you
contrast it to what you felt like this
morning before the session opened up
you're hoping i'll give you something
right now because you want to take a
trade
and it only comes because you don't know
anything right now
you don't know what you want to do
you want to focus on the common goal is
that this information is going to take
you to the understanding of knowing what
it is that you are going to do and when
you don't want to do it
to stop distracting yourself by going
through old content
don't even watch my free tutorials this
month just focus on this because believe
me it's a lot it's a lot of stuff
then and only then
start amplifying it you know by doing
the other stuff and the new things that
we teach in february going forward but
there's a lot of things that you need to
be paying attention to for this month if
you miss this
you're going to struggle the rest of the
mentorship
and i mean that
and if you don't stay it's because you
didn't take my words to heart right now
because you don't you're not you're not
trying to do it and guess what there's
no shame in that because if you don't
want to do the work what's required here
you're not going to make it in trading
regardless if we had everything i was
going to teach in this whole entire
mentorship
it's all between your ears it's going to
be the problem
so this is the dividing marker for many
of you if you can't submit to what's
required and that you have to do in
january
you might just hang it up
just you know forget about it don't
worry about it and you know go back to
watching free tutorials and youtube
videos and and then be content with that
and don't let it beat you up because you
have now arrived at that's the final
decision maker because if you're not
going to be organized if you're not
going to be disciplined to do the work
that's necessary you're never going to
trade
not in fine profitability it won't
happen it's not going to happen
you want
reality you want truth that's what this
is
you won't make money at all unless you
submit and do the things i'm gonna teach
you in january
everything
if you don't do these things
with one thousand percent of surety
you're wasting your time with me you're
wasting your money with me and you're
never going to be profitable with the
things that i teach it's not going to
happen you'll have hit and miss results
and you're going to undo everything
because you're going to just go nuts
you're going to just over trade trying
to get it all back and you don't need to
do any of those types of things
you can be very boring about it
and that's what you want you want to be
boring you want you want that same
feeling when you go to work
it's the same thing every day
same people every day that's what you
want your trading to be same thing i
know in 60 days looking back that's
where i need to be focusing on
last 40 days where that's what i need to
be focusing on last 20 days that's what
i need to be focusing on take that
information cast it forward
those levels cast it forward they're
going to be influential in the future
and there's going to be new levels that
create highers and lows 20 days going
forward
40 days going forward 60 days going
and by doing that you get a future level
to draw a vertical line on
and look back 20 40 and 60 days and if
you get an overlap
that's when the magic happens
and with that kids i'm going to close it
wish you a very good day and i will have
the recording up as soon as i'm humanly
possible can
i guess i do have to do another session
so this one might have to go on a little
bit later because i do want to do a live
recap another live recap but a recap of
today's price action and then i'll have
this one up afterwards so uh because it
takes a little bit more time for this
longer ones to compress
and
hopefully you guys found it insightful
i'm going to
wish you all a very good day
and good luck and good trading