okay folks welcome to the January 2017 ICT mentorship long-term analysis Lesson 1.1
we're teaching implementing Macro analysis and this teaching is Quarterly shifts and IPDA data ranges.
the Quarterly Market Shift
okay if there is an algorithm
if our belief is that there is a automated price delivery engine that takes care of providing efficiency in the delivery of price.
the efficiency of trading at every potential trading price available per asset.
we're going to be dealing specifically with Forex for this teaching.
but the effect of a Quarterly Market Shift is in Universal and all asset classes.
but I want to ask you a question just for a moment try to imagine the world as investing.
if it were all completely random, if the market in fact was random, how could anyone reasonably have an EDGE.
think about it.
Statistics, really what is it?
you're still counting the odds of something that's already happening,
and attributing that to some future unseen event.
So there's no guarantee that just if the markets were completely random,
if we had based our system,
if our analysis concepts are based on the effects of Randomness in the marketplace,
we're left with the conclusion that yes!
things may have happened 50 times as their last 60 times.
and therefore an EDGE could be a defined.
but that does not equate to future events that have not been seen yet.
that's the falsehood of teaching.
the idea that the markets are completely random.
if the markets were in fact completely random I myself would never have an interest in them.
because I would have no trust in the fact that there was any measure of prognostication that would fulfill a profitable condition as an outcome.
my belief is that the markets are 100 percent engineered.
they're absolutely controlled to the very pip in the Foreign Exchange Market.
I've proven many times in the past over many years how we can call specific price levels to the pip.
sometimes it varies a little bit. many times going right to the pip as an exit or a target.
and my opinion about that is, if I can do that multiple times throughout the year.
that in itself, regardless of what I believe, I'm going to be able to communicate to you from my understanding about the marketplace.
if I could do that to me that proves that there is in fact zero randomness to the marketplace.
because if it was randomness I could not be that precise about my forecasts.
and where I believe the market was going to go going to go.
if we understand and can agree that the markets do in fact have a element of control.
and this is in the form of a price engine algorithm at the Central Bank level.
they set the price. they allow the markets to move to a predefined range for the day.
for the most part are. sometimes that things may occur that they send the price outside of the predetermined range.
but for the most part the interbank price delivery algorithm or IPDA has data ranges that it works Within
and by understanding what those ranges are we can go into the marketplace with a pre determined idea where the algorithm will do its work, where is it pulling the information from, what dates what ranges and what specific highs and lows is the algorithm reaching to as a reference point.
that's what this teaching is going to talk about specifically today.
I want to remind you and I've talked just briefly about this in the free tutorial section as I was going through all of the teachings that I provided for the online community.
as it trades the Foreign Exchange Market I teach it there is a market structure shift that takes place every three to four months.
and for the most part that's Universal. doesn't apply just to the Foreign Exchange Market but it does apply to all asset classes.
this effect takes place because the market has to generate new interest.
it has to have a new sense of urgency a missed opportunity is a lost opportunity in many people's eyes as a Trader.
so the markets have a tendency to move around and gyrate around every 3 to 4 months.
what was true or what was seen as a directional movement in the marketplace over the last 2 or 3 months may not in fact be true for the next coming 2 to 3 or 4 months in Market Direction.
so I'm going to counsel you to always look at price on a Macro level.
it means a monthly weekly and daily timeframe and learn to anticipate intermediate price swings.
it doesn't matter if the market is predisposed to go up on a primary bullish Market or a primary down market,
you can still fare it out rather significant intermediate-term retracements in either strong uptrends or down trends.
if you understand this component you'll also be able to weather the Deep retracement sometimes in long-term position trading that is required.
you'll also understand that by understanding that there's intermediate-term retracements on these HTF levels.
and if you're a long-term position Trader as this month is aimed at teaching you.
also have no problem and no emotional commitment to not holding the position forever.
but in fact taking some of the position off waiting for that retracement.
and then going back in adding that same position you just took off or a portion of that position off,
your long-term position trade and then adding it back in to recapitalize on that further movement higher.
every 3 to 4 months there's going to be a change in Direction.
it may cause a consolidation or it may cause a retracement of whatever price swing has been unfolding up to that moment.
the fact that the market is in a primary uptrend or a downtrend that's going to be the whether or not the market has a deep retracement on a HTF basis or if it goes into consolidation.
if the market is in a strong uptrend many times you won't see much of a retracement but you will see consolidation or trading range form and they'll capitalize new long positions that way.
and then sometimes they'll take the market below a short-term low on a daily chart and then send it higher after that would be the extent of any kind of retracement.
but either way I want you to look at the marketplace there's always some intermediate-term play to trade on every 3 to 4 months on every asset class.
if the market you're looking at or studying is in a significant range-bound environment.
and look at a market that is potentially moving up to a new uptrend or downtrend stage in its PA.
by doing so it will also get you in line with potential long-term trends moving higher or lower respectively to what you would be seeing in your charts.
we're going to talk a lot about that this month but let's get into a little bit more nuts and bolts about how we can use if the data ranges and the Quarterly market shift.
obviously my view on the marketplace is if we can focus in on what the Smart-Money is doing with their money, how are they allocating funds, how are they moving into the marketplace.
if we can mimic those characteristics in our own trading, hopefully, the outcome should be we have high probability conditions when we look at Smart-Money accumulation for buy programs.
the buy program is when the market goes through a series of successive days sessions that are consecutive regardless of what timeframe it is.
you can see a buy program on a hourly chart. you can see a buy program on a 4 hour. chart you see a buy program on a daily. and or weekly or monthly.
but the trading timeframe that we're using for this month is primarily the daily chart.
so if we're going to be anticipating a buy program that means we're going to be expecting a series of UP-days and it could last as long as several months.
it doesn't have to be a few days.
but a few days up on the daily chart can still be considered a buy program.
if it's reaching for a measure of liquidity that would be above the recent market highs.
when we're looking for Smart-Money accumulation for buy programs what we're essentially expecting is manipulation in the Underlying vs. the Benchmark.
now what is the Underlying and what is the Benchmark?
what we're going to be looking at again specifically dealing with the Foreign Exchange market for this teaching.
but we will be talking about Commodities. we will be talking about stocks. and we'll be talking about interest rate markets as well.
in the same venue that we're teaching here but I want to keep the topics very concise about one asset class at a time to avoid any kind of confusion on you as a student.
but the manipulation of the Underlying.
the Underlying is what you're actually trading.
and the Benchmark is what you're measuring the potential manipulation or lack thereof.
for Smart-Money accumulation for a buy program on a daily chart the Benchmark is going to sometimes make a Lower-Low while the Underlying makes a Higher-Low.
this would indicate the strong buying pressure under the Underlying issue or in this case the currency that you're Trading
it's failing to make a Lower-Low whereas the Benchmark would be making a Lower-Low.
it's showing relative strength so therefore you would expect a measure of upside movement
another scenario where Smart-Money accumulation for buy programs would come in the way is.
the Underlying or the currency that you're trading makes a Lower-Low while the Benchmark makes a Lower-High.
and this is for Inverse-Correlated Benchmarks to currency and I'll give you an example.
for the point number 2 where it says Benchmark makes Lower-Low, Underlying makes Higher-Low.
in this case that statement could be true by saying the $DXY makes a Lower-Low while the $USDJPY makes a Higher-Low.
that would be an accumulation buy program.
the Underlying or currency that you're Trading makes a Lower-Low but the Benchmark makes a Lower-High.
in this case this would be true in the sense that if we were looking at say the GBPUSD makes a Lower-Low while the $DXY makes a Lower-High.
what that would indicate is while the dollar was failing to make a Higher-High in respect to making a Lower-Low in the GBPUSD.
it's indicating that the pound is actually going under an Old-Low to scoop up SSL.
so therefore we would anticipate a Turtle-Soup scenario on a daily chart.
Benchmark makes Higher-High Underlying makes Higher-Low.
in this case it's stating in a condition that would be the dollar making a Higher-High which would look like relative strength for the dollar.
but the Underlying or in this case we'll use the pound dollar makes a Higher-Low.
that pound dollar should have made a Lower-Low but it was unwilling to make that Lower-Low.
so therefore the Relative-Strength is in the buyside on pound vs. dollar and the dollar is actually going above an Old-High to take the buy stops above and on high.
and then reject we would look for a Turtle-Soup in the daily in that condition.
Smart-Money distribution for sell programs
we'll look at the 4 conditions we use for that.
again the manipulation in the Underlying vs. the Benchmark.
is what we're studying this is all relative to the Daily timeframe only nothing less than a daily chart
the Benchmark makes a Higher-High while the Underlying makes a Lower-High.
in this case that would be the dollar making a Higher-High while the Underlying or in this case it would be the USDJPY makes a Lower-High.
that would be a sell program we're showing heavy distribution in the USDJPY pair
Underlying makes a Higher-High while the Benchmark makes a Higher-Low.
this could be true in the sense that the GBPUSD makes a Higher-High while the $DXY makes a Higher-Low.
in this case what it's implying is for instance if the Underlying is the pound dollar and it makes a Higher-High.
it's reaching above an Old-High to get the BSL for a Turtle-Soup sell.
and the $DXY is actually failing to make a Lower-Low so the Underlying strength is in the $DXY
lastly for a sell program on the daily chart.
the Benchmark makes a Lower-Low while the Underlying makes a Lower-High.
in this case it would be the $DXY makes a Lower-Low while the pound dollar makes a Lower-High.
the $DXY making a Lower-Low while the pound making a Lower-High.
the pound dollar while making a Lower-High showing relative weakness while the Benchmark $DXY makes that Lower-Low it would look like the $DXY is breaking lower.
so therefore support broken is going to see continuation go lower.
but in fact what's actually happening is the $DXY would be breaking the previous low to accumulate all the sell stops below an Old-Low
while the pound dollar was unwilling to make a Higher-High because it's already booked enough shorts and it's heavily under distribution
we will be seeing heavy selling in the pound dollar based on the relative weakness
because it was failing to make a Higher-High while the $DXY made a Lower-Low.
all that said and it was probably a little bit confusing for you but I gave you some Replacements.
but the rules are as they were explained just a moment ago on the previous slide
but you can see everything set here we'll go through it briefly
Smart-Money accumulation for buy programs
we're specializing in the manipulation in the Underlying vs. the Benchmark
and that's seen in this sense that the $DXY makes a Lower-Low while the dollar Swiss
for example makes a Higher-Low that would be bullish for the dollar Swiss
euro dollar makes a Lower-Low while the $DXY makes a Lower-High that would be seen as bearishness for the dollar and the
bullishness for the euro dollar because it went below an Old-Low to scoop up the SSL and then you would see a rejection or a Turtle-Soup long
the $DXY makes a Higher-High and the euro dollar makes a Higher-Low
and that would be Relative-Strength for the euro dollar and the move above the old high on the $DXY would be a Turtle-Soup sell
after running the buy stops liquidity.
and the Smart-Money distribution for sell programs
again focusing on manipulation in the Underlying vs. the Benchmark
the $DXY makes a Higher-High at the same time the dollar Swiss would be making a Lower-High
that would be relative weakness in the dollar Swiss pair and the $DXY making a move of an Old-High
would be a run on buy stops for a dollar and then you would see rejection after that and looking for lower prices on $DXY
the $DXY and the dollar Swiss are Closely-Correlated and just like the dollar Swiss being close to Chloride to $DXY
so is dollar CAD when oil is not an issue and dollar yen is also Closely-Correlated to the $DXY
positively or Naturally-Correlated uh vs. the euro dollar in the dollar Index they're Inversely-Correlated
so that means whatever the euro dollar is doing the option seeing in the dollar Index and this third example for the
sell  program euro dollar makes a higher high while the $DXY makes a Higher-Low a Relative-Strength in the $DXY and Underlying weakness
should be expected after euro dollar takes that Old-High out running out to buy stops liquidity
and the daily chart should see lower prices in that condition $DXY makes a Lower-Low while the euro dollar makes a Lower-High
that's relative weakness in the euro dollar pair while the $DXY does in fact go below that Lower-Low
the dollar that's would be scooping up the SSL below an Old-Low and then rejection and trading higher on the $DXY thus pushing your dollar lower
okay but we're looking at here the $DXY is a monthly chart.
and what I did was outlined a full year January to January.
and I want you to take a look at the price swings in between all of these reference points vertically.
as you can see there's a couple different market shifts that take place.
and this is what it looks like if you have it set up on every 4 months vs. the last live being every 3 months.
and I'll give you an example of seeing it again.
this is your chart divided up on every 3 months and every 4 months.
and you can still see. it gives you a really good context of where the market structure is and what market shift should take place next.
this is that same $DXY that's viewed on a weekly timeframe.
and we're looking at every 4 months for Quarterly shifts.
and we're going to drop down into a daily chart.
you can see here we have the $DXY daily.
and what I did was again I'm only using calendars starts of each month here from one January to the following years January.
or in the case of this example the New Year 2017 that we're now in looking at 2016's January 1st to January 1st of 2017.
I want you to take a look at how many times the market shifts back and forth.
and how many price swings you see over the course of a full year.
I want a daily timeframe.
you're not getting a great deal of setups and unfortunately that's the reason why most people don't trade this timeframe.
but it is a timeframe that is supportive to all other disciplines of trading and I said this multiple times.
and I kind of belabor it here. but I want you to see how the market does in fact give us a very good Macro view of the marketplace.
where it gives us framework and structure to work within.
so that way we can trade on one side of the marketplace and focus primarily there.
all right let's deal with a little bit more detail about what is a Quarterly shift.
okay on your chart you're going to delineate with a vertical line on your calendar.
at the beginning of the year you're going to find or and if you're just now starting say you're watching this video
which you shouldn't be because everyone should be watching at the same time in January 2017 as part of this mentorship
but for those that are studying again watching this video and the mentorship and their access to the content
you may look at your charts and it may be May okay it could be 3 years from now
and you could do a whole new analysis by taking a look at the chart and putting a vertical line at the beginning of the most recent past month.
okay for instance we're in January right now you would put it on the first day of December
okay and you would do everything I'm about to explain to you here.
but to start it all to make it easy to explain everything I just used the January to the January Factor
and we're going to be viewing that as the anticipated Quarterly shift.
now we don't know that's going to be true but we're going to do some things to arrive at how we can calibrate that level and this is called the look back.
what you're going to be doing is you're
going to look back from your month of
study wherever that is in time
regardless of what when you start your
analysis the most recent past month okay
you want to be using that first trading
day of that month put a vertical line on
your chart and then from that point on
you're going to be looking back to the
left you're going to be looking back to
the left of that vertical line that you
place on your chart
60 trading days
40 trading days and 20 trading days now
why am I giving you those 3
parameters
the algorithm will reach back about
3 trading months worth of data
that's the average where it'll reach
back for now there's other times where
it will go into further ranges but for
now I'm just teaching you how to look
for the most Salient points of reference
on the daily chart
the 60 the 40 and the 20 trading days
left of the most recent calendar month
put your vertical line on that's
your beginning marker point and you're
going to delineate what 60 days to the
left of that is what 40 days to the left
of that is and what 20 days and they're
all trading days not calendar days
you're going to basically in those
ranges you're going to identify
institutional order flow what was the
market doing
60 days ago to now
or
instead of a vertical line of that most
recent month that's delineated in your
chart also to the left of that vertical
line you place on your chart
you're going to be looking back over
the 60 the 40 and the 20 past trading
days to the left of that past month
and you're going to look for recent
institutional reference points
I'm gonna look for an old price High
you're gonna look at old price low why
are you doing that you're looking for a
potential liquidity pool that would be
resting above it or if those highs have
a lot of Wicks you're going to be
looking for rejection blocks which would
be a move above the bodies of the
candles for a potential sell-off
or below an Old-Low that has long Wicks
on it you'd be looking for the bodies of
the candle to house some
sell  side liquidity below that for a
rejection block
or sell stops below an old blow if
there's not a whole lot of Wicks to the
lows that would be defined in the last
60 to 40 to 20 trading days
you'll be looking for bearish order
blocks pool shoulder blocks in the last
60 days and you're going to look
specifically around the last 60 around
40 in the last 20 days basically you're
looking back the last 3 trading
months
and you'll be looking for fair value
gaps and any liquidity voids as well
once you identify
over the last 60 trading days okay
you're using the previous
closed calendar month as your beginning
reference point again as an example
right now today it's January 6th 2017.
and if I were to use this method I would
look at December 1st 2016. my vertical
line would be on that calendar day and
then I would book 60 trading days to the
left of that on my chart I would look 40
trading days to the left of that and I
would look 20 trading days to the left
of that December 1st or whatever the
first trading day would be for December
2016.
and I'll be looking for over those 3
months where's the high and where's the
low if the market has been trading
higher I'm going to frame everything off
of the market low if it's been trading
lower I'm going to trade frame
everything off of the market High
so again I'll repeat that for you
you're looking back left
60 trading days at the maximum over
those last 60 trading days you're
determining what was the institutional
order flow over those last 3 months
was it trading higher collectively or
was it trading lower collectively
as a whole
sometimes you can look at it and it'll
be a rather large trading range and
that's okay still you'll be able to do
things with that as well but for now you
want to see what's more significant was
there a significant intermediate-term
price low formed in the last 60 trading
days to the left
or was it a significant intermediate
term high that formed whichever is true
and whichever is obvious to you then you
put your vertical line on that high or
that low
so now you're calibrating it to the
market structure that's in place right
now
once you do that what you're doing is
you're anchoring your vertical line to a
previous market structure shift
okay so let's go back to our daily chart
of the $DXY okay and this is
what we had earlier
in the presentation I had January 1st
2016 to January 1st 2017.
okay and I'm going to do what I just
explained to you
if we were looking at the market in
January 1st of 2016 we're going to
actually do
what I explained
just a moment ago and this is what we
end up at we would be moving to December
the first trading day there
vs. January 1st of 2016. so we moved
to the left
and we noted that high and we were using
the first calendar day of the month
and they're always using that reference
point to calibrate and begin because
again if our belief is the algorithm is
systematic it's methodical it's going to
work on data ranges and it's going to
use calendar dates and it has to
reference how far to look back because
it's a numerical reference point so now
we know how we can calibrate just like
the algorithm will will Define it in the
sense of every 3 months there is a
shift also in the last 3 months
where is the liquidity at and that's
essentially what we're going to be
talking specifically dealing with in the
next teaching with the open float but
for here to get to that understanding in
the next teaching I have to teach you
how to calibrate your market structure
so that way you can see where the market
is most likely going to reach for
so now we have our reference point on
our vertical line all the way to the
left the furthest most left vertical
line again delineated at December 1st
2015 and now we're anchored now we're
going to do the look back on that
vertical line we're going to be looking
at the range
that was created in the last 60 trading
days from that vertical line that we
adjusted and anchored at December 1st
2015.
over the last 60 trading days what we
saw is the market traded higher
from around October 2015 so it made an
interview and term low
the market traded up and created that
short-term or any term High
at December 1st or their balance in the
last 40 trading days to the left of that
December 1st 2015 delineation with that
vertical line we also see there was a
consolidation and then expanded again
once more time higher
in the last 20 trading days to the left
of that vertical line the market just
kept pressing higher so institution
order flow was bullish
so where is the liquidity at
it's going to be what
it's going to be below the marketplace
because the market has already traded
higher
that's this reference point here
right below that October low
the market trades lower after or to the
right of December 1st 2015. once the
market trades lower
in between this reference point once we
identified where the market structure
starts to break down that means a kilo
was broken and that kilo is seen
right here
any retracement higher or movement
higher at this moment we're going to be
anticipating a move lower because the
market has already been moving bullishly
we've seen a market structure break
lower
and now we're going to be anticipating a
potential move lower in the $DXY
it could be a consolidation sideways but
we're still expecting a measure of
bearishness in the $DXY post
December 2015.
the 60 to 40 and the 20 when we look back like this again we're focusing primarily on where has the market traded from
what was the institutional order flow at that point and at the this time we can see clearly between the October and November into December 2015 the market had been Trading bullishly
I don't care about the long long term Trend right now all we're doing is looking at Quarterly shifts and this
will give you a great deal context on
how you can
do a lot of different trading but it'll
help you frame your position trades
because without understanding this you
can't incorporate Trend to get yourself
on the right side of the marketplace
there are things that we're going to
teach in the content for January that
helps you get in sync with long-term
trends but for the most part I want you
to look at how the market shifts back
and forth both directions
the markets aren't always in big
long-term trends on the higher time
frame charts they may be in a larger
range
that larger range will be trends that
would look Dynamic on a hourly chart or
15 minute timeframe but on a higher
timeframe you're still within a
well-defined range
so by using this HTF daily
chart when we see the market structure
shift bearishly
we're expecting now the next 3
months
to be a potential correction
again the reference points that I asked
you to go into and look for were all the
things we taught in September which is
the order block bullish and bearish
fair value gaps liquidity voids
Old-Highs and Old-Lows
so we're anticipating a move back into
institutional reference points then
moving lower looking for that same event
to occur looking for lower level
institutional reference points in other
words price should be drawn down to a
logical level not randomness down to a
logical level from an Institutional
vantage point where we can see where
they would want to absorb liquidity or
engineer new liquidity into the
marketplace
so using this last 60 40 and 20
idea we want to look at how price in
those ranges what is it created well the
market has moved higher
so prior to December 1st 2015 the
marketplace had an Institutional order
flow that was moving bullishly
so that means as the market was moving
higher every short-term low is going to
have SSL or sell stops
below that
so in each one of these ranges what we
can do is Define the range find the low
and then we can note that as where all
of the sell  side liquidity is
now once you have your
vertical line calibrated to the most
recent market structure shift
and you've done the look back and you've
defined all of the liquidity reference
points on the 60 40 and 20 last trading
days to the left
and you identified institution order
flow and you referred to all the recent
institutional reference points that
we've identified in brief listing
now you're going to be doing the cast forward
okay the cast forward is when you look
ahead with the same parameters we use
when we look back
we're anticipating the next market shift
in 20 to 60 trading days again because
if we understand and we our belief is
the market will have a gyration a new
directional bias okay or a shift in
sentiment or as I call it a Quarterly shift
we cast forward 20 days to the right of
our vertical line when the last shift
was 40 days ago
in other words if we've seen a market
structure shift
after a vertical line was delineated if
we see the market shift
in the last 40 days to the left of where
we're at now
we cast forward 40 more days because
we're always using a reference point of
60 days
we cast forward 40 days
when the last shift was 20 days ago
again the common denominator is it's 60
days of range that we're always using
we do this until we reach the extreme of
the projected 3 month limit in other
words where there would be another
vertical line drawn on our chart or
capping 3 months
so what does that look like this is what
it looks like here
this is called the cast forward where we
have delineated a calendar first trading
day at 2015 December 1st as we did
moments ago
we have a 20-day range a 40-day range
and a 60-day range
added to the right of our
December 1st 2015 delineation or the
vertical line and now what we have is
a future
day range or a data range the algorithm
is going to anticipate
doing a shift in the marketplace in that
range between 60
and 20 days
if we've seen the market structure break
down
as we saw
a moments ago by delineating this low
here
then we're looking for a market move
going lower
to fill in a potential liquidity void
seen here
in the range of 60 days to the right of
our market structure shift delineation
that we have at December 1st 2015.
we expect a
setup on the daily chart essentially in
the next 60 days so that tells you a
time Horizons you could have to wait
sometimes as long as 60 trading days
now this is the reason why I'm not a
heavy positioned Trader because I don't
have the capacity to wait that long for
the next trade some of you that may be
perfect for you but for me personally it
doesn't fit my cup of tea but it doesn't
have to require you trading for that
entire duration you can use this to get
daily bias contacts you can get
short-term setups and you can get
long-term objectives where the market
should be moving over weeks and months
vs. limiting your scope on a
short-term intraday basis and marrying
those lower timeframes
now we're looking at the euro dollar in
the same way but obviously like we
mentioned earlier the U.S dollar is
going to be inversely related to the
euro dollar
if we're expecting bearishness on the
$DXY we would be expecting
bullishness on the euro dollar
so in the same way we're going to add 20
days to the right of our 2015 December
1st 40 days to the right of that
vertical line and then we're going to
add 60 days to the right of that line
and on mt4 what you're going to do is
you can just use a trend line
and anchor it to your vertical line
drive it out to the right and let go of
it for a little bit and click back on
the right end of it and drag it out some
more and you'll see the number that
gives you a range is pull that out until
you get to 20 to 40 into 60 and then
you'll have the delineations that would
be necessary to frame out how far the
IPDA data ranges go
I want you to see that the high formed
here
on the euro dollar look how it falls
directly right at the 60 day
if the data range
Nails it on the very high
now this is a daily chart folks okay so
think about what we're doing here we're
mapping out where the highest probable
time
when the time range should be
influential in when the setups occur now
we're going to have a lot of tools to
help us
move down into a lot more Precision even
with this timeframe but you have to
understand when the setups occur
again if it's something that's not
random and if it is in fact manipulated
and controlled there should be
characteristics that repeat themselves
and it should be measurable and we
should be able to see things repeat
themselves based on a criteria
the algorithm will seek to do something
in the first 20 days the first 40 days
and up to 60 days after the most recent
market structure shift we saw a high
form on the $DXY and expected
the market to move lower because it
broke its market structure bearishly
we can see the euro dollar made a low
here December 1st 2015 and price moved
higher breaking market structure
bullishly for it
in between
the vertical lines okay once you have
calibrated your market structure
on a Quarterly basis and we're assuming
back in back in 2015 December 1st that
we would have calibrated there now again
I'm going to give you this as a homework
because I want you to go through your
charts and do this very exercise and
you're going to see it's not form fitted
it's the same stuff that you can do in
your own charts don't just use what I'm
using here go into your charts and do
the very thing that I'm showing you here
assume that you started doing the
analysis in for instance July of 2016
and do the same thing okay and you'll
see it still helps you it'll give you
all the data points that you would be using
but if we see that we're expecting
bullishness on the part of the euro
dollar because the $DXY was
expected to go bearishly
after December 2015
that means all the way up into March
2016 we have a stance that the
bearishness in the dollar should bode
well for bullishness on the euro dollar
so between those 2 reference points
because we understand that December 1st
okay we go out forward 3 to 4
months we go as far as March 1st
and by having March 1st
defined as the beginning of the new
month out that far away we project
that
limit on the Quarterly range
in between December 1st and March 1st we
would be expecting a bullish signal to
form in the euro dollar and a bear
signal to form in the $DXY
getting back to what we mentioned
earlier about buy programs and sell
programs the scenario would be even
looking at a daily chart
there's going to be a
manipulation that takes place even on a
HTF daily let's go back to
the $DXY
okay do you see the highs
here
all these Highs are forming inside of
the data range
of 60 days to the right of the beginning
of December 2015.
so all of these highs in here
Higher-Higher-Higher-Higher
is seeing what after the market
structure break below this low here
all these retracements higher all that
did was close in this liquidity void
when this void closed in up here
inside of the data range of 60 days
we had to measure
is there all this Justified
by using a inversely related currency
like the euro dollar now we can go and
take a look at the lows that were
forming in the euro dollar
here's 20 days 40 days and 60 days to
the right of the delineation setting our
new marker for the Quarterly shift
look at the lows here
in the euro dollar
all the way up to the 60-day data range
the lows were higher in the euro dollar
so this was under what
accumulation
the Underlying which would be traded
because we don't trade the $DXY
we use it as a Benchmark the Underlying
is failing to make a Lower-Low again at
the same time
that the Benchmark is making higher
highs by all standards this looks like
bullishness every time a new high is
formed and it looks like it's trying to
go higher all it's doing is inching up
the clothes in this liquidity void that
reference point that we talked about at
the beginning of this teaching this is
what it's looking to close in it's
pressing higher
at the same time all this entire High
business is not being seen with lower
lows in the euro dollar and it's
occurring
in between
where we delineate the market structure
shift here we go out 3 months that
means there's going to be a move that
takes place in the next 3 months on
the daily chart we're looking for it to
happen within 60 days of a new calendar
month
if this data range will go out and
project that long
the 60-day delineation nails the very
high so you have a buy-in here
and it ends right here after closing in
this void
okay
so essentially what we're doing is we're
framing the market Quarterly
and it gives us a context to look at the
market modularly so we can take the
PA and really look inside of
it and look for setups instead of just
being lost in the whole
grand scheme of things looking at the
candles highs and lows and all that
business you have to understand there's
a the Rhythm
and there's a there's a method behind
how price is delivered even on a daily
chart like this every 3 months to
4 months there's going to be a shake
up in the market there's going to be a
sentiment shift there's going to be
a change in Trend okay there's going to
be excitement injected into the
marketplace to cause interest in a
specific asset class especially if it's
an asset class that's been dormant for a
while it hasn't been traded much they
tend to take those markets and shake
them up
so by looking the market and breaking it
down like this it gives us a great deal
of context it's specific it's measurable
it gives us a very clear indication of
what we're doing and how how long it
should take to form and then looking for
the signs to create these setups
you can see here at the lows we had a
market structure shift that was bullish
on the $DXY if we had these
highs in here taken out on the upside so
no highs were violated on the upside
prior to this High here on the daily so
institution order flow broke to
bullishness here because of the shift in
market structure
the market's trading lower here okay now
we have another divider okay at June
1st 2016.
so all you're doing is adding another
vertical line once you have one you go
out in time you add these individually
okay
now you can calibrate them as you see
fit based on what the market's doing but
I'm going to resist the temptation to
calibrate it based on this market
structure shift here because you could
do the same thing here once this market
structure breaks foolishly here
you can go back to May 1st and use that
as your delineation and then start going
20 days 40 days 60 days to the right of
it okay and then draw another vertical
line every 3 months or so and then
that will be the same thing to be
accomplished here but I want to keep
everything as it is here because I don't
want to do any more that's necessary to
teach this specific principle because
we're going to build on it as we go
through January's content
but I want you to take a look at what
this is done we have a low here
on the $DXY we have a low here
on the $DXY that's lower and
then we have another Lower-Low on the
$DXY after the market structure
has broken to the bullish side
so once we have an interruption in the
down move okay notice also it's been
essentially six months of down movement
on the dollar
that's about when you're going to see
the shake-up that takes place and
there's also going to be a seasonal
influence that we're going to talk about
in January as well but for this movement
here I want you to take a look at the
relationship of how the dollar makes
these Lower-Lows in here
let's go back to the euro dollar at the
same time let's see what was going on
around June of 2016 in the euro
well we're not seeing that Higher-High
that would be reasonably expected
as we saw Lower-Lows in dollar let's go
back again
we have Lower-Lows in the dollar
at the same time we should be seeing
Higher-Highs in the euro dollar
it's not happening we see a Higher-High
here but you have to look at every
institutional reference point we have an
Old-High back here
relatively this is not higher it's
actually lower this is a market that's
heavily being distributed
this market run up here is just a run on
BSL taking the buy stops
out on short players already and then
the market trades lower
in between the vertical lines to
delineate the next market shift
okay there's a Quarterly shift that
takes place every 3 or 4 months
and you can see that these
Smart-Money accumulation and
distribution programs are very easy to
see in PA but you have to
Define it in such a way where you now
look for it to occur
also notice and I'll leave this for your
own personal study
how many days away
to the right of this calendar start
that's just High form
I'll leave that for your personal study
I'll also counsel you to take a look at
this day right here
this is the election
okay even on the day of the election
there is
exactly out to 60 days
to the right of of here 60 days on the
empty mt4 platform now it's the very
very high that gives us the sell-off so
initially it opened up traded higher on
the euro dollar and rejected and traded
aggressively lower
this Higher-High
again here's the Old-High
this Higher-High is not being seen
with a Lower-Low in the $DXY
so dollars being accumulated the
Underlying strength is in dollar can't
go lower
and
the euro dollar only went higher to take
out the buy stops they're going to
reject that as
false strength which is suspect rally
and the price moved lower
as a result of it
so I want you to go through this notes this
is going to require you a lot of
thinking as that's why I said this month
is going to be a lot of information
that's why you have to have a video
recording every single day and they have
to be pre-recorded if I do any live
sessions this entire month of January
there's no way I have enough time in the
day and also live my own personal life
to be able to complete all the things
that's necessary to cover long-term
analysis and have it all encapsulated in
the first month of 2017 and then again
framework going forward
so go through the notes on this one again go through
your charts also using it as well and
again in summary all you're doing is
you're looking for a obvious break and
shift in the marketplace like this was
one here
okay the market trades higher and then
if we were looking at the market in
February
we could go back to January 1st and put
our marker there and then go out 20 days
40 days 60 days and you'd get something
here
we're looking back and see where the
liquidity is resting you're looking back
to find what liquidity is and you're
looking forward or to the right of it to
get the very next setup in terms of the
data range you're going to know how long
it takes potentially before the next
setup forms
and how far back you look for the
liquidity reference points for where the
stops are on the above or below the lows
and where the liquidity voids and gaps
are that you want to be referencing so
it gives you context and believe me
we're gonna have lots of examples of
this for January's content but for the
most part I want you to look at the
market in a Quarterly basis I want you
to be able to calibrate your market
shifts okay on a Quarterly basis how
it's being defined in this video and
regardless of where you're at in time
like for instance
say it was November 14 2016.
what month would you calibrate your
vertical line to to start
if you said October 1st 2016 you're
accurate you're correct if you said
anything other than that you're wrong
okay you want to go back to the previous
closed month you want to go back one
full calendar month where it traded from
the first trading day to the last
trading day and then created a new month
by doing that you calibrate yourself
that way you'll be able to see what it
is doing reference wise
and then you start walking forward from
there when you see an obvious change in
Trend which we saw up here we have a
market structure break here bearishly
for the Euro all this rallying up is
just another attempt to do what we saw
happening
in the dollar back here when it had a
market structure break bearishly it
traded higher up the closing the void
and then sold off
the same thing is just being seen here
market structure break here smart comes
up take out BSL and
Underlying weakness seen here
the heavy distribution and the market
goes lower as a result of it again we'll
talk more on this as we go through the
content throughout the year but
for January we'll touch more on this
because I'm quite sure while your gears
are turning now and you're probably
really excited about what you're seeing
some of you invariably are going to want
to send me emails I didn't understand
this I didn't understand that don't do
that yet hold off on sending emails and
wait and see if the content doesn't
answer your questions by the end of this
month
until the next video wish you good luck
and good Trading